<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000736A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000736A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000736A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000736A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000736A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000736A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000736A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000736A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000736A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000736A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000736</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893466</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05K001/03</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>174</class>
<subclass>255000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Arrangements to provide mechanical stiffening elements to a thin-core or coreless substrate</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ajit</given-name>
<middle-name>V.</middle-name>
<family-name>Sathe</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chandler</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ANTONELLI TERRY STOUT AND KRAUS</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>SUITE 1800</address-1>
<address-2>1300 NORTH SEVENTEENTH STREET</address-2>
<city>ARLINGTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22209</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In substrate packaging and mounting, such as for a flip chip mounted on a thin-core or coreless substrate, a high degree of rigidness and support is imparted to the substrate, to overcome bending/flexing/distortion during mounting/packaging of the chip and to prevent possible chip damage, by a stiffener. Such a stiffener may be of one or multiple pieces in any suitable shape/form to allow its non-interfering positioning on the substrate, and made by any suitable process of any suitable material, including conductive material and material capable of withstanding the temperatures of chip mounting/bonding operations. Such a stiffener prevents bending/flexing/distortion of thin-core and coreless substrate arrangements during mounting/interconnection processes to achieve thinner and more light-weight electronics specifically afforded by thin-core/coreless substrate arrangements while lowering manufacturing time/costs. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to arrangements to provide mechanical stiffening elements to a thin-core or coreless substrate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Mounting and packaging technologies of semiconductor circuits appear to be continuously in transition, with the continuing goals to achieve, for example, greater ease in mounting, lower manufacturing costs, more reliable mounting and packaging, and reduction in size and weight. Several mounting and packaging technologies which may emerge in the future are that of thin-core and coreless substrate packaging and mounting technologies. More specifically, there is significant drive from the mobile (e.g., notebooks, cellular phones and personal digital assistants (PDAs)) section of the electronics industry to achieve thinner and more light-weight electronics arrangements. Needed are mounting and packaging arrangements allowing thin-core and coreless substrate mounting and packaging technologies to be successfully implemented.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING(S) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The foregoing and a better understanding of the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description of example embodiments and the claims when read in connection with the accompanying drawings, all forming a part of the disclosure of this invention. While the foregoing and following written and illustrated disclosure focuses on disclosing example embodiments of the invention, it should be clearly understood that the same is by way of illustration and example only and that the invention is not limited thereto. The spirit and scope of the present invention are limited only by the terms of the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The following represent brief descriptions of the drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> relates to a perspective view of an example flip chip pin grid array (FC-PGA) system useful in explanation and understanding of background and example embodiments of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the example <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of the example <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a simplistic side view of the example <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a magnified partial cross-sectional view of a part of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA system as taken along the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> cross-sectional line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, such view being useful in explanation and understanding of background and example embodiments of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is another magnified, partial cross-sectional view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, but which illustrates an alternative example of a FC-PGA arrangement which has a thin-core substrate, and which has an example stiffener arrangement as one example embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is another magnified, partial cross-sectional view which shows another alternative example of a FC-PGA arrangement which has a coreless substrate, and which has an example edge stiffener arrangement as another example embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a simplified (without stiffener) cross-sectional view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> example FC-PGA thin-core substrate arrangement, or the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> example FC-PGA coreless substrate arrangement, with pressure applied thereto, resulting in disadvantageous bending/flexing distortion of the thin-core or coreless substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a perspective, partially-exploded view of an example FC-PGA system having an example stiffener arrangement according to one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a top view of the example <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> FC-PGA system, and showing a top view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> example stiffener; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a simplified cross-sectional view as taken along cross-sectional lines <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, such view being useful in illustrating the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> stiffener, and illustrating the improved rigidity or stiffening support of a thin-core or coreless substrate having the example stiffener of the present invention attached thereto; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a top view similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, but having an example multi-piece stiffener arrangement according to another example embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> likewise illustrates a top view having an example multi-piece stiffener arrangement according to another example embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> also likewise illustrates a top view having an example alternatively-shaped stiffener according to another example embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a perspective, partially-exploded view of another example FC-PGA system having an example edge stiffener arrangement of another example embodiment of the present invention being applied thereto; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a top view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> FC-PGA system after the example edge stiffener has been applied thereto; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, such view being useful in illustrating an example shape of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15 and 16</cross-reference> example edge stiffener. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Before beginning a detailed description of the subject invention, mention of the following is in order. When appropriate, like reference numerals and characters may be used to designate identical, corresponding or similar components in differing figure drawings. Further, in the detailed description to follow, example sizes/models/values/ranges may be given, although the present invention is not limited to the same. Further, the drawings may not be to accurate dimensional scale. Well-known power/ground connections to substrates, ICs and other components may not be shown in great detail within the FIGS. for simplicity of illustration and discussion, and so as not to obscure the invention. Further, arrangements may be shown in simplistic diagram form in order to avoid obscuring the invention, and also in view of the fact that specifics with respect to implementation of such diagram arrangements are highly dependent upon the platform within which the present invention is to be implemented, i.e., such specifics should be well within purview of one skilled in the art. Where specific details are set forth in order to describe example embodiments of the invention, it should be apparent to one skilled in the art that the invention can be practiced without, or with variation of, these specific details. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> While the following detailed description will describe example embodiments of the stiffener arrangements applied to thin-core substrates and coreless substrates in the context of an example flip chip (FC) pin grid array (PGA) arrangement (FC-PGA), practice of the present invention is not limited to such context, i.e., practice of the present invention may have uses with other types of chips and with other types of mounting and packaging technologies, e.g., flip chip ball grid array (FC-BGA). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Turning now to detailed description, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> relates to a perspective view of an example FC-PGA system useful in explanation and understanding of background and example embodiments of the present invention. More particularly, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates an integrated circuit (IC) printed circuit board (PCB) carrier package system, and more particularly, an example FC-PGA system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> formed of a substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> having a FC <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> mounted thereto, FC under-fill <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, pins <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, die side components (DSCs) <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, a plurality of exposed electrical interconnections <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and an indexing mark <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. The substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be, for example, a fiber-reinforced (FR) resin substrate, the FC <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be a solder-bumped FC die, and the under-fill <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> may be an epoxy under-fill. The pins <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> may be arranged in a PGA, and may be formed of copper alloy or Kovar material which is plated with nickel (Ni) and gold (Au). The die side components (DSCs) <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> are optional, and may be, for example, decoupling capacitors or resistors. In some industry embodiments, DSCs may be prohibited from a die side of the substrate. The exposed electrical interconnections <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> may be, for example, exposed laminate interconnections (described hereinafter). Finally, the indexing mark <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> may be a gold triangle, and serve as an index for, for example, a pin number <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The FC-PGA <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may further include (not shown) an integrated heat spreader (IHS) mounted on top of FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> through a thermal interface agent such as thermal grease or conductive epoxy. The IHS may be of any suitable size, and be made of any suitable material, for example, nickel-coated copper. A heat sink (not shown) may in turn be mounted on top of the IHS, or even directly on the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, again using a thermal agent. The FC-PGA arrangement is, in turn, insertable (indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>) into a socket <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of an electronic system <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> (e.g., a notebook computer, cell phone, PDA, etc.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Turning next to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, there is shown a bottom view of the example <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA substrate. More specifically, the bottom view <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> illustrates an example layout of a bottom (or pin) side PGA, pin side components (PSCs) <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> (e.g., decoupling capacitors and resistors), and also various industry dimensional notations (D, D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, G<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, G<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and H) not important to discussion of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of the example <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA substrate. More specifically, such top view <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> illustrates a die mounting area <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> as well as a FC under-fill area <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, and further shows various industry dimensional notations (B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and C<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) not important to discussion of the present invention, as well as DSC <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (in dashed-line form). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a simplistic side view of the example <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA substrate. More specifically, the simplistic side view <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> further includes various dimensional notations, with dimensional notations of interest including A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which represents a die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> (or die&plus;IHS) height above substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and A<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which represents a substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> thickness. Other dimensional notations (G<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and L) are not of interest to discussion of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Turning now to more detailed illustration and discussion of relevant constructions of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a magnified partial cross-sectional view of a part of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> FC-PGA system as taken along the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> cross-sectional line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, such view being useful in explanation and understanding of background and example embodiments of the present invention. More particularly, the magnified partial cross-sectional view <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> more clearly illustrates that the FC-PGA substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is a pinned, laminated printed circuit board (PCB) structure in the form of an organic structure including an internal core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> which may be, for example, a FR substrate formed of bismaleimide triazine (BT) resin reinforced with glass fiber, with a transition temperature (Tg) ranging from 165-175&deg; C. The core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> may typically be 0.7-0.8 mm in thickness, and further, may be surrounded by multi-laminate layers on both sides of the core. More particularly, die side laminate layers <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> may be provided on a die side of the core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>, whereas pin side laminate layers <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> may be provided on a pin side of the core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>. The multi-laminate layers generally contain additional power, ground and signaling interconnects <highlight><bold>517</bold></highlight>, for example, in the form of copper traces separated by dielectric layers, to provide electrical interconnections between the pins <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and the substrate lands <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> (which, in turn, interface with and electrically interconnect to the FC bumps <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> of the FC <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Further included as substrate interconnection structures are via holes <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> drilled through the core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> and/or the laminate layers <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>, and filled with electrically-conductive material to provide appropriate interlayer electric conduction paths. The FC <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is more clearly shown as having a FC under-fill <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> associated therewith for bonding and hermetic sealing, while PSCs <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> are more clearly shown as having a PSC under-fill <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> associated therewith for bonding and hermetic sealing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Whereas the internal core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> typically may be, for example, 0.7-0.8 mm in thickness, the laminate layers <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> may be, for example, constructed of a plurality of 15 &mgr;m copper interconnect laminate layers, and, for example, 30 &mgr;m dielectric laminate layers. Overall, a thickness dimension (A<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>; <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of the substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be, for example, in a thickness range of 1.0-1.2 mm. In contrast, the die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be, for example, in a thickness range of 0.6-0.9 mm, and typically may be 0.8 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> example thick core substrate arrangement is advantageous in that the thick core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> affords a high degree of rigidness or stiffness to the FC-PGA substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> such that, when the FC <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is mounted and interconnected to the substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> via high pressure and heat (i.e., a high temperature thermo-bonding process), the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> FC-PGA experiences no, or a negligible amount of, bending and flexing. Accordingly, the FC <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can be securely and reliably mounted and interconnected to the substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In contrast, the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> thick core substrate FC-PGA is disadvantageous in terms of thickness and weight. More specifically, as previously indicated, there is significant drive from the mobile (e.g., notebooks, cell phones and PDAs) section of the electronics industry to achieve thinner and more light-weight electronics arrangements, and accordingly, there is interest in developing thin-core and coreless substrate arrangements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> More specifically, turning first to an illustration and discussion of a thin-core substrate arrangement, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is another magnified, partial cross-sectional view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, but which illustrates an alternative example of a FC-PGA arrangement which has a thin-core substrate, and which has an example stiffener arrangement as one example embodiment of the present invention. Only differences between <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference> will be discussed for the sake of brevity. That is, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates an arrangement <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>, including a substrate <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> composed of a thin-core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>&prime; which may be in a thickness range of, for example, 0.1-0.5 mm, and more specifically, 0.4 mm, for example. The thin-core <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>&prime; may be constructed of FR substrate materials as previously discussed, or alternatively, may be of differing materials affording an even higher degree of rigidity. A remainder of the construction is substantially the same as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> likewise including die side laminate layers <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>&prime;, pin side laminate layers <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>&prime;, laminate interconnections <highlight><bold>517</bold></highlight>&prime;, vias <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>&prime;, and substrate lands <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight>&prime;. In comparing the background <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> arrangement having the thick core substrate of the example 0.8 mm core thickness, note that the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> arrangement having the thin-core substrate of the example 0.4 mm core thickness results in a thickness savings of approximately 0.4 mm, as well as a corresponding weight savings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Turning next to description of a coreless substrate arrangement, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is another magnified, partial cross-sectional view which shows another alternative example of a FC-PGA arrangement which has a coreless substrate, and which has an example edge stiffener arrangement as another example embodiment of the present invention. More specifically, the arrangement <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> includes a substrate <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight> in which the core has been omitted, such that the substrate <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight> corresponds only to a combination of the die side laminate layers <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>&Prime; and pin side laminate layers <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>&Prime;. In comparing again with the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> arrangement, note that the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> coreless substrate arrangement results in an even greater thickness savings of approximately 0.8 mm, and again, substantial weight savings. Again, the various laminate copper interconnect layers and dielectric layers <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>&Prime;, <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>&Prime;, laminate interconnections <highlight><bold>517</bold></highlight>&Prime;, vias <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>&Prime; and lands <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight>&Prime; may be as previously discussed, or alternatively, may be of differing materials affording an even higher degree of rigidity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As thin-core/coreless substrate technologies are in their infancy or even just conceptual, the thin-core/coreless substrate arrangements pose significant technical challenges with respect to mechanical strength for pinning, assembly, handling during testing, socket engagement, etc. More particularly, discussion now turns to special considerations required with respect to the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> thin-core substrate arrangement, and the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> coreless substrate arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> More particularly, attention turns to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, which is a simplified (without stiffener) cross-sectional view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> example FC-PGA thin-core substrate arrangement, or the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> example FC-PGA coreless substrate arrangement, with pressure applied thereto. More specifically, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a side view <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> thin-core substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime; or <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> coreless substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&Prime; having pressure <highlight><bold>805</bold></highlight> applied thereto, e.g., for the purpose of FC pressure/high temperature mounting and interconnecting. Due to the reduced rigidity or stiffness, the result is disadvantageous bending/flexing distortion of the thin-core or coreless substrate. That is, as shown in exaggerated form in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the thin-core/coreless substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&Prime; experiences substantial bending or flexing distortion upon pressure application. That is, the thin-core/coreless substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&Prime; does not have sufficient rigidity as does the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> thick core substrate arrangement. The bending or flexing distortion is disadvantageous in a significant number of ways. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> More particularly, first, the bending or flexing may result in unequal pressure distribution and stresses applied across the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and thus a very distinct possibility is FC die cracking. Second, the excessive bending or flexing distortion may prevent or break critical electrical bonding and interconnection between various ones of the FC-bump-<highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>/substrate-lands-<highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> pairs. Another distinct possibility is that excessive bending or flexing distortion may cause inter-laminations of the laminate layers <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>&Prime;, <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>&Prime; to experience laminate separation, which may in turn result in critical electrical interconnect disruption within the laminate layers, and even total de-lamination. A further distinct possibility of excessive bending or flexing is that it may cause cracking or improper under-fill seating of either or both of the DSC under-fill <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> or PSC under-fill <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>, leading to an imperfect bonding and/or hermetic seal (which may later cause problems due to moisture contamination). Still a further possibility is a major grid misalignment between respective pins within the PGA, such being shown in exaggerated form within <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. Any PGA pin misalignment would require an end user to do the difficult, if not impossible, task of realigning a multitude (e.g., many tens) of pins within the PGA so as to allow the FC-PGA arrangement to be mounted to another interfacing component (e.g., a zero insertion force (ZIF) socket <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>)). Last but not least, excessive bending/flexing may result in partial or total DSC and/or PSC de-lamination, resulting in separation and detachment from the substrate <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight>. Even after FC bonding, pressure exerted to the arrangement, e.g., during socket mounting or heat sink mounting, may likewise result in the excessive bending/flexing distortion, and accompanying problems, and may even result in further problems (e.g., metallic heat sink tilt/slippage resulting in contact and short-circuiting of the exposed electrical interconnections <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Discussion turns now to example embodiments useful in overcoming any excessive bending or flexing distortion. More particularly, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a perspective, partially-exploded view of an example FC-PGA system having an example stiffener arrangement according to one embodiment of the present invention. More specifically, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates a stiffened arrangement <highlight><bold>900</bold></highlight> in partial exploded view, and including an example stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> located on a major die-side plane of the substrate. The stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> may be of a windowed, rectangular shape, and may be formed of any material providing a desired degree of stiffness or rigidity to the thin-core/coreless substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime;, a non-exhaustive listing of suitable materials includes metal, plastic, glass-like materials and ceramics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As to formation, the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> may be formed through any well-known process, for example, a non-exhaustive listing of suitable processes includes molding, stamping, etching, extruding and deposition. As a further advantageous arrangement, the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> may be made of a suitable material capable of withstanding elevated temperatures, which may be experienced during a FC mounting/bonding operation, or during normal chip operating. As but one example of a suitable material, a thermoset plastic is advantageous as a stiffener in that elevated temperatures only serve to further set and strengthen such plastic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> As an additional advantageous arrangement, the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> may have adequate clearance such that it does not interfere with other FC-PGA components, such as the die, under-fill, and DSCs. Still further, while the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> may be made of a non-conductive or conductive material, if conductive, special precautions may be necessary. More particularly, an insulator material <highlight><bold>992</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>), such as an insulator gasket, may be inserted between the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> and substrate <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight> whenever desired to prevent the conductive stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> from short-circuiting any exposed electrical interconnections <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> which may cause erroneous operation of, or damage to, the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. That is, for FC-PGA arrangements, electrically conductive surfaces such as any electrically conductive stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> or metal heat sink (not shown) should not touch any part of any exposed electrical interconnections, pins, DSCs, etc., on either the die or pin side of the FC-PGA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Turning now to further relevant discussions, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a top view of the example <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> FC-PGA system, and showing a top view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> example stiffener. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a simplified cross-sectional view as taken along cross-sectional lines <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, such view being useful in illustrating the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> stiffener, and illustrating the improved rigidity of a thin-core or coreless substrate having the example stiffener of the present invention attached thereto. With regard to further detail, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates a pressure <highlight><bold>805</bold></highlight> (such as a FC mounting/connecting pressure) being applied to a thin-core substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime; arrangement or a coreless substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&Prime; arrangement having the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> thereon. As shown within <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> provides enhanced rigidity such that the substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&Prime; does not experience substantial bending or flexing distortion. Thus, the luxury of a thinner, lighter-weight device is achieved through use of the addition of a stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Further relevant <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> discussions should be noted. More particularly, dimensional notations illustrate A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is an effective die arrangement height above the substrate, and A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> represents a stiffener height above the substrate. With regard to the die arrangement height A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, if an IHS is not to be included within the arrangement, then the dimension A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> simply represents a die height above the substrate. In contrast, if an IHS is to be included within the arrangement, then Al may represent a combined height of the die and the IHS above the substrate. As one example advantageous embodiment, the stiffener height A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be equal or less than in height than A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. More particularly, as mentioned previously, an important goal of the thin-core or coreless substrate arrangements is a reduction in the overall thickness of the FC-PGA arrangement. Any height of A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> which extends above A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> disadvantageously adds to an overall thickness of the FC-PGA arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A situation where A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is substantially equal to A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> also may provide additional advantages. More particularly, with equal height, any heat sink arrangement (not shown) which is placed on top of the FC-PGA arrangement will contact both the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight>, such that a load of the heat sink is more equally distributed across a broader and more dispersed area, thus reducing the potential for heat-sink-induced damage to the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. As a further advantage, contacting of the heat sink with all of the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> results in a situation where the heat sink is prevented from tilting/shifting such that excessive edge pressure to an edge of the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is avoided, thereby again reducing the potential for damage to the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Still further, by the heat sink contacting all of the FC die <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight>, a rigidity of the heat sink may be transferred to the thin-core or coreless substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&Prime; so as to further enhance a rigidity thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Discussion turns next to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, which is a top view similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, but having an example multi-piece stiffener arrangement according to another example embodiment of the present invention. More particularly, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates a stiffener provided via a plurality of stiffener parts <highlight><bold>1290</bold></highlight> which may, for example, be in the form of simple rectangles. One aspect to note with respect to comparison of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is that, whereas the stiffener <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> provides enhanced stiffness in a plurality of directions (e.g., bi-directionally), the stiffeners <highlight><bold>1290</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> provide enhanced stiffness in substantially a single direction (e.g., uni-directionally). Such example embodiment may be advantageous to use (for weight and material savings) in situations where FC-PGA arrangements only need uni-directional stiffening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Continuing, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> likewise illustrates a top view having an example multi-piece stiffener arrangement according to another example embodiment of the present invention, while <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> also likewise illustrates a top view having an example alternatively-shaped stiffener according to another example embodiment of the present invention. That is, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> shows an example arrangement having example corner stiffeners <highlight><bold>1390</bold></highlight> providing selective stiffening, whereas <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is illustrative of the fact that any regular or non-regular geometric shape <highlight><bold>1490</bold></highlight> is suitable for the stiffener embodiments of the present invention. More specifically, practice of the stiffeners of the present invention may require only the minimum of the stiffener providing a sufficient level of stiffness to avoid excessive FC-PGA bending or flexing distortions, and that the stiffener not interfere with any other FC-PGA components. At this point in time, it should be mentioned that some predetermined degree of flexing/bending distortion may be acceptable with respect to any given FC-PGA arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective, partially-exploded view of another example FC-PGA system having an example edge stiffener arrangement of another example embodiment of the present invention being applied thereto another alternative embodiment of the present invention. More specifically, illustrated as arrangement <highlight><bold>1500</bold></highlight> are edge stiffener components <highlight><bold>1590</bold></highlight> aligned for application to the FC-PGA, with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> illustrating such edge stiffener components already applied to the FC-PGA. With regard to construction, the edge stiffener components may simply be flat, or more advantageously, may be of a generally C-shaped cross-section <highlight><bold>1590</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>), which is adapted to mate with the edge of the substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&Prime;, as is illustrated on a left-hand side of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> edge stiffener component arrangements are advantageous in that a high level of stiffening may be provided owing to the vertical sides and C-shaped cross-section. Accordingly, such edge stiffener components may be made of a thinner material. Such FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> stiffener arrangements are, however, disadvantageous in that the edge stiffener components are more difficult to manufacture, much harder to mount to a FC-PGA, and the substrate <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>&Prime; thickness must be more tightly controlled so as to fit properly within the internal channel of the edge stiffening component <highlight><bold>1590</bold></highlight>. In closing, all prior discussions are equally applicable to the example edge stiffener embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> While it is envisioned that the stiffeners of the present invention may be added to thin-core or coreless substrates after the substrates are received from manufacturers, it is envisioned that it may be more advantageous to receive thin-core or coreless substrates from manufactures having the stiffeners pre-attached thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In addition to all of the above advantages, the stiffened thin-core/coreless substrate FC-PGA arrangements of the present invention may have the further advantage of reducing packaging parameters (e.g., inductance, resistance, etc.) owing to the thinner size and reduced electrical interconnection lengths. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In concluding, reference in the specification to &ldquo;one embodiment &rdquo;, &ldquo;an embodiment &rdquo;, &ldquo;example embodiment &rdquo;, etc., means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic described in connection with the embodiment is included in at least one embodiment of the invention. The appearances of such phrases in various places in the specification are not necessarily all referring to the same embodiment. Further, when a particular feature, structure, or characteristic is described in connection with any embodiment, it is submitted that it is within the purview of one skilled in the art to effect such feature, structure, or characteristic in connection with other ones of the embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> This concludes the description of the example embodiments. Although the present invention has been described with reference to a number of illustrative embodiments thereof, it should be understood that numerous other modifications and embodiments can be devised by those skilled in the art that will fall within the spirit and scope of the principles of this invention. More particularly, reasonable variations and modifications are possible in the component parts and/or arrangements of the subject combination arrangement within the scope of the foregoing disclosure, the drawings and the appended claims without departing from the spirit of the invention. In addition to variations and modifications in the component parts and/or arrangements, alternative uses will also be apparent to those skilled in the art.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A stiffener to provide stiffening support to one of a thin-core and coreless substrate of an integrated circuit printed circuit board (IC-PCB) carrier package. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the IC-PCB carrier package being one of a flip chip pin grid array (FC-PGA) and a flip chip ball grid array (FC-BGA) carrier package. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener is substantially made of at least one of a metal-like, plastic-like, glass-like and ceramic-like material, is one of a molded, stamped, etched, extruded and deposited stiffener, and is capable of withstanding high temperatures of at least one of an IC die bonding operation and normal IC operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being planar for mounting to a die-side major planar surface of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having an internal window therein to provide clearance for at least one of a die, under-fill, die side components (DSC), and integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being a multi-part stiffener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having an above-substrate-plane height when mounted, which is less-than or equal to an above-substrate-plane height, when mounted, of one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having a top surface above a substrate-plane when mounted, which is substantially co-planar with, when mounted, a top surface of one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being adapted to co-support a heat sink, with one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, where if a main body of the stiffener is electrically conductive, the stiffener further includes an insulator to electrically insulate electrical members on stiffener-opposing areas of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being an edge stiffener for mounting to minor-planar side-surfaces of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, the edge stiffener having a non-flat cross section which is adapted to mate with the side-surfaces of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A stiffener as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, where the edge stiffener is adapted to be pre-attached to the substrate by an IC-PCB carrier package manufacturer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A thin-core or coreless integrated circuit printed circuit board (IC-PCB) carrier package comprising: a stiffener to provide stiffening support to one of a thin-core and coreless substrate of the IC-PCB carrier package. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, the IC-PCB carrier package being one of a flip chip pin grid array (FC-PGA) and a flip chip ball grid array (FC-BGA) carrier package. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, where the stiffener is substantially made of at least one of a metal-like, plastic-like, glass-like and ceramic-like material, is one of a molded, stamped, etched, extruded and deposited stiffener, and is capable of withstanding high temperatures of at least one of an IC die bonding operation and normal IC operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being planar and mounted to a die-side major planar surface of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having an internal window therein to provide clearance for at least one of a die, under-fill, die side components (DSC), and integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being a multi-part stiffener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having an above-substrate-plane height, which is less-than or equal to an above-substrate-plane height, when mounted, of one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having a top surface above a substrate-plane, which is substantially co-planar with, when mounted, a top surface of one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being adapted to co-support a heat sink, with one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, where if a main body of the stiffener is electrically conductive, the stiffener further includes an insulator to electrically insulate electrical members on stiffener-opposing areas of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being an edge stiffener mounted to minor-planar side-surfaces of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, the edge stiffener having a non-flat cross section which is mated with the side-surfaces of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An IC-PCB carrier package as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, where the edge stiffener is pre-attached to the substrate by an IC-PCB carrier package manufacturer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A packaged integrated circuit (IC) comprising: 
<claim-text>a thin-core or coreless integrated circuit printed circuit board (IC-PCB) carrier package comprising a stiffener to provide stiffening support to one of a thin-core and coreless substrate of the IC-PCB carrier package. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, the IC-PCB carrier package being one of a flip chip pin grid array (FC-PGA) and a flip chip ball grid array (FC-BGA) carrier package. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, where the stiffener is substantially made of at least one of a metal-like, plastic-like, glass-like and ceramic-like material, is one of a molded, stamped, etched, extruded and deposited stiffener, and is capable of withstanding high temperatures of at least one of an IC die bonding operation and normal IC operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being planar and mounted to a die-side major planar surface of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having an internal window therein to provide clearance for at least one of a die, under-fill, die side components (DSC), and integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being a multi-part stiffener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having an above-substrate-plane height, which is less-than or equal to an above-substrate-plane height, when mounted, of one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener having a top surface above a substrate-plane, which is substantially co-planar with, when mounted, a top surface of one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being adapted to co-support a heat sink, with one of: an IC-die, and a combination of an IC-die with an integrated heat spreader (IHS). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, where if a main body of the stiffener is electrically conductive, the stiffener further includes an insulator to electrically insulate electrical members on stiffener-opposing areas of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, the stiffener being an edge stiffener mounted to minor-planar side-surfaces of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, the edge stiffener having a non-flat cross section which is mated with the side-surfaces of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A packaged IC as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, where the edge stiffener is pre-attached to the substrate by an IC-PCB carrier package manufacturer.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>9</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000736A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000736A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000736A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000736A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000736A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
