<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003852A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003852A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003852A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003852A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003852A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003852A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003852A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003852A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003852A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003852A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003852A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003852A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003852A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003852A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003852A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003852A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003852</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894567</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B24B001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B24B007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>451</class>
<subclass>056000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>451</class>
<subclass>063000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>451</class>
<subclass>072000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>451</class>
<subclass>339000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and method for polishing multiple semiconductor wafers in parallel</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>In</given-name>
<middle-name>Kwon</middle-name>
<family-name>Jeong</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Wilson &amp; Ham</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PMB: 348 2530 Berryessa Road</address-1>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95132</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) apparatus and method for polishing semiconductor wafers utilizes multiple wafer carriers to polish a corresponding number of semiconductor wafers on a single polishing pad in parallel. In one embodiment, the wafer carriers are used to transfer semiconductor wafers between one or more wafer transfer stations and the polishing pad. In other embodiments, one or more wafer transfer arms are used to transfer the semiconductor wafers between the wafer transfer station(s) and the wafer carriers. The CMP apparatus is configured to sequentially process semiconductor wafers to increase the throughput of the apparatus. In addition, the components of the CMP apparatus are arranged such that the footprint of the apparatus is minimized. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates generally to chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) systems, and more particularly to an apparatus and method for chemically and mechanically polishing multiple semiconductor wafers on a single polishing pad. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> During a fabrication process of a high density multi-layered semiconductor device, one of the most important processing steps is planarizing a layer of a semiconductor wafer by removing uneven topographic features of the wafer. The layer planarization allows patterns that are subsequently formed above that layer to be more uniform. In the case of conductive patterns, the planarization of the underlying layer reduces the probability of electrical shorts between the conductive patterns, which is a growing concern as the density of microelectronic circuitry included in a semiconductor device is progressively increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) is a well-accepted technique to planarize a layer of a semiconductor wafer during the fabrication process by chemically and mechanically removing uneven topographic features of the wafer. A conventional CMP technique involves polishing the surface of a wafer with a rotating polishing pad using a slurry of colloidal particles in an aqueous solution. The slurry promotes planarization of the wafer surface by producing a chemical reaction with the wafer surface and by providing abrasives to &ldquo;grind&rdquo; the wafer surface with the polishing pad. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A common conventional CMP system utilizes a single wafer carrier and a single polishing pad to polish one semiconductor wafer at a time. However, CMP systems have been developed that can simultaneously polish multiple semiconductor wafers on one or more polishing pads to increase throughput. U.S. Pat. No. 5,498,199 to Karlsrud et al. describes a CMP apparatus that utilizes a multi-head wafer polish assembly with five wafer carriers to simultaneously polish five multiple semiconductor wafers on a single large polishing pad. In operation, five semiconductor wafers are sequentially placed on five loading cups of an index table, which is situated adjacent to the polishing pad. When all of the semiconductor wafers are in place, the loading cups are raised to attach the wafers onto the wafer carriers of the multi-head wafer polish assembly, which are positioned over the loading cups. The multi-head wafer polish assembly is then moved to the polishing pad, where all five semiconductor wafers are polished on the polishing pad. After the polishing, the multi-head wafer polish assembly is transferred back to the index table, where the polished semiconductor wafers are placed on five unloading cups of the index table. The loading cups and the unloading cups are situated on the index table in an alternating fashion, forming a circle of ten loading/unloading cups. The polished semiconductor wafers are then sequentially unloaded from the unloading cups. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A disadvantage of the CMP apparatus of Karlsrud et al. is that a significant amount of time is required to sequentially load new semiconductor wafers onto the loading cups before the wafers can be polished. During this period, the polishing pad remains idle. In addition, similar amount of time is required to sequentially unload polished semiconductor wafers from the unloading cups. Thus, the polishing process of the CMP apparatus of Karlsrud et al. includes substantial idle periods, which potentially decreases the throughput of the apparatus. Furthermore, the index table of the loading and unloading cups occupies a significant amount of space, which increases the footprint of the CMP apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,738,574 to Tolles et al. describes a CMP apparatus that can simultaneously polish three semiconductor wafers using multiple polishing pads. The CMP apparatus of Tolles et al. includes three polishing stations and a wafer transfer station, which are located at different quadrants about a rotational axis. Each polishing station includes a single polishing pad to polish a semiconductor wafer. The apparatus also includes four wafer carriers that are suspended from a carousel. The carousel is configured to rotate the wafer carriers such that each wafer carrier can be sequentially positioned at each of the four stations. In operation, the three semiconductor wafers on the wafer carriers positioned at the three polishing stations are polished by the polishing pads at the polishing stations. During this period, the semiconductor wafer on the wafer carrier positioned at the wafer transfer station is unloaded and a new semiconductor wafer is loaded onto that wafer carrier. After a predefined polishing period, the wafer carriers are rotated such that each wafer carrier is positioned at a subsequent station. Once the wafer carriers are properly positioned, the three semiconductor wafers at the polishing stations are polished, while the fourth semiconductor wafer at the transfer station is unloaded and a new semiconductor wafer is loaded. In this fashion, semiconductor wafers can be continuously processed by the apparatus such that each semiconductor wafer is sequentially polished at the three polishing stations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Another CMP apparatus that can simultaneously polish multiple semiconductor wafers using multiple polishing pads is described in U.S. Pat. No. 6,136,715 to Shendon et al. The CMP apparatus of Shendon et al. includes a first polishing station, a second polishing station and a wafer transfer station. The first polishing station includes a large polishing pad, while the second polishing station includes a smaller polishing pad. The apparatus also includes multiple wafer carriers that are suspended from a rotatable carousel. In one embodiment, the apparatus includes four wafer carriers. The carousel is configured to rotate the wafer carriers such that each wafer carrier can be sequentially positioned at four locations. Two of the four locations coincide with the transfer station and the second polishing station. The remaining two locations are both at the first polishing station. In operation, the three semiconductor wafers on the wafer carriers positioned at the two polishing stations are polished by the two polishing pads at the polishing stations. Thus, two wafers are polished at the first polishing station. During this period, the semiconductor wafer on the wafer carrier positioned at the wafer transfer station is unloaded and a new semiconductor wafer is loaded onto that wafer carrier. After a predefined polishing period, the wafer carriers are rotated such that each wafer carrier is positioned at a subsequent location. Once the wafer carriers are properly positioned, the three semiconductor wafers at the polishing stations are polished, while the fourth semiconductor wafer at the transfer station is unloaded and a new semiconductor wafer is loaded. This cycle is repeated to sequentially polishing additional semiconductor wafers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A concern with the above-described CMP apparatuses with multiple polishing pads is that the time required to unload a polished semiconductor wafer and then to load a new semiconductor wafer at the wafer transfer station is typically shorter in duration than the polishing time at the polishing stations. Thus, the new semiconductor wafer must remain idle until end of the polishing time. Consequently, valuable processing time is wasted at the transfer station for each semiconductor wafer to be polished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In view of the above concerns, there is a need for an apparatus and method for chemically and mechanically polishing semiconductor wafers that provides increased efficiency and reduced footprint for the apparatus. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) apparatus and method for polishing semiconductor wafers utilizes multiple wafer carriers to polish a corresponding number of semiconductor wafers on a single polishing pad in parallel. In one embodiment, the wafer carriers are used to transfer semiconductor wafers between one or more wafer transfer stations and the polishing pad. In other embodiments, one or more wafer transfer arms are used to transfer the semiconductor wafers between the wafer transfer station(s) and the wafer carriers. The CMP apparatus is configured to sequentially process semiconductor wafers to increase the throughput of the apparatus. In addition, the components of the CMP apparatus are arranged such that the footprint of the apparatus is minimized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A CMP apparatus in accordance with the invention includes an object transfer station that is configured to sequentially receive objects, a polishing pad having a polishing surface to polish the objects, and a transferring mechanism for sequentially transferring the objects between the object transfer station and the polishing pad to exclusively polish the objects on the polishing pad. The transferring mechanism is configured to transfer at least two current objects from the object transfer station to different locations of the polishing pad such that the two current objects can be simultaneously polished on the polishing surface of the polishing pad. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The CMP apparatus may further include a pad conditioning system. The pad conditioning system includes a first pad conditioner and a second pad conditioner that are configured to selectively engage the polishing surface of the polishing pad to condition the polishing pad. In an embodiment, the CMP apparatus further includes an object unload station that is vertically positioned with respect to the object transfer station. The object unload station is configured to exclusively receive the objects that have been polished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the transferring mechanism includes a first object carrier and a second object carrier that are each configured to secure one of the objects to be polished. In this embodiment, the transferring mechanism may further include a first mechanical arm that is connected to the first object carrier and a second mechanical arm that is connected to the second object carrier. The first mechanical arm is configured to transfer the first object carrier between the object transfer station and the polishing pad, while the second mechanical arm is configured to transfer the second object carrier between the object transfer station and the polishing pad. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments, the CMP apparatus includes first and second object carriers that are positioned about the polishing surface of the polishing pad to engage the polishing surface of the polishing pad. Each of the first and second object carriers is configured to secure one of the objects to be polished. In these embodiments, the transferring mechanism may include an object transfer arm that is configured to transfer some of the objects between the object transfer station and the first object carrier and to transfer some of the objects between the object transfer station and the second object carrier. Alternatively, the transferring mechanism may include a first object transfer arm and a second object transfer arm. The first object transfer arm is configured to exclusively transfer some of the objects between the object transfer station and the first object carrier, while the second object transfer arm is configured to exclusively transfer some of the objects between the object transfer station and the second object carrier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A method of polishing surfaces of objects in accordance with the invention includes the steps of sequentially receiving a first object and a second object at an object transfer station, sequentially transferring the first and second objects from the object transfer station to different locations on a polishing surface of a polishing pad, exclusively polishing the first and second objects on the polishing surface of the polishing pad, and sequentially outputting the first and second objects that have been polished on the polishing surface of the polishing pad. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The method may include a step of conditioning the polishing pad using a first pad conditioner and a second pad conditioner. In an embodiment, the step of conditioning the polishing pad includes selectively scanning the polishing surface of the polishing pad with only one of the first and second pad conditioners. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the step of sequentially transferring the first and second objects includes directly transferring the first and second objects from the object transfer station to the different locations on the polishing surface of the polishing pad using a first object carrier and a second object carrier. In other embodiments, the step of sequentially transferring the first and second objects includes transferring the first object from the object transfer station to a first object carrier and transferring the second object from the object transfer station to a second object carrier. In these other embodiments, the first and second object carriers are positioned about the polishing surface of the polishing pad. In one embodiment of the other embodiments, the step of transferring the first object from the object transfer station to the first object carrier and the step of transferring the second object from the object transfer station to the second object carrier are performed by a single object transfer arm. In another embodiment of the other embodiments, the step of transferring the first object from the object transfer station to the first object carrier is performed by a first object transfer arm and the step of transferring the second object from the object transfer station to the second object carrier is performed by a second object transfer arm. In these other embodiments, the step of sequentially outputting the first and second objects may include transferring the first and second objects to an object unload station, which is vertically positioned with respect to the object transfer station. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Other aspects and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, illustrated by way of example of the principles of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top view of a chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) apparatus in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side view of the CMP apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of a CMP apparatus in accordance with a second embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is side view of the CMP apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the CMP apparatus in accordance with an alternative second embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is top view of a CMP apparatus in accordance with a third embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a process flow diagram of a method of polishing surfaces of semiconductor wafers in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention is shown. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top view of the CMP apparatus, while <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side view of the CMP apparatus. The CMP apparatus operates to process two semiconductor wafers in parallel such that approximately twice as many semiconductor wafers can be polished as compared to a conventional CMP apparatus that sequentially processes semiconductor wafers one wafer at a time. However, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is designed such that footprint of the apparatus is only nominally increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> utilizes a single polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> that can accommodate two wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B. Thus, two semiconductor wafers W can be simultaneously polished on different locations of the polishing surface of the polishing pad using the two wafer carriers, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The polishing pad is situated on a rotatable base <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Thus, the polishing pad can be rotated by the rotatable base. The polishing pad may be any type of polishing pad that can be used to polish a surface of a semiconductor wafer. As an example, the polishing pad may be of the type that contains abrasive particles on the pad surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are connected to mechanical arms <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B, respectively, that can sequentially move the wafer carriers between the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and a wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A comprises an arm frame <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>A, a rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>A, and an arm shaft <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>A. The arm shaft <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>A connects the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A to the rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>A, which is attached to the arm frame <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>A. The rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>A is configured to rotate the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>A by rotating the arm shaft <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>A. Furthermore, the rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>A is configured to raise and lower the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>A by moving the arm shaft <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>A along the vertical direction, as indicated by the arrow <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>A. Thus, the rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>A is able to control the pressure being applied on the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by the semiconductor wafer W on the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A. The arm frame <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>A of the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A is connected to an arm control mechanism <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>A, which is configured to pivot the arm frame about a fixed axis <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Thus, the arm control mechanism <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>A controls the lateral positioning of the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A by pivoting the arm frame <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B also comprises an arm frame <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>B, a rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>B and an arm shaft <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>B that are connected in the same manner as the corresponding components of the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A. Similar to the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A, the rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>B of the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B is configured to rotate the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>B by rotating the arm shaft <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>B, and is also configured to raise and lower the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>B by moving the arm shaft <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>B along the vertical direction, as indicated by the arrow <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>B. Furthermore, the arm frame <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>B of the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B is connected to an arm control mechanism <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>B, which is configured to pivot the arm frame <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>B about a fixed axis <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Thus, the arm control mechanism <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>B controls the lateral positioning of the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B by pivoting the arm frame <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Since the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B are attached to different mechanical arms <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B, each of the wafer carriers can be independently manipulated. Thus, each of the wafer carriers can be independently transferred between the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, as long as the other wafer carrier is not in the path of the moving wafer carrier. In addition, each of the wafer carriers can also be independently raised and lowered to selectively engage the wafer unload/load transfer station or the polishing pad. Furthermore, each of the wafer carriers can be independently rotated to individually polish semiconductor wafers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is configured to accommodate one semiconductor wafer at a time. The wafer unload/load transfer station operates to sequentially receive semiconductor wafers to be polished, for example, from a supply of semiconductor wafers (not shown). These semiconductor wafers are then sequentially transferred to the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> for polishing by the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B. The polished semiconductor wafers are sequentially returned to the wafer unload/load transfer station by the wafer carriers, where the polished wafers are then transmitted to the next destination, for example, a post-CMP cleaning system (not shown). Thus, the wafer unload/load transfer station operates as both the ingress and the egress for the CMP apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Turning back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> further includes a pad conditioning system <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The pad conditioning system includes a pair of pad conditioners <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>B that are connected to arms <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B. The underlying surfaces of the pad conditioners may include known pad conditioner material, such as embedded diamond particulates or plastic bristles, to deglaze the surface of the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The arms of the pad conditioning system are connected to a drive mechanism <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, which controls the independent lateral movements of the arms across the surface of the polishing pad. Thus, each of the pad conditioners can be independently scanned over the surface of the polishing pad to condition the polishing pad. The drive mechanism also independently controls the vertical movements of the arms to ensure that sufficient pressure on the polishing pad is being applied by the pad conditioners <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>B for pad conditioning. The pad conditioning system also includes rotational drive mechanisms (not shown) that are connected to the pad conditioners to independently rotate the pad conditioners during pad conditioning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In operation, one of the pad conditioners <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is selected to condition the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. If the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A is moved to the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, then the pad conditioner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A is selected. However, if the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B is moved to the wafer unload/load transfer station, then the pad conditioner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>B is selected. The drive mechanism <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of the pad conditioning system <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> pivots the arm <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> that is attached to the selected pad conditioner, e.g., the pad conditioner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A, so that the pad conditioner is laterally moved across the polishing pad, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. When the selected pad conditioner is positioned over the polishing pad, the drive mechanism may also lower the pad conditioner to ensure that sufficient pressure is being applied onto the polishing pad by the pad conditioner for proper conditioning. After the polishing pad is conditioned by the selected pad conditioner, the above-described operation is repeated to condition the polishing pad with the other pad conditioner, e.g., the pad conditioner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> also includes a microcontroller <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> that is connected to the arm control mechanisms <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>B. The microcontroller controls the arm control mechanisms, as well as the rotational-and-vertical drive mechanisms <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>B of the mechanical arms <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B. Thus, the microcontroller is able to control the lateral and vertical movements of the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B and the rotational speeds of the wafer carriers. The microcontroller may also control the rotation of the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the operation of the pad conditioning system <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The wafer processing operation of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is now described. Initially, the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B may be positioned over the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, as illustrated by the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The wafer processing operation begins when a first semiconductor wafer is received at the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> from an external source, e.g., a wafer cassette. The first semiconductor wafer may be transmitted to the wafer unload/load transfer station using any conventional method, such as a wafer transfer arm for transporting a semiconductor wafer. Next, one of the mechanical arms <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B, e.g., the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A, is pivoted by the arm control mechanism <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>A to position the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A over the wafer unload/load transfer station. The wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A is then lowered by the rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>A of the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A to secure the first semiconductor wafer onto the bottom of the wafer carrier. As an example, the first semiconductor wafer may be secured to the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A using a vacuum. The wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A is then raised along with the first semiconductor wafer and transferred back to the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, where the first semiconductor wafer is polished. The first semiconductor wafer is polished by engaging the first semiconductor wafer to the surface of the polishing pad, during which the wafer is rotated by the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and the polishing pad is rotated by the rotatable base <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> After the first semiconductor wafer is removed from the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A, a second semiconductor wafer is received at the wafer unload/load transfer station. The other mechanical arm, e.g., the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B, is then pivoted by the arm control mechanism <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>B to position the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B over the wafer unload/load transfer station. The mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B is pivoted when the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A is positioned over the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to ensure that the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B do not collide while being transferred between the wafer unload/load transfer station and the polishing pad. The wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B is then lowered by the rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>B of the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B to secure the second semiconductor wafer onto the bottom of the carrier. The wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B is then raised along with the second semiconductor wafer and transferred back to the polishing pad, where the second semiconductor wafer is simultaneously polished on the polishing pad along with the first semiconductor wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The first and second semiconductor wafers are polished on the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> for a predefined polishing period. However, the polishing of the first semiconductor wafer begins prior to the polishing of the second semiconductor wafer. Thus, the polishing period for the first wafer is terminated before the polishing period for the second wafer. At the end of the polishing period, the first semiconductor wafer is removed from the polishing pad and transferred back to the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by laterally moving the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A from the polishing pad to the wafer unload/load transfer station using the pivoting motion of the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A. The polished first semiconductor wafer is then placed on the wafer unload/load transfer station, where the polished wafer is removed and transmitted to the next destination, for example, a post-CMP cleaning system (not shown). After the polished first semiconductor wafer is removed from the wafer unload/load transfer station, a third semiconductor wafer to be polished is received at the wafer unload/load transfer station. The third semiconductor wafer is then picked up by the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and processed in the same manner as the first semiconductor wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> At the end of the polishing period for the second semiconductor wafer, the second wafer is removed from the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and transferred back to the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by moving the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B from the polishing pad to the wafer unload/load transfer station using the pivoting motion of the mechanical arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B. The polished second semiconductor wafer is then placed on the wafer unload/load transfer station, where the polished wafer is removed and transmitted to the next destination. After the polished second semiconductor wafer is removed from the wafer unload/load transfer station, a fourth semiconductor wafer to be polished is received at the wafer unload/load transfer station. The fourth semiconductor wafer is then picked up by the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B and processed in the same manner as the second semiconductor wafer. In this fashion, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can continually process two semiconductor wafers in a parallel manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Concurrent to the processing of the semiconductor wafers, the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is conditioned by the pad conditioning system <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. When the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A is transferred to the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, the pad conditioner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A is swept across the polishing pad to condition the pad, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Similarly, when the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B is transferred to the wafer unload/load transfer station, the pad conditioner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>B is swept across the polishing pad to condition the pad. The polishing pad may be conditioned each time one of the wafer carriers is transferred to the wafer unload/load transfer station. Alternatively, the polishing pad may be conditioned less frequently. The frequency of the pad conditioning by the pad conditioners may be adjusted as needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, a CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> in accordance with a second embodiment of the invention is shown. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, while <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a side view of the apparatus. Similar to the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B, the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the pad conditioning system <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. However, in this embodiment, the wafer carriers are held in position over the polishing pad and cannot be transferred between the polishing pad and the wafer unload/load transfer station. Thus, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes wafer transfer arms <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>B that can transfer semiconductor wafers between the wafer unload/load transfer station and the wafer carriers, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The wafer transfer arms are attached to the arm control mechanisms <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>B, which move the wafer transfers arms to carry semiconductor wafers between the wafer unload/load transfer station and the wafer carriers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A is attached to an arm shaft <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>A, which is connected to a rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>A. The rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism is configured to rotate the attached wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A by rotating the arm shaft <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>A. Furthermore, the rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>A is configured to raise and lower the attached wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A by moving the arm shaft <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>A along the vertical direction. The rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>A is connected to a rail <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>A, which is attached to an upper surface <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>. The upper surface may be the housing of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The rail <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>A is operatively connected to a lateral drive mechanism <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>A, which translates the rotational-and-drive mechanism <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>A, the arm shaft <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>A and the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A along the rail <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>A. Thus, the lateral drive mechanism <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>A is able to laterally oscillate the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A during polishing of a semiconductor wafer. The wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B is similarly connected to an arm shaft <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>B, a rotational-and-vertical drive mechanism <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>B, a rail <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>B and a lateral drive mechanism <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>B. Since the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B are attached to different mechanisms, each of the wafer carriers can be independently raised and lowered to engage the polishing pad, and can also be independently rotated to individually polish semiconductor wafers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The wafer processing operation of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is similar to the wafer processing operation of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. Initially, the wafer transfer arms <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>B may be positioned away from the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, as illustrated by the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The wafer processing operation begins when a first semiconductor wafer is received at the wafer unload/load transfer station from an external source, e.g., a wafer cassette. Next, one of the wafer transfer arms, e.g., the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A, is moved by the associated arm control mechanism <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>A to transfer the first semiconductor wafer from the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A. The first semiconductor wafer is then secured on the bottom of the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and polished on the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. As an example, the first semiconductor wafer may be secured to wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A using a vacuum. The first semiconductor is polished by lowering the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A to engage the first semiconductor wafer to the surface of the polishing pad, during which the wafer is rotated by the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and the polishing pad is rotated by the rotatable base <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> After the first semiconductor wafer is removed from the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A, a second semiconductor wafer is received at the wafer unload/load transfer station. The other wafer transfer arm, e.g., the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>B, is then moved by the arm control mechanism <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>B to transfer the second semiconductor wafer from the wafer unload/load transfer station to the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B. The second semiconductor wafer is then secured on the bottom of the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B and polished on the polishing pad in the same manner as described above with respect to the first semiconductor wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Similar to the wafer processing operation of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the first and second semiconductor wafers are polished on the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> for a predefined polishing period. However, the polishing of the first semiconductor wafer begins prior to the polishing of the second semiconductor wafer. Thus, the polishing period for the first semiconductor wafer is terminated before the polishing period for the second semiconductor wafer. At the end of the polishing period, the first semiconductor wafer is removed from the polishing pad by raising the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A, and is then transferred from the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A back to the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A. The polished first semiconductor wafer is then placed on the wafer unload/load transfer station, where the polished wafer is removed and transmitted to the next destination. After the polished first semiconductor wafer is removed from the wafer unload/load transfer station, a third semiconductor wafer to be polished is received at the wafer unload/load transfer station. The third semiconductor wafer is then transferred from the wafer unload/load transfer station to the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A by the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A and processed in the same manner as the first semiconductor wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> At the end of the polishing period for the second semiconductor, the second wafer is removed from the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by raising the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B, and is then transferred back to the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>B. The polished second semiconductor wafer is then placed on the wafer unload/load transfer station, where the polished wafer is removed and transmitted to the next destination. After the polished second semiconductor wafer is removed from the wafer unload/load transfer station, a fourth semiconductor wafer to be polished is received at the wafer unload/load transfer station. The fourth semiconductor wafer is transferred to the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B by the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>B and processed in the same manner as the second semiconductor wafer. In this fashion, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> continually processes two semiconductor wafers in a parallel manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Similar to the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment, the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is conditioned by the pad conditioning system <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> during the wafer processing operation. When the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A is being loaded with a semiconductor wafer to be polished, the pad conditioner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A is swept across the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to condition the pad, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Similarly, when the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B is being loaded with a semiconductor wafer to be polished, the pad conditioner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>B is swept across the polishing pad to condition the pad. The polishing pad may be conditioned each time one of the wafer carriers is being loaded with a new semiconductor wafer. Alternatively, the polishing pad may be conditioned less frequently. The frequency of the pad conditioning by the pad conditioners may be adjusted as needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In an alternative second embodiment, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes two wafer transfer stations <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, instead of the single wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is used exclusively as a wafer load station. Thus, only semiconductor wafers that are to be polished by the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are received at the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. The received semiconductor wafers are then carried to the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B by the wafer transfer arms <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>B (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>) for polishing. In contrast, the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> is used exclusively as a wafer unload station. Thus, only semiconductor wafers that have been polished by the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are received at the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. These polished semiconductor wafers are then removed from the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> and transferred to the next destination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the wafer transfer stations <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> are vertically positioned such that the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is situated directly above the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. However, the positions of these wafer transfer stations may be reversed. The configuration of the wafer transfer stations <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> ensures that the footprint of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is minimized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> in accordance with a third embodiment of the invention is shown. The CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> is similar to the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the second embodiment in that the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B are held in position over the polishing pad <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. However, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> utilizes a single wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> to transfer semiconductor wafers between the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Thus, the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> performs the functions of both wafer transfer arms <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>B of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The wafer processing operation of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> is similar to the wafer processing operation of the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The only significant difference between the two wafer processing operations is that the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> utilizes a single wafer transfer arm, i.e., the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>, to transfer semiconductor wafers between the wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and to transfer semiconductor wafers between the wafer unload/load transfer station and the wafer carrier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Similar to the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may include the vertically positioned wafer transfer stations <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>, instead of the single wafer unload/load transfer station <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Thus, in this arrangement, only semiconductor wafers that are to be polished by the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> are received at the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. The received semiconductor wafers are then carried to the wafer carriers <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>B by the wafer transfer arm <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> for polishing. In addition, only semiconductor wafers that have been polished by the CMP apparatus <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> are received at the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. These polished semiconductor wafers are then removed from the wafer transfer station <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> and transferred to the next destination. In an alternative configuration, the wafer transfer stations <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> may be horizontally positioned such that the upper surfaces of the wafer transfer stations are substantially planar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> A method of polishing surfaces of semiconductor wafers in accordance with the present invention is described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. At step <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight>, first and second semiconductor wafers are sequentially received at a wafer transfer station. Next, at step <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight>, the first and second semiconductor wafers are sequentially transferred from the wafer transfer station to different locations on the polishing surface of a polishing pad. In one embodiment, the first and second semiconductor wafers are transferred from the wafer transfer station to the polishing pad by wafer carriers. In another embodiment, the first and second semiconductor wafers are transferred from the wafer transfer station to the polishing pad in two stages. During the first stage, the first and second semiconductor wafers are sequentially transferred from the wafer transfer station to the wafer carriers by one or more wafer transfer arms. In this embodiment, the wafer carriers are held over the polishing pad and cannot be moved between the wafer transfer station and the polishing pad. During the second stage, the first and second semiconductor wafers are lowered to the polishing surface of the polishing pad by the wafer carriers. At step <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>, the first and second semiconductor wafers are polished on the polishing surface of the polishing pad. Next, at step <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight>, the polished first and second semiconductor wafers are sequentially output. In one embodiment, the polished first and second semiconductor wafers are transferred back to the original wafer transfer station. In another embodiment, the polished first and second semiconductor wafers are transferred to a different wafer transfers station, which is vertically positioned with respect to the original wafer transfer station. If additional semiconductor wafers are received at the original wafer transfer station, steps <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> are repeated for the next two semiconductor wafers. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for polishing surfaces of objects comprising: 
<claim-text>an object transfer station that is configured to sequentially receive said objects; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a polishing pad having a polishing surface to polish said objects; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for sequentially transferring said objects between said object transfer station and said polishing pad to exclusively polish said objects on said polishing pad, said sequentially transferring means being configured to transfer at least two current objects of said objects from said object transfer station to different locations on said polishing pad such that said two current objects can be simultaneously polished on said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said sequentially transferring means includes a first object carrier and a second object carrier, each of said first and second object carriers being configured to secure one of said objects to be polished. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said sequentially transferring means further includes a first mechanical arm that is connected to said first object carrier and a second mechanical arm that is connected to said second object carrier, said first mechanical arm being configured to transfer said first object carrier between said object transfer station and said polishing pad, said second mechanical arm being configured to transfer said second object carrier between said object transfer station and said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second mechanical arms are configured to independently pivot about fixed axes to transfer said first and second object carriers between said object transfer station and said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second mechanical arms are configured to rotate said first and second object carriers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second mechanical arms are configured to rotate said first and second object carriers at independent rotational speeds. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second mechanical arms are configured to move said first and second object carriers along a vertical direction that is substantially perpendicular to said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second mechanical arms are configured to independently move said first and second object carriers along said vertical direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a first object carrier and a second object carrier that are positioned about said polishing surface of said polishing pad to engage said polishing surface of said polishing pad, each of said first and second object carriers being configured to secure one of said objects to be polished. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said sequentially transferring means includes an object transfer arm that is configured to transfer some of said objects between said object transfer station and said first object carrier and to transfer some of said objects between said object transfer station and said second object carrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said sequentially transferring means includes a first object transfer arm and a second object transfer arm, said first object transfer arm being configured to exclusively transfer some of said objects between said object transfer station and said first object carrier, said second object transfer arm being configured to exclusively transfer some of said objects between said object transfer station and said second object carrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a rotational drive mechanism that is connected to said first and second object carriers, said rotational drive mechanism being configured to independently rotate said first and second object carriers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a vertical drive mechanism that is connected to said first and second object carriers, said vertical drive mechanism being configured to independently move said first and second object carriers along a vertical direction that is substantially perpendicular to said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a lateral drive mechanism that is connected to said first and second object carriers, said lateral drive mechanism being configured to move said first and second object carriers along a lateral direction that is substantially parallel to said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a pad conditioning system, said pad conditioning system including a first pad conditioner and a second pad conditioner that are configured to selectively engage said polishing surface of said polishing pad to condition said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said pad conditioning system includes a first pad conditioning arm and a second pad conditioning arm that are connected to said first and second pad conditioners to independently move said first and second pad conditioners across said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an object unload station that is vertically positioned with respect to said object transfer station, said object unload station being configured to exclusively receive said objects that have been polished. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for polishing surfaces of objects comprising: 
<claim-text>an object transfer station; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a polishing pad having a polishing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first mechanical arm having a first object carrier, said first object carrier being configured to secure a first object to be polished, said first mechanical arm being configured to directly transfer said first object between said object transfer station and said polishing pad using said first object carrier; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second mechanical arm having a second object carrier, said second object carrier being configured to secure a second object to be polished, said second mechanical arm being configured to directly transfer said second object between said object transfer station and said polishing pad using said second object carrier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second mechanical arms are configured to independently pivot about fixed axes to transfer said first and second object carriers between said object transfer station and said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second mechanical arms are configured to independently rotate said first and second object carriers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second mechanical arms are configured to independently move said first and second object carriers along a vertical direction that is substantially perpendicular to said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a pad conditioning system, said pad conditioning system including a first pad conditioner and a second pad conditioner that are configured to engage said polishing surface of said polishing pad to condition said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said pad conditioning system includes a first pad conditioning arm and a second pad conditioning arm that are connected to said first and second pad conditioners to independently move said first and second pad conditioners across said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for polishing surfaces of objects comprising: 
<claim-text>an object transfer station; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a polishing pad having a polishing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first object carrier and a second object carrier that are positioned about said polishing surface of said polishing pad to engage said polishing surface of said polishing pad, each of said first and second object carriers being configured to secure an object to be polished; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an object transfer mechanism that is configured to directly transfer said objects between said object transfer station and said first and second object carriers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said object transfer mechanism includes an object transfer arm that is configured to transfer some of said objects between said object transfer station and said first object carrier, said object transfer arm being further configured to transfer some of said objects between said object transfer station and said second object carrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said object transfer mechanism includes a first object transfer arm and a second object transfer arm, said first object transfer arm being configured to exclusive transfer some of said objects between said object transfer station and said first object carrier, said second object transfer arm being configured to exclusively transfer some of said objects between said object transfer station and said second object carrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said object transfer mechanism includes a rotational drive mechanism that is connected to said first and second object carriers, said rotational drive mechanism being configured to independently rotate said first and second object carriers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said object transfer mechanism includes a vertical drive mechanism that is connected to said first and second object carriers, said vertical drive mechanism being configured to independently move said first and second object carriers along a vertical direction that is substantially perpendicular to said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said object transfer mechanism includes a lateral drive mechanism that is connected to said first and second object carriers, said lateral drive mechanism being configured to independently move said first and second object carriers along a lateral direction that is substantially parallel to said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a pad conditioning system, said pad conditioning system including a first pad conditioner and a second pad conditioner that are configured to engage said polishing surface of said polishing pad to condition said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said pad conditioning system includes a first pad conditioning arm and a second pad conditioning arm that are connected to said first and second pad conditioners to independently move said first and second pad conditioners across said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an object unload station that is vertically positioned with respect to said object transfer station, said object unload station being configured to exclusively receive said objects that have been polished. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A method of polishing surfaces of objects comprising: 
<claim-text>sequentially receiving a first object and a second object at an object transfer station; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially transferring said first and second objects from said object transfer station to different locations on a polishing surface of a polishing pad; </claim-text>
<claim-text>exclusively polishing said first and second objects on said polishing surface of said polishing pad; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially outputting said first and second objects that have been polished on said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of sequentially transferring said first and second objects includes directly transferring said first and second objects from said object transfer station to said different locations on said polishing surface of said polishing pad using a first object carrier and a second object carrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of sequentially transferring said first and second objects includes pivoting mechanical arms about fixed axes to move said first and second object carriers from said object transfer station to said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of sequentially transferring said first and second objects includes transferring said first object from said object transfer station to a first object carrier and transferring said second object from said object transfer station to a second object carrier, said first and second object carriers being positioned about said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of transferring said first object from said object transfer station to said first object carrier and said step of transferring said second object from said object transfer station to said second object carrier are performed by a single object transfer arm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of transferring said first object from said object transfer station to said first object carrier is performed by a first object transfer arm and said step of transferring said second object from said object transfer station to said second object carrier are performed by a second object transfer arm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of sequentially outputting said first and second objects includes transferring said first and second objects to an object unload station, said object unload station being vertically positioned with respect to said object transfer station. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of exclusively polishing said first and second objects on said polishing surface of said polishing pad includes independently rotating said first and second objects. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of exclusively polishing said first and second objects on said polishing surface of said polishing pad includes independently moving said first and second object across said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of exclusively polishing said first and second objects on said polishing surface of said polishing pad includes independently applying pressure on said first and second objects toward said polishing surface of said polishing pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a step of conditioning said polishing pad using a first pad conditioner and a second pad conditioner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of conditioning said polishing surface of said polishing pad includes selectively scanning said polishing surface of said polishing pad with only one of said first and second pad conditioners.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003852A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003852A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003852A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003852A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003852A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003852A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003852A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003852A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
