<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002269A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002269A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002269A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002269A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002269A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002269A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002269A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002269A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002269A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002269A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002269A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002269A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002269A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002269A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002269</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896396</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05K007/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H05K007/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>361</class>
<subclass>796000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Emission compliant device enclosure with interchangeable bezel</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Virginia</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Keating</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Encinitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Juan</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Ortiz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mark</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Zisek</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BLAKELY SOKOLOFF TAYLOR &amp; ZAFMAN</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>12400 WILSHIRE BOULEVARD, SEVENTH FLOOR</address-1>
<city>LOS ANGELES</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90025</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A sub-bezel coupled to an electronic device to block electronic emissions and allow for a bezel to be interchangeable. Because the bezel is not needed to block electronic emissions to allow the device to pass through regulatory testing, the bezel can be designed and added after regulatory testing without the electronic device having to be sent back through regulatory testing. Being able to interchange the bezel allows companies to lower projection risks. If a customer projection for a electronic device is too high because the customer does not buy as many electronic devices as expected, the bezel can be changed and the excess electronic devices can be sold to a different customer without having to send all the changed electronic devices back through regulatory testing. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to device enclosures and in particular, interchangeable bezels for device enclosures. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE RELATED ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Electronic devices may give off electronic emissions that can interfere with neighboring electronic devices. Regulatory testing is usually required for the electronic devices to insure that the electronic devices are not giving off electronic emissions above a certain level. The electronic devices are usually enclosed by an enclosure and a bezel on the front of the enclosure to contain the electronic device&apos;s electronic emissions and block out the electronic emissions from external sources. Usually, the bezels have different customer preferred designs on them depending on the customer buying the specific electronic device that the bezel will be coupled to. Once coupled to the enclosure of the electronic device, the bezel is usually hard to change. A company wanting to change the bezel must take the bezel off, attach a new bezel to the electronic device, and then send the electronic device with the new bezel back through regulatory testing. This process can make changing the bezel very expensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In addition, the companies making the electronic devices for the customers must predict how many of each electronic device the company can sell to each customer and then build the appropriate number of electronic devices with each customer&apos;s preferred bezel design. If a customer buys fewer than the amount predicted for them, left over electronic devices are not easily sold to other customers. The left over electronic devices must be modified by removing the bezel, putting on the new bezel with the new customer&apos;s design, and then retested. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Other devices that give off electronic emissions and must be tested face similar problems. These devices include but are not limited to set top boxes. Any changes to the bezel of the device may allow more electronic emissions to escape and therefore the device may need to be retested.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>shows an embodiment with a detached sub-bezel and bezel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows an embodiment with a coupled sub-bezel and a detached bezel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an embodiment with a flange and a sub-bezel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a bezel that may be used with an embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a reverse view of an embodiment with a bezel and without a top panel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a flowchart for assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows an embodiment without a top panel to show a bezel attached to the front.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The following description makes reference to numerous specific details in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. However, it is to be noted that not every specific detail need be employed to practice the present invention. Additionally, well-known details, such as particular materials or methods, have not been described in order to avoid obscuring the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>an electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, such as a network appliance, is shown. The electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> shown has an electronic device with an enclosure with side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, top panel <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> that at least partially surrounds the electronic device. The enclosure may be made of several different materials including but not limited to steel and aluminum alloys. The enclosure material may be processed in several different ways. For example, the enclosure may be steel electro-galvanized G30, smooth tempered, and semi-bright to bright finish. The panels for the enclosure may be manufactured in several different ways including but not limited to stamp pressing. The side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> may be stamped pressed separately from the bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and then welded onto the bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and each other to form an enclosure, or the side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and the bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be stamped pressed as a single piece and then the side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> can be folded up from the bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and then welded on their sides to form an enclosure. Besides welding the panels, such as bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, panels may be coupled to each other using parts such as but not limited to interlocking parts, snaps, and screws. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The enclosure may serve several different purposes. For example, the enclosure may keep together and secure internal parts of the electronic device. The enclosure can also serve to block out the electronic emissions coming out of or going into the electronic device. However, the enclosure may not stop the electronic emissions from going into or out of front opening <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>the front opening <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> may allow the electronic emissions to escape from inside electronic device. Also, the electronic emissions from other electronic devices may enter the electronic device through the front opening <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and possibly disrupt operations inside the electronic device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The electronic device also may have a component securing panel <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> which may be attached to the electronic device. The electronic device components such as button <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and light emitting diode (LED) <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> may be any electronic device component on the electronic device such as but not limited to dials, buttons, electronic displays, connectors, and lights or LEDs. The component securing panel <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may not be wide enough to cover the front opening <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. In addition, component securing panel <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may not be attached to the electronic device and may need a front panel to secure to. Also shown is a detached sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>an embodiment of the invention with a single piece forming the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, side-panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is shown. The side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be folded up from the bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and welded together at their sides to form an enclosure. Other methods of coupling the sides such as interlocking parts and screws are also within the scope of the invention. The electronic device components may be secured by the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> without a component securing panel <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>). In another embodiment, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> may be stamp pressed as one piece and then sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> may be folded up. The sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> piece may then be coupled to side panel <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, top panel <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and side panel <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which may be stamp pressed as one piece and then side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> folded from top panel <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, an embodiment of the invention is shown as an electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> with an electronic device secured inside the side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the top panel <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and the back panel <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the enclosure. Furthermore, sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be coupled to the front of the electronic device to secure component securing panel <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (view obscured in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) and shield a substantial portion of the electronic emissions from entering or leaving the front opening. However, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may secure the electronic device components without a component securing panel. The electronic device components, such as the button <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the LED <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> may stick out through sub-bezel holes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, respectively, in order to be accessible. The sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be made of several different materials including but not limited to steel and aluminum alloys. The sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> material may be processed in several different ways. For example, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be steel electro-galvanized G30, smooth tempered, and semi-bright to bright finish. The sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be manufactured in several different ways including but not limited to stamp pressing. The sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be attached to the enclosure in several different ways to shield a substantial portion of electronic emissions entering and leaving the electronic device. For example, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be formed as a single piece with the bottom panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and then folded up along the sub-bezel&apos;s bottom edge. The sides of the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may then be coupled to the side panels <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. In another embodiment, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be formed separately and then be welded, brazed, or screwed onto the enclosure. The sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may also be coupled to the enclosure by fasteners such as but not limited to adhesive, screws, rivets, or a friction fit. Other ways of coupling the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are also within the scope of the invention. Alternately, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may not be coupled to the enclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Continuing with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is shown as a lip extending outward from sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. In another embodiment, the flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be an extension of the side, top, and bottom panels in the form of a lip extending outward from the enclosure. The flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be used to block light from entering the electronic device if the electronic device is further coupled to a bezel, such as bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Also seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may have front slots <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The front slots <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be used in conjunction with side slots on the enclosure such as side slot <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for bezel snaps <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) to snap and un-snap. Slots in the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and the enclosure such as the front slots <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the side slot <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be small enough to keep the electronic emissions to a minimum. If not small enough to sufficiently block the electronic emissions, the slots may also be shielded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Continuing with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may have clearance holes <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> for fasteners such as self-locking screws <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The self-locking screws <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> may be used to secure bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to the front of the electronic device (as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). The self-locking screws <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> may be needed in addition to bezel snaps <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to hold bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> in place and prevent theft of bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> (as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, with sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in place, a substantial portion of the electronic emissions may be shielded from entering or leaving the electronic device. In addition, the electronic device should be protected from external electronic emissions that may affect the electronic device&apos;s operation. With the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in place, the electronic device should pass regulatory testing to be in compliance with applicable emission regulations before bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> (as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) is coupled to the electronic device. Bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may be coupled to the enclosure by fasteners such as but not limited to snaps, screws, and adhesive. Bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may also be coupled to the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> by a fastener such as but not limited to snaps, screws, rivets, and adhesive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is shown with the side snaps <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and bezel holes <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may be made of materials such as but not limited to plastic, steel, and aluminum alloys. For example, bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may be made of ABS plastic, which may be flame retardant with a flammability rating of <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>-Z<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. In addition, bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can be manufactured using several different processes such as but not limited to vacuum molded processing, extrusion, injection die molding, and stamp pressing. Bezel thickness <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may vary depending on the electronic device, but should be small enough that the electronic device components, such as the button <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the LED <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, can be accessed through the bezel holes <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. If the bezel thickness <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is too great, the end of the electronic device components, such as the button <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, may not extend past the front of bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. If the electronic device components do not extend past the front of bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, they may be hard to access or read. The bezel thickness <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be greater away from the electronic device components, such as the button <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. For example, the ends of the bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may be designed thicker than the rest of the bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Because the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> (as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) may shield a substantial portion of the electronic emissions entering or leaving the electronic device, the bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> does not have to be designed to shield against emissions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> reverse view of an embodiment of the invention is shown. The self-locking screws <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> may pass through the clearance holes <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and screw into and terminate in bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> at screw holes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> to hold bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The screws <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> may serve to hold bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> secure against the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and may deter theft of bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. To remove bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the top panel <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> (seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) may be removed before the screws <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> are removed. Then bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may be removed by undoing the bezel&apos;s fasteners, for example, the side snaps <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from the side slots <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Also as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, flange slot <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is shown on bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Flange slot <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may fit over flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). In another embodiment, the flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may extend over the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and at least partially fit inside the flange slot <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> when bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is coupled to the electronic device. In another embodiment of the invention, there may be no flange slot <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, but instead, the flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may fit against bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. In another embodiment, the flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be on the bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the flange slot <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may be on the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may block external light from leaking into the front of the electronic device or leaking onto the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Light shining on the electronic device or the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may degrade the appearance of the electronic device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, an embodiment of the invention is shown in the form of a flowchart. At block <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, an electronic device is at least partially surrounded with an enclosure. At block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, a sub-bezel is coupled to the enclosure. The sub-bezel may shield a substantial portion of electronic emissions from entering or leaving the electronic device. The electronic device may then be ready to pass through emission testing. At block <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, a bezel may be coupled using a fastener. At block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, the bezel may be coupled to the enclosure, or, at block <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, the bezel may be coupled to the sub-bezel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, an embodiment of the invention is shown as an electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> with a bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> coupled to an electronic device, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, or the enclosure surrounding the electronic device. Because the top panel <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, has been removed, the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be seen behind bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The electronic device components <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> should be accessible through the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may vary in appearance from customer to customer. However, because the electronic device is already shielded by the enclosure and the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the electronic device will not have to be sent back for regulatory testing each time bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is switched out. In addition, bezel <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may be added after the regulatory testing making it cheaper for companies to make electronic devices for several different customers and then make the bezels <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> depending on projected customer buys. If a customer projection is too high, such that a specific customer buys fewer electronic devices than expected, the electronic devices made for that customer can be fitted with the bezels <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for a different customer, such as a customer for which the customer projection was too low. Without the sub-bezel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, old bezels would have to be removed, a new bezel coupled to the electronic device, and then the electronic device with the new bezel may have to be sent through regulatory testing again. This can make refitting bezels potentially very costly for the companies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Other devices that give off electronic emissions and may go through regulatory testing can also benefit from having a sub-bezel and interchangeable bezels. These devices include but are not limited to set top boxes. With interchangeable bezels, these devices can be tested with the sub-bezels in place and their bezel can be added later and changed if need be without needing to retest the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Although an exemplary embodiment of the invention has been shown and described in the form of interchangeable bezels, many changes, modifications, and substitutions may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the claimed invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an electronic device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an enclosure at least partially surrounding said electronic device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sub-bezel coupled to said enclosure to block electronic emissions through a front of the enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electronic device is a network appliance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said enclosure comprises: 
<claim-text>a side panel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom panel; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a top panel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sub-bezel is to block electronic emissions from the electronic device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electronic device has components selected from a group comprising dials, buttons, electronic displays, connectors, and lights. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sub-bezel and said bottom panel are one piece. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sub-bezel and said enclosure are one piece. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said enclosure includes a material selected from a group comprising steel and aluminum alloys. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sub-bezel includes a material selected from a group comprising steel and aluminum alloys. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a bezel coupled to said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bezel is coupled to said enclosure by fasteners selected from a group comprising snaps, screws, and adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bezel includes a material selected from a group comprising plastic, steel, and aluminum alloys. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bezel is made of ABS plastic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bezel is coupled to said sub-bezel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bezel is coupled to said sub-bezel by a fastener selected from a group comprising snaps, screws, rivets, and adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bezel is coupled to said sub-bezel by self-locking screws inserted through said sub-bezel and terminating in said bezel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said enclosure has a flange extending over said sub-bezel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flange at least partially fits inside said bezel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flange partially blocks external light from passing into said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>at least partially surrounding an electronic device with an enclosure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling a sub-bezel to said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising coupling a bezel to said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein coupling a bezel includes coupling with a fastener selected from a group comprising snaps, screws, and adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising coupling said bezel to said sub-bezel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A system comprising: 
<claim-text>a electronic device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an enclosure partially surrounding said electronic device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sub-bezel coupled to said enclosure to block electronic emissions from a front of said enclosure in compliance with applicable emission regulations. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a bezel coupled to said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electronic device is a server. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sub-bezel is to block emissions from said electronic device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said sub-bezel is to shield a substantial portion of said electronic emissions from entering or leaving the front of the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002269A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002269A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002269A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002269A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002269A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002269A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002269A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
