<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002253A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002253A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002253A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002253A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002253A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002253A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002253A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002253A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002253A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002253A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002253A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002253A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002253A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002253A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002253</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895602</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05K005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>361</class>
<subclass>687000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>714</class>
<subclass>010000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>361</class>
<subclass>695000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>High availability small foot-print server</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hillyard</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bill</given-name>
<middle-name>N.</middle-name>
<family-name>Gallas</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Queen Creek</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mark</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Summers</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BLAKELY SOKOLOFF TAYLOR &amp; ZAFMAN</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>12400 WILSHIRE BOULEVARD, SEVENTH FLOOR</address-1>
<city>LOS ANGELES</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90025</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A novel high availability small foot-print server is described in which four or more separate computer modules and associated power supply and communication connections or other units are clustered together in a single server chassis to occupy a limited amount of space while providing maximum accessibility for administrative, maintenance, installation, or other purposes. Each separate computer module is equipped with its own fan or blower box to provide redundancy in the case of fan or blower box failure. The server chassis is contoured to provide for natural interconnection such that more than one high availability small foot-print server may be stacked together to take up the same amount of floor, shelf, or desk space as a single server. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to computer servers. In particular, the present invention relates to an improved server design for housing and cooling multiple computer modules, power supplies, bus routers, and the like, in a limited space. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Advances in computer technology have allowed individuals and businesses to operate multiple full-scale computer server systems from within the home and small or remote offices. In this environment, or any other environment where floor and desk space is limited, it is important that the computer equipment occupies a relatively small amount of space while receiving adequate ventilation and access to power supplies and network connections that enable communication over the Internet or a private network. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> There are a number of prior art solutions to assist with the installation of multiple pieces of computer equipment in a compact space, such as the traditional rack mounted server or a Local Area Network (LAN) closet. For example, servers are housed in large computer cases (i.e. mini-towers) that can either sit on the floor or that can be built into a rack-mounted chassis. The traditional rack-mounted servers are approximately 19 inches wide, and do not to make the most efficient use of space. They also fail to adequately address the ventilation, communication, and power supply needs of the computers they house. The LAN closet, while a compact storage area, renders the computers somewhat inaccessible and may also fail to address the necessary ventilation, communication, and power supply needs of the computers that they house. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Another popular prior art solution for simplifying the installation of multiple pieces of computer equipment is to make them stackable, thereby eliminating the need for an external rack. For example, Intel Corporation, the assignee of the present application for patent, sells a line of 5- and 8-port communication hubs under the trademark Intel InBusiness&reg;, that utilize a stackable modular design. However, such individual stackable modules also fail to address the ventilation, communication, and power supply needs of multiple pieces of equipment in a limited space. For example, multiple central processing units (CPUs) present in a typical server system require a reliable cooling flow of air (i.e. system air) in order to operate properly. Since the stackable, rack-mounted, and LAN closet solutions do not address the individual system air cooling requirements of each CPU, there exists an undesirable single point of failure if the air cooling system in the area where the CPUs are located fails. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> What is needed, therefore, is a new approach that simplifies the installation of multiple pieces of computer equipment in a limited space, while providing support for the ventilation, communication, and power supply needs of each piece of equipment in a manner that is accessible, fault-tolerant, and efficient. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be described by way of exemplary embodiments, but not limitations, illustrated in the accompanying drawings in which like references denote similar elements, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective view of a high availability small foot-print server chassis in accordance with one embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective view of two high availability small foot-print server chassis stacked one on top of the other in accordance with one embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a rear perspective view of a high availability small foot-print server chassis housing multiple computer modules in accordance with one embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a front perspective view of a single computer module capable of being housed in a high availability small foot-print server chassis as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and in accordance with one embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a front perspective view of the single computer module illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> in accordance with one embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a rear perspective view of the interior of the single computer module illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> in accordance with one embodiment; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates the flow of air through the interior of the single computer module illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> in accordance with one embodiment. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In the following description various aspects of the present invention, a high availability small foot-print server will be described. Specific details will be set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. However, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that the present invention may be practiced with only some or all of the described aspects of the present invention, and with or without some or all of the specific details. In some instances, well-known features may be omitted or simplified in order not to obscure the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Parts of the description will be presented using terminology commonly employed by those skilled in the art to convey the substance of their work to others skilled in the art, including terms that refer to computer system components, such as servers, routers, hubs, buses, hard drives, memory, input/output (I/O), racks, chassis, computer cases, power supplies, and the like. The terminology further includes operations performed by a computer system, and their operands, such as transmitting, receiving, and the like. As well understood by those skilled in the art, these operands take the form of electrical, magnetic, or optical signals, and the operations involve storing, transferring, combining, and otherwise manipulating the signals through electrical, magnetic or optical components of a system. The term system includes general purpose as well as special purpose arrangements of these components that are standalone, adjunct or embedded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Various operations will be described as multiple discrete steps performed in turn in a manner that is most helpful in understanding the present invention. However, the order of description should not be construed as to imply that these operations are necessarily performed in the order they are presented, or even order dependent. Lastly, repeated usage of the phrase &ldquo;in one embodiment&rdquo; does not necessarily refer to the same embodiment, although it may. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective view of a high availability small foot-print server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. As shown, the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is an approximately rectangular-shaped cube for housing multiple server units. The server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprises five surfaces including a top surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, a bottom surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> disposed substantially parallel to the top surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, a front surface <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> disposed substantially perpendicular to the top <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and bottom <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> surfaces, and opposing side surfaces <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The opposing side surfaces <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are uniformly disposed substantially parallel to each other while at the same time substantially perpendicular to the top <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, bottom <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, and front <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> surfaces. The rear of the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is open in order to receive one or more server modules, power supply, communications hub, or other server component housed within the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be integrally constructed of a substantially rigid material, the approximate dimensions of which are a width of 12 inches by a depth of 9 inches by a height of 7 inches, thereby making the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> suitable for placing on a desktop or shelf, without occupying the majority of the desktop or shelf surface <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Of course, other dimensions of the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be used without departing from the scope of the invention, as long as the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> creates a relatively small foot-print on a typical desktop or shelf surface <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, and is sufficiently small in height to reasonably allow three or more server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to be stacked atop one another. In one embodiment, the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may also be assembled, in whole or in part, from individually formed surfaces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, joined or fastened together in a permanent or semi-permanent (i.e. allowing for disassembly) fashion into a single server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> without departing from the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment, the front surface <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> contains a series of openings <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> that allow for visual inspection of a server computer module, power supply, communications hub, or other server component contained within the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, including the visual inspection of any status lights or indicators on the server component that may be visible through the openings <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The remaining areas of the front surface not taken up by the openings <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may be either flat or contoured without departing from the scope of the invention. In one embodiment, the opposing side surfaces <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be contoured in a convex fashion as illustrated; however other contours of the side surfaces <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may also be employed without departing from the scope of the invention, including side surfaces <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> that are substantially flat, or without any contour. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The top surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and bottom surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are compatibly contoured into depressed areas <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and raised areas <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> such as the opposing sinusoidal wave contours in the illustrated embodiment. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the contours of the top <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and bottom <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> surfaces are such that one server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be stacked on top of another identically contoured server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a natural interconnecting fashion. Other compatible contours of the top <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and bottom <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> surfaces other than the illustrated opposing sinusoidal wave contours may be employed without departing from the scope of the invention. An unlimited number of server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be interconnected in a stacked fashion as illustrated, although a reasonable stack would be two (as illustrated) or three server chassis to provide up to twelve or so server computer modules and associated power supplies and communication connections in a limited space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a rear perspective view of a high availability small foot-print server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> housing multiple server computer modules <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> in accordance with one embodiment. As illustrated, the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is open in the rear and encases an internal rack <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> that is comprised of multiple slots <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that may each be occupied by a single computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, with at least one slot <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> reserved for a power supply, communications hub, or other unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, that is capable of providing power and/or an integrated network interface to individual computer modules <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the internal rack <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is provided for ease of inserting or removing the computer modules <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> or other unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> into or from the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a sliding fashion. In one embodiment, the internal rack <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may be integrated with the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> such that the internal rack <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is fixed and each computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> or other unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is inserted or removed individually from server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a sliding fashion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment the rear of server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is entirely open allowing unfettered access to each single computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> housed in slots <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, as well as unfettered access to the power supply, communications hub, or other unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> housed in slot <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> of internal rack <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> encased in server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the integrated network interface of unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may be an Ethernet hub or switch, which is known in the art. Alternatively, the integrated network interface of unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may be an Infiniband hub, which is an emerging standard for an interconnect network protocol that is known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> illustrate a rear and front perspective view, respectively, of a single computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> capable of being housed in a high availability small foot-print server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and in accordance with one embodiment. The computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be a embedded computer with a hard drive, memory and associated I/O as is known in the art. The computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is encased in an Electro-Magnetic Compatibility (EMC) enclosure <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, also referred to as a &ldquo;Faraday box,&rdquo; that covers all sides of the computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, including the top <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, bottom <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, front <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, rear <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, and the two sides <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> of the computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to shield each computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> from the neighboring computer modules <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> housed in the other slots <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of internal rack <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> encased by server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the EMC enclosure <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is provided with a lip <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> extending lengthwise along the top and bottom side edges. The lip <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> of EMC enclosure <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is designed to fit within each individual slot <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of rack <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> in server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> so as to secure the insertion or removal of the server computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> as well as to guide the computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> into proper position within the slot <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the EMC enclosure <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is fastened to computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> using a fastener <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in a manner that is known in the art. In one embodiment, the EMC enclosure <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is equipped on the top <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> with a vent <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> that is positioned over a fan (<highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) within computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to allow the unobstructed flow of air into the fan intake opening (<highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the rear end <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> of computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> contains, among other features, the outlets and inlets for the various ports, connections, and sockets of the computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> for receiving cable, modem, or peripheral connections, whereas the front end <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> of the computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> contains, among other features, the various status or other indicators <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> that may be visible through openings <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> with the top <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> of the EMC enclosure <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> removed to reveal the interior and selected components therein. As illustrated, each individual computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes, among other components, its own fan or blower box <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> equipped with a fan intake opening <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> for drawing in air through the vent <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> of the EMC enclosure <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> from the surrounding environment within the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in which the computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is housed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> again illustrates computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> with the top <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> of the EMC enclosure <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> removed to reveal the interior and selected components therein, and further illustrates the flow of air <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> from the fan or blower box <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, a continuing air flow <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>, cools the interior and other components of computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, with an exiting air flow <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> out of annular openings <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> in the rear <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> of computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to exit finally through the open rear of the server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in which the computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is housed. The provision of a fan or blower box <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> in each individual computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> housed in server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> insures that there is not a single point of failure in the air cooling system, since without proper air cooling, the computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> will fail. By eliminating this single point of failure in the air cooling system, the small foot-print server is capable of providing redundancy amongst the computer modules <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> such that one computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> can take over when a neighboring one fails due to air cooling or other failure. Therefore, the small foot-print server of the present invention provides for improved fault-tolerance and high availability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, a novel high availability small foot-print server is described in which one or more separate computer modules <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and associated power supply and communication connections or other unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may be clustered together in a single server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to occupy a limited amount of space while providing maximum accessibility for administrative, maintenance, installation, or other purposes. For example, one computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be slaved to another neighboring computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> housed in the same server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, or a single computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> can be serviced or replaced without bringing down the neighboring modules <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Clustering the computer modules <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> together with the supporting unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> in an integrated fashion can facilitate a software-controlled automatic fail-over such that the small foot-print server of the present invention provides improved fault tolerance and high availability. In addition, each separate computer module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is equipped with its own fan or blower box <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> to provide further redundancy in the case of fan or blower box failure. The server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is contoured to provide for natural interconnection such that more than one high availability small foot-print server may be stacked together to take up the same amount of floor, shelf, or desk space as a single server chassis <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> would. From the foregoing description, those skilled in the art will recognize that many other variations of the present invention are possible. Thus, the present invention is not limited by the details described. Instead, the present invention can be practiced with modifications and alterations within the spirit and scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A small foot-print server comprising: 
<claim-text>a server chassis having a small foot-print; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first computer module housed in the server chassis, the first computer module having a first fan; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second computer module housed in the server chassis, the second computer module having a second fan operating independently of the first fan; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a communication module housed in the server chassis having an integrated network interface coupled to the first and second computer modules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a power supply module housed in the server chassis coupled to the first and second computer modules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the small foot-print is not more than 12 inches wide by 9 inches deep. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second computer module is a backup to the first computer module when the first fan fails. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second computer modules share access to the integrated network interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second computer modules derive power from the power supply module. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first computer module is housed in the server chassis in a first slot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second computer module is housed in the server chassis in a second slot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first computer module is capable of insertion into the first slot without disturbing the second computer module. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first computer module is capable of insertion into the first slot without disturbing the second computer module in the second slot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first computer module is capable of removal from the first slot without disturbing the second computer module in the second slot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the integrated network interface is an Ethernet hub. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the integrated network interface is an Ethernet switch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the integrated network interface is an Infiniband hub. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a contour of a top surface of the server chassis is shaped to permit stacking a second server chassis atop the server chassis in a natural interconnecting fashion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The small foot-print server of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the contour of the top surface of the server chassis is a first sinusoidal wave, and a contour of a bottom surface of the server chassis is a second sinusoidal wave, the second sinusoidal wave contour being aligned to oppose the first sinusoidal wave contour to achieve a natural interconnect between the stacked chassis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A server chassis comprising: 
<claim-text>a receptacle having five sides perpendicularly disposed to form an opening on the sixth side to receive a first computer module having a first fan, and second computer module having a second fan independent of the first fan, the first computer module operating to automatically fail over to the second computer module when the first fan of the first computer module fails, the receptacle having a small foot-print on a horizontal surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The server chassis of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the opening receives a communication module that is capable of coupling to the first and second computer module to provide a common integrated network interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The server chassis of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the opening receives a power module that is capable of coupling to the first and second computer module to provide a common power supply. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The server chassis of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a top side and a bottom side of the server chassis is shaped to permit stacking a second server chassis atop the server chassis in a natural interconnecting fashion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The server chassis of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the top side of the server chassis is shaped as a first sinusoidal wave, and the bottom side is shaped as a second sinusoidal wave, wherein the second sinusoidal wave shape is aligned to oppose the first sinusoidal wave shape to achieve a natural interconnect between the stacked chassis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The server chassis of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the small foot-print is not more than 12 inches wide by 9 inches deep on the horizontal surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method for a high availability small foot-print server comprising: 
<claim-text>inserting a first computer module into a server chassis having a small footprint, the first computer module having a first fan; </claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting a second computer module into the server chassis without disturbing the first computer module, the second computer module having a second fan operating independently of the first fan; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling the first computer module to automatically fail over to the second computer when the first fan fails. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>inserting a communication module into the server chassis, the communication module providing an integrated network interface to the first and second computer modules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>inserting a power module into the server chassis, the power supply module providing a common power supply to the first and second computer modules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the small foot-print is not more than 12 inches wide by 9 inches deep, enabling the server chassis to occupy a limited space on a horizontal work surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>stacking the server chassis atop a second server chassis, wherein a contour of a bottom surface of the server chassis and a contour of a top surface of the second server chassis are compatibly shaped to permit the server chassis to interconnect to the second server chassis in a natural manner. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the contour of the bottom surface of the server chassis is a first sinusoidal wave, and a contour of the top surface of the second server chassis is a second sinusoidal wave, the second sinusoidal wave contour being aligned to oppose the first sinusoidal wave contour to achieve a natural interconnect between the stacked chassis.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002253A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002253A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002253A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002253A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002253A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002253A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002253A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
