<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001724A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001724A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001724A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001724A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001724A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001724A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001724A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001724A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001724A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001724A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001724A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001724A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001724</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10171819</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020614</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>GB 01 14797.4</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010616</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>GB 01 21900.5</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010911</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>005720</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Access mechanism and engagement mechanism for a vehicle door</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robin</given-name>
<family-name>Willats</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Preston</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<family-name>Emson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>West Midlands</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sidney</given-name>
<family-name>Fisher</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>West Midlands</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gurbinder</given-name>
<family-name>Kalsi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>West Midlands</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Nigel</given-name>
<family-name>Spurr</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Solihull</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jean</given-name>
<family-name>Didier</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Anould</city>
<country-code>FR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alan</given-name>
<family-name>Dixon</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chester</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stephen</given-name>
<family-name>Drysdale</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Northampton</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CARLSON, GASKEY &amp; OLDS, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>400 WEST MAPLE ROAD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 350</address-2>
<city>BIRMINGHAM</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48009</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A touch sensitive access system for fitment to a vehicle and arranged such that, when touched, the means signals unlatching of a door latch of a door of said vehicle, wherein the access system is programmed only to signal unlatching once a vehicle user has ceased touching the access means. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority to Great Britain patent application numbers GB 01 14797.4 filed Jun. 16, 2001 and GB 01 21900.5 filed Sep. 11, 2001. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a vehicle access means and engagement means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> More particularly, the present invention relates to vehicle access means and engagement means that replace conventional exterior door handles mounted on vehicle doors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A number of problems are associated with the use of conventional exterior door handles. Because of the necessary positioning of exterior door handles in an ergonomic position close to the upper edge of the door panel (where it easily falls to hand) and remote from the door hinge in the case of conventional vehicle passenger doors, the styling freedom of the vehicle is restricted. Additionally, positioning is restricted due to the desire for an easy connection to the vehicle latch mechanism which is usually mounted on the rear shut face of a passenger door. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Another problem with conventional handles is associated with the punching out of a hole in the outer door panel. The hole is needed to accommodate the handle, but may also crease the exterior panel thus compromising its aesthetics. Such holes may also compromise the security of the vehicle. The fact that it is difficult to fit a handle flush with the exterior door panel results in the use of handles that generate wind noise and aerodynamic drag whilst the vehicle is in motion. The use of conventional door handles also adds weight to the vehicle and adds to the number of mechanical parts. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention seeks to overcome, or at least mitigate, the problems of the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> One aspect of the present invention is a touch sensitive access means fitted to a vehicle and arranged in use, when touched, to unlatch a door or said vehicle and/or facilitate the deployment of an engagement means to be engaged by a vehicle user to assist in the opening of the vehicle door. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention is a foot operated access means fitted to a vehicle arranged in use, when actuated, to unlatch a vehicle door and/or facilitate the deployment of an engagement means to be engaged by a vehicle user to assist in operating the vehicle door. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Another third aspect of the present invention is access means for a vehicle comprising an exterior mirror, the mirror being arranged, in use, such that engagement thereof by a vehicle user unlatches a vehicle door and/or facilitates deployment of an engagement means to be engaged by a vehicle user to assist in opening the door. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention is engagement means for engagement by a vehicle user to assist in the opening of a vehicle door, the engagement means being a handle, the handle being deployed from a retracted position, in use, in response to a signal from vehicle entry means.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the present invention will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a portion of a vehicle including access means according to one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view through a vehicle door having access means according to a second embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a cutaway side elevational view through a door having access means according to a third embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a portion of a vehicle incorporating access means according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a portion of a vehicle including access means according to a fifth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a portion of a vehicle including engagement means according to a sixth embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a portion of a vehicle including engagement means according to a seventh embodiment of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic block diagram illustrating the interrelationship and function of an access control system incorporating access means and engagement means according to an embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Conventional vehicle door handles essentially serve two functions: firstly, they act as access means to unlatch the associated door and secondly as engagement means by providing a surface that a vehicle user may engage in order to open the door once unlatched. Thus, the terms &ldquo;access means&rdquo; and &ldquo;engagement means&rdquo; as used below should be understood as means whose primary function is access and engagement respectively, although the means may also perform a secondary function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> there is shown a perspective view of a passenger door <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for a vehicle <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> such as a passenger car. In place of a conventional handle that both unlatches the vehicle and provides a surface by which a vehicle user may engage the door to open it, there is provided access means that is touch sensitive which, in this embodiment, is a touch pad <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The touch pad <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is in turn connected to a controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) and communicates therewith as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Although in this embodiment, the touch pad is shown in the position of a conventional door handle, in other embodiments the touch pad <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or other touch-sensitive means may be positioned elsewhere on the vehicle such as the passenger door window, the wing mirrors or on another vehicle panel. The touch pad <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be pressure sensitive or detect contact due to a change in its conductivity, but in either case there should be substantially no deflection of the surface being touched. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Turning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B, a</cross-reference> strain gauge <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is secured to the inner face of the outer skin <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of door <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> resulting in the outer skin <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> being, in effect, the touch sensitive means. The strain gauge is in turn connected to the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and communicates therewith as described below. It can be seen that the strain gauge <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is located in approximately the same position as touch pad <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment, but because it is located on the inner face of the door skin, the door skin is uninterrupted, and does not require any apertures to be provided therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In use, when a user contacts the appropriate region of the door skin and exerts a pressure P. The (albeit small) deformation of the skin <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> causes the conductivity of the strain gauge <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to change. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> An alternative strain gauge arrangement is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference>. In this embodiment, the gauge <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is secured in a snaking arrangement to the inner face of the door skin <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Thus, in this embodiment, the user may touch substantially anywhere on the door skin for detection by the strain gauge to occur. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments strain gauges could alternatively be arranged on the door hinge <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, latch <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, striker <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> or door seal (not shown) so as to detect pressure applied to the door <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, force transducers may be used in place of the strain gauge. Additionally or alternatively, a strain gauge may be arranged on the window seal (not shown) to detect movement of the window glass <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> relative to the rest of the door <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, or a transparent touch sensitive sheet of the type used on computer monitors and the like could be applied to the window to enable the user to gain entry by pressing on the window glass <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Turning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> there is shown a foot operated access means such as a foot operated pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> mounted to the sill area <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of a vehicle. In this embodiment, actuation of the pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in the direction A signals the controller as described in more detail below. Alternatively, the pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be pressure sensitive, so that no actual deflection occurs. In a preferred embodiment, the pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is only deployed from a stowed position in the sill <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> when actuation thereof is required, thus preventing the fouling of the pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> on foreign objects when the vehicle is in motion. One advantage of this arrangement is that the pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be actuated when the user has no free hands. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a fifth embodiment of the invention in which a vehicle wing mirror <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is used in the place of the conventional door handle as access means. In one class of embodiment, the mirror <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be simply be provided with a switch or touch-sensitive means similar to the first embodiment in order to signal the controller. Alternatively, where a vehicle is provided with powered mirrors, physical movement of the mirror <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in a direction B may be converted into a signal that is sent to the controller to initiate release as described in more detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Turning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, there is illustrated an engagement means according to a sixth embodiment of the invention. In this embodiment the engagement means comprises a deployable handle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> that in normal circumstances is retracted within the vehicle door. However, upon a signal from a vehicle controller, the handle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is deployed from the &ldquo;waistline&rdquo; (the sill portion where the door panel meets the window) <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the vehicle. In one embodiment, the handle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is merely provided as a convenient surface that a vehicle user may engage to open the door <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. However, in variant form, the handle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may also be operably connected to the vehicle latch such that engagement thereof causes the door to become unlatched. The interaction of the handle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the controller is described in more detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The engagement means according to a seventh embodiment of the invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. In this embodiment the engagement means is provided by the window sill <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the door <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Clearly, for reasons of security, the door window <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> will usually be left in a closed position when the vehicle is left unattended. However, when a signal is received from the controller as described in more detail below, this causes the window regulator (<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) to lower the window glass <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and thus enable a vehicle user to grasp the sill or top of the window glass and open the door. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> in which an overall access control system incorporating various aspects of the present invention is shown in schematic form. It can be seen that at the heart of the system is the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is preferably in the form of a microprocessor and may be a stand-alone controller for access control or may be integrated into an overall controller for a number of vehicle functions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, an authorization device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in the form of a transponder is carried by a vehicle user. When the user walks into range of a scanner <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> associated with the vehicle, the scanner <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> interrogates the authorization device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> using radio frequency or other electromagnetic waves and the like in order to determine whether that particular authorization device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> permits access to the vehicle <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. If access is permitted, the scanner <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> signals the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to unlock electrically operable door lock <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and in certain classes of embodiment to also unlatch electrically operable door latches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In installations where the authorization device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> causes just the unlocking of the door locks <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the user then actuates either touch pad <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, door skin <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, window <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> or wing mirror <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by hand or foot pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> by foot (the various alternative means being illustrated by broken lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). Actuating the relevant access means signals the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> which in turn signals the unlatching of door latches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> preferably also signals the deployment of either handle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (if fitted) or the window regulator <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to drop the window glass <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> so that a surface is available for the user to engage by hand and open the door <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. In its simplest form, however, specific engagement means may be dispensed with because the force exerted on the door by the door seals (not shown) is generally sufficient to cause the door to open enough when the door is unlatched for a user to engage an edge of the door by hand and open it. In some cases of embodiment the door hinge and/or door check may also exert an outward force that tends to cause the door to open. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, when a touch pad <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or strain gauge <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is used as an access means and is mounted on the door <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> only signals the unlatching of the door once the user ceases to touch the touch pad <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, door skin or window. This avoids the possibility of the force due to contact between the user&apos;s hand and the touch pad, door skin or window counteracting the seal force and preventing the door opening by a sufficient amount, and also substantially avoids the risk of user discomfort being caused by the door opening against their fingers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> If the vehicle is fitted with a foot pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the signal from the scanner <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> preferably causes the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to signal the lowering of the foot pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> from a retracted position in the sill to a deployed position where it may be actuated by the foot of the vehicle user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In embodiments where the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> signals the unlatching of the door latch <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in response to signals from the scanner <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the access means may be dispensed with. Similarly, in embodiments where the handle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is operably connected to the latch(es) <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the access means may be dispensed with. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Once the vehicle user has entered the vehicle and closed the door, the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> signals the retraction of the pop-up handle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or of pedal <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> as appropriate, or signals the closure of the window <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Optionally, a vehicle motion detector (not shown) may be connected to the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> such that the controller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may signal the locking of door locks <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> if the vehicle exceeds a certain predetermined speed such as 5 kilometers per hour, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> To summarize, the access means of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may operate separately or in conjunction with the engagement means of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. Likewise, the engagement means of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> may operate separately from the access means of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> It should be understood that numerous changes may be made within the scope of the present invention. For example, the system may be adapted for use with other vehicle doors such as sliding doors or rear doors and alternative types of scanner such as sonar, ultrasonic or infra-red type scanners may be used in place of a radio frequency scanner. The invention may be adapted for use with conventional remote keyless entry (RKE) &ldquo;plip&rdquo;-type locking devices rather than a passive entry system. Furthermore, touch sensitive means such as strain gauges may be employed as exit means on the inside of doors to permit exit from as well as entry to vehicles. Likewise, the engagement means described above may be deployed from the interior of the vehicle to assist in closing vehicle doors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The foregoing description is only exemplary of the principles of the invention. Many modifications and variations of the present invention are possible in light of the above teachings. The preferred examples of this invention have been disclosed, however, so that one of ordinary skill in the art would recognize that certain modifications would come within the scope of this invention. It is, therefore, to be understood that within the scope of the appended claims, the invention may be practiced otherwise than as specifically described. For that reason the following claims should be studied to determine the true scope and content of this invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A touch sensitive access system for fitment to a vehicle and arranged such that, when touched, the access system signals unlatching of a door latch of a door of the vehicle, wherein the access system is programmed to signal unlatching once a vehicle user has ceased touching the access system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system is a touch pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system is provided on the vehicle door. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system is located proximate an upper edge of a door skin of the door. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a strain gauge positioned on an inner face of the door skin detects touch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a strain gauge fitted to at least one of a hinge, a latch, a striker, and a seal of a door incorporating the door skin detects touch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system is provided on a vehicle mirror. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a strain gauge associated with a window detects touch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system further signals deployment of an engagement system arranged to be engageable by a vehicle user to assist in the opening and closing of the vehicle door. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An access system arranged such that, when actuated, the access system signals unlatching of a vehicle door latch and signals deployment of an engagement system arranged to be engageable by a vehicle user to assist in opening and closing the vehicle door. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system is a foot operated pedal fitted to a vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system is locatable in a sill area of the vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system is operably connected to a passive entry system and the access system is moved from a retracted position to a deployed position when the passive entry system signals the unlocking of the vehicle door. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a controller arranged to receive signals from the access system and control operation of the door latch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the access system is an exterior mirror arranged such engagement thereof by a vehicle user signals unlatching of the vehicle door latch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a touch sensitive device is provided on the mirror to detect engagement thereof by a vehicle user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein physical movement of the mirror is detectable to indicate engagement thereof by a vehicle user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The access system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a controller the controller being arranged to receive signals from the access system and control operation of the door latch and a passive entry system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An engagement system for engagement by a vehicle user to assist in the opening and closing of a vehicle door, the engagement system being retractable in response to a signal from a vehicle entry system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The engagement system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the engagement system is a handle deployable from a waist-line area of the vehicle door. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The engagement system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a window pane portion of the vehicle door is retractable in response to said signal from said vehicle entry system to permit engagement. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The engagement system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the vehicle entry system comprises a passive entry system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The engagement system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the vehicle entry system includes at least one of a touch sensitive access system, a foot operated access system and a vehicle exterior mirror access system having an input.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001724A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001724A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001724A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001724A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001724A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001724A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
