<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002019A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002019A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002019</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10186411</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03B021/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>353</class>
<subclass>119000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Lubricating micro-machined devices using fluorosurfactants</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301984</doc-number>
<document-date>20010630</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Seth</given-name>
<family-name>Miller</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sachse</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TEXAS INSTRUMENTS INCORPORATED</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P O BOX 655474, M/S 3999</address-1>
<city>DALLAS</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75265</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of lubricating MEMS devices using fluorosurfactants <highlight><bold>42. </bold></highlight>Micro-machined devices, such as a digital micro-mirror device (DMD&trade;) <highlight><bold>940, </bold></highlight>which make repeated contact between moving parts, require lubrication in order to prevent the onset of stiction (static friction) forces significant enough to cause the parts to stick irreversibly together, causing defects. These robust and non-corrosive fluorosurfactants <highlight><bold>42, </bold></highlight>which consists of a hydrophilic chain <highlight><bold>40 </bold></highlight>attached to a hydrophobic fluorocarbon tail <highlight><bold>41, </bold></highlight>are applied by nebulization and replace the more complex lubricating systems, including highly reactive PFDA lubricants stored in polymer getters, to keep the parts from sticking. This lubrication process, which does not require the use of getters, is easily applied and has been shown to provide long-life, lower-cost, operable MEMS devices. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to micro-electromechanical systems (MEMS) devices and particularly to lubricating the surfaces of the moving parts in such devices. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Micro-machined or micro-electro-mechanical systems (MEMS) devices, where there is repeated physical contact between moving parts, require lubrication to prevent the onset of stiction (static friction). This stiction can be strong enough to cause the parts to stick irreversibly together, making the devices inoperable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> For example, in the digital micromirror device (DMD&trade;) of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, which is one type of a MEMS device, the mirror/yoke <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> assemblies rotate on torsion hinges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> attached to support posts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> until the yoke tips <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> contact (land on) landing pads <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> located on a lower substrate layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. It is this mechanical contact between the yoke landing tips <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the landing pad sites <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> that is of particular relevance to this invention. In some cases the mirror/yoke assemblies become slow in lifting off the landing pad, affecting the response of the device and in other cases the assemblies become permanently stuck to the landing pads. One of the primary causes of stiction has been shown to be that of the landing tips scrubbing into the metal landing pads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> This &ldquo;sticking&rdquo; problem has been addressed by lubricating or passivating the metal surfaces of the devices to make them &ldquo;slick.&rdquo; Getters have been used in the device package to store the lubricants in order to maintain a low stiction environment for all moving parts over long device lifetimes. One lubricant used is powdered perfluordecanoic acid (PFDA), which tends to decrease the Van der Waals forces associated with the mirror assemblies in the DMD&trade; or any moving parts in a MEMS device, and thereby reduces the tendency for the mirrors to stick to the landing pads. However, PDFA has a very reactive molecule, which can react with other package constituents, causing severe damage to the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a drawing of a typical DMD&trade; device package. This shows the DMD&trade; <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> mounted in a package frame <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with attached cover glass (package lid) <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The cover glass <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is usually made opaque <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> on the underside with a transparent aperture for optical interfacing with the device. As mentioned, this stiction problem has normally been addressed by attempting to control the environment inside the packages. For example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates how PFDA getters <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and/or moisture gathering getters are attached to the underside of the glass cover <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by means of an adhesive <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The getters are used to both collect moisture in the package and provide lubrication (PFDA) to the moving parts in the DMD&trade;. These getters may also be installed in empty areas within the package cavity. However, the PFDA lubricants are reactive and difficult to handle in a manufacturing environment and as a result, tend to drive up the cost of packaged MEMS devices. The moisture getters are used to control rather large amounts of moisture in-the package, which should only be present if the getters themselves are misprocessed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> What is needed is a robust, non-corrosive lubricant that can be easily applied, without the use of getters, to the surface of MEMS devices to prevent the moving parts from sticking together. The fluorosurfactant lubricant of the present invention meets these requirements. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> This invention discloses a method of lubricating MEMS devices using fluorosurfactants. Micro-machined devices, which make repeated contact between moving parts, require lubrication in order to prevent the onset of stiction (static friction) forces significant enough to cause the parts to stick irreversibly together. These fluorosurfactants, which are applied by nebulization and therefore do not require the use of getters, replaces complex lubricating systems in conventional devices, including highly reactive PFDA lubricants stored in polymer getters, to keep the parts from sticking. Although fluorosurfactants are overall stickier than the commonly used PFDA lubricants, they are easy to apply, tend to be non-reactive to MEMS surfaces, and have been shown to be effective in providing longer-life, lower-cost, devices with no additional sticking parts after an initial burn-in period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Fluorosurfactants contains a hydrophilic (water like) chain attached to a hydrophobic fluorocarbon. The molecules spontaneously align with the hydrophillic regions pointed towards the surfaces of the device&apos;s moving parts with the hydrophobic fluorocarbons pointing into the air between the parts. When the moving parts touch, they are lubricated by the fluorocarbons. The material is a liquid, and if scraped away by the contacting parts, it will spontaneously flow back into the contact area, restoring lubrication around the point of contact. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> For a more complete understanding of the present invention, and the advantages thereof, reference is now made to the following descriptions taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a drawing of a DMD&trade;, one type of MEMS device, with moving part that requires lubrication to prevent the parts from sticking, thereby making the device inoperable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a drawing of a typical DMD&trade; package with getters added to provide a controlled environment to help prevent stiction between the MEMS device&apos;s moving parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a drawing showing getters used for both storing PFDA lubricants and for collecting moisture inside a typical MEMS package to help prevent the moving parts from sticking. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sketch showing the hydrophillic and hydrophobic sides of the fluorosurfactant used in the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a sketch illustrating how the fluorosurfactant lubricant molecules spontaneously align with the hydrophillic regions pointed towards the surface of the parts and the hydrophobic fluorocarbon tails pointing into the air between the moving parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a sketch illustrating the effect of surfactant lubrication of the present invention, showing the molecules spontaneously aligning with the hydrophillic regions pointed towards the surface of the moving parts in the MEMS device and the hydrophobic fluorocarbon tails pointing into the air between the moving parts, providing lubrication to the moving parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are graphs of life test data for DMD&trade; devices lubricated with the fluorosurfactant of the present invention, showing that after an initial burn-in period there are very few new defects at normal operating voltages, which indicates the effectiveness of this lubrication. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>shows over 10,000 micro-mirrors landed in the positive direction and then the mirrors being released as the applied energy is reduced. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows over 10,000 micro-mirrors landed in the negative direction and then the mirrors being released as the applied energy is reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a process flow diagram for the back-end fabrication of a MEMS device that is lubricated with the fluorosurfactant of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cut-away drawing of a wafer of DMD&trade; devices showing the rotating yoke/mirror assembly (moving part), where the surfaces are nebulized with the fluorosurfactant of the present invention to prevent sticking. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a MEMS based projection display system where the lifetime of the system is considerably extended through the nebulization of the MEMS moving parts with the fluorosurfactant of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The present invention uses a fluorosurfactant to lubricate the moving parts of a MEMS device. These fluorosurfactants are readily available materials that can be applied to the surfaces of the devices by a nebulization procedure, which is akin to spraying it on but with very small particles of the material. These lubricants, which are non-corrosive and very compatible with the MEMS fabrication process, remain robust over long extended periods of time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sketch describing the fluorosurfactant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the present invention. The surfactant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> contains a hydrophillic <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> (water like) chain or tail attached to a hydrophobic <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> fluorocarbon tail. While the hydrophillic <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> regions are capable of uniting with or taking up water, the hydrophobic fluorocarbon <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> regions do not take up water, but contain non-reactive halo-carbons; i.e., such as carbon, fluorine, and in some cases hydrogen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> When applied to a MEMS device, the surfactant molecules will display some degree of local order at the surface the device, as described in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Generally, molecules of the fluorosurfactant will spontaneously align with their fluoronated hydrophobic tails <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> pointing towards the air interface <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and the hydrophillic tails <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> pointing towards the surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the device. For some surfactants, 100 percent of the molecules will align this way to give a crystalline order. However for most surfactants there will be a few stragglers that will align in the opposite direction with the hydrophillic tail <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> pointing towards the air interface <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and the hydrophobic tail <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> pointing towards the surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, although most of the molecules will align in the correct way, as shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a sketch illustrating the effect of fluorosurfactant lubrication on the moving parts in a DMD&trade; MEMS device, where the mirror yoke <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> rotates on torsion hinges <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> until the tip <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the yoke makes contact <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> (lands on) with the landing pad <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. This illustrates the surfactant molecules properly aligned with the hydrophillic tails <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> pointing towards the surface of the landing pad <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and yoke assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, respectively, and the hydrophobic tails <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> pointing into the air interface between the moving parts. In operation, when the moving parts touch, they are lubricated by the fluorocarbons. Since the material is a liquid, when it is scraped or scrubbed away during contact of the parts, it will spontaneously flow back into the contact area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, restoring lubrication and preventing sticking of the parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are graphs showing the results of life testing DMD&trade; devices lubricated with the fluorosurfactant of the present invention. This shows data taken after the surfactant was applied at 0 hours <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> before burn-in and then for multiple additional readings <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> taken up to 5000 hours later. This shows the effectiveness of lubricating the moving parts with the fluorosurfactant of the present invention. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, sufficient energy (&gt;15 units) is applied to land over 10,000 micro-mirrors in the positive (&plus;x degrees) direction. Similarly, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, sufficient energy is applied to land over 10,000 micro-mirrors in the negative (&minus;x degrees) direction. In both cases, as the operating energy is decreased from &gt;15 units (normal operating energy is &gt;15 units) to 0 units, more than 90% of the landed mirrors lift-off their landing pads. Below 0 energy, a reset voltage is applied to lift-off the remaining mirrors that are not permanently stuck. As shown, after an initial burn-in period <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, the device stabilizes with the mirrors lifting-off consistently, without additional stuck mirrors, as the energy is decreased and the reset voltage is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a process flow diagram for the back-end fabrication of a MEMS device that is lubricated with the fluorosurfactant of the present invention. The process is comprised of fabricating wafers <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of a particular MEMS device having moving parts, partially sawing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> the devices apart but leaving them slightly attached, testing <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> the individual chips on the wafer, completing the sawing <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> or. separation of the chips, packaging the individual chips <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, nebulizing <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> by spraying the surfaces of the chips with a fine mist of the fluorosurfactant of the present invention, and attaching lids <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> or cover glasses to the package. Although shown applied at the device level, the nebulization can also be applied at the wafer level. This process uses readily available surfactants, which are robust over time, to provide lubrication to all moving parts of the MEMS device. The process is non-corrosive relative to the typical materials found in MEMS devices. A range of various surfactants can be used to prevent stiction in MEMS devices, while at the same time eliminating the need for getters and thereby reducing the packaging costs of the devices substantially. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows a small portion of a DMD&trade; <highlight><bold>940</bold></highlight> device that is built-up in four levels, these being a memory substrate level <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, an address electrode/landing pad level <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, a yoke/hinge level <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, and a mirror level <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight>, as indicated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The substrate <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> contains an orthogonal array of CMOS address circuits over which a reflective micromirror superstructure with mechanical moving parts is fabricated. A thick oxide <highlight><bold>900</bold></highlight> isolation layer, which has vias for connecting to the CMOS address circuits, is placed on top of the CMOS array in the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The mirror superstructure is then fabricated on top of this isolation layer <highlight><bold>900</bold></highlight>, beginning with an Aluminum metal-3 layer <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, which includes yoke address electrodes <highlight><bold>910</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>911</bold></highlight> and landing pads <highlight><bold>912</bold></highlight>. The address electrodes <highlight><bold>910</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>911</bold></highlight> connect through vias <highlight><bold>913</bold></highlight> to the respective binary outputs of the CMOS address circuits in the substrate <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The next layer <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> consists of the yoke <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight> and torsion hinge <highlight><bold>922</bold></highlight> structure, mirror address electrodes <highlight><bold>925</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight>, electrode post <highlight><bold>927</bold></highlight> and hinge posts <highlight><bold>923</bold></highlight> and post caps <highlight><bold>924</bold></highlight>. The yoke <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight>, which supports a mirror assembly <highlight><bold>930</bold></highlight> on the top level <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight>, is suspended in air above the metal-3 layer <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> and rotates about a diagonal axis, on the torsion hinges <highlight><bold>922</bold></highlight>, until the yoke landing tips <highlight><bold>921</bold></highlight> contact the landing pads <highlight><bold>912</bold></highlight> below. The geometry of the yoke <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight> and the spacing between the metal-3 level <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> and the yoke/hinge level <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> determines the tilt angle of the yoke/mirror structure. The hinge posts <highlight><bold>923</bold></highlight> sit on top of and in contact with the metal landing pads <highlight><bold>912</bold></highlight> at the metal-3 level <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, so that the yoke and landing pads are at the same electrical potential. The mirror address pads <highlight><bold>925</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight> are attached to the yoke addressing pads <highlight><bold>910</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>911</bold></highlight> by additional posts <highlight><bold>927</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The top level <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> consists of the reflective mirrors <highlight><bold>930</bold></highlight> and mirror posts <highlight><bold>931</bold></highlight>, which ride on top of the yoke <highlight><bold>905</bold></highlight>, tilting typically &plus;/&minus;10&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In operation, electrostatic forces cause the mirror/yoke structure <highlight><bold>930</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight> to rotate on its torsion axis, defined along the torsion hinges. These electrostatic forces are established by the voltage potential difference between the yoke address electrodes <highlight><bold>910</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>911</bold></highlight> and the yoke <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight> and between the mirror address electrodes <highlight><bold>925</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight> and the mirror <highlight><bold>930</bold></highlight>, respectively. In each case, these forces are a function of the reciprocal of the distance between the two plates; i.e., <highlight><bold>910</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>911</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>925</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>930</bold></highlight>. As the rigid yoke/mirror structure rotates on its axis, the torsion hinges <highlight><bold>922</bold></highlight> resist deformation with a restoring torque that is an approximate linear function of the angular deflection of the structure. The structure rotates until either this restoring torsion beam torque equals the established electrostatic torque or until the yoke/mirror structure is mechanically limited in its rotation, i.e., the yoke tips <highlight><bold>921</bold></highlight> land on the landing pads <highlight><bold>912</bold></highlight>. It is at this point of contact between the yoke tips <highlight><bold>921</bold></highlight> and the landing pads <highlight><bold>912</bold></highlight> that stiction occurs, which can render a particular mirror permanently inoperable or slow to respond to the electrostatic forces, thereby causing a device defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> By nebulization of the metal surfaces of the devices using the fluorosurfactant of the present invention, highly reliable, lower-cost, DMD devices can be produced. Although overall these parts have stickier surfaces than conventional PFDA lubricated parts, the mirrors have been shown to be effective in lifting off their landing pads without additional stuck mirrors, after an initial burn-in period. Test devices have been operated for a period of &gt;5000 hours with no additional stuck mirrors. This process is effective since the molecules of the fluorosurfactant spontaneously align with their fluoronated hydrophobic tails <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> pointing towards the air interface <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and between the moving parts their hydrophillic tails <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> pointing towards the moving surfaces <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the device, thereby lubricating the areas of contact between moving parts. As the lubricant is scrubbed away during contact, the surfactant quickly flows back into the area to assure a lubricated contact, thereby eliminating sticking between the parts. Also, the fluorosurfactants are non-corrosive to the typical surfaces of MEMS device, thereby leading to a long operating life for the devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a MEMS based projection display system where the lifetime of the system is considerably extended through the nebulization of the MEMS device&apos;s moving parts with the fluorosurfactant of the present invention. One example of such a system is a DMD&trade; projection display. In the projector, light from a light source <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is focused on to the MEMS DMD&trade; device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by means of a condenser lens <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, placed in the path of the light. An electronic controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, is connected to both the DMD&trade; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the light source <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and used to modulate the DMD&trade; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and to control the light source <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. For all DMD&trade; pixels positioned towards the light source (ON pixels), the incoming light beam is reflected into the focal plane of a projection lens <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, where it resized and projected on to a viewing screen <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to form an image <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, DMD&trade; pixels positioned away from the light source (OFF pixels), as well as any stray light reflected from various near flat surfaces on and around the DMD&trade;, are reflected into a dark trap <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and discarded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In operation, if a DMD&trade; mirror sticks in either the ON or OFF binary state it causes a bright white or solid black defect on the display screen, respectively. For obvious reasons, more than just a handful of these defects are unacceptable in a display. By applying the process of the present invention where all surfaces of the MEMS device are nebulized with a fluorosurfactant, the moving parts are sufficiently lubricated to eliminate the sticking of mirrors over the required long lifetimes of the projector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> While this invention has been described in the context of preferred embodiments, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that the present invention may be modified in numerous ways and may assume embodiments other than that specifically set out and described above. Accordingly, it is intended by the appended claims to cover all modifications of the invention that fall within the true spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of lubricating MEMS devices, comprising the step of nebulization of all moving surfaces of said MEMS device with a fluorosurfactant wherein 
<claim-text>said fluorosurfactant contains a water-like hydrophillic chain attached to a hydrophobic fluorocarbon. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said hydrophillic regions of said fluorosurfactant spontaneously aligns towards the surface of said moving parts of a MEMS device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said hydrophobic fluorocarbon tails of said fluorosurfactant aligns pointing into the air between the moving parts of said MEMS device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the areas of contact between said moving parts are lubricated. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said fluorosurfactant remains a liquid at the surface of said moving parts, such that when scrapped away by contacting surfaces of said moving parts, said fluorosurfactant spontaneously flows back, restoring lubrication to said contact area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said fluorosurfactant is non-corrosive to the surfaces of said MEMS devices, thereby contributing to highly-reliable, long-life, operating parts. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A back-end process for fabricating MEMS devices with fluorosurfactant lubricated micro-machined parts, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>fabricating a wafer of said MEMS devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>partially sawing said wafer of said MEMS devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>testing said wafer of said partially sawn MEMS devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>completing sawing said wafer of said MEMS devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>packaging operable devices from said sawn wafer of MEMS devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>lubricating all surfaces of said packaged MEMS devices by applying a nebulized fluorosurfactant to said surfaces, wherein said fluorosurfactant contains a water-like hydrophillic chain attached to a hydrophobic fluorocarbon; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching a lid to said package. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said hydrophillic regions of said fluorosurfactant spontaneously aligns towards the surface of said moving parts of a MEMS device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said hydrophobic fluorocarbon tails of said fluorosurfactant aligns pointing into the air between the moving parts of said MEMS device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the areas of contact between said moving parts are lubricated. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said fluorosurfactant remains a liquid at the surface of said moving parts, such that when scrapped away by contacting surfaces of said moving parts, said fluorosurfactant spontaneously flows back, restoring lubrication to said contact area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of lubricating all surfaces of said MEMS devices at the wafer level by applying a nebulized fluorosurfactant to said surfaces. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A MEMS device operable for modulating light having fluorosurfactant lubricated moving parts, comprising: 
<claim-text>a silicon substrate consisting of an array of CMOS memory circuits; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a planarized thick oxide isolation layer deposited on top of said substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>metal yoke address electrodes and landing pads fabricated over said planarized isolation layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotating yoke assembly attached to thin metal torsion hinges, said hinges supported by hinge posts extending above said landing pad metal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>mirror address electrodes attached to top of additional posts extending above said yoke address pads; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>highly reflectively metal mirrors mounted to mirror posts attached to and extending above said rotating yoke assembly, wherein 
<claim-text>all surfaces of said MEMS device are lubricated to prevent sticking by means of a fluorosurfactant nebulization, said fluorosurfactant containing a water-like hydrophillic chain attached to a hydrophobic fluorocarbon. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said hydrophillic regions of said fluorosurfactant spontaneously aligns towards the surface of said moving parts of a MEMS device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said hydrophobic fluorocarbon tails of said fluorosurfactant aligns pointing into the air between the moving parts of said MEMS device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the areas of contact between said moving parts are lubricated. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said fluorosurfactant remains a liquid at the surface of said moving parts, such that when scrapped away by contacting surfaces of said moving parts, said fluorosurfactant spontaneously flows back, restoring lubrication to said contact area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said yoke assembly rotates due to electrostatic forces until the tips of said yoke assembly contact said landing pads, said contact area being lubricated by a flow of fluorosurfactant lubricant to prevent the sticking of said moving parts between said yoke tips and landing pads. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A projection display system using a MEMS spatial light modulator with fluorosurfactant lubricated moving parts to prevent sticking of said parts, comprising: 
<claim-text>a light source for producing a beam of light along a first light path; </claim-text>
<claim-text>light condensing optics in said first light path for focusing said light on to the surface of said MEMS spatial light modulator; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said MEMS spatial light modulator receiving said focused light from said condensing optics, said light being modulated on a pixel-by-pixel basis and reflected off said spatial light modulator surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>control electronics for receiving image data and controlling the modulation of said light focused on to the surface of said MEMS spatial light modulator; </claim-text>
<claim-text>light reflected off said MEMS spatial light modulator&apos;s binary-ON pixels being reflected along a second light path; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection lens inserted in said second light path; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection viewing screen receiving light from said projection lens in said second light path to form of a visible image; </claim-text>
<claim-text>light reflected off said spatial light modulator&apos;s binary-OFF pixels being reflected along a third light path; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a light trap for receiving and discarding reflected light along said third light path; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the moving parts of said light modulator being lubricating with a fluorosurfactant. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The display system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said MEMS spatial light modulator further comprises: 
<claim-text>a silicon substrate having a digital memory array; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a planarized oxide isolation layer attached to the top of said memory array; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a metal yoke address electrode and landing pad layer attached to the top of said oxide layer, metal yoke and hinge assemblies suspended by posts above said address electrodes on landing pad layer by means of metal posts; </claim-text>
<claim-text>metal mirror address electrodes extended on posts above said yoke address electrodes; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>metal mirrors attached to said yokes by means of metal mirror posts. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The display system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said yoke/hinge/mirror structure is suspended above said landing pad layer and is operable to rotate through positive and negative angles due to electrostatic forces established by an electric field created by a voltage potential difference applied between said yoke address electrodes and said yoke assembly and simultaneously between said mirror address electrodes and said mirror; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said yoke having landing tips that come in contact with said landing pads to mechanically limit said rotation at a precise angle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said contact area being lubricated by fluorosurfactant nebulization to prevent the sticking of moving parts, wherein said fluorosurfactant contains a water-like hydrophillic chain attached to a hydrophobic fluorocarbon. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said hydrophillic regions of said fluorosurfactant spontaneously aligns towards the surface of said moving parts of a MEMS device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said hydrophobic fluorocarbon regions of said fluorosurfactant aligns pointing into the air between the moving parts of said MEMS device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the areas of contact between said moving parts are lubricated. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said fluorosurfactant remains a liquid at the surface of said moving parts, such that when scrapped away by contacting surfaces of said moving parts, said fluorosurfactant spontaneously flows back, restoring lubrication to said contact area.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002019A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
