<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001182A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001182A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001182A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001182A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001182A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001182A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001182</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10232794</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020828</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L027/108</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>296000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Memory integrated circuitry</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10232794</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020828</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09930787</doc-number>
<document-date>20010814</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09930787</doc-number>
<document-date>20010814</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>08842230</doc-number>
<document-date>19970422</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6297129</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Luan</given-name>
<family-name>Tran</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Meridian</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alan</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Reinberg</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>WELLS ST. JOHN ROBERTS GREGORY &amp; MATKIN P.S.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>601 W. FIRST AVENUE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1300</address-2>
<city>SPOKANE</city>
<state>WA</state>
<postalcode>99201-3828</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Memory integrated circuitry includes an array of memory cells formed over a semiconductive substrate and occupying area thereover, at least some memory cells of the array being formed in lines of active area formed within the semiconductive substrate which are continuous between adjacent memory cells, said adjacent memory cells being isolated from one another relative to the continuous active area formed therebetween by a conductive line formed over said continuous active area between said adjacent memory cells. At least some adjacent lines of continuous active area within the array are isolated from one another by LOCOS field oxide formed therebetween. The respective area consumed by individual of said adjacent memory cells is ideally equal to less than 8F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, where &ldquo;F&rdquo; is no greater than 0.25 micron and is defined as equal to one-half of minimum pitch, with minimum pitch being defined as equal to the smallest distance of a line width plus width of a space immediately adjacent said line on one side of said line between said line and a next adjacent line in a repeated pattern within the array. The respective area is preferably no greater than about 7F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, and most preferably no greater than about 6F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to formation of memory integrated circuitry. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The reduction in memory cell and other circuit size required for high density dynamic random access memories (DRAMs) and other circuitry is a continuing goal in semiconductor fabrication. Implementing electric circuits involves connecting isolated devices through specific electric paths. When fabricating silicon and other material into integrated circuits, it is necessary to isolate devices built into the substrate from one another. Electrical isolation of devices as circuit density increases is a continuing challenge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> One method of isolating devices involves the formation of a semi-recessed or fully recessed oxide in the non-active (or field) area of the substrate. These regions are typically termed as &ldquo;field oxide&rdquo; and are formed by LOCal Oxidation of exposed Silicon, commonly known as LOCOS. One approach in forming such oxide is to cover the active regions with a layer of silicon nitride that prevents oxidation from occurring therebeneath. A thin intervening layer of a sacrificial pad oxide is provided intermediate the silicon substrate and nitride layer to alleviate stress and protect the substrate from damage during subsequent removal of the nitride layer. The unmasked or exposed field regions of the substrate are then subjected to a wet (H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O) oxidation, typically at atmospheric pressure and at temperatures of around 1000&deg; C., for two to four hours. This results in field oxide growth where there is no masking nitride. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> However at the edges of the nitride, some oxidant also diffuses laterally. This causes the oxide to grow under and lift the nitride edges. Because the shape of the oxide at the nitride edges is that of a slowly tapering oxide wedge that merges into another previously formed layer of oxide, it has commonly been referred to as a &ldquo;bird&apos;s beak&rdquo;. The bird&apos;s beak is a lateral extension or encroachment of the field oxide into the active areas where the devices are formed. Although the length of the bird&apos;s beak depends upon a number of parameters, the length is typically from 0.05 micron&mdash;0.15 micron per side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> This thinner area of oxide resulting from the bird&apos;s beak provides the disadvantage of not providing effective isolation in these regions, and as well unnecessarily consumes precious real estate on the semiconductor wafer. Further, as circuit density commonly referred to as device pitch falls below 1.0 micron, conventional LOCOS techniques begin to fail due to excessive encroachment of the oxide beneath the masking stack. The closeness of the masking block stacks in such instances can result in effective joining of adjacent bird&apos;s beaks, thus effectively lifting the masking stacks and resulting in no masking effect to the oxidation. To prevent this, LOCOS active area masks typically need to be spaced further apart than the minimum capable photolithographic feature dimension where such falls below 0.3 micron, especially where 2-dimensional encroachment occurs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The problem is exemplified in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. There illustrated is an array <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of staggered active area regions or islands <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of a dynamic random access memory array. The areas surrounding each of the subject islands would constitute LOCOS field oxide. Active area islands <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are formed along a line <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> along which a plurality of DRAM cells are ultimately formed. Islands <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> form a part of another line along which DRAM cells of the array are formed. Dimension <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> constitutes a separation distance between adjacent lines of active area, whereas dimension <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> constitutes the separation distance between adjacent active areas in the same line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Unfortunately, dimension <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> typically ends up being at least 1.5 times as great as dimension <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> because of the bird&apos;s beak encroachment in two directions. Specifically, the ends of the desired active areas are subjected to bird&apos;s beak oxide encroachment both from the ends of the desired active area regions as well as laterally from the sides of such regions. However at the lateral edges of the particular active area mask not at an end, such as where the arrowhead of dimension <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in region <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is shown contacting the active area edge, the field oxide mask is only exposed to one dimensional oxide encroachment, that being only from laterally outside. Accordingly, the degree of encroachment is not as great along the edges as at the ends of the active area masks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrated layout is typically utilized to result in individual memory cells throughout the array occupying area equal to 8F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. A folded bit line array architecture is also utilized to provide acceptable and superior signal-to-noise performance in conjunction with the 8F<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>cell array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> LOCOS field oxide isolation is generally accepted within the industry to fail when the minimum photolithographic feature dimension falls below 0.3 micron due to the above end-to-end encroachment. The typical alternate isolation technique in such instances is trench isolation. For example, an article by Chatterjee et al. from the 1996 Symposium On VLSI Technology Digest Of Technical Papers, at page 156, entitled, &ldquo;A Shallow Trench Isolation Study For 0.25/0.18 Micron CMOS Technologies and Beyond&rdquo;, provides that &ldquo;As high performance CMOS technology is scaled down to the current 0.35-0.25 micron generation, shallow trench isolation (STI) becomes indispensable due to its advantages compared to the conventional LOCOS-type isolation, viz. smaller channel-width encroachment, better isolation/latch-up characteristics, planar topography, and smaller junction edge capacitance.&rdquo; &lsqb;emphasis added&rsqb; In STI, trenches are formed in the semiconductive substrate and filled with oxide such that the LOCOS bird&apos;s beak is eliminated. Trench isolation does, however, have its own other processing drawbacks. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, the invention provides memory integrated circuitry having at least some individual memory cell size of less than 8F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, where &ldquo;F&rdquo; is defined as equal to one-half of minimum pitch, with minimum pitch being defined as equal to the smallest distance of a line width plus width of a space immediately adjacent said line on one side of said line between said line and a next adjacent line in a repeated pattern within the array. In one preferred implementation, adjacent memory cells are isolated from one another by field oxide where &ldquo;F&rdquo; is no greater than 0.25 micron. In another aspect, at least some of those memory cells of the array are formed in lines of active area which are continuous between adjacent memory cells in the line, with said adjacent memory cells being isolated from one another by a conductive line over said continuous active area between said adjacent memory cells. In yet another aspect, the invention provides the memory circuitry in the form of DRAM having word lines and bit lines, with the bit lines preferably comprising D and D* lines formed in a folded bit line architecture within the array. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments of the invention are described below with reference to the following accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top diagrammatic view of an active area layout of a portion of a prior art dynamic random access memory array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top diagrammatic partial view of a portion of an array and peripheral circuitry thereto of dynamic random access memory circuitry in accordance with the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top diagrammatic partial view utilized in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> array illustrating a preferred folded bit line architecture.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> This disclosure of the invention is submitted in furtherance of the constitutional purposes of the U.S. patent Laws &ldquo;to promote the progress of science and useful arts&rdquo; (Article 1, Section 8). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top view of a portion of a semiconductive substrate (such as monocrystalline silicon) illustrating memory integrated circuitry <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> comprising an array area <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of memory cells and peripheral circuitry area <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. In the context of this document, the term &ldquo;semiconductive substrate&rdquo; is defined to mean any construction comprising semiconductive material, including, but not limited to, bulk semiconductive materials such as a semiconductive wafer (either alone or in assemblies comprising other materials thereon), and semiconductive material layers (either alone or in assemblies comprising other materials). The term &ldquo;substrate&rdquo; refers to any supporting structure, including, but not limited to, the semiconductive substrates described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> An array of word lines <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is formed over the substrate. An array of bit lines and capacitors (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) are formed outwardly of word lines <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. Continuous lines of active area <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are formed within the silicon substrate beneath word lines <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. Continuous active areas <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are ideally formed in substantially straight lines throughout the array, run perpendicularly relative to word lines <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, and alternatingly extend to opposing peripheral circuitry areas, as shown. Channel stop implants (not shown) are also preferably provided between active area lines <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to minimize cell to cell leakage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Conductive isolation lines <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, extending substantially parallel with word lines <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, run substantially perpendicular with and are formed over continuous active area lines <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Isolation lines <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> serve to electrically isolate immediately adjacent memory cells along a given continuous active area line within the array which do not share a common bit contact from one another. Such lines are subjected to a suitable potential, such as ground or a negative voltage, to effectively provide such isolation function. Isolation lines <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> alternate throughout the array between respective pairs of two adjacent word lines <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> between which bit contacts are formed. The illustrated word lines <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and isolation lines <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are ideally formed utilizing photolithography to have respective conductive widths which are less than or equal to 0.25 micron, and as well to preferably provide separation between the conductive areas of immediately adjacent lines at also less than or equal to 0.25 micron. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Further, preferably all of the continuous active area lines within the array are formed with and isolated from one another by LOCOS oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> formed therebetween. Such are most preferably formed utilizing nitride LOCOS masking material provided by photolithography where the distance between immediately adjacent nitride masking blocks is less than or equal to 0.25 micron. The field oxide is also most desirably grown to be less than or equal to 2500 Angstroms thick to minimize bird&apos;s beak encroachment into each active area to less than or equal to 0.05 micron per side where device pitch (device width plus the space between immediately adjacent devices) is 0.4 micron or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Circles <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> represent exemplary storage node contacts for DRAM capacitors formed along one continuous active area line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Such are not shown in the adjacent continuous active area regions for clarity in the drawings. Circles <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> represent bit line contacts. Bit line contact <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is shared by the two DRAM cells which utilize contacts <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> to connect active area with the respective storage nodes of the capacitors. Outline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> represents that area consumed over the substrate by an exemplary individual memory cell of the DRAM array. Such is equal to about 3F&times;2F, or less, where &ldquo;F&rdquo; is defined as equal to one-half of minimum pitch, with minimum pitch (i.e., &ldquo;P&rdquo;) being defined as equal to the smallest distance of a line width (i.e., &ldquo;W&rdquo;) plus width of a space immediately adjacent said line on one side of said line between said line and a next adjacent line in a repeated pattern within the array (i.e., &ldquo;S&rdquo;). Thus in the preferred implementation, the consumed area of a given cell is no greater than about 6F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, which is less than 8F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. Alternately, but less preferred, the consumed area is no greater than about 7F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. Ideally, &ldquo;F&rdquo; is no greater than 0.25 micron. Utilization of continuous active area as described above facilitates limiting bird&apos;s beak encroachment to one dimension and facilitates utilization of LOCOS isolation between active area lines where &ldquo;F&rdquo; falls below 0.3 micron. Accordingly at &ldquo;F&rdquo; equal to 0.25 micron, the area consumed by most if not all individual memory cells within the array will be less than 0.5 micron<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, more preferably no greater than 0.4375, micron<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, and most preferably no greater than 0.375 micron<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiments of the invention are ideally encompassed in a folded bit line array, such as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Such comprises a plurality of sense amplifiers <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> having respective pairs of true &ldquo;D&rdquo; bit lines <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and complement &ldquo;D*&rdquo; bit lines <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>&prime; extending from one side of the amplifiers. Memory cells are formed and the intersections of bit lines <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and wordlines <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and of bit lines <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>&prime; and word lines <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> U.S. patent application Ser. No. 08/530,661 listing Brent Keeth and Pierre Fazan as inventors is incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In compliance with the statute, the invention has been described in language more or less specific as to structural and methodical features. It is to be understood, however, that the invention is not limited to the specific features shown and described, since the means herein disclosed comprise preferred forms of putting the invention into effect. The invention is, therefore, claimed in any of its forms or modifications within the proper scope of the appended claims appropriately interpreted in accordance with the doctrine of equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Memory integrated circuitry comprising: 
<claim-text>an array of memory cells formed in lines over a semiconductive substrate and occupying area thereover, the respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array being equal to less than 8F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, where &ldquo;F&rdquo; is no greater than 0.25 micron and is defined as equal to one-half of minimum pitch, with minimum pitch being defined as equal to the smallest distance of a line width plus width of a space immediately adjacent said line on one side of said line between said line and a next adjacent line in a repeated pattern within the array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least some of the minimum pitch adjacent lines of memory cells within the array being isolated from one another by LOCOS field oxide formed therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the memory cells comprise DRAM cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein individual of the lines of memory cells are substantially straight throughout the array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the LOCOS field oxide between adjacent lines is less than or equal to 2500 Angstroms thick. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than about 7F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells if within the array is no greater than about 6F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Memory integrated circuitry comprising: 
<claim-text>an array of memory cells formed over a semiconductive substrate and occupying area thereover, at least some memory cells of the array being formed in lines of active area formed within the semiconductive substrate which are continuous between adjacent memory cells, said adjacent memory cells being isolated from one another relative to the continuous active area formed therebetween by a conductive line formed over said continuous active area between said adjacent memory cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the respective area consumed by individual of said adjacent memory cells being equal to less than 8F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, where &ldquo;F&rdquo; is no greater than 0.25 micron and is defined as equal to one-half of minimum pitch, with minimum pitch being defined as equal to the smallest distance of a line width plus width of a space immediately adjacent said line on one side of said line between said line and a next adjacent line in a repeated pattern within the array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least some of the minimum pitch adjacent lines of memory cells within the array being isolated from one another by LOCOS field oxide formed therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein individual of the lines of continuous active area are substantially straight throughout the array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the LOCOS field oxide between adjacent lines is less than or equal to 2500 Angstroms thick. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the memory cells comprise DRAM cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than about 7F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than about 6F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Dynamic random access memory circuitry comprising: 
<claim-text>an array of word lines and bit lines formed over a semiconductive substrate defining an array of DRAM cells occupying area over the semiconductive substrate, at least some DRAM cells of the array being formed in lines of active area formed within the semiconductive substrate beneath the word lines and which are continuous between adjacent DRAM cells, said adjacent DRAM cells being isolated from one another relative to the continuous active area formed therebetween by a conductive line formed over said continuous active area between said adjacent DRAM cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the respective area consumed by individual of said adjacent memory cells being equal to less than 8F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, where &ldquo;F&rdquo; is no greater than 0.25 micron and is defined as equal to one-half of minimum pitch, with minimum pitch being defined as equal to the smallest distance of a line width plus width of a space immediately adjacent said line on one side of said line between said line and a next adjacent line in a repeated pattern within the array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least some of the minimum pitch adjacent lines of memory cells within the array being isolated from one another by LOCOS field oxide formed therebetween; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the bit lines comprise D and D* lines formed in a folded bit line architecture within the array. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein individual of the lines of continuous active area are substantially straight throughout the array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the LOCOS field oxide between adjacent lines is less than or equal to 2500 Angstroms thick. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than about 7F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than about 6F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Dynamic random access memory circuitry comprising: 
<claim-text>an array of word lines and bit lines formed over a bulk silicon semiconductive substrate defining an array of DRAM cells occupying area over the semiconductive substrate, the word lines and bit lines having respective conductive widths which are less than or equal to 0.25 micron, the DRAM cells within the array being formed in lines of active area formed within the silicon substrate beneath the word lines and which are continuous between adjacent DRAM cells, said adjacent DRAM cells being isolated from one another relative to the continuous active area formed therebetween by respective conductive lines formed over said continuous active area between said adjacent DRAM cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least some adjacent lines of continuous active area within the array being isolated from one another by LOCOS field oxide formed therebetween, said LOCOS field oxide having a thickness of no greater than 2500 Angstroms; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the respective area consumed by individual of said adjacent memory cells being equal to less than 0.5 micron<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the bit lines comprise D and D* lines formed in a folded bit line architecture within the array. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein individual of the lines of continuous active area are substantially straight throughout the array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than 0.4375 micron<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than 0.375 micron<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Dynamic random access memory circuitry comprising: 
<claim-text>an array of word lines and bit lines formed over a semiconductive substrate defining an array of DRAM cells occupying area over the semiconductive substrate, at least some DRAM cells of the array being formed in lines of active area formed within the semiconductive substrate beneath the word lines and which are continuous between adjacent DRAM cells, said adjacent DRAM cells being isolated from one another relative to the continuous active area formed therebetween by a conductive line formed over said continuous active area between said adjacent DRAM cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the respective area consumed by individual of said adjacent memory cells being equal to less than 8F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, where &ldquo;F&rdquo; is defined as equal to one-half of minimum pitch, with minimum pitch being defined as equal to the smallest distance of a line width plus width of a space immediately adjacent said line on one side of said line between said line and a next adjacent line in a repeated pattern within the array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the bit lines comprise D and D* lines formed in a folded bit line architecture within the array. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein individual of the lines of continuous active area are substantially straight throughout the array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein F is no greater than 0.25 micron. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than about 7F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The memory integrated circuitry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said respective area consumed by at least some individual memory cells within the array is no greater than about 6F<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001182A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001182A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001182A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
