<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002312A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002312A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002312</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896616</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010630</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11C027/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/31</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>046000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>763000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Pore structure for programmable device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tyler</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lowrey</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TROP PRUNER &amp; HU, PC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>8554 KATY FREEWAY</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 100</address-2>
<city>HOUSTON</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>77024</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In an aspect, an apparatus is provided that sets and reprograms the state of programmable devices. In an aspect, the quantity of programmable material is minimized, and the programmable material that is reprogrammed from an amorphous to a crystalline state, and vice versa, is localized on a contact. In an aspect, a method is provided such that an opening is formed through a dielectric exposing a contact formed on a substrate. A spacer is formed within the opening and a programmable material is formed within the opening such that the spacer reduces the programmable material on the contact. A conductor is formed on the programmable material and the contact transmits to a signal line. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Programmable devices, including phase change memory devices that can be programmed by modifying the state of a phase change material. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Typical computers, or computer related devices, include physical memory, usually referred to as main memory or random access memory (RAM). Generally, RAM is memory that is available to computer programs and read-only memory (ROM) is memory that is used, for example, to store programs that boot a computer and perform diagnostics. Typical memory applications include dynamic random access memory (DRAM), static random access memory (SRAM), erasable programmable read-only memory (EPROM), and electrically erasable programmable read-only memory (EEPROM). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Solid state memory devices typically employ micro-electronic circuit elements for each memory bit (e.g., one to four transistors per bit) in memory applications. Since one or more electronic circuit elements are required for each memory bit, these devices may consume considerable chip &ldquo;real estate&rdquo; to store a bit of information, which limits the density of a memory chip. The primary &ldquo;non-volatile&rdquo; memory element of these devices, such as an EEPROM, typically employ a floating gate field effect transistor device that has limited re-programmability and which holds a charge on the gate of field effect transistor to store each memory bit. These classes of memory devices are also relatively slow to program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Phase change memory devices use phase change materials, i.e., materials that can be electrically switched between a generally amorphous and a generally crystalline state, for electronic memory application. One type of memory element originally developed by Energy Conversion Devices, Inc. of Troy, Mich. utilizes a phase change material that can be, in one application, electrically switched between a structural state of generally amorphous and generally crystalline local order or between different detectable states of local order across the entire spectrum between completely amorphous and completely crystalline states. Typical materials suitable for such application include those utilizing various chalcogenide elements. These electrical memory devices typically do not use field effect transistor devices as the memory storage element, but comprise, in the electrical context, a monolithic body of thin film chalcogenide material. As a result, very little chip real estate is required to store a bit of information, thereby providing for inherently high density memory chips. The state change materials are also truly non-volatile in that, when set in either a crystalline, semi-crystalline, amorphous, or semi-amorphous state representing a resistance value, that value is retained until reprogrammed as that value represents a physical state of the material (e.g., crystalline or amorphous). Thus, phase change memory materials represent a significant improvement in non-volatile memory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> One characteristic common to solid state and phase change memory devices is significant power consumption particularly in setting or reprogramming memory elements. Power consumption is significant, particularly in portable devices that rely on power cells (e.g., batteries). It would be desirable to decrease the power consumption of a memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Another characteristic common to solid state and phase change memory devices is limited reprogrammable cycle life from/to an amorphous and crystalline state. Further, over time the phase change material can fail to reliably reprogram from/to an amorphous and a crystalline state. It would be desirable to increase the programmable cycle life of the phase change memory material.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Advantages of the invention will become apparent upon reading the following detailed description and upon reference to the drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an embodiment of an array of memory elements; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> schematically illustrates a cross-sectional planar side view of a portion of a semiconductor substrate having dielectric trenches formed therein defining a z-direction thickness of a memory cell in accordance with one embodiment of forming a memory element on a substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, through the same cross-sectional view, after the introduction of dopants to form an isolation device for a memory element; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> after forming trenches; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> depicts a schematic top view of the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> after forming contacts; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, through the same cross-sectional view, after forming a masking material and a dielectric material; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> depicts another cross-section view of the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, after forming an opening through the dielectric exposing the contact; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, through the same cross-sectional view, after conformally forming a spacer within the opening; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, through the same cross-sectional view, after etching the spacer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> depicts the same cross-sectional view of the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, after forming programmable material, a barrier and a conductor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> depicts the same cross-sectional view of the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, after patterning the programmable material, barrier and conductor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> depicts another cross-sectional view of the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> depicts the same cross-sectional view of the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, after forming a dielectric material and a signal line; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> depicts one method of forming a memory device having a structure similar to that described by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> depicts one system embodiment including a memory having a structure similar to that described by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Exemplary embodiments are described with reference to specific configurations. Those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that various changes and modifications can be made while remaining within the scope of the appended claims. Additionally, well-known elements, devices, components, circuits, process steps and the like may not be set forth in detail in order to avoid obscuring the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A memory device utilizing programmable material to determine the state of memory elements of the device is described that reprograms to an amorphous and crystalline state with improved (generally lower) power consumption relative to previous devices. In an embodiment, a minimized quantity of programmable (e.g. phase change) material is utilized, and the programmable material to be set/reprogrammed is localized on a contact with generally even current distribution. In another embodiment, a method of fabricating a programmable memory device is described such that an opening is formed through a dielectric exposing a contact formed on a substrate. A spacer is formed within the opening and programmable material is subsequently formed within the opening. The spacer minimizes the programmable material on the contact and minimizes the overall quantity of programmable material utilized by the memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The described memory device and method provides improved device reliability, improved programmable cycle life, and lower cost and scalability relative to previous devices. Further, in an embodiment, the apparatus is manufacturable with conventional process toolsets and facilities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a schematic diagram of an embodiment of a memory array comprised of a plurality of memory elements presented and formed in the context of the description provided herein. In this example, the circuit of memory array <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes an xy grid with memory elements <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> electrically interconnected in series with isolation devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> on a portion of a chip. Address lines <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (e.g., columns) and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (e.g., rows) are connected, in one embodiment, to external addressing circuitry in a conventional manner. One purpose of the xy grid array of memory elements in combination with isolation devices is to enable each discrete memory element to be read and written without interfering with the information stored in adjacent or remote memory elements of the array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> A memory array such as memory device <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> can be formed in a portion, including the entire portion, of a substrate. A typical substrate includes a semiconductor substrate such as a silicon substrate. Other substrates including, but not limited to, substrates that contain ceramic material, organic material, or glass material as part of the infrastructure are also suitable. In the case of a silicon semiconductor substrate, memory array <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> can be fabricated over an area of the substrate at the wafer level and then the wafer reduced through singulation into discrete die or chips, some or all of the die or chips having a memory array formed thereon. Additional addressing circuitry (e.g., decoders, etc.) can be formed as known to those of skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> illustrate an embodiment of the fabrication of representative memory element <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> depicts a portion of substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> that is, for example, a semiconductor (e.g., silicon) substrate. In this example, a P-type dopant such as boron is introduced in portion <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In one example, a suitable concentration of P-type dopant is on the order of about 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>19 </superscript></highlight>to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>20 </superscript></highlight>atoms per cubic centimeters (atoms/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>) rendering portion <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> representatively P<highlight><superscript>&plus;&plus;</superscript></highlight>. Overlying portion <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, in this example, is portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of P-type epitaxial silicon. In one example, the dopant concentration is on the order of about 10<highlight><superscript>16 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>17 </superscript></highlight>atoms/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> also depicts shallow trench isolation (STI) structures <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> formed in epitaxial portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. As will become apparent in the subsequent discussion, STI structures <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> serve, in one aspect, to define the z-direction thickness of a memory cell, with at this point only the z-direction thickness of a memory cell defined. In one embodiment, memory cell z-direction regions <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>B are patterned as strips with the x-direction dimension greater than the z-direction dimension. In another aspect, STI structures <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> serve to isolate individual memory elements from one another as well as associated circuit elements (e.g., transistor devices) formed in and on the substrate. Current state of the art photolithography techniques utilized to pattern STI structures define the z-direction thickness of memory cell regions <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>B can produce feature sizes (z-direction thickness) as small as 0.25 microns (&mgr;m). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> after further fabrication operations in memory cell regions <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>B. Within each memory cell region (strip), overlying epitaxial portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is first conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. In one example, first conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is N-type doped polysilicon formed by the introduction of, for example, phosphorous or arsenic to a concentration on the order of about 10<highlight><superscript>18 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>19 </superscript></highlight>atoms/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>(e.g., N<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> silicon). In this example, first conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> serves as an address line, a row line (e.g., row line <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). Overlying first conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is an isolation device (e.g., isolation device <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). In one example, the isolation device is a PN diode formed of N-type silicon portion <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (e.g., dopant concentration on the order of about 10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>18 </superscript></highlight>atoms/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>) and P-type silicon portion <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> (e.g., dopant concentration on the order of about 10<highlight><superscript>19 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>20 </superscript></highlight>atoms/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>). Although a PN diode is shown, it is to be appreciated that other isolation structures are similarly suitable. Such devices include, but are not limited to, metal oxide semiconductor (MOS) devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> from an xy perspective after forming trenches <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> in epitaxial portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Trenches <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> are formed, in this example, orthogonal to STI structures <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Trenches <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> define the x-direction thickness of a memory cell. According to current photolithographic techniques, a suitable feature size for the x-direction thickness is as small as 0.25 &mgr;m. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> also depicts memory cells <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>B separated by trenches <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>, having a z-direction thickness defined by STI structures <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and an x-direction thickness defined by trenches <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>. The definition of the x-direction thickness involves, in one embodiment, an etch to the conductor or signal line <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> of the memory line stack to define memory cells <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>B of memory cell region <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>A. In the case of an etch, the etch proceeds through the memory line stack to, in this example, a portion of conductor or signal line <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. A timed etch can be utilized to stop an etch at this point. Following the patterning, N-type dopant is introduced at the base of each trench <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> to form pockets <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> having a dopant concentration on the order of about 10<highlight><superscript>18 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>20 </superscript></highlight>atoms/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>(e.g., N<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>region) between memory cells <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Following the introduction of pockets <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, a dielectric material such as silicon dioxide is introduced in trenches <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> to form STI structures <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. The superior surface (as viewed) may then be planarized with, for example, a chemical-mechanical polish. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> depicts an xz perspective of the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> with memory cells (e.g., memory cells <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>B) separated by STI structures <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> (i.e., an xy perspective) following the formation of a material of, in this example, refractory metal silicide such as cobalt silicide (CoSi<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) in a portion of p-type silicon portion <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to define contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, in one aspect, serves as a low resistance material in the fabrication of peripheral circuitry (e.g., addressing circuitry) of the circuit structure on the chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> after the introduction of masking material <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. As will become more clear later, masking material <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> serves, in one sense, as an etch stop for a subsequent etch operation. In one embodiment, a suitable material for masking material <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> is a dielectric material such as silicon nitride (Si<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> also depicts dielectric material <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> introduced over the structure to a thickness on the order of 100 &angst; to 50,000 &angst; sufficient to blanket memory cells <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>B. In one embodiment, dielectric material <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. In another embodiment, dielectric material <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is a material selected for its reduced thermal conductivity, &kgr;, preferably a thermal conductivity less than &kgr;<highlight><subscript>SiO</subscript></highlight><highlight><subscript><highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></subscript></highlight>, more preferably three to 10 times less &kgr;<highlight><subscript>SiO</subscript></highlight><highlight><subscript><highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></subscript></highlight>. As a general convention, SiO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and Si<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>have &kgr; values on the order of 1.0. Thus, in addition to SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, suitable materials for dielectric material <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> include those materials that have &kgr; values less than 1.0. Certain high temperature polymers having &kgr; values less than 1.0, include carbide materials, Aerogel, Xerogel (&kgr; on the order of 0.1) and their derivatives. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, through the same cross-sectional view, after forming openings <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> through dielectric <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and masking material <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>, exposing contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, openings <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> are formed by patterning of circular holes etched through dielectric <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and masking material <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>, using conventional photolithography and dry etching techniques. In terms of state of the art photolithography techniques, circular openings as small as 0.25 &mgr;m in diameter can be patterned. It is to be appreciated that, in addition to circular openings, other openings such as rectangular openings could alternatively be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, through the same cross-sectional view, after forming spacer material <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> within openings <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and on dielectric <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, spacer material <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> is conformally formed, for example by chemical vapor deposition of tetra-ethyl-ortho-silicate (TEOS) on the substrate. At this point of fabrication, spacer material covers contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> within openings <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> after spacer material <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> is etched to form dielectric spacers (spacer material portions <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>A) inside openings <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, spacer material <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> is anisotropically etched using a timed etch. In one aspect, that will become more clear later, spacer material <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> serves to reduce the quantity of programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>) on contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> after introducing programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> within openings <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, on contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and on dielectric <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, a phase change material that has a property such that a physical state (e.g., crystalline, amorphous) can be modified with the application of an amount of energy (e.g., electrical energy, thermal energy). Chalcogenide materials having the general formula are known to be suitable for this purpose such that chalcogenide materials can be introduced on the substrate and on contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> by conventional deposition techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As further illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, following the introduction of programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, barrier material <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> is formed on programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> and conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is formed on barrier material <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>, in accordance with an embodiment. Barrier material <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> serves, in an aspect, to prevent any chemical reaction between programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> and conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. In an embodiment, programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, spacer <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>, barrier material <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> and conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> are formed using conventional patterning techniques. In an embodiment, barrier material <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> includes at least one of titanium and titanium nitride. Titanium and/or Titanium nitride coatings can be deposited uniformity on a substrate, showing good adhesion in that they resist flaking, blistering, chipping and peeling. In an embodiment, programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> includes a phase change material of a chalcogenide alloy and contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> includes CoSi<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. In an embodiment, chalcogenide alloys suitable as programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> include at least one element from column VI of the Periodic Table Of The Elements. In an embodiment, Ge<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Sb<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Te<highlight><subscript>5 </subscript></highlight>is utilized as programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>. Other chalcogenide alloys utilized as programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> include GaSb, InSb, InSe, Sb<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Te<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, GeTe, InSbTe, GaSeTe, SnSb<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Te<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>, InSbGe, AginSbTe, (GeSn)SbTe, GeSb(SeTe), and Te<highlight><subscript>81</subscript></highlight>Ge<highlight><subscript>15</subscript></highlight>Sb<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In the structure illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the contact area of programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> and contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is minimized by the presence of spacer material portions <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>A. In an aspect, the dimensions of openings <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> expose a first contact area of contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. In an aspect, a second contact area, less than the first contact area, is exposed by spacer material <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and/or spacer material portions <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>A. By minimizing the quantity of programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, the quantity of programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> that undergoes, for example, a phase change from/to amorphous and crystalline on contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> (as shown by region <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>) is localized. Region <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>, shown between spacer material portions <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>A, defines a limited and localized programming region of programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, adding to the programmable reliability from and to an amorphous and crystalline state of programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>. In general, by localizing the phase change area, less current is required through programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> during programming and reading, and less power consumption results. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In an aspect, current passes, in general, from conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> through programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> to contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> with even distribution, minimizing current non-uniformity, and avoiding hot spots throughout programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> and contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Further, because less current is utilized through programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, the resistivity of contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> can be minimized, thereby providing flexibility in regards to choice of material selected for contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> depicts the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, from an xy perspective, after forming openings <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>. Openings <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> serve, in one aspect, to define the x-direction thickness of programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, barrier material <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> and conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Openings <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> serve, in another aspect, to isolate individual memory elements from one another as well as associated circuit elements (e.g., transistor devices) formed on the substrate. In one embodiment, openings <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> are formed by patterning of openings through conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, barrier material <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> and programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>. The patterning can be accomplished using conventional photolithographic and etch techniques. In this example, the etching proceeds through conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, barrier material <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> and programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, to the exclusion of dielectric <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. According to current photolithographic techniques, a suitable feature size for the x-direction thickness of openings <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> include as small as 0.25 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> depicts another cross-sectional view, from the yz perspective, of the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. A heat sink, as illustrated by an area generally defined by lines <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> maintains a more stable temperature and cooler interface between programmable material <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> and contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> shows the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> after forming dielectric material <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> over conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Dielectric material <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> is, for example, SiO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or other suitable material that is formed on conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> to electronically isolate conductor <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Following the formation, dielectric material <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> is planarized and a via is formed in a portion of the structure through dielectric material <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>, dielectric material <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, and dielectric material <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> to contact <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. The via is filled with conductive material such as tungsten (W) and a barrier material such as a combination of titanium (Ti) and titanium nitride (TiN). Techniques for introducing dielectric material <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>, forming and filling conductive vias, and planarizing are known to those skilled in the art. The structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> also shows additional conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> formed and patterned to mirror that of conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (e.g., row line) formed on substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Mirror conductor line material <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> mirrors conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and is coupled to conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> through the conductive via. By mirroring a doped semiconductor such as N-type silicon, mirror conductor line material <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> serves, in one aspect, to reduce the resistance of conductor or signal line material <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> in a memory array, such as memory array <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. A suitable material for mirror conductor line material <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> includes an aluminum material, such as an aluminum alloy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> describes a method in forming a programmable memory device in accordance with an embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Further, as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16, a</cross-reference> memory array such as memory device <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) wherein the individual memory cells have a structure similar to that described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> and the accompanying text can be incorporated into a suitable system. In one embodiment, system <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> includes microprocessor (CPU) <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight>, input/output (I/O) port <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>, and memory <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight>. Microprocessor <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight>, I/O port <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>, and memory <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> are connected by data bus <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight>, address bus <highlight><bold>716</bold></highlight> and control bus <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight>. Microprocessor <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> fetches instructions or reads data from memory <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> by sending out an address on address bus <highlight><bold>716</bold></highlight> and a memory read signal on control bus <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight>. Memory <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> outputs the addressed instruction or data word to microprocessor <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> on data bus <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight>. Microprocessor <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> writes a data word to memory <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> by sending out an address on address bus <highlight><bold>716</bold></highlight>, sending out the data word on data bus <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight>, and sending a memory write signal to memory <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> on control bus <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight>. I/O port <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight> is utilized to couple to at least one of input device <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> and output device <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight>. An individual memory cell in memory <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> such as memory device <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) includes a contact on a substrate, a dielectric on the contact having an opening exposing the contact, a programmable (e.g. phase change) material formed within the opening and on the contact, and a conductor in contact with the, e.g., programmable material. The programmable material is either read or written depending on the operation. In a read operation, the phase of phase change material is determined by whether or not current can pass between the conductor and the contact. If current can pass, the data signal can be configured a &ldquo;1&rdquo;. If a current cannot pass, the data can be configured a &ldquo;0&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Having disclosed exemplary embodiments, modifications and variations may be made to the disclosed embodiments while remaining within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a dielectric on a contact, the contact formed on a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an opening through the dielectric exposing the contact; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a programmable material within the opening, the programmable material on the contact; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a conductor to the programmable material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein dimensions of the opening expose a first contact area of the contact, the method further comprising forming at least one spacer within the opening on the contact, the spacer exposing a second contact area of the contact having dimensions less than the first contact area, wherein the programmable material is on the second contact area of the contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a barrier material between the programmable material and the conductor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the contact transmits to a signal line, the method further comprising forming an isolation device between the contact and the signal line. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the at least one spacer comprises: 
<claim-text>conformally forming at least one spacer on a surface of the dielectric and within the opening, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>anisotropically etching the at least one spacer from the surface of the dielectric. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anisotropically etching comprises anisotropically etching with an agent that is selective for the spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a contact on a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a dielectric on the contact, the dielectric having an opening exposing the contact; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a programmable material formed within the opening, the programmable material on the contact; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conductor in contact with the programmable material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein dimensions of the opening expose a first contact area of the contact, the apparatus further comprising a spacer within the opening on the contact, the spacer exposing a second contact area of the contact having dimensions less than the first contact area, wherein the programmable material is on the second contact area of the contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a barrier material between the programmable material and the conductor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a signal line in contact with the contact; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an isolation device between the contact and the signal line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one spacer comprises a conformally formed spacer on the dielectric, and wherein the at least one spacer comprises an anisotropically etched spacer from the dielectric. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the programmable material comprises a chalcogenide memory element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A system comprising: 
<claim-text>a microprocessor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an input/output (I/O) port; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory including a contact on a substrate, a dielectric on the contact having an opening exposing the contact, a programmable material formed within the opening and on the contact, and a conductor in contact with the programmable material; and wherein the microprocessor, the I/O port, and the memory are connected by a data bus, an address bus and a control bus. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein dimensions of the opening expose a first contact area of the contact, the system further comprising a spacer within the opening on the contact, the spacer exposing a second contact area of the contact having dimensions less than the first contact area, wherein the programmable material is on the second contact area of the contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a barrier material between the programmable material and the conductor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a signal line in contact with the contact; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an isolation device between the contact and the signal line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one spacer comprises a conformally formed spacer on the dielectric, and wherein the at least one spacer comprises an anisotropically etched spacer from the dielectric. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the programmable material comprises a chalcogenide memory element.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>15</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030002312A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
