<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004442A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004442A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004442A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004442A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004442A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004442A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004442</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10184475</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>201 10 876.3</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010630</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61H007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61H015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>019000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>022000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>017000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>070000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>098000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>104000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>113000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>102000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>112000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>601</class>
<subclass>136000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Foot care apparatus and attachments</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Klaus</given-name>
<family-name>Hafemann</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Essen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Patent Law Offices of Rick Martin, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>416 Coffman Street</address-1>
<city>Longmont</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80501</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A care or treatment attachment for a foot care apparatus, comprising at least one movable care or treatment element as well as a coupling piece, with which the attachment can be connected to the movement of a motor-driven driving shaft <highlight><bold>8 </bold></highlight>inside the foot care apparatus <highlight><bold>6. </bold></highlight>The attachment comprises a housing which is secured in position on the housing so that driving movement transmitted from the driving shaft does not move the housing. A coupling piece is movable mounted in housing and is supported movably corresponding to the driving movement transmitted from driving shaft of the foot care apparatus. The coupling piece at the driven side drives a power converter for the conversion of the driving movement into a differing movement which powers the one or more movable care or treatment attachments. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority from German application no. 201 10 876.3 filed Jun. 30, 2001. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a care or treatment attachment for a foot care apparatus comprising at least one movable care or treatment element as well as a coupling piece with which the attachment can be connected to the movement of a motor-driven driving shaft of the foot care apparatus. The invention further relates to a foot care apparatus with a motor-driven driving shaft onto which a care or treatment attachment can be placed. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A foot care apparatus with a care or treatment attachment which can be placed onto a driving shaft turned rotatably by a motor is known from DE 295 02 702 U1. It is also known to have foot care apparatus as part of a foot tub, divided by a center ridge into two sub areas. Each sub area of the foot tub serves for receiving one foot. The sub areas can have inserts resting on the tub bottom to a massage of the foot soles. The ridge dividing the foot tub forms at the under side a hollow volume, in which is contained an electromotor and further electric/electronic elements required for operating the foot care apparatus. The electromotor drives a driving shaft such that it rotates, which shaft is carried through the upper side of the ridge and supports at its upper termination a crosspiece as a coupling piece. This crosspiece serves as the attachment place for a care or treatment attachment, such that it is torsion-tight, onto the coupling piece of the driving shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> During operation of the electromotor the entire attachment is set into rotation according to the turning movement of the driving shaft. As various attachments are employed the user can move the foot to use the attachment on different areas of the foot. One type of attachment is one with several rollers supported movably such that during operation of such a roller through the turning movement of the attachment and the movable support of the rollers in the attachment the user can massage their foot. Other attachments known in the art is pumice stones for abrading calluses, brushes or the like, depending on the purpose to be served with such care or treatment attachments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Conventionally such a foot care device is also equipped with a device for generating vibrations, in order to set into vibration the inserts in the tub sections in order to give an overall massage the soles of the feet. Generally the electromotor is driven independently of the vibration generation device and, in contrast to such foot care apparatus in which attachments are placed onto a vibration head covering the vibration generator, permits a considerably more specific care or treatment of individual foot regions, in particular also as it relates to treatment intensity. The known care or treatment attachments thus with their different embodiments have a rotary effect onto the particular desired foot region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Even if, in principle, with such a known foot care apparatus satisfactory care or treatment results can be attained, it would be desirable if such care or treatment attachments were also available which have a different functionality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Building on this discussed prior art, the invention therefore addresses the problem of providing an above-described care or treatment attachment for a foot care apparatus, whose functionality is fundamentally increased compared to the known ones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention has one or more attachments which have housing which is secured in position on a foot care apparatus. This means that the driving movement transmitted from the driving shaft of the electromotor onto the coupling piece does not move the housing. Rotatably mounted in the housing is coupling piece which moves corresponding to the driving movement of the driving shaft of the foot care apparatus. The coupling piece drives at the driven side a power converter for the conversion of the driving movement into a movement differing in one of its properties from the driving movement and powers one or several movable care or treatment elements driven by the power converter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In contrast to the known prior art, in the present inventions the entire attachment is not moved. The housing is secured in position on the foot care apparatus such that the housing of the attachment is decoupled from the driving movement of the foot care apparatus. This opens the capability of placing a power converter in the housing, which can then convert the driving movement of the driving shaft into a number of different types of movement so that several specific care or treatment elements can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The driving movement of the driving shaft, in principle, can be developed such that it is alternating translational or also rotational. The conversion by the power converter of a rotational turning movement of the driving shaft and the coupling piece of the attachment can serve for driving a drum supported horizontally with its rotational axis. The power converter can also be developed as an eccentric, through which a plate is set into vibration, wherein the vibration plane can extend perpendicularly to the rotational axis of the driving shaft. The vibration movement can have a rotational component or also be developed such that it is alternatingly translational. Apart from numerous other elements, as the power converter can also serve a cam disk with one or several positional cogs through which several massage push rods supported in the housing such that they are vertically movable, can be moved alternately and successively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> If a rotational turning movement of the driving shaft is provided, the housing of the attachment can, for example, be held torsion-tight by bars or pins projecting downwardly, which engage corresponding cutouts of the foot care apparatus. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The primary aspect of the present invention is to provide an improved foot care apparatus and attachments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Other aspects of this invention will appear from the following description and appended claims, reference being made to the accompanying drawings forming a part of this specification wherein like reference characters designate corresponding parts in the several views. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A care or treatment attachment for a foot care apparatus, comprising at least one movable care or treatment element as well as a coupling piece, with which the attachment can be connected to the movement of a motor-driven driving shaft <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> inside the foot care apparatus <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is disclosed. The attachment comprises a housing which is secured in position on the housing so that driving movement transmitted from the driving shaft does not move the housing. A coupling piece is movable mounted in housing and is supported movably corresponding to the driving movement transmitted from driving shaft of the foot care apparatus. The coupling piece at the driven side drives a power converter for the conversion of the driving movement into a differing movement which powers the one or more movable care or treatment attachments. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic cross section through a foot care device of the present invention according to a first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the care or treatment attachment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternate embodiment of a care or treatment attachment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic perspective view a care or treatment attachment of another alternate embodiment.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Before explaining the disclosed embodiment of the present invention in detail, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited in its application to the details of the particular arrangement shown, since the invention is capable of other embodiments. Also, the terminology used herein is for the purpose of description and not of limitation. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A foot care device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comprises a foot tub <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which is divided into two subtubs <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime; by a ridge <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the subtubs <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime; can be filled with liquid. The bottom of the subtubs <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime; is conventionally covered with an insert <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>&prime;, which serves for massaging the soles of the feet of a user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The ridge <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> supports a foot care system overall denoted by the reference number <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, which comprises an electromotor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, a driving shaft <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and a care or treatment attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. For the sake of clarity, further required components, such as electric switches or the like are not shown. The electromotor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is fastened torsion-tight in the hollow volume <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> formed by ridge <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. At the upper end of the driving shaft <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is disposed a crosspiece <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> as a coupling device, onto which the coupling piece <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the care or treatment attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> can be placed such that it is torsion-tight. The care or treatment attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> comprises a housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, which is secured torsion-tight in position on the ridge <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> via pins <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, projecting downwardly and engaging corresponding cutouts <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of ridge <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or other attachment mechanism known in the art. Within housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> the coupling piece <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is supported corresponding to the rotational driving movement of the driving shaft <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The care or treatment attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> supports a drum <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> whose rotational axis is disposed such that it extends horizontally. For converting the rotational turning movement of the coupling piece <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with a vertical rotational axis into the rotational turning movement of the drum <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> a power converter (not shown) is provided. Any of the known the art methods of converting rotational movement, for example two bevel gears meshing with each other at the front side, can be used in the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The care or treatment attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and coupling piece <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is detachable from the driving shaft <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> or its crosspiece <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and can readily be exchanged for another attachment. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is shown in a non-operating position. To actuate attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and electromotor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> the attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> must be pressed downwardly according to the depicted direction of the arrow A, through which movement an electric contact is closed and the electromotor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is powered. The actuation can be accomplished with the foot to be treated. It is understood that the electromotor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> can also be driven through a manual switch (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the attachment <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> with its drum <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> on an enlarged scale. The directions of movement of the coupling piece <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and of the drum <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are therein again identified with arrows B and C respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a further care or treatment attachment <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> whose coupling piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can also be driven rotationally. As the care or treatment element in the attachment <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> has a plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> provided with a sandpaper-like granulation, which can be set into movement through a power converter disposed in housing <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of attachment <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> into an alternatingly translational movement&mdash;as indicated by the double arrow D. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> A further care or treatment attachment <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, whose rotationally driven coupling piece <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> drives a cam disk (not shown) with one or more positional cogs disposed in housing <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. On the topside of the cam disk reside six massage push rods M, which, according to the disposition of the positional cogs on the cam disk, during a rotational turning movement of the coupling piece <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and corresponding to the cam disk are alternately raised for massaging as is known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The description of the invention makes clear that with the care or treatment attachments according to the invention a multiplicity of attachments, in particular markedly differing from one another in terms of their functionality, is possible, allowing a variety of specific care or treatments can be carried out. Especially useful is the application of such care or treatment attachments for foot care apparatus, which are part of a foot care device with a tub, since in this case all elements are combined in a single foot care device. However, in principle the foot care apparatus can also be employed individually and independently of a relatively large foot care device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Although the present invention has been described with reference to preferred embodiments, numerous modifications and variations can be made and still the result will come within the scope of the invention. No limitation with respect to the specific embodiments disclosed herein is intended or should be inferred. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> List of Reference Symbols </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> 1 Foot care device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> 2 Foot tub </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> 3 Ridge </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> 4, 4&prime; Subtub </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> 5, 5&prime; Insert </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> 6 Foot care apparatus </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> 7 Electromotor </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> 8 Driving shaft </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> 9 Care or treatment attachment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> 10 Hollow volume </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> 11 Crosspiece </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> 12 Coupling piece </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> 13 Housing </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> 14 Pin </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> 15 Pin </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> 16 Cutout </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> 17 Cutout </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> 18 Drum </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> 19 Care or treatment attachment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> 20 Coupling piece </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> 21 Plate </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> 22 Housing </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> 23 Care or treatment attachment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> 24 Coupling piece </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> 25 Housing </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> M Massage push rods </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A care or treatment attachment for a foot care apparatus having a motor-driven driving shaft comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing having an attachment mechanism to removably attached the housing to the foot care apparatus; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupling piece rotatably mounted within the housing and which connects to the motor drive shaft and is turned within the housing by the motion of the drive shaft; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a power converter mounted inside the housing for converting the motion of the coupling piece into a movement differing in one of its properties from the driving movement from one or several movable care or treatment elements driven by the power converter. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The attachment of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the coupling piece is rotatably supported in the housing of the attachment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The attachment of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the power converter changes the rotational turning movement of the coupling piece, having rotational axis which is substantially vertical, into a rotational turning movement of a drum serving as care or treatment element having a horizontal rotational axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The attachment of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the power converter functions to convert of the rotational turning movement of the coupling piece into an alternatingly translational movement. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The attachment of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the power converter further comprises a cam disk with one or several positional cogs, through which several massage push rods are alternatingly moved as care or treatment elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The attachment of claims <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, wherein the attachment mechanism further comprises: 
<claim-text>bars or pins projecting downward from the housing; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>corresponding cutouts on the surface of the foot care apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A foot care apparatus with a motor-driven driving shaft onto which a care or treatment attachment can be placed, wherein associated with the foot care apparatus is at least one care or treatment attachment as claimed in one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">6</dependent-claim-reference>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004442A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004442A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004442A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
