<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00001.NB SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00001.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00002.NB SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00002.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00003.NB SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00003.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00004.NB SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00004.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00005.NB SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00005.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00006.NB SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00006.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00007.NB SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00007.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-M00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-M00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001108A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001108A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001108</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10153622</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020524</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01J033/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>250</class>
<subclass>492300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Particle beam processing apparatus and materials treatable using the apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10153622</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020524</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09434380</doc-number>
<document-date>19991105</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6426507</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Imtiaz</given-name>
<family-name>Rangwalla</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Andover</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Harvey</given-name>
<family-name>Clough</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>North Andover</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>George</given-name>
<family-name>Hannafin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hudson</city>
<state>NH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Energy Sciences, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow,</name-1>
<name-2>Garrett &amp; Dunner, L.L.P.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1300 I Street, N.W.</address-1>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005-3315</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention is directed to a particle beam processing apparatus that is smaller in size and operates at a higher efficiency, and also directed to an application of such apparatus to treat a coating on a substrate of a treatable material, such as for flexible packaging. The processing apparatus includes a particle beam generating assembly, a foil support assembly, and a processing assembly. In the particle beam generating assembly, electrons are generated and accelerated to pass through the foil support assembly. In the flexible packaging application, the substrate is fed to the processing apparatus operating at a low voltage, such as 110 kVolts or below, and is exposed to the accelerated electrons to treat the coating on the substrate. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. application Ser. No. 09/434,380 filed Nov. 5, 1999, issued as U.S. Pat. No. ______</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a particle beam processing apparatus and materials treatable using such apparatus. In particular, this invention relates to a particle beam processing apparatus including a particle generating assembly, a foil support assembly having a thin foil, and a processing zone. When the treatable material is exposed to the particles generated by the apparatus, the particles cause a chemical reaction on a coating of the material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A particle beam processing device is commonly used to expose a substrate or coating to highly accelerated particle beams, such as an electron beam (EB), to cause a chemical reaction on the substrate or coating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> An electron is a negatively charged particle found in all matter. Electrons revolve around the nucleus of an atom much like planets revolve around the sun. By sharing electrons, two or more atoms bind together to form molecules. In EB processing, energetic electrons are used to modify the molecular structure of a wide variety of products and materials. For example, electrons can be used to alter specially designed liquid coatings, inks and adhesives. During EB processing, electrons break bonds and form charged particles and free radicals. These radicals then combine to form large molecules. By this process, the liquid is transformed into a solid. This process is known as polymerization. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Liquid coatings treated with EB processing may include printing inks, varnishes, silicone release coatings, primer coatings, pressure sensitive adhesives, barrier layers and laminating adhesives. EB processing may also be used to alter and enhance the physical characteristics of solid materials such as paper, substrates and non-woven textile substrates, all specially designed to react to EB treatment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A particle beam processing device generally includes three zones, i.e., a vacuum chamber zone where a particle beam is generated, a particle accelerator zone, and a processing zone. In the vacuum chamber, a tungsten filament is heated to about 2400K, which is the thermionic emission temperature of tungsten, to create a cloud of electrons. A positive voltage differential is then applied to the vacuum chamber to extract and simultaneously accelerate these electrons. Thereafter, the electrons pass through a thin foil and enter the processing zone. The thin foil functions as a barrier between the vacuum chamber and the processing zone. Accelerated electrons exit the vacuum chamber through the thin foil and enter the processing zone at atmospheric conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Electron beam processing devices that are commercially available at the present time generally operate at a minimum voltage of 125 kVolts. These existing EB units utilize thin foil made of titanium having a thickness of 12.5 micrometers, to cure coatings on substrates that are being fed through the processing devices at a rate of 800-1000 feet per minute. Such an EB unit may be purchased from Energy Sciences, Inc. of Wilmington, Mass., Model No. 125/105/1200. The current technology cannot be used in certain industries, e.g., flexible food packaging. An EB unit operating at 125 kVolts deposits substantial amounts of the energy onto the polyethylene based sealant films which contact the food being packaged. This deposit causes off-odors in the films and increases its seal initiation temperatures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The efficiency of such EB units can be improved by reducing the operating voltage below 125 kVolts. In addition, operating below 125 kVolts allows better control of the depth of energy deposition and minimizes the electron energy absorbed by the sealant films. However, when the voltage is reduced below 125 kVolts, the kinetic energy of the electrons traveling through the titanium foil decreases because more energy is being absorbed by the titanium foil, causing the foil to heat up excessively. Excessive heat causes the titanium foil to become blue, brittle, and lose its mechanical strength. Excessive heat also poses a problem with heat management of the system. Consequently, the feed rate of the substrate must be substantially reduced which makes the processing device commercially unviable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In light of the foregoing, there is a need for a particle beam processing device that operates more efficiently, is smaller in size, has a reduced power demand, and is cheaper to construct. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The advantages and purposes of the invention will be set forth in part in the description which follows, and in part will be obvious from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The advantages and purposes of the invention will be realized and attained by the elements and combinations particularly pointed out in the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> To attain the advantages and in accordance with the purposes of the invention, as embodied and broadly described herein, one aspect of the invention is directed to a particle beam treatable material comprising a substrate having a top side and a bottom side, and a particle beam treatable lacquer coating on the top side of the substrate. The lacquer coating is treated by exposure to highly accelerated particles generated by a particle beam processing device operating at a voltage in a range of 110 kVolts or below to cause a chemical reaction to the lacquer coating. The particle beam treatable material also comprises a radiation labile layer on the bottom side of the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A second aspect of the invention is directed to a method for making a particle beam treatable material. The method comprises providing a substrate having a top side and a bottom side, applying a radiation labile layer on the bottom side of the substrate, applying a particle beam treatable lacquer coating on the top side of the substrate, and exposing the lacquer coating to highly accelerated particles generated by a particle beam processing device operating at a voltage of 110 kVolts or below to cause a chemical reaction to the lacquer coating without effecting the radiation labile layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A third aspect of the invention is directed to a particle beam processing device that is smaller in size than currently available devices and that has higher efficiency for causing a chemical reaction on a substrate. The device comprises </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> a power supply, a vacuum pump to create and maintain a vacuum environment in a vessel, and a particle generating assembly located in a vacuum vessel and connected to the power supply operating at a first voltage in a range of 110 kVolts or less. The particle generating assembly includes at least one filament for generating a plurality of particles upon heating. The device also comprises a foil support assembly and a processing assembly. The foil support assembly operates at a second voltage, which is higher than the first voltage, to permit at least a portion of the particles to travel from the first to the second voltage and exit the foil support assembly. The foil support assembly may comprise a thin foil made of titanium or alloys thereof having a thickness of 10 micrometers or less, or a thin foil made of aluminum or alloys thereof having a thickness of 20 micrometers or less. The processing assembly receives the particles exiting the foil support assembly for use to cause the chemical reaction. A machine yield (K) of the processing device is determined according to:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>K</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <mrow>
      <mi>D</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>s</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>e</mi>
        <mo>&CenterDot;</mo>
        <mi>S</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>p</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>d</mi>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mi>C</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>u</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>nt</mi>
    </mrow>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00001" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00001.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00001" wi="216.027" he="17.03835" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> whereby: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> K is machine yield measured in Mrads&middot;feet/min/mAmp, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Dose is energy absorbed per unit mass measured in Mrads, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Speed is feed rate of the substrate measured in feet/min, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Current is a number of electrons extracted from the heated filament measured in mAmp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A fourth aspect of the invention is directed to a method for causing a chemical reaction on a substrate in a particle beam processing device. The method comprises creating and maintaining a vacuum in a particle generating assembly having at least one filament, heating the at least one filament to create a plurality of particles, and operating the particle generating assembly at a first voltage having a range of 110 kVolts or less. The method also comprises operating a foil support assembly having a thin foil at a second voltage, which is higher than the first voltage, to cause at least a portion of said particles to travel from the first voltage to the second voltage, and to exit the vacuum in the particle generating assembly. The thin foil may be made of titanium or alloys thereof and having a thickness of 10 micrometers or less. Alternatively, the thin foil may be made of aluminum or alloys thereof and having a thickness of 20 micrometers or less. The method further comprises passing the exiting particles through the thin foil to enter a processing assembly where the substrate is exposed to the particles. A machine yield (K) of the processing device is determined by:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>K</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <mrow>
      <mi>D</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>s</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>e</mi>
        <mo>&CenterDot;</mo>
        <mi>S</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>p</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>d</mi>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mi>C</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>u</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>nt</mi>
    </mrow>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00002" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00002.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00002" wi="216.027" he="17.03835" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> whereby: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> K is machine yield measured in Mrads&middot;feet/min/mAmp, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Dose is energy absorbed per unit mass measured in Mrads, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Speed is feed rate of the substrate measured in feet/min, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Current is a number of electrons extracted from filament measured in mAmp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary and explanatory only and are not restrictive of the invention as claimed. Additional advantages will be set forth in the description that follows, and in part will be understood from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The advantages and purposes may be obtained by means of the combinations set forth in the attached claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate several embodiments of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention. In the drawings, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the particle beam processing device according to one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a voltage profile of an electron beam; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a front view of the particle beam processing device according to the preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a chart of depth dose profiles as a function of thickness of titanium foil measured at an operating voltage of 90 kVolts; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a chart of machine yields for a processing device having a width of 1.5 feet as a function of operating voltage measured using titanium foil thicknesses of 5, 8, 10 and 12.5 micrometers; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a chart of depth dose profiles as a function of thickness of titanium foil measured at various operating voltages; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a chart of energy absorbed by the thin foil as a function of the incident energy in keV measured using titanium foil thicknesses of 17, 12.5, and 8 micrometers; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a crosslinking reaction on a substrate as the substrate passes through a particle beam processing device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a polymerization reaction on a substrate as the substrate passes through the particle beam processing device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a sterilization reaction on a substrate as the substrate passes through the particle beam processing device; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a cross-section view of a length of a web for flexible packaging material according to an embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made in detail to several embodiments of apparatus, materials, and methods consistent with the invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts. Moreover, the invention will be further clarified by the examples which follow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> A particle beam processing device according to the present invention can be made relatively small in size and to operate at high efficiency due to at least two aspects of the invention; (1) the operating voltage is reduced to 110 kVolts or less, and (2) the thin foil, if made of titanium or alloys thereof, has a thickness of 10 micrometers or less, and if made of aluminum or alloys thereof, has a thickness of 20 micrometers or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the principles of the present invention, a particle beam processing device comprises a power supply, a particle generating assembly, a foil support assembly, and a processing assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> schematically illustrates a particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> consistent with the principles of this invention, including power supply <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, particle beam generating assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, foil support assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, and processing assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Power supply <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> preferably provides an operating voltage of 110 kVolts or less, more preferably in a range of 90-100 kVolts, to the processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Power supply <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may be of a commercially available type that includes multiple electrical transformers located in an electrically insulated steel chamber to provide high voltage to particle beam generating assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to produce particles, such as electrons. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Particle beam generating assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is preferably kept in a vacuum environment of vessel or chamber <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In an EB processing device, particle generating assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is commonly referred to as an electron gun assembly. Evacuated chamber <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may be constructed of a tightly sealed vessel in which particles, such as electrons, are generated. Vacuum pump <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) is provided to create a vacuum environment in the order of approximately 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>Torr. Inside the vacuum environment of chamber <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, a cloud of electrons are generated around filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> when high-voltage power supply <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> sends electrical power to heat up filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> then glows white hot and generates a cloud of electrons. Electrons are then drawn from filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to areas of higher voltage, since electrons are negatively charged particles, as described below and accelerated to extremely high speeds. Filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may be constructed of one or more wires commonly made of tungsten, and may be configured to be spaced evenly across the length of foil support <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and emits electron beams across the width of a substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, particle beam generating assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may include an extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, a terminal grid <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, and a repeller plate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Repeller plate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> repels electrons and sends the electrons toward extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Repeller plate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> operates at a different voltage, preferably slightly lower, than filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to collect electrons escaping from filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> away from electron beam direction as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, operating at a slightly different voltage, preferably higher than filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, attracts electrons away from filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and guides them toward terminal grid <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> controls the quantity of electrons being drawn from the cloud, which determines the intensity of the electron beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Terminal grid <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, operating generally at the same voltage as extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, acts as the final gateway for electrons before they accelerate to extremely high speeds for passage through foil support assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> According to one embodiment of the present invention, for example, filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may operate at &minus;110,000 Volts and foil support assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may be grounded or set at 0 Volt. Repeller plate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be selected to operate at &minus;110,010 Volts to repell any electrons towards filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and terminal grid <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may be selected to operate in a range of &minus;110,000 Volts to &minus;109,700 Volts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The electrons then exit vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and enter the foil support assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> through a thin foil <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> to penetrate a coated material or substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for the chemical reaction. The chemical reaction includes, for example, polymerization, crosslinking or sterilization. The speed of the electrons may be as high as or above 100,000 miles per second. Foil support assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may be made up of a series of parallel copper ribs (not shown). Thin foil <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, is securely clamped to the outside of foil support assembly <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> to provide a leak-proof vacuum seal inside chamber <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. High speed electrons pass freely between the copper ribs, through thin foil <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and into substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> being treated. To prevent an undue energy loss, the foil is preferably made as thin as possible while at the same time providing sufficient mechanical strength to withstand the pressure differential between the vacuum state inside particle generating assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and processing assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the principles of this invention, the particle beam generating device can be made smaller in size and operate at a higher efficiency level when the thin foil of the foil support assembly is made of titanium or alloys thereof and having a thickness of 10 micrometers or less, preferably in a range of 3-10 micrometers, more preferably in a range of 5-8 micrometers. Alternatively, thin foil <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> may also be constructed of aluminum or alloys thereof having a thickness of 20 micrometers or less, preferably in a range of 6-20 micrometers, more preferably in a range of 10-16 mircometers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Once the electrons exit the foil support assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, they enter the processing assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> where the electrons penetrate a coating or web substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and cause a chemical reaction resulting in polymerization, crosslinking or sterilization. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the coating or web substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is being fed into the processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to enter processing assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Processing assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> includes a web entrance <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> where substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> enters, rollers <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> to guide and deliver substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through the processing assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, and a web exit <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> where substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> exits the processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The product being treated is instantaneously transformed, needs no drying or cooling and contains many new and desirable physical properties. Products can be shipped immediately after processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The particle beam processing device may include a protective lining surrounding at least a portion of the periphery of the device to absorb radiation, such as X-ray, emitted when the electrons decelerate as they are absorbed in matter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> protective lining <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> surrounds the periphery of processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, such as evacuated chamber <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and processing assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Protective lining <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> absorbs substantially all X-rays created when electrons decelerate in matter. The thickness and material selected for protective lining <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> form a function primarily determined by the desired absorption rate of the X-rays. In one embodiment, protective lining <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is preferably capable of absorbing X-ray radiation at an absorption rate with residuals less than or equal to approximately 0.1 mrem/hour. The unit mrem/hour represents an absorption of 0.1 mili radiation equivalent to man per one hour. One milirem is equivalent to 1 milirad for electrons and X-rays. One way to measure the radiation emitted is by measuring the absorption at a distance of 10 cm away from protective lining <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> by an instrument such as an ionization chamber instrument commercially known as Bicron RSO-5. To further enhance safety measure of particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a safety interlock switches (not shown) may be provided to ensure safe operation by automatically stopping production whenever interlocks are opened. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The particle beam processing device may further include a processor, such as a computerized microprocessor, to regulate the quantity of electrons generated so the electron beam output is proportional to the feeding speed of the substrate. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> process control system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is provided to control several processes including but not limited to maintaining the required vacuum environment, initiating system operation with predetermined voltages and filament power, synchronizing electron generation with process speed to maintain constant treatment level, monitoring functions and interlocks, and providing warnings and/or alarms whenever the system functions exceed set limits or an interlock problem is detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In operation, particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> works as follows. A vacuum pump <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) evacuates air from chamber <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to achieve a vacuum level of approximately 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>Torr, at which point processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is fully operational. In particle generating assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, particle gun assembly components, including repeller plate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and terminal grid <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, are set at three independently controlled voltages which initiate the emission of electrons and guide their passage through foil support <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> During the particle beam processing, a combination of electric fields inside evacuated chamber <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> create a &ldquo;push/pull&rdquo; effect that guides and accelerates the electrons toward thin foil <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of foil support <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, which is at ground (0) potential. The quantity of electrons generated is directly related to the voltage of extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. At slow production speeds, extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is set at a lower voltage than at high speeds, when greater voltage is applied. As the voltage of extractor grid <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> increases, so does the quantity of electrons being drawn from filament <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The coatings to be cured, for example, inks, adhesives and other coatings, generally require a low oxygen environment to cause the chemical conversion from a liquid state into a solid state. Therefore, the particle beam processing device according to this invention may include, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> plurality of nozzles <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> distributed in processing zone <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> to inject gas other than oxygen to displace the oxygen therein. In one embodiment, nitrogen gas is selected to be pumped into processing zone <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> through nozzles <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> to displace the oxygen that would prevent complete curing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> As can be seen from the description above, particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be calibrated to achieve extremely high precision specification because process control system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be set to provide the exact depth level of cure desired on a substrate or coating. Process control system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> calculates the dose and the depth of electron penetration into the coating or substrate. The higher the voltage, the greater the electron speed and resultant penetration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Dose is the energy absorbed per unit mass and is measured in terms of megarads (Mrad), which is equivalent to 2.4 calories per gram. A higher number of electrons absorbed reflects a higher dose value. In application, dose is commonly determined by the material of the coating and the depth of substrate to be cured. For example, a dose of 5 Mrad may be required to cure a coating on a substrate that is made of rice paper and having a mass density of 20 gram/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. Dose is directly proportional to the operating beam current which is the number of electrons extracted, and inversely proportional to the feed speed of the substrate, as expressed by the following formula:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Dose&equals;<highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>&middot;(<highlight><italic>I/S</italic></highlight>)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> whereby I is the current measured in mAmp, S is the feed speed of the substrate measured in feet/min, and K is a proportionality constant which represents a machine yield of the processing device, or the output efficiency of that particular processing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The following examples as illustrated in the charts shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are provided as a result of a series of experiments. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the relationship between depth dose profiles and mass density of the coatings with respect to three different thicknesses of the thin foil as measured at an operating voltage of 90 kV. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates the relationship between operating voltage (&ldquo;High Voltage&rdquo;) as measured in kVolts and the machine yield K for a processing device having a width of 1.5 feet with respect to thin foil made of titanium having thicknesses of 5, 8, and 12.5 micrometers. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates the relationship between depth dose profiles and mass density of the coatings with respect to various operating voltages. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates the relationship between energy absorbed by the thin foil (&ldquo;dE&rdquo;) measured in keV and incident energy or operating voltage measured in keV with respect to three titanium foil having thickness of 17, 12.5, and 8 micrometers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The goal of the present invention is to increase the output efficiency of the processing device by applying an operating voltage that is as low as possible to reduce the power needed to generate the operating voltage which makes the processing device more compact and cheaper to build. Thus, as shown in the depth dose profiles of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the optimum curve preferably moves closer towards an imaginary vertical line crossing the X-axis representing the density of the coating to be cured. However, as previously discussed, reducing the operating voltage causes a tremendous heat problem which renders the processing device not commercially viable. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 7</cross-reference>, heat problem can be solved by utilizing a titanium foil that has a thickness of 10 micrometers or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The data taken in these experiments was measured utilizing thin film dosimetry techniques. Dosimetry techniques involve nylon films which have thicknesses in the range of 9-10 micrometers. The dosimeters contain a radiochromic dye that changes color from colorless to blue when the dye is exposed to electromagnetic radiation. The intensity of the blue color is directly proportional to the amount of radiation exposure obtained from the nylon films. By measuring the intensity or optical density of the blue color using a densitometer, one can convert the measured optical density to the absorbed dose in Mrads. The conversion from optical density to dose in Mrads is achieved by prior calibration of the dosimeters and the densitometer using Co<highlight><superscript>6o </superscript></highlight>Gamma facility at the National Institute of Standards and Technology, Gaithersburg, Md. These experiments utilized Dosimeters Model FWT-60-810 manufactured by Far West Technology, Goleta, Calif. and Densitometer Model 92 SXN 3285 manufactured by Far West Technology, Goleta, Calif. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The result of a first experiment, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, indicates that particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> using thin foil <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> that is made of titanium having a thickness of less than 12.5 micrometer improves the electron penetration in substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In the first experiment, thin film nylon dosimeters were used to measure the penetration capability of electrons. The parameters for this experiment include: a constant operating voltage of 90 kVolts, a dose of 5 Mrads, and a thin titanium foil. Three specimens were tested to study three different titanium foil thicknesses of 12.5, 8, and 5 micrometers, one for each foil thickness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The three specimens were made of thirty dosimeters, each having a surface area of approximately 2&times;2 cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. These dosimeters were divided into three stacks, each stack containing an arrangement of ten dosimeters one on top of the other. One edge of each stack of dosimeters was taped to a polyester carrier having a thickness of 125 micrometer. The three polyester carriers were then taped to a paper substrate and fed through processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to receive radiation treatment. The first stack was treated in processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with 12.5 micrometer titanium foil; the second stack with 8 micrometers, and the third stack with 5 micrometers. Following the radiation treatment, the three stacks were annealed in an oven at 60&deg; C. for 5 minutes. The dosimeters were then separated, individually measured on the densitometer, and converted to dose in terms of Mrads. For each stack, the dose values obtained were normalized to the first dosimeter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the data resulted from this experiment with the Y-axis representing the normalized dose for each stack and the X-axis representing the mass density in terms of gram/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. The mass density was obtained by measuring the dosimeters mass density that resulted in 10 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. It is assumed that the first point is at one half of the mass density, and then each mass density is added to it for subsequent points. This experiment concludes that the thinner the foil is used in particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the higher electron penetration on substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is achieved. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The result of a second experiment, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, indicates that thinner foil not only improves electron penetration on a substrate, but also increases the efficiency or machine yield K. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In the second experiment, similar to the first experiment, thin film nylon dosimeters were used to measure the machine yield K of a processing device having a width of 1.5 feet at various operating voltages measured in kVolts. Four measurements were run to study four different titanium foils having thicknesses of 12.5, 10, 8, and 5 micrometers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The value of machine yield K was obtained by calculating the average of nine individual dosimeter chips. Each dosimeter of 2&times;2 cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>was taped on one edge to a polyester carrier. Each polyester carrier contained nine dosimeters. The polyester carrier was taped to the paper substrate and fed through processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to receive radiation treatment. After irradiation the dosimeters were annealed at 60&deg; C. for 5 minutes. Thereafter, the optical density and the dose value were measured. For each measurement, processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> was set to deliver 4 Mrads to the dosimeters. Processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> included several gauges (not shown) to indicate the feed rate of the substrate in feet/minute and the current of the particle beam in mAmp. The average dose was determined and used to calculate the K value according to the following equation:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mi>K</mi>
    <mo>&af;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mi>M</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>r</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>a</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>d</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>s</mi>
        </mrow>
        <mo>-</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>f</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>e</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>e</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>t</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>/</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>min</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>/</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>m</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>A</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>mp</mi>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <mrow>
      <mi>D</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>s</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>e</mi>
        <mo>&af;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>M</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>r</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>a</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>d</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>s</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
      <mo>&times;</mo>
      <mi>S</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>p</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>d</mi>
        <mo>&af;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>f</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>e</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>e</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>t</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>/</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>min</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mi>C</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>u</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>n</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>t</mi>
        <mo>&af;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mi>m</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>A</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>m</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>p</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00003" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00003.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00003" wi="216.027" he="23.04855" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The same procedure was repeated for all voltages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows the data resulted from this experiment with the Y-axis representing the machine yield K and the X-axis representing the operating voltages in kVolts. This experiment concludes that thinner foil increases the efficiency or machine yield K. Machine yield K of the processing device in accordance with the present invention increases, and reaches an optimum value at the corresponding optimum operating voltage. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, when a 10 micrometer titanium foil is used and the processing device operates at 110 kVolts, the machine yield reaches approximately 23. When an 8 micrometer titanium foil is used and the processing device operates at 100 kVolts, the machine yield reaches approximately 30 at 90-100 kVolts. Similarly, when a 5 micrometer titanium foil is used and the processing device operates at 70 kVolts, the machine yield reaches almost 30. Comparing the machine yield K between the processing device using 12.5 micrometer titanium foil and the processing devices using 10, 8 and 5 micrometers titanium foils, the following relationship is deduced:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>K&gE;20/L</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> for a 10 micrometer titanium foil operating at a voltage of 80-110 kVolts; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> for an 8 micrometer titanium foil operating at a voltage of 70-110 kVolts; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> for a 5 micrometer titanium foil operating at a voltage of 60-110 kvolts; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> wherein L is the width of the processing device measured in feet, in this case 1.5 feet. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 3 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> The result of a third experiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, illustrates one advantage of operating processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> at a voltage of 110 kVolts or less in the field of Flexible Food Packaging. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> In the third experiment, depth dose profiles for processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> at various operating voltages were measured according to the procedure described earlier with respect to the first experiment. A typical application of flexible food packaging is the packaging for processed meat and cheese which commonly include three layers top film, adhesive, and sealant. For example, Table 1 below provides a typical packaging layers and their normalized thicknesses, measured in grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="77PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Top film of 0.5 mil polyester type (PET):</entry>
<entry>17.0 gram/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Adhesive:</entry>
<entry>&ensp;3.0 gram/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Sealant of polyethylene copolymer:</entry>
<entry>40.0 gram/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Electron beam has generally been used to cure the adhesive in between the top film and the sealant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, EB processing device currently available in the market, which operates at 125 kVolts, sufficiently cured the adhesive at a depth of 20 gram/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, curing the top film and the adhesive. However, it deposited significant dose to the sealant layer at a depth of 60 gram/m<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>(top film, adhesive, and sealant). The polyethylene based sealant layer, which contacts the food being packaged, emits undesirable odors when it absorbs the dose deposited thereon. In addition, the deposited dose also increases the seal initiation temperatures, thus making it difficult to heat seal. These two effects on the sealant layer prevent the current EB processing device from meeting the demands for flexible food packaging industry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> consistent with the principles of the present invention overcomes the problems of prior processing device by operating at a voltage range of 110 kVolts or less, preferably 90-100 kVolts, at a commercially viable substrate feed rate. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, at the operating voltage of 110 kVolts or less, one can properly cure the adhesive at a depth of 20 gram/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, yet impart significantly less dose, and thus cause less damage to the sealant film. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 4 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> The result of a fourth experiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, describes the relation between the energy absorbed by the titanium foil as a function of its operating voltage measured in kVolts. This study compared three different titanium foil thicknesses of 17, 12.5, and 8 micrometers. The studies on the 17 and 12.5 micrometers were performed at the National Institute of Standards and Technology according to the electron energy dissipation in titanium foil using MonteCarlo calculations. Based on the data resulted from these studies, data for the 8 micrometer titanium foil was extrapolated. This study confirms that thinner foil absorbs less energy, especially at lower voltages. Therefore, a processing device utilizing foil having a thickness of 10 micrometers or less solves the heat management problem since energy absorbed by the foil converts to power resulting in heat management issues with the foil. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Because the processing device according to the present invention can operate at an operating voltage of 110 kVolts or less, not only that the size of power supply to generate the operating voltage can be reduced, but also the size of evacuated vessel to contain the particle beam generating assembly can be substantially reduced. Furthermore, the thickness of protective lining can be reduced because less severe radiation is emitted by the electrons exiting the evacuated vessel at a slower rate when the operating voltage is 110 kVolts or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In application, a particle beam processing device may be used in a manufacturing process, such as electron beam (EB) processing, to treat a substrate or a coating exposed to the device. The treatment may include a chemical reaction, such as polymerization, crosslinking, or sterilization. When the substrate or coating is exposed to highly accelerated electrons, a reaction occurs in which the chemical bonds in the substrate or coating are broken and a new, modified molecular structure is formed. This application applies broadly to any particle beam, but for exemplary purposes, the electron beam is particularly described. The following will describe possible chemical reactions that could occur during EB processing. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 5 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Crosslinking is a chemical reaction that alters and enhances the physical characteristics of the material being treated. In a crosslinking process, an interconnected network of chemical bonds or links develops between large polymer chains to form a stronger molecular structure. Application of EB processing by crosslinking reaction includes, for example, when a plastic like substrate or rubber substrate is treated with electrons, the large polymers in these products develop many linking bonds. These bonds increase the product&apos;s performance and its resistance to weakening at elevated temperatures. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates the crosslinking reaction on substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A as substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A passes under the particle beam processing device, schematically referred to as <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, from an untreated state on the left area <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A, into an exposure area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>A, to a treated state on the right area <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 6 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Like crosslinking, polymerization is a process in which several individual groups of molecules combine together to form one large group called a polymer. This causes significant physical changes in the product being treated and results in many desirable physical characteristics such as high gloss and abrasion resistance. For example, when exposed to accelerated electrons during EB processing, furniture coatings and adhesives are transformed almost instantaneously from a liquid (uncured) state into a non-tacky (cured) solid state. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates the polymerization reaction on substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B as substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B passes under particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, from an untreated state on the left area <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B, into an exposure area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>B, to a treated state on the right area <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 7 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Sterilization is a process of destroying contaminating microorganisms by rendering them sterile or unable to reproduce. EB sterilization occurs when electrons are directed into the microorganisms whereby breaking the DNA chains which control reproduction. Once a product has been sterilized, no microbial decomposition can take place. Since electrons act as a physical sterilizing agent rather than a chemical one, they do not change the chemistry of the target product or leave any residual chemicals. EB sterilization offers a number of advantages over chemical sterilization techniques, such as those that use hydrogen peroxide and ethylene oxide. For example, EB sterilization may be used to sterilize medical supplies and sensitive food products as well as their respective packaging, whereas chemical sterilization could not be used. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates the sterilization reaction on substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C as substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C passes under particle beam processing device, schematically referred to as <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, from an untreated state on the left area <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>C, into an exposure area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>C, to a treated state on the right area <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> In recent years, application of an EB processing has received wide acceptance in many different industries. For example, in the packaging industry, flexible packaging has experienced a tremendous successful growth compared to its counterpart rigid and semi-rigid packaging, such as cans and bottles packaging. One reason for this success over the rigid and semi-rigid packaging alternatives is that flexible packaging offers cost and source reduction. The particle beam processing device according to this invention, generally referred to in the industry as an EB machine, may be used to satisfy requirements of this industry, including to provide a flexible packaging material that is less expensive and meets the health and safety standards set forth by government agencies, such as the Food and Drug Administration. Cost reduction may be accomplished by using less raw material and employing an improved manufacturing technique. As an additional benefit, reducing the raw material also appreciably appeals to this industry as environmentally friendly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> As described above in Example 3 and exemplified in Table 1, a typical flexible packaging material currently available in the market comes in a laminate form, which means it has a minimum of two main layers: a top polymer film and a bottom polymer film, with an adhesive sandwiched or laminated between the top and bottom films. Each of the top and bottom films usually comes in the form of continuous sheet rolled around a cylindrical core or spool. The adhesive may be applied, for example, by squeezing it out of a nozzle into a nip area between a pair of rollers, one for guiding the top film, and another for the bottom film. Generally, also laminated and protected between the top and bottom films is a printing of the product label. The print is commonly a reversed image of the actual label itself. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Also currently known in the industry is an application of the particle beam processing device made according to the teaching of this application in the pet food packaging industry. For example, it is well known to use the EB machine of this invention to cure or polymerize a lacquer coating on the pet food packaging material such as multi-wall bag. Pet food packaging material is usually constructed of a layer of high strength paper and a lacquer coating to protect the label printed on the paper. It has been known to cure the lacquer coating on the paper by feeding the paper into a particle beam processing device of the present invention normally operating at a voltage of 110 kVolts to cure the lacquer coating, transforming the lacquer coating from a liquid phase to solid almost instantaneously. The lacquer coating is EB cured and designed to provide gloss, abrasion resistant and desired coefficient of friction (COF). After the EB lacquer is applied, the paper is further processed where other layers of paper and plastic film are glued onto the paper containing EB lacquer making the multi-wall bug substrate. After filling the contents, the paper packaging is then generally sealed by sewing the top and bottom edges of the packaging. The pet food packaging material does not include a bottom polymer film, which is normally made of polyethylene for heat sealing the packages when the EB lacquer is applied and cured with EB. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> It is known that if the radiation from the particle beam processing device deposits significant dose to the bottom polymer film, thereby altering the sealing characteristics of the bottom polymer film, and causing the film to emit undesirable odors and raising the seal initiation temperatures thus making it difficult to heat seal the packages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to an application of the particle beam processing device to a treatable material, such as for a flexible food packaging, whereby the treatable material includes a substrate, a particle beam treatable lacquer coating, and a radiation labile layer, such as a sealing layer, whereby the particle beam causes the lacquer coating to chemically react without effecting the radiation labile layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Application of the particle beam processing device made according to this invention can be found in many industries including, for example, packaging, insulation films, reflective coatings and reflective materials, solar films, etc. Other fields, such as outer space suits and aircrafts, may also find this invention useful. For exemplary purposes, an embodiment of the present invention is discussed with respect to an application of the particle beam processing device in the flexible food packaging field. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Consistent with the principles of the present invention, in order to reduce material resources and production costs of current packaging material, this application provides a particle beam treatable material including a substrate and a lacquer coating applied on the substrate, the lacquer coating being formulated for exposure to highly accelerated particles, such as those generated by the particle beam processing device of this invention, to cause a chemical reaction to the lacquer coating. The particle beam processing device operates at a voltage in a range of 110 kVolts or below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11, a</cross-reference> packaging material <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> consistent with the principles of the present invention includes a substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a top side <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and a bottom side <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, and a lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> applied on top side <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, packaging material <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is schematically shown to go through a particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of this invention in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. Substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is generally in the form of a continuous web. However, this invention anticipates that substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also be in the form of a sheet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, such as an over-print varnish (OPV), is formulated for exposure to highly accelerated particles schematically illustrated and referred to as arrows <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>. Particles <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> may be electron beams such as those electrons generated by particle beam generating assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of this invention. When exposed to electron beams <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>, lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is treated by going through a chemical reaction, i.e., a polymerization process in which it is physically transformed from a liquid state to a solid state (illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> as reference number <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>). This polymerization process is commonly referred to as being a curing process. Advantageously, lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be cured theoretically almost instantaneously or practically within approximately a few mili-seconds. For the manufacturers of consumer food products, like chocolate bars, potato chips, candies, dried fruits, etc., where mass quantity production is essential, this is a tremendous breakthrough since packaged products can be quickly shipped to suppliers and consumers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> serves several purposes, including protecting the ink of a label print <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> from smearing and scratching, providing traction to enable the web to run through the EB machine, and for aesthetic reasons, presenting a high gloss finish to the packaged product. Lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be made of a functional group, such as acrylate ester including multifunctional acrylates for free radical polymerization, vinyl ethers, cycloaliphatic diepoxide and polyol systems, for cationic polymerization. The lacquer coating may also include wefting agents and other additives to control coefficient of friction (COF) and import desired functional properties, such as gas and aroma barrier properties. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> For example, the following are possible candidates for the multifunctional acrylate: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> acrylated polyols with molecular weights from 150 to 600; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> polyester acrylates with molecular weights from 1000 to 2000; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> polyether acryiates with molecular weights from 200 to 1500; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> polyester urethane acrylates with molecular weights from 400 to 2000; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> polyurea acrylates with molecular weights from 400 to 2000; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> epoxy acrylates with molecular weights from 300 to 1000; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> mixtures of multifunctional acrylates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> More particularly, the multifunctional acrylate may include pentaerythritol tetraacrylate, ditrimethylol propane tetraacrylate, trimethylolpropane triacrylate, glycerol triacrylate, triacrylate ester of tris-t2hydroxy-ethyll isocyanurate, hexanediol diacrylate, and dipentaerythritol hexacrylate, and ethoxylated and propoxylated derivatives thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may have a normalized thickness (expressed in terms of its mass density) in a range of 0.5-20 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. In one embodiment, lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> preferably has a thickness in a range of 1-10 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, and more preferably 2-5 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> Also consistent with the principles of the present invention, lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is preferably treated using the EB machine having a power supply and operating at a voltage of 110 kVolts or below. For one application, the operating voltage of the EB machine may be in a range of 60-110 kVolts, or preferably between 70-110 kVolts, and more preferably between 90-110 kVolts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be treated using the EB machine which generates electrons emitting energy in a range of 0.5-10 Mrads to cure lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. In one example, the emitted electron energy is preferably in a range of 1-7 Mrads, or preferably in a range of 2-5 Mrads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Also consistent with the principles of the present invention, substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be made of a material such as polyolefins, including oriented polypropylene (OPP), cast polypropylene, polyethylene and polyethylene copolymer; polystyrene; polyesters, including polyethylene terephthalate (PET), or polyethylene naphthalate (PEN); polyolefin copolymers, including ethylene vinyl acetate, ethylene acrylic acid and ethylene vinyl alcohol (EVOH), polyvinylalcohol and copolymers thereof; polyamides, including nylon, and MXD6; polyimides; polyacrylonitrile; polyvinylchloride; polyvinyl dichloride; polyvinylidene chloride; polyacrylates; ionomers; polysaccharides, including regenerated cellulose; silicone, including rubbers or sealants; natural or synthetic rubbers; glassine or clay coated paper; paper board; craft paper; and metallized films and vapor deposited metal oxide coated polymer films, including AlO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>, SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>, or TiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> To provide desired strength to the packaging and to maintain quality of the contents of a packaged product, substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may have a thickness in a range of 10-200 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, preferably 30-90 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, or more preferably 50-70 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> Further consistent with the principles of the present invention, substrate 10 may have a barrier layer <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> applied on top side <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to maintain a prerequisite condition of the contents of a packaged product. If the contents of the packaged product are foods, such as potato chips, for example, the prerequisite condition may include flavor, freshness, taste, crispness, color, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Barrier layer <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> may be applied by a technique commonly known as vacuum deposition process whereby a layer of, for example, vaporized aluminum, aluminum oxides (AlO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>), silicone oxides (SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>), or other suitable materials is deposited onto substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to maintain the prerequisite condition of the contents of a packaged product. In a vacuum deposition process using an aluminum oxide, the process also known as a metallization, whereby aluminum is heated to above melting temperature under a vacuum condition in a chamber. A continuous web is run through the vacuum chamber filled with molten aluminum via a series of rollers. Under a controlled condition, the molten aluminum is deposited on either one or both of its surfaces creating a precise thickness of aluminum metallization on the web. This metallization can be seen, for example, as the shiny silver-colored coating on the inner side of a bag of potato chips. In one embodiment, barrier layer <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> may have a thickness in a range of 100-1000 Angstroms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> Label print <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be applied directly on top side <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, usually, but not necessarily, on top of the barrier layer <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. When substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes barrier layer <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, label print <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be applied after application of barrier layer <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> onto substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Label print <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> according to this invention may be applied as a surface print, as oppose to the reverse printing. Surface printing may be performed using the currently available techniques, such as flexography printing, rotor gravuare printing, offset lithography printing, spray printing, etc. Generally, in a printing zone of the EB machine, continuous sheet of substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is run through a series of rollers (not shown) to receive the surface printing on its top side <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> by one of those printing techniques. Preferably, in the flexible packaging industry, printing is done by a flexography method. Label print <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be any types of well known flexography inks, including solvent based, water based, and electron beam curable ink, such as Unicure&trade; available from Sun Chemicals Ink of Northlake, Ill. This invention further anticipates that lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and label print <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> on substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be simultaneously treated when they pass through the particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> Yet further consistent with the principles of the present invention, substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may have a radiation labile layer defined as a layer of material susceptible to radiation damage. Radiation labile layer may be a sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>, applied on bottom side <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> is provided to facilitate sealing of the packaging material and to give structure to the packaging without being chemically altered by the radiation from the particle beam processing device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. To give structure to the packaging, sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> may be provided with a thickness in a range of 5-50 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, preferably 8-<highlight><bold>35 grams/m</bold></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, more preferably 12-25 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, or most preferably 15-20 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. Sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> may be applied to bottom side <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> of flexible substrate <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> by any conventional means, such as an extrusion method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> In a consumer food producing company, after lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> has been treated, substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, commonly in a form of a continuous web, goes through a cutting process whereby the continuous sheet is first folded to become a continuous tube, then cut to size to make individual bags, arranged in an assembly line to be sealed on one end of the bags. In the cutting process, continuous sheet of substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be run through various rollers to make a continuous U-shaped sheet so that sealing layers <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> are on two inner legs of the U-shaped sheet facing each other. The tips of the legs of the U-shaped sheet may then be sealed to make the continuous tube ready for cutting to individual bag sizes. Then, the assembly line of individual bags goes through a filling process whereby contents of the packaging are filled into the individual bags, and each of the individual bags is sealed on the other end to close the packaging. It is also possible to provide substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a form of individual sheets, either already cut to size or ready to be cut to size. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> Sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> may be made of a material suitable for sealing a packaged product, such as by heat sealing, cold sealing, or other equivalent sealing processes. When sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> is provided for heat seal layer, sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> may be made of polymers preferably having a melting point at a temperature range of 100-150 degrees Celcius. Examples of such polymers are polyethylene, polyvinylacetate, ethylene propylene copolymer, terpolymer ethylene acrylic acid, metallocene, ionomer, and combination thereof. For bagging snack foods, like potato chips, for example, sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> may be made of polyethylene or polyethylene/polypropylene copolymer terploymer having a melting temperature range of 110-140 degrees Celcius. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> may be provided for cold seal layer to cold seal the packaging. In one embodiment, a cold seal adhesive may be applied to the substrate. For cold seal coating, sealing layer <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> may be made of natural rubber, polyamides, and combination thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> The following comparative examples present several applications of the web packaging material according to the present invention in the current market, including stand-up pouch packaging, confectionary packaging, and snack food packaging. As can be seen from the following examples, the web packaging material of the present invention improves the currently available packaging material by offering cost savings, better quality product, and environmental consciousness. The present invention accomplishes these improvements by using less raw material and using a low voltage EB machine to cure the packaging material. For exemplary purposes, Examples 8-10 discuss the polymers in terms of their normalized thickness measured in grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 8 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">STAND-UP POUCH PACKAGING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> Stand-up pouch packaging is used to package, for example, cookies, nuts, dried fruits, etc. In today&apos;s market, packaging for stand-up pouches is made in a laminate form, i.e., at least two layers of polymers being laminated to sandwich an adhesive layer. The following is an example of stand-up pouch packaging in the current market:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="77PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Polymer Laminates</entry>
<entry>Thickness</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>in Current Market</entry>
<entry>(in grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Polyester type (PET)</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Reverse printing</entry>
<entry>&mdash;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Adhesive (extruded polyethylene)</entry>
<entry>12</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Metallized oriented polypropylene (OPP)</entry>
<entry>15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Adhesive (extruded polyethylene)</entry>
<entry>12</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Low density polyethylene</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Total</entry>
<entry>85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> A packaging material made consistent with the principles of the present invention may have the following construction for a stand-up pouch packaging:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="77PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Packaging Material</entry>
<entry>Thickness</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>of the Present Invention</entry>
<entry>(in grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Over-print varnish (OPV)</entry>
<entry>&lt;5</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Surface printing</entry>
<entry>&mdash;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Metallized oriented polypropylene (OPP)</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Extruded polyethylene (PE) coating</entry>
<entry>20</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Total</entry>
<entry>&lt;75&ensp;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> In the exemplified embodiment, over-print varnish of lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is about 3-5 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>thick and is curable with an EB machine at least 2.0 Mrads and operating at a range of 80-110 kVolts. It can be seen that the web packaging made according with the principles of the present invention uses less raw material than the conventional stand-up pouch packaging by about 10 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, which is a raw material saving of almost 15-20%. In addition, the web packaging made according with the principles of the present invention offers energy and cost savings related to reducing several operating or processing steps. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 9 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CONFECTIONARY PACKAGING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> Confectionary packaging is used to package, for example, candies and candied products. The following is an example of confectionary packaging in the current market:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00004">
<number>4</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="21PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="105PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="91PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Polymer Laminates</entry>
<entry>Thickness</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>in Current Market</entry>
<entry>(in grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Oriented polypropylene (OPP)</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Reverse printing</entry>
<entry>&mdash;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Water-based adhesive</entry>
<entry>&ensp;2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Oriented polypropylene (OPP)</entry>
<entry>28</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Cold seal adhesive pattern coated</entry>
<entry>&mdash;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Total</entry>
<entry>48</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> A packaging material made consistent with the principles of the present invention may have the following construction for a confectionary packaging:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00005">
<number>5</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="21PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="105PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="91PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Packaging Material</entry>
<entry>Thickness</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>of the Present Invention</entry>
<entry>(in grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Over-print varnish (OPV)</entry>
<entry>&lt;5</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Surface printing</entry>
<entry>&mdash;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Oriented polypropylene (OPP)</entry>
<entry>35</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Cold seal adhesive pattern coated</entry>
<entry>&mdash;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Total</entry>
<entry>&lt;40&ensp;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> In this example, over-print varnish of lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is curable with an EB machine at least 2.0 Mrads and operating at a range of 80-110 kVolts. It can be seen that the web packaging made according with the principles of the present invention uses less raw material than the conventional packaging, a material cost saving of about 8 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>or 10-15%. In addition, the web packaging made according with the principles of the present invention offers energy and cost savings related to reducing several operating or processing steps. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 10 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SNACK FOOD PACKAGING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Snack food packaging is used to package, for example, potato chips, corn chips, and pretzels. The following is an example of snack food packaging in the current market:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00006">
<number>6</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="21PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="105PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="91PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Polymer Laminates</entry>
<entry>Thickness</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>in Current Market</entry>
<entry>(in grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Oriented polypropylene (OPP)</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Reverse printing</entry>
<entry>&mdash;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Adhesive (extruded polyethylene)</entry>
<entry>15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Metallized heat sealable OPP</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Total</entry>
<entry>51</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> A packaging material made consistent with the principles of the present invention may have the following construction for a snack food packaging:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00007">
<number>7</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="77PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Packaging Material</entry>
<entry>Thickness</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>of the Present Invention</entry>
<entry>(in grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Over-print varnish (OPV)</entry>
<entry>&lt;5</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Surface printing</entry>
<entry>&mdash;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Metallized oriented polypropylene (OPP)</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Extruded PE for heat sealing and bulk</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Total</entry>
<entry>&lt;41&ensp;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> In this example, over-print varnish of lacquer coating <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is also curable with an EB machine at 2.0 Mrads and operating at a range of 80-110 kVolts. It can be seen that the web packaging made according with the principles of the present invention uses less raw material than the conventional packaging, a cost saving of about 10 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>or 15%. In addition, the web packaging cured with the EB machine according with the principles of the present invention offers substantial energy savings as compared with the conventional oven operation used in the current market. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> The process described above offers several advantages, such as, the particle beam processing happens virtually instantaneously, commonly operates at room temperature and produces no emissions or air pollution since particle beam coating materials are 100% solids. In addition, the coatings do not contain harmful solvents or volatile organic compounds. In addition, energy costs to operate EB is substantially lower than operating ovens used today. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made in the particle generating assembly, foil support, processing zone, and process control system, as well as the materials chosen for the web packaging material, and the materials chosen for the thin foil, the filaments or particle generating components, and in construction of the particle beam processing system as well as other aspects of the invention without departing from the scope or spirit of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> Other embodiments of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art from consideration of the specification and practice of the invention disclosed herein. It is intended that the specification and examples be considered as exemplary only, with a true scope and spirit of the invention being indicated by the following claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A particle beam treatable material, comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate having a top side and a bottom side; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a particle beam treatable lacquer coating on the top side of the substrate, the lacquer coating treated by exposure to highly accelerated particles generated by a particle beam processing device operating at a voltage in a range of 110 kVolts or less to cause a chemical reaction to the lacquer coating; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a radiation labile layer on the bottom side of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lacquer coating is selected from a functional group consisting essentially of acrylate ester and multi-functional acrylate for free radical polymerization, vinyl ethers, cycloaliphatic diepoxide and polyol systems, and for cationic polymerization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multifunctional acrylate is selected from a group consisting essentially of: 
<claim-text>acrylated polyols with molecular weights from 150 to 600; </claim-text>
<claim-text>polyester acrylates with molecular weights from 1000 to 2000; </claim-text>
<claim-text>polyether acryiates with molecular weights from 200 to 1500; </claim-text>
<claim-text>polyester urethane acrylates with molecular weights from 400 to 2000; </claim-text>
<claim-text>polyurea acrylates with molecular weights from 400 to 2000; </claim-text>
<claim-text>epoxy acrylates with molecular weights from 300 to 1000; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>mixtures of multifunctional acrylates. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multifunctional acrylate is further selected from a group consisting of: pentaerythritol tetraacrylate, ditrimethylolpropane tetraacrylate, trimethylolpropane triacrylate, glycerol triacrylate, triacryl ate ester of tris-t2hydroxy-ethyll isocyanurate, hexanediol diacrylate, and dipentaerythritol hexacrylate, and ethoxylated and propoxylated derivatives thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lacquer coating has a normalized thickness in a range of 0.5-20 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the highly accelerated particles emit energy in a range of 0.5-10 Mrads to cause the chemical reaction to the lacquer coating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the chemical reaction is a polymerization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polymerization cures the lacquer coating by transforming from a liquid state to a solid state. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the chemical reaction is a sterilization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the chemical reaction is a cross-linking. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate is made of a material selected from a group consisting essentially of: polyolefins, including oriented polypropylene (OPP), cast polypropylene, polyethylene and polyethylene copolymer; polystyrene; polyesters, including polyethylene terephthalate (PET), or polyethylene naphthalate (PEN); polyolefin copolymers, including ethylene vinyl acetate, ethylene acrylic acid and ethylene vinyl alcohol (EVOH), polyvinylalcohol and copolymers thereof; polyamides, including nylon, and MXD6; polyimides; polyacrylonitrile; polyvinylchloride; polyvinyl dichloride; polyvinylidene chloride; polyacrylates; ionomers; polysaccharides, including regenerated cellulose; silicone, including rubbers or sealants; natural or synthetic rubbers; glassine or clay coated paper; paper board; craft paper; and metallized films and vapor deposited metal oxide coated polymer films, including AlO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>, SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>, or TiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate has a normalized thickness in a range of 10-200 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a label print printed on the top side of the substrate and protected by the lacquer coating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a barrier layer on one of the top and bottom sides of the substrate to maintain a condition of contents of a packaged product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a label print printed on the top side of the barrier layer and protected by the lacquer coating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the barrier layer is applied by a vacuum deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the barrier layer comprises a layer of vaporized aluminum, including a layer of aluminum oxides (AlO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the layer of vaporized aluminum has a thickness in a range of 100-1000 Angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the barrier layer comprises a layer of silicon oxides (SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the layer of silicon oxides (SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>) has a thickness in a range of 100-1000 Angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the radiation labile layer is a sealing layer made of a material suitable to heat seal a packaged product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the heat seal layer is made of a polymer having a melting point at a temperature range of 100-150 degrees Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the heat seal layer is made of a material selected from a group consisting of polyethylene, polyvinylacetate, ethylene propylene copolymer, terpolymer ethylene acrylic acid, metallocene, ionomer, and combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the radiation labile layer is a sealing layer made of a material suitable to cold seal a packaged product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cold seal layer is made of a material selected from a group consisting of natural rubber, polyamides, and combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The particle beam treatable material of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the radiation labile layer has a normalized thickness in a range of 5-50 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A method for making a particle beam treatable material, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a substrate having a top side and a bottom side; </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a radiation labile layer on the bottom side of the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a particle beam treatable lacquer coating on the top side of the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing the lacquer coating to highly accelerated particles generated by a particle beam processing device operating at a voltage of 110 kVolts or below to cause a chemical reaction to the lacquer coating without effecting the radiation labile layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lacquer coating is selected from a functional group consisting essentially of: acrylate ester for free radical polymerization, vinyl ethers, cycloaliphatic diepoxide and polyol systems, for cationic polymerization, and multifunctional acrylate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multifunctional acrylate is selected from a group consisting essentially of: 
<claim-text>acrylated polyols with molecular weights from 150 to 600; </claim-text>
<claim-text>polyester acrylates with molecular weights from 1000 to 2000; </claim-text>
<claim-text>polyether acryiates with molecular weights from 200 to 1500; </claim-text>
<claim-text>polyester urethane acrylates with molecular weights from 400 to 2000; </claim-text>
<claim-text>polyurea acrylates with molecular weights from 400 to 2000; </claim-text>
<claim-text>epoxy acrylates with molecular weights from 300 to 1000; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>mixtures of multifunctional acrylates. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multifunctional acrylate is further selected from a group consisting essentially of: pentaerythritol tetraacrylate, ditrimethylolpropane tetraacrylate, trimethylolpropane triacrylate, glycerol triacrylate, triacrylate ester of tris-t2hydroxy-ethyll isocyanurate, hexanediol diacrylate, and dipentaerythritol hexacrylate, and ethoxylated and propoxylated derivatives thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lacquer coating has a normalized thickness in a range of 0.5-20 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying a lacquer coating comprises applying by one of a roll coating application, an offset gravuare application, a direct gravuare application, and a combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the highly accelerated particles emit energy in a range of 0.5-10 Mrads to cause the chemical reaction to the lacquer coating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the chemical reaction comprises a polymerization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polymerization cures the lacquer coating transforming from a liquid state to a solid state. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate is made of a material selected from a group consisting essentially of: polyolefins, including oriented polypropylene (OPP), cast polypropylene, polyethylene and polyethylene copolymer; polystyrene; polyesters, including polyethylene terephthalate (PET), or polyethylene naphthalate (PEN); polyolefin copolymers, including ethylene vinyl acetate, ethylene acrylic acid and ethylene vinyl alcohol (EVOH), polyvinylalcohol and copolymers thereof; polyamides, including nylon, and MXD6; polyimides; polyacrylonitrile; polyvinylchloride; polyvinyl dichloride; polyvinylidene chloride; polyacrylates; ionomers; polysaccharides, including regenerated cellulose; silicone, including rubbers or sealants; natural or synthetic rubbers; glassine or clay coated paper; paper board; craft paper; and metallized films and vapor deposited metal oxide coated polymer films, including AlO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>, SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>, or TiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate has a normalized thickness in a range of 10-200 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising applying a label print on the top side of the substrate, the label print being protected by the lacquer coating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying a label print comprises applying by one of a flexography printing, a rotor-gravuare printing, an offset lithography printing, a spray printing, and a combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising applying a barrier layer on one of the top and bottom sides of the substrate to maintain a condition of contents of a packaged product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising applying a label print on the top side of the barrier layer and protected by the lacquer coating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying a barrier layer is performed by a vacuum deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying a barrier layer further comprises applying a layer of vaporized aluminum, including a layer of aluminum oxides (AlO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the layer of vaporized aluminum has a thickness in a range of 100-1000 Angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying a barrier layer further comprises applying a layer of silicon oxides (SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the layer of silicon oxides (SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>) has a thickness in a range of 100-1000 Angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying a radiation labile layer further comprises applying a heat seal layer to heat seal a packaged product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying a heat seal layer further comprises extruding the heat seal layer onto the bottom side of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the heat seal layer is made of a polymer having a melting point at a temperature range of 100-150 degrees Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the heat seal layer is made of a material selected from a group consisting of polyethylene, polyvinylacetate, ethylene propylene copolymer, terpolymer ethylene acrylic acid, metallocene, ionomer, and combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying a radiation labile layer further comprises applying a cold seal layer to cold seal a packaged product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cold seal layer is made of a material selected from a group consisting of natural rubber, polyamides, and combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cold seal layer has a normalized thickness in a range of 5-50 grams/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. A particle beam processing device of small size and high efficiency that causes a chemical reaction on a substrate, comprising: 
<claim-text>a power supply; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vacuum pump to create and maintain a vacuum environment in a vessel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a particle generating assembly located in a vacuum vessel and connected to the power supply operating at a first voltage in a range of 110 kVolts or less, the particle generating assembly including at least one filament for generating a plurality of particles upon heating; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a foil support assembly operating at a second voltage, which is higher than the first voltage, to permit at least a portion of said particles to travel from the first to the second voltage and exit the foil support assembly, the foil support assembly comprising a thin foil made of titanium or alloys thereof having a thickness of 10 micrometers or less; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing assembly for receiving said particles exiting the foil support assembly for use to cause said chemical reaction, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a machine yield (K) of the processing device is determined according to: </claim-text>
<claim-text> 
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00004">
<number>4</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>K</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <mrow>
      <mi>D</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>s</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>e</mi>
        <mo>&CenterDot;</mo>
        <mi>S</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>p</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>d</mi>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mi>C</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>u</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>nt</mi>
    </mrow>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00004" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00004.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00004" wi="216.027" he="17.03835" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby: </claim-text>
<claim-text>K is machine yield measured in Mrads&middot;feet/min/mAmp, </claim-text>
<claim-text>Dose is energy absorbed per unit mass measured in Mrads, </claim-text>
<claim-text>Speed is feed rate of the substrate measured in feet/min, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>Current is a number of electrons extracted from the heated filament measured in mAmp. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. A particle beam processing device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the machine yield (K) is equal to or above 20/L where L is the width of the processing device measured in feet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. A particle beam processing device of small size and high efficiency that causes a chemical reaction on a substrate, comprising: 
<claim-text>a power supply; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vacuum pump to create and maintain a vacuum environment in a vessel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a particle generating assembly located in a vacuum vessel and connected to the power supply operating at a first voltage in a range of 110 kVolts or less, the particle generating assembly including at least one filament for generating a plurality of particles upon heating; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a foil support assembly operating at a second voltage, which is higher than the first voltage, to permit at least a portion of said particles to travel from the first to the second voltage and exit the foil support assembly, the foil support assembly comprising a thin foil made of aluminum or alloys thereof having a thickness of 20 micrometers or less; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing assembly for receiving said particles exiting the foil support assembly for use to cause said chemical reaction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a machine yield (K) of the processing device is determined according to: </claim-text>
<claim-text> 
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00005">
<number>5</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>K</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <mrow>
      <mi>D</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>s</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>e</mi>
        <mo>&CenterDot;</mo>
        <mi>S</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>p</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>d</mi>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mi>C</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>u</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>nt</mi>
    </mrow>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00005" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00005.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00005" wi="216.027" he="17.03835" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby: </claim-text>
<claim-text>K is machine yield measured in Mrads&middot;feet/min/mAmp, </claim-text>
<claim-text>Dose is energy absorbed per unit mass measured in Mrads, </claim-text>
<claim-text>Speed is feed rate of the substrate measured in feet/min, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>Current is a number of electrons extracted from filament measured in mAmp. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. A particle beam processing device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the machine yield (K) is equal to or above 20/L where L is the width of the processing device measured in feet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. A method for causing a chemical reaction on a substrate in a particle beam processing device, comprising: 
<claim-text>creating and maintaining a vacuum in a particle generating assembly having at least one filament; </claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the at least one filament to create a plurality of particles; </claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the particle generating assembly at a first voltage having a range of 110 kVolts or less; </claim-text>
<claim-text>operating a foil support assembly having a thin foil at a second voltage, which is higher than the first voltage, to cause at least a portion of said particles to travel from the first voltage to the second voltage, and to exit the vacuum in the particle generating assembly, the thin foil being made of titanium or alloys thereof and having a thickness of 10 micrometers or less; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>passing the exiting particles through the thin foil to enter a processing assembly where the substrate is being exposed to the particles; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a machine yield (K) of the processing device is determined by: </claim-text>
<claim-text> 
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00006">
<number>6</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>K</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <mrow>
      <mi>D</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>s</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>e</mi>
        <mo>&CenterDot;</mo>
        <mi>S</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>p</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>d</mi>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mi>C</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>u</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>nt</mi>
    </mrow>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00006" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00006.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00006" wi="216.027" he="17.03835" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby: </claim-text>
<claim-text>K is machine yield measured in Mrads&middot;feet/min/mAmp, </claim-text>
<claim-text>Dose is energy absorbed per unit mass measured in Mrads, </claim-text>
<claim-text>Speed is feed rate of the substrate measured in feet/min, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>Current is a number of electrons extracted from filament measured in mAmp. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 58</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the machine yield (K) is equal to or above 20/L where L is a width of the processing device measured in feet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. A method for causing a chemical reaction on a substrate in a particle beam processing device, comprising: 
<claim-text>creating and maintaining a vacuum in a particle generating assembly having at least one filament; </claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the at least one filament to create a plurality of particles; </claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the particle generating assembly at a first voltage having a range of 1 10 kVolts or less; </claim-text>
<claim-text>operating a foil support assembly having a thin foil at a second voltage, which is higher than the first voltage, to cause at least a portion of said particles to travel from the first voltage to the second voltage, and to exit the vacuum in the particle generating assembly, the thin foil being made of aluminum or alloy thereof and having a thickness of 20 micrometers or less; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>passing the exiting particles through the thin foil to enter a processing assembly where the substrate is being exposed to the particles, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a machine yield (K) of the processing device is determined according: </claim-text>
<claim-text> 
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00007">
<number>7</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>K</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <mrow>
      <mi>D</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>s</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mi>e</mi>
        <mo>&CenterDot;</mo>
        <mi>S</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>p</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>d</mi>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mi>C</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>u</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>e</mi>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mstyle>
        <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
      </mstyle>
      <mo>&it;</mo>
      <mi>nt</mi>
    </mrow>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00007" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00007.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00007" wi="216.027" he="17.03835" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-M00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby: </claim-text>
<claim-text>K is machine yield measured in Mrads&middot;feet/min/mAmp, </claim-text>
<claim-text>Dose is energy absorbed per unit mass measured in Mrads, </claim-text>
<claim-text>Speed is feed rate of the substrate measured in feet/min, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>Current is a number of electrons extracted from filament measured in mAmp. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The method of claim <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, wherein the machine yield (K) is equal to or above 20/L where L is a width of the processing device measured in feet.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001108A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
