<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001528A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001528A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001528A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001528A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001528A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001528A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001528A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001528A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001528A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001528A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001528</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10164612</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020610</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-37071</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01J023/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>315</class>
<subclass>500000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>315</class>
<subclass>502000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Ion implanting system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Young-Byeong</given-name>
<family-name>Joo</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Suwon-city</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HARNESS, DICKEY &amp; PIERCE, P.L.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 8910</address-1>
<city>RESTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>20195</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An ion implanting system including an ion implanting chamber for implanting an ion into a semiconductor wafer, a load lock chamber for loading the semiconductor wafer into the ion implanting chamber, a turbo pump for creating a high vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber, a low vacuum pump for creating a low vacuum atmosphere in the turbo pump, a cryo pump controller for generating a control signal to control a pumping operation of the turbo pump, a control voltage generator for generating a control voltage in response to the control signal generated from the cryo pump controlle, an interface for generating a starting signal in response to the control voltage, and a turbo pump controller for applying a voltage to operate the turbo pump and the low vacuum pump in response to the starting signal output from the interface. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of Korean Patent Application No. 2001-37071, filed on Jun. 27, 2001, under 35 U.S.C. &sect;119, the entirety of which is hereby incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an ion implanting system, and more particularly, to a vacuum pump for an ion implanting system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> An ion implanting system includes a source chamber, an ion beam chamber, a main chamber, and a load lock chamber. Theses chambers include at least one vacuum pump for creating a vacuum atmosphere therein, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A conventional ion implanting system includes at least one cryo pump, usable as a vacuum pump, for creating a vacuum atmosphere in a main chamber and at least one cryo pump for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber. Further, the at least one cryo pump for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber is usually smaller in size and operated at higher revolutions per minute (rpm) than the at least one cryo pump for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the main chamber. Hence, the cryo pump(s) for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber is contaminated with impurities more easily than the cryo pump(s) for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the main chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A cryo pump creates a vacuum atmosphere in a chamber by condensing and removing gas molecules that contact a cooling portion refrigerated by liquid hydrogen or liquid helium. When an inside of the cryo pump becomes saturated so that an inside temperature of the cryo pump rises, the cryo pump exhausts impurities therein during a regeneration operation. The regeneration operation includes inputting high temperature nitrogen gas into the cryo pump to vaporize the condensed impurities and outwardly exhaust the vaporized impurities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In other words, when a cryo pump is contaminated with the impurities, an inside temperature of the cryo pump rises. When the inside temperature exceeds a set temperature, an error state is indicated, whereby an operation of the cryo pump is stopped. In order to clean an inside of the cryo pump, an operator initiates a regeneration operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Since the cryo pump for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber is contaminated with impurities more easily than the cryo pump for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the main chamber, the cryo pump for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber requires more frequent regeneration operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a conventional ion implanting system. The ion implanting system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> includes a source chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, an ion beam chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a roughing pump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, cryo pumps <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and valves V<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to V<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The source chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> ionizes gas molecules externally injected. The ion beam chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> accelerates ions input from the source chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to generate an ion beam. The main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> irradiates the ion beam from the ion beam chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> into a semiconductor wafer (not shown). The load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> load/unload the semiconductor wafer into/from the main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The cryo pumps <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> create a high vacuum atmosphere in the main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> creates a high vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and vacuum lines VL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to VL<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The valve V<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> opens or closes a channel between the source chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the ion beam chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The valve V<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> opens or closes a channel between the ion beam chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The valves V<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to V<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> open or close channels between the main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the cryo pumps <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, respectively. The valves V<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to V<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> open or close channels between the main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, respectively. The value V<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> opens or closes a channel between the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the vacuum line VL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> applies control signals for controlling the cryo pumps <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, respectively, and generates an error signal in response to temperature sensing signals &ldquo;a&rdquo; to &ldquo;e&rdquo;, respectively, applied from the cryo pumps when a temperature within the cryo pumps <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> exceeds a set temperature. The compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> generates control voltages STARTA and RUNA to the cryo pumps <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in response to the control signals applied from the cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. STARTA and RUNA are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> as the control voltages for controlling the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A vacuum pumping operation of the ion implanting system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Semiconductor wafers (not shown) are loaded into cassettes (not shown) of the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The valves V<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to V<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are opened, and the valve V<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is closed. A low vacuum atmosphere is created in the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the vacuum lines VL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to VL<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> by the roughing pump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The roughing pump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> performs a pumping operation to maintain a pressure of about 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The valve V<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is closed, and the valves V<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and V<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to V<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are opened. A high vacuum atmosphere is created in the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the vacuum lines VL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to VL<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> by the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A high vacuum atmosphere is created such that compressed helium gas from the compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> reduces a temperature of a gas to be refrigerated. The roughing pump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> performs a pumping operation to maintain to a pressure of about 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr to about 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr. The cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> performs a pumping operation to create a high vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the vacuum lines VL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to VL<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> when the compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> applies the control voltages STARTA and RUNA to the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in response to the control signal applied from the cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The valves V<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to V<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> arranged between the main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are opened, and the cassettes of the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> that load the semiconductor wafers are placed into the main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, an ion implanting process is performed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> However, since the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for creating a vacuum in the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is smaller in size and operates at higher revolutions per minute (rpm) than the cryo pumps <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for creating a vacuum in the main chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is more easily contaminated than the cryo pumps <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A temperature sensing diode (not shown) detects whether the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is contaminated or not. The cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> receives a temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&rdquo; output from the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and indicates an error state when a temperature inside the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> exceeds a set temperature, thereby stopping an operation of the ion implanting system. The cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> performs a regeneration operation to remove the impurities therein and normal operation may continue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The regeneration operation is performed as follows: nitrogen (N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) gas is input to the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and therefore an inside pressure of the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> rises and reaches a set pressure of an attached relief valve (not shown). The relief valve is opened to outwardly exhaust the impurities and the nitrogen gas inside the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> As a result, in the conventional ion implanting system, when the inside temperature of the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> exceeds a set temperature, an error occurs, whereupon a regeneration operation should be performed after stopping the ion implanting system. Also, the ion implanting process cannot be continued until the regeneration operation is completed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> As described above, in a conventional ion implanting system, a cryo pump for creating a vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber is easily contaminated, and a regeneration operation should be performed often, which lowers the operational performance of the conventional ion implanting system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> To overcome the problems described above, exemplary embodiments of the present invention describe an ion implanting system having higher operational performance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> At least one exemplary embodiment of the present invention provide an ion implanting system, including an ion implanting chamber for implanting an ion into a semiconductor wafer; a load lock chamber for loading the semiconductor wafer into the ion implanting chamber; a turbo pump for creating a high vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber; a low vacuum pump for creating a low vacuum atmosphere in the turbo pump; a cryo pump controller for generating a control signal to control a pumping operation of the turbo pump; a control voltage generator for generating a control voltage in response to the control signal generated from the cryo pump controller; an interface for generating a starting signal in response to the control voltage; and a turbo pump controller for applying a voltage to operate the turbo pump and the low vacuum pump in response to the starting signal output from the interface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The control voltage generator may be a compressor. The interface may include at least two converters, the first converter converting the control voltage into a digital signal to generate the starting signal, the second converter converting a normal operation sensing signal output from the turbo pump controller into an analog signal to generate a temperature sensing output signal. The first converter may include a first relay operating in response to the control voltage, and a first switch turning on, when the first relay is operated, to generate the starting signal. The second converter may include a second relay operating in response to the normal operation sensing signal, and a current converting circuit for converting a current of the temperature sensing output signal when the second relay is operated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The current converting circuit may include two diodes serially connected and generate the temperature sensing output signal, and a second switch connected between the two diodes, the second switch connecting both of the two diodes when the second relay is not operated and connecting either of the two diodes when the second relay is operated. The interface may further include an overload sensor for applying the voltage to the low vacuum pump in response to the control voltage and for cutting off the voltage when an overload of the low vacuum pump is sensed. The overload sensor may include a third switch for applying the voltage to the low vacuum pump in response to the control voltage, and a third relay for applying the voltage transferred from the third switch to the low vacuum pump and for cutting off the voltage when an overload of the low vacuum voltage is sensed. The turbo pump controller may include a starter for applying the voltage to the turbo pump in response to a signal applied from the first converter, and a normal operation sensor for receiving a signal applied from the turbo pump to sense a normal operation of the turbo pump in order to generate the normal operation sensing signal.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> For a more complete understanding of the present invention and the advantages thereof, reference is now made to the following descriptions taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which like reference numerals denote like parts, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a conventional ion implanting system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating an ion implanting system according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating an, exemplary embodiment of a turbo pump controller and the interface of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating another exemplary embodiment of the turbo pump controller and the interface of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFFERED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made in detail to exemplary embodiments of the present invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating an ion implanting system according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. The ion implanting system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> includes a turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, a roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, a turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and an interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> instead of the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Like reference numerals of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> denote like components and perform like operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> serves to pump the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> creates a vacuum in the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> controls an operation of the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Input and output (I/O) signals to and from the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, i.e., a starting signal PW and a normal operation sensing signal TS, may be digital signals, and control voltages STARTA and RUNA and a temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo; may be analog signals. The interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is arranged to enable signal transmission between the compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> converts the control voltage STARTA and RUNA outputted from the compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into digital signals and applies them to the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Also, the interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> converts the normal operation sensing signal TS into analog signals to generate the temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo; and apply it to the cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In other words, instead of the cryo pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> that often requires a regeneration operation, the ion implanting system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> includes the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> that does not perform a regeneration operation to create a high vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A vacuum pumping operation of the ion implanting system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The valve V<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is closed, and the valves V<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to V<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are opened. The roughing pump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> performs a pumping operation to create a low vacuum atmosphere in the vacuum lines VL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to VL<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the load lock chambers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> applies a control signal for controlling the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to the compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> outputs the control voltages STARTA and RUNA. The interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> converts the control voltages STARTA and RUNA into digital signals to output the starting signal PW, and converts the normal operation sensing signal TS into an analog signal to generate the temperature sensing output signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo;. When an overload is generated in a motor of the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> also cuts off application of the starting signal PW to the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and cuts off the applied voltage to the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, thereby stopping an operation of the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> applies a voltage to the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in response to the starting signal PW, and receives signals applied from the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in order to sense a normal operation to generate the normal operation sensing signals TS. The turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> receives a voltage applied in response to the starting signal PW to perform a high vacuum pumping operation. The roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> receives an applied voltage to perform a low vacuum pumping operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating an exemplary embodiment of the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> includes diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, switches SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and relays <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> includes a diode D<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, photo couplers PT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and PT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a switch SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, an inverter I and a normal operation sensor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The photo coupler PT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes a transistor Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a diode D<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and the photo coupler PT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> includes a transistor Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and a diode D<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> When an operation of the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is not performed, the switch SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to a contact point &ldquo;y&rdquo;, and the switches SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are opened. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> When the control signals STARTA and RUNA are applied so as to perform a pumping operation, the relay <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> operates to close the switch SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. When the starting signal PW is generated, a current flows through the diode D<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, whereby light is emitted. The transistor Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is turned on to close the switch SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and an AC voltage is applied to the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, whereupon the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> perform a pumping operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> When the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> performs a pumping operation abnormally, the normal operation sensor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> receives a signal applied to the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to generate a signal having a logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level. The inverter I inverts the signal having a logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level to generate a signal having a logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level. Hence, a current flows through the diode D<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and light is emitted, whereupon the transistor Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is turned on. When the transistor Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is turned on, the relay <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> operates to make the switch SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> contact to a contact point &ldquo;x&rdquo;. Consequently, a current flows through only the diode D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. That is, an amount of current for the temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo; increases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> performs a pumping operation normally, the normal operation sensor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> receives a signal applied from the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to generate a signal having a logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level. The inverter I inverts the signal having a logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level to generate a signal having a logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level. Hence, the relay <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> does not operate, whereupon the switch SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> contacts the contact point &ldquo;y&rdquo; &ldquo;as is&rdquo;. Consequently, current flows through the diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and an amount of a current for the temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo; is maintained &ldquo;as is&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> receives the temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo; and determines whether the current of the temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo; has increased or not. When the current of the temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo; has increased, the cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> determines that the temperature has risen, thereby indicating an error state. However, if the current of the temperature sensing signal &ldquo;a&prime;&rdquo; is substantially the same, the cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> determines that a pumping operation being performed normally. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As described above, signal transmission between the compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and between the cryo pump controller <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is performed by the interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating an another exemplary embodiment of the turbo pump controller <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the interface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> further includes switches SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, SW<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and a relay <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> added to the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Like reference numerals of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> denote like components and perform like operations. The relay <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> senses an overload differently from the relays <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> When an operation of the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is not performed, the switch SW<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is opened, and the switch SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is closed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> When the control voltages STARTA and RUNA are applied so as to perform a pumping operation, the relay <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> operates to close the switch SW<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and an AC voltage is applied to the switch SW<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the relay <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> performs a pumping operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> When an overload is generated in the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and a current flowing through a motor of the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> increases, the relay <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> operates to cut off an applied voltage to the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Also, the switches SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are closed, and therefore an applied voltage to the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is cut off, thereby stopping an operation of the turbo pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the roughing pump <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As described above, one or more exemplary embodiments of the present invention include a turbo pump instead of a cryo pump for creating a vacuum in the load lock chambers, and therefore, a regeneration operation is not required, which improves the operational performance of the ion implanting system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been particularly shown and described with reference to exemplary embodiments thereof, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that the foregoing and other changes in form and details may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An ion implanting system, comprising: 
<claim-text>an ion implanting chamber for implanting an ion into a semiconductor wafer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a load lock chamber for loading the semiconductor wafer into the ion implanting chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a turbo pump for creating a high vacuum atmosphere in the load lock chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a low vacuum pump for creating a low vacuum atmosphere in the turbo pump; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cryo pump controller for generating a control signal to control a pumping operation of the turbo pump; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control voltage generator for generating a control voltage in response to the control signal generated from the cryo pump controller; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an interface for generating a starting signal in response to the control voltage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a turbo pump controller for applying a voltage to operate the turbo pump and the low vacuum pump in response to the starting signal output from the interface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the control voltage generator is a compressor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the interface includes at least first and second converters, the first converter converting the control voltage into a digital signal to generate the starting signal, the second converter converting a normal operation sensing signal output from the turbo pump controller into an analog signal to generate a temperature sensing output signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first converter includes a first relay operating in response to the control voltage, and a first switch turning on, when the first relay is operated, to generate the starting signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second converter includes a second relay operating in response to the normal operation sensing signal, and a current converting circuit for converting a current of the temperature sensing output signal when the second relay is operated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the current converting circuit includes at least two diodes serially connected and generating the temperature sensing output signal, and a second switch connected between the two diodes, the second switch connecting both of the two diodes when the second relay is not operated and connecting either of the two diodes when the second relay is operated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the interface further includes an overload sensor for applying the voltage to the low vacuum pump in response to the control voltage and for cutting off the voltage when an overload of the low vacuum pump is sensed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the overload sensor includes a third switch for applying the voltage to the low vacuum pump in response to the control voltage, and a third relay for applying the voltage transferred from the third switch to the low vacuum pump and for cutting off the voltage when an overload of the low vacuum voltage is sensed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the turbo pump controller includes a starter for applying the voltage to the turbo pump in response to a signal applied from the first converter, and a normal operation sensor for receiving a signal applied from the turbo pump to sense a normal operation of the turbo pump in order to generate the normal operation sensing signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001528A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001528A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001528A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001528A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001528A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
