<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001361A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001361A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001361</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10231781</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020828</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B62D053/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>280</class>
<subclass>433000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Carrier assembly for a fifth wheel</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10231781</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020828</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09613329</doc-number>
<document-date>20000707</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60186838</doc-number>
<document-date>20000303</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gregory</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Laarman</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Holland</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jose</given-name>
<family-name>Alguera</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>New-Isenburg</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SAND &amp; SEBOLT</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>4801 DRESSLER RD., N.W.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 194</address-2>
<city>CANTON</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>44718</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A carrier assembly for a fifth wheel mounted on a semi-trailer tractor in which there are a pair of generally parallel spaced rail assemblies. Each of these rail assemblies comprises a bed plate, a rack of teeth superimposed over said bed plate and a rack cover plate superimposed over said rack of teeth and a plurality of vertical axially spaced bolting means extending through said rack cover plate, rack of teeth and base bed plate. The carrier assembly also includes a slider assembly comprising a pair of spaced generally parallel axial elements each of which is superimposed over one of said bed plates. There is also a transverse element connecting said generally parallel axial elements, and said slider assembly supports a tooth engaging means for selectively employed the rack of teeth on the rail assemblies. Arrangements are disclosed which enable the carrier assembly to be attached to the tractor and rear stops to be attached to the rest of the assembly without welding. Arrangements for facilitating motion of the slider assembly and for reducing or eliminating debris accumulation are also disclosed. Another arrangement is disclosed which resists shear forces. The present invention also encompasses a connecting and disconnecting device for a fifth wheel assembly. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a divisional of nonprovisional application Ser. No. 09/613,329 filed Jul. 7, 2000, which claimed priority from provisional application Ser. No. 06/186,838 filed Mar. 3, 2000. This application incorporates by reference the disclosures of both of these applications.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Technical Field </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to fifth wheel assemblies for coupling semi-trailers to tractors. More particularly the invention relates to a method and apparatus for assisting the precise positionment of an adjustable fifth wheel carrier assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Background Information </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Large highway freight trailers are usually coupled to an associated tractor by means of a fifth wheel assembly whereby the tractor rear drive axles directly support a portion of the trailer load burden. Usually, the fifth wheel coupling and support point is located along the length of the tractor between the rear drive wheels and the front steering wheels thereby distributing the front trailer burden between the driver and the steering wheels. The exact percentage of load desirably placed upon the front steering wheels is a variable dependent upon many factors including the axle loading road surface, the tractor equipment, the weather, the weight of the trailer and the preference of the driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Some degree of control over these variables is provided by a fifth wheel receiver that is mounted on a slide carrier assembly. The carriage assembly is rail guided and includes an anchoring mechanism for securing the slidable assembly at the desired point along the tractor length between the driving and steering wheel axles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In fifth wheel carrier assemblies heretofore in use, the parallel rail assemblies have been welded to an angle that is bolted to the frame of the tractor. This arrangement is inconvenient for original equipment manufacturer, (O.E.M.) installation and may result in welds which may be disuniform and possible damage to the tractor body when it becomes necessary to remove and replace the carrier assembly. Replacing the carrier assembly, which is fixed to the tractor in this way, also usually necessitates the use of a relatively centralized maintenance facility for this procedure. A need, therefore, exists for a way to assemble and mount the fifth wheel carrier assembly on a tractor at other locations and to do so without the detriments attended to welding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Heretofore, such fifth wheel carrier assemblies have also conventionally been provided with a stop feature that prevents rearward movement of the slider assembly. These stop features have usually been welded to the rail assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Many O.E.M. fifth wheel installations are ordered for dealer inventory and showrooms. When a purchaser is identified, it is often necessary (due to customer specifications) to change the fifth wheel height. Thereby, necessitating removal of this carriage assembly. A need, therefore, exists to provide easy removal of the rear stop to facilitate an easy change in fifth wheel height. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A second disadvantage to such construction is that there may be quality concerns with the welds and cracks may develop after use in the field. A need exists, therefore, for a way to place such stop features which avoids these problems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another problem which has sometimes been experienced with the prior art systems is that substantial resistance to moving the slider assembly on the rail assemblies may develop with the result that part wear may increase and substantially more force may be required to move the slider assembly. Accordingly, there is a need for a means to increase the ease of moving the slider assembly on the rail assemblies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> It is also found that debris may tend to infiltrate and accumulate in the carrier assembly. Such debris may necessitate increased maintenance or may reduce the life of the assembly. A need, therefore, also exists for a way to reduce or eliminate such debris infiltration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> When a semi-trailer/tractor starts and stops suddenly, large loads may be created on the fifth wheel carrier locking (plunger/rack interface) ably. It is desirable to distribute these loads over several mounting bolts, thus reducing the shear load. There is, therefore, a need for a way of providing support against such shear loads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The carriage locking device on prior art relies upon spring force to close and hold the locking plungers in. There is a need to provide a convenient way to close the locking mechanism, to identify that the lock in plungers are engaged and provide a secondary lock in device to ensure that they stay locked once closed. As the locking plungers and rack wear (through use) it is desirable to adjust for this wear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Finally, when connecting a trailer a locking mechanism is desirable that assures the driver that it is closed, is readily inspectable that is locked and provides a secondary security to keep it closed. In many commonly used arrangement, there is no such device, or if provided it often requires release the secondary security device to the use of two hands. A need, therefore, exists for a connection and disconnection mechanism which provides a secondary security device that can be easily inspected and can be operated quickly and easily using only one hand. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It is an objective of the present invention to provide a way to fix fifth wheel carrier assemblies to the tractor and to form integrated rail elements without the necessity of welding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> It Is another objective of the present invention to provide a rear stop for a fifth wheel carrier assembly without having to weld such features onto the carrier base so that the slider assembly can be easily removed from the rail assemblies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> It is also an objective of the present invention to provide a means for more easily moving the slider assembly on the rail assembly elements of a fifth wheel carrier assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> It is still another objective of the present invention to provide a way to reduce or eliminate the infiltration and accumulation of debris in the carrier assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> It is also an objective of the present invention to provide a means for shear load sharing when a tractor moves from a linear path to a curve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> It is also an objective of the present invention to provide a slide locking mechanism that contains a secondary securing mechanism that is reading inspectable for proper locking and ensures that it remains locked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> It is still a further objective of the present invention to provide a means for quickly and easily operating the connection and disconnection mechanism on the fifth wheel assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the present invention there is a carrier assembly for a fifth wheel mounted on a semi-trailer tractor in which there are a pair of generally parallel spaced rail assemblies. Preferably each of these rail assemblies comprises a bed plate, a rack of teeth superimposed over said bed plate and a rack cover plate superimposed over said rack of teeth and a plurality of vertical axially spaced bolting means extending through said rack cover plate, rack of teeth and base bed plate. The assembly also includes a slider assembly comprising a pair of spaced generally parallel axial elements each of which is superimposed over one of said bed plates. There is also a transverse element connecting said generally parallel axial elements and supporting a tooth engaging means for selectively employing the rack of teeth on the rail assemblies. The slider assembly may then be fixed in an axial position when said tooth engaging means are employed. Axial movement of the slider on said bed plates is also possible when the tooth engaging means are not employed to permit a positional adjustment of said fifth wheel on the trailer. In this embodiment the rail assembly is connected to the tractor by bolting means which preferably will also be used to form the bed plate, rack of teeth and rack cover plate into an integral rail assembly. The disadvantages of bolting the rail assemblies to the tractor are thereby avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the invention comprises a carrier assembly in which there are a pair of generally parallel spaced rail assemblies extending from a front end of said carrier assembly to a rear end of said carrier assembly. The slider assembly comprises a pair of spaced generally parallel axial elements each of which is superimposed over one of said bed plates, and a transverse element connects said generally parallel axial elements and supports a tooth engaging means for selectively employing said rack of teeth to cause the slider to be fixed in an axial position when said tooth engaging means are employed. Axial movements of said slider on said bed plates is possible when said tooth engaging means are not employed to permit a positional adjustment of said fifth wheel on the trailer. A rear stop is bolted to the rail assemblies by means of this invention, the slider assembly can be easily removed from the rail assemblies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the present invention, there is also a pair of generally parallel spaced rail assemblies on which a slider assembly, as is described above, is superimposed. To allow the slider assemblies to be moved more easily on the bed plates by increasing contact area, slidable plates which extend laterally beyond the lateral edges of the rail assemblies are interposed between the lateral elements of the slider assemblies and the bed plate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The present invention also includes an embodiment in which there is a pair of generally parallel spaced rail assemblies extending from a front end of said carrier assembly to a rear end of said carrier assembly. Each of said rail assemblies comprises a bed plate, a rack of teeth superimposed over said bed plate and a rack cover plate superimposed over said rack of teeth. There is also a slider assembly as described above which is superimposed over the rail assemblies. The rack cover plate extends over the rack of teeth and overlaps the bed plate. Infiltration and accumulation of debris is thus avoided by this arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> There is also another embodiment in which a pair of generally parallel spaced rail assemblies extending from a front end of said carrier assembly to a rear end of said carrier assembly. Each of said rail assemblies comprising a bed plate, a rack of teeth superimposed over said bed plate and a rack cover plate superimposed over said rack of teeth. The slider assembly comprises a pair of spaced generally parallel axial elements each of which is superimposed over one of said bed plates and a transverse element connecting said generally parallel axial elements and there is a tooth engaging means for selectively employing said rack of teeth on the rail assemblies to cause the slider to be fixed in an axial position when said tooth engaging means are employed and to allow axial movements of said slider on said bed plates when said tooth engaging means are not employed to permit a positional adjustment of said fifth wheel on the trailer. The rack of teeth is comprised of a plurality of generally uniform axially aligned teeth having spaces between adjacent teeth. The teeth on each of the parallel axially spaced rails are positioned in opposed relation to the teeth on the other of said axially spaced rails and at a position over at least one of the teeth the rack cover and the bed plate are pressed against said tooth, so as to share shear load resulting from sudden starts and stops so as to reduce shear loads at any one position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment an improved means of operating the connecting and disconnecting mechanism is provided. This embodiment comprises a lever, from which a lock bar extends. A &ldquo;C&rdquo; shaped lock jaw is retained by the lock bar in a locked position, but is biased to move to an unlocked position when the lever is pivoted to move the lock bar so as to at least partially release the lock jaw from the lock bar and allow the lock jaw to move to an unlocked position. Preferably the lever is moved by a handle that extends laterally from one of its end outside the fifth wheel assembly.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiment of the invention, illustrative of the best mode in which applicant contemplated applying the principles, is set forth in the following description and is shown in the drawings and is particularly and distinctly pointed out and set forth in the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of a tractor trailer combination on which various aspects of the present invention are illustrated; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are respectively a perspective, top plan, side and front view of a preferred embodiment of the carrier assembly for a fifth wheel of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective exploded view of the carrier assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top plan schematic view of a pair of rail assemblies used in a prior art carrier assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an end view of a prior art rail assemblies shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic end view of a pair of rail assemblies along with relating apparatus used in the carrier assembly of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a top plan view of a rack cover plate used in a rail assembly of the carrier assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an end view of the rack cover plate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a detailed view of the area in circle <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the integral rack used in a rail assembly of the carrier assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a front elevational view of the integral rack shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the bed plate used in a rail assembly of the carrier assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a front view of the bed plate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a detailed view of the area in circle <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a top plan view of a rear stop used in the carrier assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is an end view of the rear stop shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a schematic top view of a rail assembly with welded rear stops used in a prior art carrier assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is an end view of the rail assembly with welded rear stops shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a schematic top plan view of the rail assembly with rear stop used in the carrier assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is an end view of the rail assemblies and rear stop shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a fragmented side elevational view of a rail assembly used in the carrier assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a schematic end view of a pair of rail assemblies showing slide features used in a prior art carrier assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is a schematic end view of a pair of rail assemblies including a sled feature as may be used in a carrier assembly as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a bottom plan view of a fifth wheel which includes a preferred opening feature of the present inventions in a locked position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> is an end view of the fifth wheel shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view through <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference> is a bottom plan view of the fifth wheel shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> in an intermediate opening position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference> is an end view of the fifth wheel shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference> is a bottom plan view of the fifth wheel shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> in an open position; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference> is an end view of the fifth wheel shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> highway tractor-trailer unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown to include a powered tractor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a trailer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> connected by a fifth wheel hitch assembly <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for relative articulation about a vertical axis. As is explained in greater detail hereafter, the fifth wheel is mounted on a carrier assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Propulsive power of the tractor unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is delivered to driving wheels <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Tractor directional steering is controlled by front wheels <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Trailer secured wheels <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> carry the aft end of the trailer load and are served by a braking mechanism that may be engaged independently of the tractor wheel brakes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> To illustrate the objective of a position adjustable fifth wheel unit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> the value X is shown as the distance between the fifth wheel vertical hitch axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the tractor steered wheel plane <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. If the fifth wheel hitch axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is shifted to the aft of the tractor by a distance Y the percentage of trailer load carried by the tractor steering wheels is correspondingly reduced and the load carried by the tractor driving wheels <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Referring to the figures generally and in particular to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the carrier assembly is shown generally at numeral <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. This carrier assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a base made up of spaced parallel rail assemblies <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Each of these rail assemblies includes a bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> an integral rack of teeth <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and a rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. On the bed plate there are a plurality of bolt receiving apertures as at aperture <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>). On the integral rack of teeth <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> there are a plurality of apertures as at aperture <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> which are aligned with apertures on the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. On the rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> there are also a plurality of bolt receiving apertures as at aperture <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and each of these apertures are aligned with apertures in the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the integral rack of teeth <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. These aligned apertures receive bolts as at bolt <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> which are engaged with a nut <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>). These bolt and nut combinations allow the rail assemblies <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to be formed as an integral unit and also attach them to the frame <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) of the tractor and thereby avoid welding. The rail assemblies as at rail assembly <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> also include shear resistance spacers <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and bracket <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> which are connected to the assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> respectively by bolts <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. These bolts are also connected by nuts as at nut <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> in the case of bolt <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. As will be explained in greater detail hereafter, there are also extrusion apertures as at aperture <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> on the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and extrusion apertures as at aperture <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> on the rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Referring to the drawings generally and particularly to FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, it will be seen that the integral rack has a plurality of teeth as at tooth <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> mounted on a plate <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Between the teeth there are intermediate spaces as at space <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. It will be understood that the plate <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is integral with the teeth and may be either below or above them. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Referring again to the drawings generally and in particular to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the slider assembly is shown generally at numeral <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. Included in the slider assembly <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> there is a pair of generally parallel axial members <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. On each of these axial members there are respectively mounting brackets <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> for mounting the fifth wheel which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> in phantom lines at numeral <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. The mounting brackets <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> may preferably be welded directly to the parallel axial members <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> respectively. The slider assembly <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> has medial transverse members <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. On transverse member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> there is mounted lateral arm <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> which has distal fingers as at finger <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. In opposed relation to lateral arm <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> there is a lateral arm <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> having distal fingers as at finger <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. Restraining lateral arms <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> respectively there are springs <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Motion of these lateral arms is controlled in part by guide features as at features <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. There is also a pivot plate <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and a mounting bar <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and lateral arm <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> is pivotally mounted on this pivot plate at pivot point <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> while lateral arm <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is mounted at pivot point <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. On the pivot plate <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> there is also a forward pivot point <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> at which it is connected to a spring biased piston and cylinder combination <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. This piston and cylinder combination <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is connected at its opposed end to member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of the slider assembly through member <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). Preferably, the piston and cylinder combination <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is a pneumatic piston and cylinder combination. This piston and cylinder combination <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is spring locked biased and centers the arm control plate <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> onto guide feature <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> which serves as a stop. The connection of the fingers as at <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> with each rack of teeth <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> respectively can be ascertained by visual inspection. It will be appreciated that a positive engagement is provided which does not rely solely on spring force. An automatic spring biased arrangement is thus provided for locking the carrier assembly, which compensates for tooth wear and construction inconsistencies. It will also be appreciated that this arrangement is a positive mechanical spring biased mechanism that securely maintains the carrier assembly in a locking position when it is engaged. On the rail assemblies there is also a front transverse member <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> which is connected to the bed plates <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> by welding. Bolts <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> also serve to hold the cover plates as at plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to the rest of the rail assemblies <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> respectively. The rail assemblies also includes a rear stop member <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> from which brackets <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> extend which are connected to the rail assemblies by means of bolts <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> on bracket <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and bolts <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> on bracket <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Differences between the carrier assembly and of the present invention and that of the prior art is explained with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>. Referring particularly to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the prior art method of welding the rail assemblies is explained in greater detail as follows. Such an arrangement would include a bed plate <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, which has lateral mounting angles <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. This bed plate <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> would be welded to the mounting angles <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> by means of weld points <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. Parallel racks of teeth <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> would be welded onto the bed plate <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> by welds <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> respectively. A slide element <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> on the slider assembly is moved on the bed plate on brackets <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Similarly a lateral slider element <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> on the slider assembly is moved on the bed plate <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> on brackets <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. Comparing this prior art arrangement with the apparatus of the present invention shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, it will be appreciated that certain advantages are available with the apparatus of the present invention. First, in this prior art apparatus, welding the carrier assembly to the mounting angles is necessary. In the carrier assembly of the present invention, on the other hand, the rail assemblies <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> may be fixed to the tractor frame <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> by means of bolts and nut combinations as, for example, bolt <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and nut <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Another advantage of the present invention is also apparent from a comparison of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. It will be appreciated that in FIG. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> the rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extends inwardly over the rack of teeth <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to overlap the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. This overlap by the rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> reduces or eliminates the infiltration and accumulation of debris in the track assembly <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a common prior art arrangement for providing rear stops for the slider assembly is shown. In this arrangement there is a bed plate <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> with opposed lateral slide curls <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. To stop the slider assembly there are rear stops <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. These rear stops are attached respectively to the bed plate <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> by welds <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight>. The rear stops <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> are also attached to the mounting angles <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> by welds <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> respectively. It would be understood in the above described prior art arrangement, it would generally be necessary to cut the welded rear stops <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> in order to remove the slider assembly from the rail assemblies. On the other hand, in the arrangement of the present invention, the transverse rear stop <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> may be easily removed without damaging the rest of the assembly by loosening its attaching bolts so as to allow the slider assembly to be removed from the rail assemblies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22, a</cross-reference> common prior art arrangement for mounting the lateral slide elements on the bed plate is shown. In this arrangement there is a bed plate <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> over which a lateral slide element <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> is superimposed. Interposed between lateral slide element <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and the bed plate there are brackets <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> which extend first downwardly then laterally from the lateral slide element. Similarly there is an opposed lateral slide element <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> from which brackets <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> extend to rest upon the bed plate in the same way. A comparative detailed view of the preferred embodiment of the present invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> in which there is a bed plate <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> over which the lateral element <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> rests on a sled <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight>. This sled or slidable plate <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> has a flat base surface <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> which rests directly on the bed plate and an outward curved lateral surface <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. There are also vertical support members <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> between the lateral element <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> and the flat base surface <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight>. On the opposed side of the bed plate <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> there is another lateral element <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> which is superimposed on the sled or slidable plate <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> which also has a flat base surface <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> which rests on the other bed plate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> which is in opposed relation to bed plate <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight>. There is also a curved lateral surface <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> which curves upwardly and outwardly from the bed plate. Similarly there are vertical members <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> interposed between the lateral element <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> and the flat base surface <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated that in the above described embodiment of the present invention that the sleds or slidable plates <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> extend laterally beyond the sides of lateral elements <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>, respectively. It will also be appreciated that surface area between sleds or slidable plates <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and the bed plate <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> is significantly increased over prior art arrangements (as for example brackets <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>) so as to allow the slider assembly to move with considerably greater ease and with less part wear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Referring to the drawings generally and in particular to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>, another embodiment of the present invention is shown. This drawing shows a fragmented section of rail assembly <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in which the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, integral rack of teeth <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are shown. Bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> extend through the rack assembly as is described above and are secured respectively by nuts <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. Also shown are tooth <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, space <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and tooth <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>. Elongated aperture <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is in the rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> above tooth <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, and elongated aperture <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is in the bed plate below tooth <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>. Aperture <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> extends into tooth <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> and joins with the aforesaid apertures <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. On the opposite side of tooth <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> from space <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> there is another space <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>. To provide additional resistance from shear forces when a semi trailer/tractor starts and stops suddenly, rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is manipulated in the vicinity of aperture <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to press the rack cover plate against tooth <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> as at bend <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. Force is also applied to the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of aperture <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> to press the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> against the tooth <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> as at bend <highlight><bold>217</bold></highlight>. Referring also to FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, it will be seen that there are a plurality of elongated apertures in the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, rack of teeth <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and rack cover plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. At each of these elongated apertures, the bed plate <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and rack cover plate would be bent against an adjacent tooth in the way described above as at bends <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight> respectively on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, an embodiment which is a locking mechanism for a fifth wheel assembly is shown. This fifth wheel assembly is shown generally at <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and, except for the connecting and disconnecting mechanism described herein, is otherwise essentially conventional as is, for example, essentially disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,746,438 to Bergmann et al. which is assigned to the assignee of this application and which is incorporated herein by reference. The assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> includes a housing <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> with axial attachment points <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> for a carrier assembly. The assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> also includes, as is conventional, rearwardly projecting ramps <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>, a kingpin receiving gap <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and a blind port <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. The locking and unlocking mechanism includes a lever <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> with a medial lever pivot point <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> and a front end <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and a rear end <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> adjacent the medial lever pivot point <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. There is a lock bar <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> which has a horizontal front edge <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> and a side oblique edge <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>. There is also a &ldquo;C&rdquo; shaped lock jaw <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> which has a pivot point <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The lock jaw has a first end <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> on a recessed leg <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and a second end <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> on a major leg <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. A biasing spring <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> is attached to the lock jaw <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> rearwardly from the pivot point <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. At the front end <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> of the lever it is attached to a handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> at pivot point <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight>. The handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> has an inner end <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> and an outer grip end <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> which is a loop configuration. The outer grip end <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> loop is obliquely configured to facilitate unlocking of the locking mechanism as is explained below. It will also be appreciated that this arrangement allows the user to easily and efficiently ascertain if the assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is properly locked by visually inspecting the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. At the inner end <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> is attached to biasing spring <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> which resists the withdrawal of the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. The handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> also has steps <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> the function of which will be explained hereafter. There is also a leaf spring <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> which biases the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> into a locked position. The handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> extends from the housing <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> through a handle aperture <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> which has a widened unlocked section <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> and a narrowed locked section <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight>. The pivoting of the lever <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> at the handle end <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> forces spring <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> to bias handle <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> into the narrowed locked section <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight>. The operation of the above described locking and unlocking mechanism is as follows. The locked position of the mechanism is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In this locked position the lever <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> is in an oblique position with the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> in an inward position. The lock jaw <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is in a locked position with the horizontal front edge <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> of the lock bar <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> bearing against the recessed leg <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> of the lock jaw <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. Referring particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference>, it will be seen that the leaf spring <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> bears against the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> to maintain the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> in a lower locked position. Referring particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference>, it will be seen that the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> is in the lower locked position when in narrowed locked section <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight> of the handle aperture <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, an intermediate stage in unlocking the fifth wheel assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is shown. The handle outer grip end <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> loop is orientated upon the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> such that the effort of the driver pulling the handle loop will have a touch key to bias the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> up against leaf spring <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> forcing the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> into the widened unlocked section <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight>. This orientation of the handle loop also biases the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> forward allowing step <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> to pass through widened unlocked section <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight>. Here force is applied against the leaf spring <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> to move the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> upwardly to the widened unlocked section <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight>, which is in an upper position of the handle aperture <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated that in this upper position it is possible for the step <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> to move through the handle aperture <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> while in the lower narrowed locked section <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight> the same would not be possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that this arrangement provides a readily apparent visual indication of whether the assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is locked or not. That is, the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> will be positioned in section <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> in an unlocked position and in section <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight> in the locked position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the final step in unlocking the fifth wheel assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is illustrated. Here the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> is pulled outwardly beyond step <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>, pivoted forward and released so that step <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> is engaged on the housing <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. This action is performed against biasing spring <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>. As the driver pulls the tractor forward, the motion of the lockjaw <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> causes leg <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> to drive lever <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> outward releasing handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> from step <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> on housing <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> thereby setting the locking mechanism for recoupling. It will be appreciated that this method of unlocking the fifth wheel assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is quick and efficient and will usually be able to be accomplished with one hand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that whether the assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is locked or unlocked is also readily apparent from the position of the handle <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. That is, when the step <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> engages the housing <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, the assembly <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> will be unlocked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that there has been described a carrier assembly in which the disadvantages of welding the assembly to the tractor are avoided. This carrier assembly also allows the rear stops to be easily and economically removed to facilitate removal of the slider assembly. This carrier assembly also includes features which facilitate movement of the slider assembly on the rail assembly and reduce part wear. This carrier assembly also reduces or eliminates debris infiltration into the apparatus and which shares shear loads. It will also be appreciated that means have been described which allow quick and easy connection and disconnection of the fifth wheel and which provides means for quick visual to ascertain whether the assembly in locked or unlocked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the improved Carrier Assembly for a Fifth Wheel apparatus is simplified, provides an effective, safe, inexpensive, and efficient device which achieves all the enumerated objectives, provides for eliminating difficulties encountered with prior devices, and solves problems and obtains new results in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing description, certain terms have been used for brevity, clearness, and understanding; but no unnecessary limitations are to be implied therefrom beyond the requirement of the prior art, because such terms are used for descriptive purposes and are intended to be broadly construed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the description and illustration of the invention is by way of example, and the scope of the invention is not limited to the exact details shown or described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Having now described the features, discoveries, and principles of the invention, the manner in which the Carrier Assembly for a Fifth Wheel is constructed and used, the characteristics of the construction, and the advantageous new and useful results obtained; the new and useful structures, devices, elements, arrangements, parts, and combinations are set forth in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An improved locking mechanism for a fifth wheel assembly for a tractortrailer truck, said truck having a tractor and a trailer; the trailer having a trailer coupling plate with a downwardly extending kingpin; the tractor having the fifth wheel assembly mounted thereon; the fifth wheel assembly having an assembly coupling plate for coupling with the trailer coupling plate; the assembly coupling plate including a pair of rearwardly projecting ramps separated by a kingpin-receiving gap having a blind port to receive the kingpin; the improved locking mechanism comprising: 
<claim-text>a lever pivotally movable between locked and unlocked positions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lock bar pivotally connected to the lever; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lockjaw movable between locked and unlocked positions; the lockjaw being retained by the lock bar in a locked position adjacent the blind port; the lockjaw being biased to move to the unlocked position when the lever is pivoted to the unlocked position to move the lock bar to at least partially release the lock jaw from the lock bar. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fifth wheel assembly has a housing, the lever extending from a front end to a rear end inside the housing; and a handle having an inner end and an outer grip end and extending laterally from the lever adjacent the front end of the lever. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the outer grip end of the handle extends to a position outside the housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the handle is spring biased against being moved outwardly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the handle extends through an aperture in the housing, the aperture having an unlocked section and a locked section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the unlocked section has a first width and the locked section has a second width differing from the first width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second width is narrowed compared to the first width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the handle is spring biased to remain in the narrowed locked section when the lock jaw is in the locked position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the handle has at least one step which passes through the aperture in the unlocked section when the handle is withdrawn. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step cannot pass through the narrowed locked section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the handle has a terminal loop which is obliquely oriented to facilitate the withdrawal and locking of the handle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the handle has an unlocked position and a locked position providing a means for visually ascertaining if the assembly is locked. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the handle is in an outward position in the unlocked position and in an inward position in the locked position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein there is a first step on the handle which engages the housing to retain the handle in the unlocked position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein there is a second step on the handle which engages the housing to retain the handle in the locked position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lever includes a front and a rear end; the lock bar being pivotally connected to the lever at a medial pivot located intermediate the front and rear ends. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lock jaw is generally C-shaped and has a first end and a second end, the lock bar engaging the first end in the locked position of the lock jaw and the second end in the unlocked position of the lock jaw. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An improved locking mechanism for a fifth wheel assembly for a tractor-trailer truck, said truck having a tractor and a trailer; the trailer having a coupling plate with a downwardly extending kingpin; the tractor having the assembly mounted thereon; the assembly having a coupling plate for coupling with the trailer coupling plate; the assembly coupling plate including a pair of rearwardly projecting ramps separated by a kingpin-receiving gap having a blind port to receive the kingpin; the improved locking mechanism comprising: 
<claim-text>a lever having a front end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lock bar extending from the lever; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lock jaw retained by the lock bar in a locked position adjacent the blind port, but biased to move to an unlocked position when the lever is pivoted to move the lock bar to at least partially release the lock jaw from the lock bar, allowing the lock jaw to move; arid </claim-text>
<claim-text>the assembly including a housing having an aperture formed therein through which a handle passes, the handle extending from adjacent the front end of the lever. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The improved locking mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the aperture has unlocked and locked sections having different widths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An improved locking mechanism for a fifth wheel assembly for a tractor-trailer truck, said truck having a tractor and a trailer; the trailer having a coupling plate with a downwardly extending kingpin; the tractor having the assembly mounted thereon; the assembly having a coupling plate for coupling with the trailer coupling plate; the assembly coupling plate including a pair of rearwardly projecting ramps separated by a kingpin-receiving gap having a blind port to receive the kingpin; the improved locking mechanism comprising: 
<claim-text>a lever; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lock bar extending from the lever; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a C-shaped lockjaw having first and second ends retained by the lock bar in a locked position adjacent the blind port, but biased to move to an unlocked position when the lever is pivoted to move the lock bar to at least partially release the lock jaw from the lock bar, allowing the lock jaw to move; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the lock bar engaging the lock jaw on the first end in the locked position and on the second end in the unlocked position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030001361A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
