<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001749A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001749A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001749A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001749A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001749A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001749A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001749A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001749A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001749A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001749A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001749A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001749A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001749A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001749A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001749</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10158929</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020603</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-193938</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2002-57025</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20020304</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G08B021/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>667000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Seating condition detecting system for vehicle</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shoichi</given-name>
<family-name>Ishida</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Obu-city</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>LAW OFFICES OF DAVID G. POSZ</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2000 L STREET, N.W.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 200</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20036</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A seating condition detecting system has four load sensors, a belt tension sensor and a self-diagnostic system. The first and second abnormal ranges are set for detecting abnormal operations of the system. The upper limit of the first range is set so that a total load becomes heavier as a belt tension becomes higher. The lower limit of the second range is set so that the total load becomes heavier as the belt tension deviates from the point at which the total load becomes lightest. When the total load falls in the first range or the second range, an abnormal operation of the seating condition detecting system is determined. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is based on and incorporates herein by reference Japanese Patent Applications No. 2001-193938 filed on Jun. 27, 2001 and No. 2002-57025 filed on Mar. 4, 2002. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a seating condition detecting system for a vehicle. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In recent years, performance and functions of airbags installed in a vehicle have been improving as attentions to the safety of vehicles increases. It is desired to standardize a system that detects seating conditions of a vehicle occupant and controls airbag inflation based on the detected condition. The seating conditions include seating position and posture of the occupant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A seating condition detecting system has load sensors and a seating condition detecting unit. The load sensors detect loads on springs that support a seat at four positions, right front, left front, right rear and left rear, from underneath. The seating condition detecting unit detects a seating condition of a vehicle occupant based on the loads measured by the load sensors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> However, if the seating condition of the vehicle occupant is not properly determined, the airbag cannot be appropriately inflated for the occupant. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention therefore has an objective to provide a seating condition detecting system with a self-diagnostic function of determining normal or abnormal operations of the system so that an airbag is appropriately inflated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In a vehicle, a seat is supported on four elastic bodies, such as springs, located at right front (RF), left front (LF), right rear (RR) and left rear (LR) underneath the seat. The seating condition detecting system of the present invention has four load sensors to detect loads to which the elastic bodies are subjected. Each sensor is exclusively used for load detection of each elastic body. For instance, the right front (RF) load sensor detects a load to which the RF elastic body is subjected. The seating condition detecting system determines a seating condition of vehicle occupant based on the loads detected by the load sensors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> If the load sensors operate properly, the loads detected by the load sensors are equal to or heavier than 0 whether the occupant is seated. Therefore, if one of the detected loads is negative and its absolute value is equal to or heavier than a predetermined value, the operation of the system is determined as abnormal. To make this determination, the self-diagnostic function is used. The abnormal operation may be caused in the following conditions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The load to which the elastic body is subjected cannot be properly detected due to the defective sensor that detects the load. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A harness of the vehicle is jammed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The seat has a structural strain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Some kind of object is stuck under the seat or in spaces existing sides of the seat. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A force is exerted on the seat from the side.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The above and other objectives, features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description made with reference to the accompanying drawings. In the drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a seating condition detecting system according to the first to the seventh embodiments of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an explanatory schematic view showing a vehicular seat on which a vehicle occupant is seated; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a graph showing belt tension vs. total loads with normal and abnormal ranges indicated with shaded areas according to the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a graph showing abnormal ranges for loads that each load sensor detects according to the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a graph showing a difference between loads with normal and abnormal ranges indicated according to the third embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a graph showing a difference between loads with normal and abnormal ranges, indicated as shaded. areas, according to the third embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a graph showing thresholds and abnormal ranges, indicated as shaded areas, for loads detected by load sensors and for belt tension detected by a belt tension sensor according to the fourth and fifth embodiments; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a seating condition detecting system that has an integrated ECU where the seating condition detecting ECU and airbag ECU are integrated according to modifications of the first to the seventh embodiments; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a graph showing thresholds and abnormal ranges, indicated as shaded areas, for loads detected by load sensors according to the sixth embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a graph showing thresholds and abnormal ranges, indicated as shaded areas, for loads detected by load sensors according to a modification of the sixth embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a graph showing thresholds and abnormal ranges, indicated as shaded areas, for loads detected by load sensors according to the seventh embodiment; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a graph showing thresholds and abnormal ranges, indicated as shaded areas, for loads detected by load sensors according to a modification of the seventh embodiment. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiments of the present invention will be explained with reference to various embodiments that has the same construction shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;First Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a seating condition detecting system has a right front (RF) load sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, a left front (LF) load sensor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a right rear (RR) load sensor <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a left rear (LR) load sensor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a seating condition detecting ECU (electronic control unit) <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and a belt tension sensor <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The belt tension sensor detects belt tension of a seat belt <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> that restrains the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or secures the child seat. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The RF load sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> detects a load to which a right front (RF) elastic body (spring) is subjected. The spring supports a seat frame <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> from underneath at right front. The LF load sensor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> detects a load to which a left front (LF) elastic body (spring <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) is subjected. The spring <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> supports a seat frame <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> from underneath at left front. The right rear (RR) load sensor <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> detects a load to which a right rear (RR) elastic body (spring) is subjected. The spring supports the seat frame <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> from underneath at right rear. The left rear (LR) load sensor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> detects a load to which a left rear (LR) elastic body (spring <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>) is subjected. The spring <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> supports the seat frame <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> from underneath at left rear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> A seating condition determination program is stored in the seating condition detecting ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. That is, this ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is programmed to determine a seating condition of a vehicle occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> based on the loads detected by the load sensors by executing the determination program. The seating conditions to be determined are as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is seated in the center of the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, or off center toward the right or left. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is seated in the center of the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, seated off center toward the front, leaning back or reclining on the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is an infant (in a child seat), a. child or an adult. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is heavy or light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A self-diagnostic program is stored in the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is thus programmed to determine whether the operation of the system is normal. An airbag ECU <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> controls inflation of the airbag, stored in a storage space of steering wheel or dashboard, at a vehicle collision. This control is performed based on the seating condition of the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> immediately before the collision detected by the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In the first embodiment, the self-diagnostic program detects an abnormal operation of the seating condition detecting system when the total of loads detected by the load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> falls into the first abnormal range (too light load range) <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> or the second abnormal range (too heavy load range) <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. When a child seat is mounted on the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the total load increases as the tightness of the child seat mounting (belt tension) increases. This is true for any kind of child seat as long as the belt tension sensor <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and all load sensors operate normally. The normal relationship between the total load and belt tension is indicated with characteristic curves <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight>. Those curves indicate the load total in different experiment settings against the belt tension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The first abnormal range <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is set so that the upper limit <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> of the range <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> becomes higher as the belt tension increases. When the total load falls into the first abnormal range <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the program determines the operation of the system as abnormal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> When the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> wears the seat belt <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the belt tension is low, as indicated with data points <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Different kinds of marks indicate the total load in different experimental settings. The second abnormal range <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is set so that the lower limit <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the range <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> also becomes higher as the belt tension deviates from the point <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> at which the total load becomes lightest. When the total load and belt tension are within the range <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the program determines the operation of the system as abnormal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The abnormal operation of the system may be caused in the following conditions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The load to which the elastic body <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is subjected cannot be properly detected because the seat belt <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> or one or more load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The belt tension cannot be properly detected because the belt tension sensor <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A harness of the vehicle is jammed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has a structural strain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Some kind of object is stuck under the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> or in spaces existing sides of the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> A force is exerted on the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> from the side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> If the system operates abnormally, an airbag cannot be inflated appropriately for the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Since the system detects its abnormal operation with the self-diagnostic function, the inappropriate airbag inflation can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Second Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The second embodiment has the same construction as the first embodiment. However, the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is programmed to determine an abnormal operation of the system when at least one of the detected loads is less than a negative threshold TH<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, TH<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, TH<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or TH<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The negative threshold is set for each load value detected by each load sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The negative threshold is used is because if the load sensors operate properly, the loads detected by the load sensors are equal to or heavier than 0 whether the occupant is seated. When the detected loads become negative, it is considered that a vehicular seat is lifted for some reason, for instance, some substance is stuck underneath the seat. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are configured so that loads in both negative value (tensile loads) and positive value can be detected. For instance, the output voltage of the sensor is set to 2.5 V when a load is equal to 0 kg. If the voltage varies between 0 V and 5 V, the voltage becomes 5 V at the heaviest load in the positive value range and 0 V at the lightest load in the negative value range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The abnormal operation of the system may be caused in the following conditions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The load to which the elastic body <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is subjected cannot be properly detected because the load sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that has detected the load less than the threshold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> A harness of the vehicle is jammed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has a structural strain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Some kind of object is stuck under the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> or in spaces existing sides of the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> A force is exerted on the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> from the side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Third Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The third embodiment has the same construction as the first embodiment. However, the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is programmed to determine the seating condition that includes properness and a sitting posture of the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The sitting posture means that the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is seated off center toward the front or back, or reclining on the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. These conditions are determined by calculating differences between the detected loads as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> With its self-diagnostic program, the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> determines the seating condition of the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by subtracting the LF load from the RF load and the RL load from the RR load. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Abnormal ranges <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are set as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The abnormal range <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is set around a range of RF&minus;LF&gE;0 and RR&minus;LR&lE;0. If RF&minus;LF&gE;0, the seating condition is determined as off-center toward the right. If RR&minus;LR&lE;0, the seating condition is determined as off-center toward the left. Therefore, these two results contradict each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The abnormal range <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is set around a range of RF&minus;LF&lE;0 and RR&minus;LR&gE;0. If RF&minus;LF&lE;0, the seating condition is determined as off-center toward the left. If RR&minus;LR&gE;0, the seating condition is determined as off-center toward the right. Therefore, these two results contradict each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Abnormal ranges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are set as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The abnormal range <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is set around a range of RF&minus;RR&gE;0 and LF&minus;LR&gE;0. If RF&minus;RR&gE;0, the seating condition is determined as off-center toward the front. If LF&minus;LR&lE;0, the seating condition is determined as leaning back or reclining. Therefore, these two results contradict each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The abnormal range <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is set around a range of RF&minus;RR&lE;0 and LF&minus;LR&gE;0. If RF&minus;RR&lE;0, the seating condition is determined as leaning back or reclining. If LF&minus;LR&gE;0, the seating condition is determined as off-center toward the front. Therefore, these two results contradict each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The abnormal operation may be caused in the following conditions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The loads to which the elastic body <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> are subjected cannot be properly detected because at least one of the load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> A harness of the vehicle is stuck. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has a structural strain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Some kind of object is stuck under the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> or in spaces exist sides of the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> A force is exerted on the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> from the side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Fourth Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The fourth embodiment includes an empty seat detecting sensor <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in addition to the construction of the first embodiment. The ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is programmed to determine an abnormal operation of the system. The abnormal operation is determined when one of the loads detected is heavier than a threshold TH<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, TH<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, TH<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> or TH<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> although an empty seat is detected by the empty seat sensor <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The thresholds TH<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to TH<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are set for each load value detected by each load sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The abnormal operation of the system may be caused in the following conditions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The belt tension cannot be properly detected because the belt tension sensor <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is defective </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The seating condition of the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> cannot be detected because the empty seat detecting sensor <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The belt tension sensor <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and empty seat detecting sensor <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are both defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> A vehicular harness is disconnected or stuck. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has a structural strain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Some kind of object is stuck under the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> or in spaces exist sides of the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> A force is exerted on the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> from the side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Fifth Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The fifth embodiment has the same construction as the fourth embodiment. However, the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is programmed to determine an abnormal operation of the system when belt tension is higher than a threshold TH<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> although an empty seat is detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The abnormal operation of the system may be caused in the following conditions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> The belt tension cannot be properly detected because the belt tension sensor <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The seating condition of the occupant <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> cannot be detected because the empty seat detecting sensor <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The belt tension sensor <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and empty seat detecting sensor <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are both defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> A harness of the vehicle is disconnected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Sixth Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Regarding the seating condition detecting system according to the second embodiment, the self-diagnosis operation can be modified by setting the thresholds TH<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to TH<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in a different way as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>. In an example shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, when any three of the load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> have detected loads less than 20 kg (for instance, TH<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to TH<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the remaining one sensor has detected a load more than 40 kg (for instance, TH<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> determines the operation of the system as abnormal. The outputs of the load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may saturate and become full-scale. The abnormal operation may be caused in the following conditions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The load to which the spring <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is subjected cannot be properly detected because the RF load sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, which has detected the load more than 40 kg, is defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> A harness of the vehicle is jammed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has a structural strain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Some kind of object is stuck under the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> or in spaces exist sides of the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> A force is exerted on the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> form the side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> In another example shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, when any three of the load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> have detected loads less than 30 kg (for instance, TH<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to TH<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the remaining one sensor has detected a load more than 30 kg (for instance, TH<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> determines the operation of the system as abnormal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Seventh Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Regarding the seating condition detecting system according to the second embodiment, the self-diagnosis operation can be modified by setting the thresholds TH<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to TH<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in different ways as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference>. In an example shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, when any three of the load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> have detected loads more than 10 kg (for instance, TH<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to TH<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the remaining one sensor has detected a load less than &minus;30 kg (for instance, TH<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), the ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> determines the operation of the system as abnormal. The outputs of the load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may saturate and become full-scale. The abnormal operation may be caused in the following conditions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> The load to which the spring <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is subjected cannot be properly detected because the RF load sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, which has detected the load less than &minus;30 kg, is defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> A harness of the vehicle is stuck. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> The seat has a structural defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Some kind of object is stuck under the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> or in spaces exist sides of the seat <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> A force is exerted on the seat from the side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> In another example shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, when any three of the load sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> have detected loads more than &minus;10 kg (for instance, TH<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to TH<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the remaining one sensor has detected a load less than &minus;10 kg (for instance, TH<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), the program determines the operation of the system as abnormal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> The present invention should not be limited to &gt;the embodiment previously discussed and shown in the figures, but may be implemented in various ways without departing from the spirit of the invention. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, an integrated ECU <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, in which the seating condition detecting ECU <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and airbag ECU <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are integrated, can be used. When the abnormal operation of seating condition detecting system is detected, a warning can be provided to prompt a user to have the system for service or to stop improper operation. The warning may be provided with a buzzer or light. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A seating condition detecting system comprising: 
<claim-text>a right front load sensor for detecting a load to which a right front elastic body that supports a right front part of a seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left front load sensor for detecting load to which a left front elastic body that supports a left front part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right rear load sensor for detecting load to which a right rear elastic body that supports a right rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left rear load sensor for detecting load to which a left rear elastic body that supports a left rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seating condition detecting means for detecting a seating condition of a vehicle occupant based on the loads detected by the load sensors; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a belt tension sensor for detecting tension of a seat belt that restrains the vehicle occupant or secures a child seat; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a self-diagnostic means for determining an abnormal operation when a total load detected by the load sensors falls into a first abnormal range that is set so that an upper limit of the range becomes higher as the belt tension becomes higher or within a second abnormal range that is set so that a lower limit of the range becomes higher as the belt tension deviates from the point at which the total load becomes lowest. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A seating condition detecting system comprising: 
<claim-text>a right front load sensor for detecting load to which a right front elastic body that supports a right front part of a seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left front load sensor for detecting load to which a left front elastic body that supports a left front part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right rear load sensor for detecting load to which a right rear elastic body that supports a right rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left rear load sensor for detecting load to which a left rear elastic body that supports a left rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seating condition detecting means for detecting a seating condition of a vehicle occupant based on the loads detected by the load sensors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a self-diagnostic means for determining an abnormal operation when at least one of the loads detected by the load sensors has a negative value and its absolute value is heavier than a predetermined value. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A seating condition detecting system comprising: 
<claim-text>a right front load sensor for detecting load to which a right front elastic body that supports a right front part of a seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left front load sensor for detecting load to which a left front elastic body that supports a left front part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right rear load sensor for detecting load to which a right rear elastic body that supports a right rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left rear load sensor for detecting load to which a left rear elastic body that supports a left rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seating condition detecting means for detecting a seating condition of a vehicle occupant based on the loads detected by the load sensors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a self-diagnostic means for determining an abnormal operation when differences between the right front load and left front load, and between the right rear load and left rear load, both indicating seating position of the vehicular occupant either rightward or leftward, contradict each other, or when differences between the right front load and right rear load, and between the left front load and left rear load, both indicating seating position of the vehicular occupant either forward or backward, contradict each other. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A seating condition detecting system comprising: 
<claim-text>an empty seat detecting sensor for detecting presence or absence of a vehicle occupant or a child seat; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a belt tension sensor for detecting belt tension of a seat belt that restrains a seated vehicle occupant or secures the child seat; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right front load sensor for detecting load to which a right front elastic body that supports a right front part of a seat on which the child seat is mounted or the vehicle occupant is seated from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left front load sensor for detecting load to which a left front elastic body that supports a left front part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right rear load sensor for detecting load to which a right rear elastic body that supports a right rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left rear load sensor for detecting load to which a left rear elastic body that supports a left rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seating condition detecting means for detecting a seating condition of the vehicle occupant based on the loads detected by the load sensors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a self-diagnostic means for determining an abnormal operation when at least one of the loads detected by the load sensors is heavier than a predetermined value although an empty seat is detected by the empty seat detecting sensor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A seating condition detecting system comprising: 
<claim-text>an empty seat detecting sensor for detecting presence or absence of a vehicle occupant or a child seat; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a belt tension sensor for detecting belt tension of a seat belt that restrains a seated vehicle occupant or secures the child seat; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right front load sensor for detecting load to which a right front elastic body that supports a right front part of a seat on which the child seat is mounted or the vehicle occupant is seated from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left front load sensor for detecting load to which a left front elastic body that supports a left front part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right rear load sensor for detecting load to which a right rear elastic body that supports a right rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left rear load sensor for detecting load to which a left rear elastic body that supports a left rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seating condition detecting means for detecting a seating condition of the vehicle occupant based on the loads detected by the load sensors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a self-diagnostic means for determining an abnormal operation when the belt tension higher than a predetermined value is detected although an empty seat is detected by the empty seat detecting system. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A seating condition detecting system comprising: 
<claim-text>a right front load sensor for detecting load to which a right front elastic body that supports a right front part of a seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left front load sensor for detecting load to which a left front elastic body that supports a left front part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right rear load sensor for detecting load to which a right rear elastic body that supports a right rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left rear load sensor for detecting load to which a left rear elastic body that supports a left rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seating condition detecting means for detecting a seating condition of the vehicle occupant based on the loads detected by the load sensors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a self-diagnostic means for determining an abnormal operation when any three of the four loads detected by the load sensors are equal to or lighter than a first threshold and the remaining load is heavier than a second threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A seating condition detecting system comprising: 
<claim-text>a right front load sensor for detecting load to which a right front elastic body that supports a right front part of a seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left front load sensor for detecting load to which a left front elastic body that supports a left front part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a right rear load sensor for detecting load to which a right rear elastic body that supports a right rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a left rear load sensor for detecting load to which a left rear elastic body that supports a left rear part of the seat from underneath is subjected; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seating condition detecting means for detecting a seating condition of the vehicle occupant based on the loads detected by the load sensors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a self-diagnostic means for determining an abnormal operation when any three of the four loads detected by the load sensors are equal to or heavier than a first threshold and the remaining load is lighter than a second threshold.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001749A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001749A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001749A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001749A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001749A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001749A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001749A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
