<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002638A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002638A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002638A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002638A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002638</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893149</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010626</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F003/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G06F013/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H04M011/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>379</class>
<subclass>110010</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>379</class>
<subclass>102030</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>046000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Interactive TV using remote control with built-in phone</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<middle-name>Bernhard</middle-name>
<family-name>Kaars</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Cupertino</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS ELECTRONICS N.V.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Corporate Patent Counsel</name-1>
<name-2>U.S. Philips Corporation</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>580 White Plains Road</address-1>
<city>Tarrytown</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10591</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A remote control device comprises a telephone and a touch screen functionality to enable the user to participate in interactive TV programs and interact with advertisements. This approach is independent of the infrastructure delivering traditional content, and independent of the configuration of an STB. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to supplying information that has a relationship with content information being received by an end-user&apos;s consumer electronics (CE) apparatus. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;Interactive TV&rdquo; (ITV) refers to enhancing TV programs with interactive services for the end-user. These services include, e.g., retrieving electronic information from, or sending electronic information to, specific Web sites via a dedicated set-top box (STB) within a context of the live-broadcast program. Examples of ITV are games for a TV audience, or interacting with an advertisement being broadcast. For example, Wink Communications provides an end-to-end system for low-cost electronic commerce on television. Their enhanced broadcasting system allows advertisers and others to create interactive enhancements to traditional TV programs. Viewers can purchase products or order brochures with a click of their remote control communicating with a STB or TV set that has the Wink client software built-in, during an enhanced program. OpenTV, Inc., provides software for STBs that enables digital interactive television for enhanced applications such as e-commerce. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> ITV typically requires a dedicated infrastructure according to the specifications of the service provider, equipment manufacturer and network operator or cable provider. The inventor has realized that it is an advantage if the end-user or consumer receives the additional information related to a TV program, or a radio program, etc., without modifications being necessary to the conventional infrastructure used for supply of those programs to the end-user, including to the end-user device for receiving these programs, i.e. radios, TV sets and STBs. The inventor has also realized that the device receiving that additional information is preferably an item that is native to the home entertainment environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> For these and other reasons, the inventor proposes to equip a remote control device (RC) with a communication apparatus such as a wireless telephone or pager, to receive the additional information from a server via a telephone network. The telephone or pager is preferably a built-in component. The RC has a display monitor that serves as a GUI. The monitor preferably has a touch screen functionality such as on the Pronto (TM) RC of Philips Electronics. The broadcast of the program causes the additional information to be sent to the RC. The additional information is displayed as, e.g., text or icons, on the GUI. User-interaction with the text or icons causes output data to be sent back via the telephone network to the server mentioned above or to another server. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Applications may need to be able to cope with the characteristic delays of the networks. Various services can be introduced on cell phones that rely on real-time or semi-real-time delivery of various data. E.g., subscribers can program a stock order system to provide an SMS alert when a stock price passes a certain value. Moreover, for accurate synchronization, watermarks can be embedded in the program. These allow, for example, that all the data required to respond to a certain event in the broadcast is already available on the RC but its rendering is triggered after the associated watermark is detected in the actual broadcast. Another method is to send data in advance and to put a time-stamp on it for its validity. Advantages are manifold. For example, interactive TV is enabled in a manner that is independent of a configuration of an STB, as the invention uses the telephone as communication medium. Further, the RC/telephone combination is independent of the STB&apos;s or TV&apos;s content delivery infrastructure (cable, satellite, etc.). TV shows or broadcast stations can fund a dedicated remote (e.g., distinguishable by the color of the housing, the ccf files controlling the GUI, the shape of the housing, etc.). The RC supports business models wherein TV shows, TV networks and stations and original content providers are revenue sources for the RC platform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> One way of implementing the synchronization between TV program and data delivery to the RC is to do everything in real-time. The current, so-called two-screen Interactive TV (watching TV while browsing the Web on a PC) uses a similar synchronization. Disney does this for &ldquo;Millionaire&rdquo; and MTV 2 does it with most of their programs as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Another way is to send messages to the phone or pager at the time that an EPG schedule indicates that a certain program is being broadcast. The phone does not need to have access to this schedule. A separate, central system interprets the EPG and triggers the relevant phones. This system needs to be aware of the differences in time in the different zones and it needs to be aware which RC-phones are present in which zones. A registration procedure may take care of this. Alternatively, cell-phone technology does have the possibility to track the geographical location of the device, e.g., through satellite based (e.g., GPS) or radio triangulation (e.g., MPS). Still another way of synchronizing is having the RC recognize the TV program. This implementation is robust against program shifts, both accidental and intended. Enabling technologies include, e.g., watermarks (embedded in the audio and/or video) and fingerprints (used to recognize the audio and/or video). The RC-phone detects the watermark, or calculates the fingerprint, calls the server, and requests instructions that match the watermark data or the fingerprint. For fingerprints in content information see, e.g., U.S. Pat. No. 5,668,603, herein incorporated by reference. Synchronizing with the playback of previously recorded content information is possible by the same mechanisms of watermarking and fingerprinting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An aspect of the invention resides in a method of enabling a consumer to receive data under control of content information being played out at home equipment of the consumer. The content information has been supplied via a supply infrastructure, e.g., cable, satellite, etc. The method comprises supplying the data via a data network that is independent of the supply infrastructure. The data is supplied to a bi-directional telecom apparatus at the consumer, e.g., prior to the play-out of the content information or functionally simultaneously with the content being played out. The data is rendered upon the apparatus receiving a control signal caused by the content information being played out, either as streamed or received, or as played out from a recording apparatus. In an embodiment, the data is supplied by a server and is personalized according to a user profile based on an identity of the telecom apparatus. For example, the data represent instant buy buttons for products that relate to the semantic context of a TV broadcast. The buttons can be rendered on the display of the touch screen of the remote control device. In an example, the data for the buttons has been downloaded from the server on the remote for selectively being rendered upon detection of an associated watermark in the content being played out. The server downloads data for only specific ones of these buy buttons to this remote control as match the user profile. Alternatively, if all buttons have been downloaded, only specific ones are rendered under control of the watermark, as fit this user&apos;s profile. This selective rendering is achieved by, e.g., marking the data for each button as matching or conflicting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> For completeness, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,414,761 and 5,748,716, both herein incorporated by reference, disclose an RC receiving control codes via a telephone line for being programmed into the remote&apos;s memory in the configuration phase of the remote. The remote does not have an onboard telephone or another telecom apparatus for enabling a user interactive broadcast based on operational use of the remote using typically bi-directional communication with a server within an Interactive TV context.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The invention is explained in further detail below, by way of example, and with reference to the accompanying drawing, wherein <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a system in the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> As briefly discussed above, the invention relates to a remote control device (RC) for control of home entertainment equipment. The device comprises a telephone or another telecommunication apparatus for data communication. Other mechanisms can be used that allow the RC to communicate independently of the TV infrastructure. E.g., a modem and telephone line, wireless IP connection, two-way pager, etc. The device preferably comprises a GUI with a display monitor, e.g., one that has a touch screen functionality. The data received by the telephone are rendered on the display monitor. User-interaction with the rendered data is enabled through the touch screen or RC buttons. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the data communication or data rendering is synchronized or otherwise put into a proper temporal relationship with the TV program or radio program being broadcast or being played back after having been recorded locally at the user&apos;s equipment. Therefore, the RC device comprises a detector for detecting a control signal in the content information being played out. The control signal serves to trigger the appropriate behavior of the RC device. The control signal is, e.g., embedded in the content information as an audio watermark. The detector is then operative to detect this audio watermark. As another example, the control signal is embedded as a video watermark. The device then cooperates with a detector (e.g., accommodated in the device or accommodated in another apparatus and communicating with the RC device through a short range coupling, e.g., Bluetooth) for detecting the video watermarking signal. Note that watermarking of the content information enables to render the data communication independent of time-shifting of the content&apos;s playback through recording. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> An aspect of the invention resides in having content information for being broadcast comprising a control signal for control of data communication via a telephone. This enables synchronizing the communication with the content information being played out, e.g., as a live broadcast or time-shifted through a recording at a digital recorder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in the invention. System <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprises a TV broadcast station <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and a TV receiver <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of a consumer receiving a program broadcast by station <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The program has associated with it an interactive service that enables communication between the end-user and a server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> via a data network <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The end-user has available a remote control device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> allows the user to control his/her home equipment through IR or RF. Device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> preferably has a display monitor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> with touch screen functionality. Device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> comprises, e.g., a Pronto (&trade;) universal programmable remote control device as manufactured by Philips Electronics. In the control mode of device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, monitor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> presents icons with which the user interacts through the touch screen. Interaction with an icon causes device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to send a specific IR or RF control command to the associated CE equipment, e.g., receiver <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> or a digital video recorder <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, or another CE apparatus. Device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> accommodates a telecommunications device <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, e.g., a cell phone or a pager, to enable data communication with server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> via network <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. In a data communication mode of device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the data communicated from server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is processed by processor <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and rendered on screen <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, e.g., as text and/or icons and/or another graphics representation. Selection of an item rendered is accomplished through user-interaction with touch screen <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The user-interaction causes data to be sent back to server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has an audio watermark receiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Receiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> detects a specific audio watermark embedded in the audio part of the content played out (live or from recorder <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>) at TV receiver <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The watermark is used to control the data communication with server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. For example, during the play-out of a specific part of content information, receiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> detects a specific watermark The watermark detected is processed by processor <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> that extracts a request to retrieve certain information from server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The request may be as little as a pointer to a specific piece of information, depending on the program broadcast. For example, processor <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> has received a look-up-table from server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> that translates the watermark into a pointer. The request is sent via phone <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> to server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The latter thereupon sends the information to phone <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> that passes it on to processor <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The information is processed and rendered on screen <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> under control of processor <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the information supply via network <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and the play-out of the content are synchronized under control of the watermark embedded in the content. A video watermark <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> can be used in addition to, or instead of, audio watermark detector <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, but may be less practical when accommodated in remote <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> because of the line of sight needed between the display of TV receiver <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and detector <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Video watermark detector <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is built-in or added to TV receiver <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and communicates with remote <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> using a short range RF communication protocol, e.g., Bluetooth. Processor <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> then controls communication device <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> in a manner similar to the one discussed above with respect to the audio watermark. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In an embodiment of the invention, telephone <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has been registered as owned by this specific user. Together with the request extracted from the watermark, phone <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> sends a unique identifier to server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> can distinguish between different users and can adapt the supply of information accordingly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In a further embodiment of the invention, the information supplied by server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> comprises advertisements for goods or services that fit in with the semantic context of the content information being played out. For example, a specific scene of a movie being played out via the user&apos;s equipment takes place in a certain geographic environment. This scene comprises a watermark. Detection of the watermark causes telephone <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> to contact server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, that in turn sends an advertisement for a vacation in that environment. The advertisement is displayed on the RC&apos;s screen. An interested user can, e.g., respond to request additional information by mail, or save the text for studying it later in more detail. As another example, the information supplied by server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> concerns information on merchandise that can be related to the broadcast. Processor <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and the GUI on Screen <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> provide the option to buy it directly by sending the user&apos;s response to Server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. As still another example, assume that the content played out is a live broadcast. The information supplied by server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> contains background information about the events being broadcast. This information may have been prepared in advance or has been compiled in real-time by an editor at the studio. The watermark now is being used as a synchronizing mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Note that the relationship between a watermark and the information caused to be supplied by server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> when the mark is detected, is preferably modifiable, dynamic or personalized. For example, server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> may keep a log of what has been supplied to this specific user on previous occasions. In this manner, the information can be different each time the user responds to the same content. If server <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> has a profile of this user, the information can be customized and tailored to the specific profile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Incorporated by reference herein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> U.S. Ser. No. 09/686,572 (attorney docket US 000183) filed Oct. 10, 2000 for Tom Dubil et al., for CONTROL CODES FOR PROGRAMMABLE REMOTE SUPPLIED IN XML FORMAT. This document relates to an Internet service that control codes available for use on a programmable universal remote. The remote controls CE equipment through IR or RF commands. A server supplies the control codes as XML data that gets processed at the receiver&apos;s set top box or PC, or the remote itself, for being properly installed on the remote. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> U.S. Ser. No. 09/427,821 (attorney docket PHA 23,786) filed Oct. 27, 1999 for Joost Kemink et al., for PDA HAS WIRELESS MODEM FOR REMOTE CONTROL VIA THE INTERNET. This document relates to combining a PDA with a wireless modem to enable remote control of CE equipment via the Internet and a local home server. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> U.S. Ser. No. 09/128,839 (attorney docket PHA 23,469) filed Aug. 4, 1998 for Jan van Ee et al., for REMOTE CONTROL HAS ANIMATED GUI. This document relates to a remote control device for remote control of home theater equipment. The device has a display with a touch screen representing a GUI. User-activation of the GUI causes its appearance to change. The change is effected through animation. Animation is the simulation of movement created by displaying a series of bitmaps. The animation lets the user perceive the change as a smooth transition. Thus the impression is avoided of an abrupt confrontation with a new lay-out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> U.S. Ser. No. 09/129,300 (attorney docket PHA 23,470) filed Aug. 5, 1998 for Jan van Ee et al., for GUI OF REMOTE CONTROL FACILITATES USER-FRIENDLY EDITING OF MACROS. This document relates to a remote control device for a home theater. The device has a macro creation/editing mode with authoring tools on the remote&apos;s GUI. One of the editing tools lets the user move a selected macro step visibly up or down the list of steps on the GUI. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A remote control device for control of home entertainment equipment, the device comprising a telecom apparatus for bi-directional communication of data via an infrastructure different from a further infrastructure for delivery of content to the equipment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the communication is controlled by a control signal in the content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the telecom apparatus comprises at least one of the following: a telephone, a pager. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising a GUI with touch screen functionality. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising a detector for detecting a signal in the content when played out via the equipment, the signal being used for controlling a rendering at the device of the data received. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method of enabling a consumer to receive data under control of content information being played out at home equipment of the consumer and having been supplied via a supply infrastructure, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>supplying the data via a data network, independent of the supply infrastructure, to a bi-directional telecom apparatus at the consumer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling to render the data upon the apparatus receiving a control signal caused by the content information being played out. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the data comprises graphics information when rendered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising personalizing the data according to a user-profile based on an identity of the telecom apparatus.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002638A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002638A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
