<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005378A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005378A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005378A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005378A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005378A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005378A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005378A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005378A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005378A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005378A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005378A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005378A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005378A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005378A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005378</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894465</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01R031/28</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>714</class>
<subclass>726000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Body bias using scan chains</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Tschanz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hillsboro</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Siva</given-name>
<middle-name>G.</middle-name>
<family-name>Narendra</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Vivek</given-name>
<middle-name>K.</middle-name>
<family-name>De</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Beaverton</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Intel Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Schwegman, Lundberg, Woessner &amp; Kluth, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 2938</address-1>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A logic unit and method incorporating body biasing using scan chains, the logic unit comprising a functional unit block including a body and a scan chain, and a variable voltage source coupled to the scan chain to receive control signals from the scan chain and coupled to the body to provide a bias voltage to the body, and the method comprising identifying a preferred body bias voltage for a functional unit block having a body; and permanently programming a plurality of control signals coupled to a variable voltage source that provides the preferred body bias voltage to the body. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to integrated circuits and, more particularly, to biasing the body of a functional unit block in an integrated circuit. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> An integrated circuit, such as a processor, includes a large number of transistors, and many of the transistors are intended to have identical operating parameters. For example, the input transistors of the logic gates in a processor are intended to have identical threshold voltages and leakage currents. Unfortunately, manufacturing process variations, such as random dopant fluctuations, over the area of a die on which an integrated circuit is fabricated, can cause transistors fabricated in different areas of the die to have different threshold voltages and leakage currents. Transistors that have different threshold voltages have different maximum operating frequencies, and transistors that have different leakage currents consume different amounts of power. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This transistor-to-transistor variation causes several inefficiencies during the operation of an integrated circuit. First, some transistors in the integrated circuit have a lower than intended threshold voltage. When operated at the integrated circuit&apos;s target operating frequency, these transistors have a larger leakage current than the transistors that have the intended threshold voltage. The larger leakage current causes the integrated circuit to consume more power than necessary. Second, some transistors in the integrated circuit have a higher than intended threshold voltage. These transistors have a maximum operating frequency that is less than the integrated circuit&apos;s target operating frequency, which prevents the integrated circuit from operating at its target operating frequency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Transistor operating frequencies can be made more uniform and leakage currents can be reduced in an integrated circuit by applying a bias voltage to the body of each transistor or group of transistors in the integrated circuit. The bias voltage can be chosen to increase the threshold voltage of each transistor, which decreases the maximum operating frequency of each transistor and decreases the leakage current in each transistor, or the bias voltage can be chosen to decrease the threshold voltage of each transistor, which increases the maximum operating frequency of each transistor. To identify the proper bias voltage for a particular group of transistors in an integrated circuit, a separate test path that duplicates the critical path (the path that must operate the fastest) for a particular group of transistors is fabricated on the die. A bias voltage is identified that causes the test path to operate correctly at the integrated circuit&apos;s target operating frequency. The identified bias voltage is then applied to all transistors in the selected group of transistors to reduce leakage current power consumption in the selected group of transistors and to prepare the selected group of transistors to operate at the integrated circuit&apos;s target operating frequency. Unfortunately, identifying a single critical path in an integrated circuit is difficult because most integrated circuits have multiple paths that are intended to operate at the same maximum frequency, and manufacturing a separate test path on a die wastes valuable die real estate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> For these and other reasons there is a need for the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a block diagram of some embodiments of a plurality of interconnected logic units according to the teachings of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a block diagram of some embodiments of one of the plurality of logic units shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> according to the teachings of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a detailed block diagram of some embodiments of one of the plurality of logic units shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> according to the teachings of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> is an illustration of a cross-sectional view of some embodiments of some of the plurality of logic units shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> formed on a die according to the teachings of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1E</cross-reference> is an illustration of a cross-sectional view of some alternative embodiments of some of the plurality of logic units shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> formed on a die according to the teachings of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow diagram of one embodiment of a method for generating a body bias voltage according to the teachings of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flow diagram of an alternative embodiment of a method for generating a body bias voltage according to the teachings of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram of some embodiments of a processor connected to a memory unit and a storage unit according to the teachings of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In the following detailed description of the invention, reference is made to the accompanying drawings which form a part hereof, and in which are shown, by way of illustration, specific embodiments of the invention which may be practiced. In the drawings, like numerals describe substantially similar components throughout the several views. These embodiments are described in sufficient detail to enable those skilled in the art to practice the invention. Other embodiments may be utilized and structural, logical, and electrical changes may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention. The following detailed description is not to be taken in a limiting sense, and the scope of the present invention is defined only by the appended claims, along with the full scope of equivalents to which such claims are entitled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a block diagram of some embodiments of a plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to the teachings of the present invention. The plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> include logic units <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The logic units <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> operate together to perform complex logic functions. In one embodiment, the plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a processor. In an alternative embodiment, the plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a digital signal processor. In another alternative embodiment, the plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a reduced instruction set processor. In still another alternative embodiment, the plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a very long instruction word processor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a block diagram of some embodiments of one of the plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> according to the teachings of the present invention. The logic unit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes a functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and a variable voltage source <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> includes a scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and a body <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The variable voltage source <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is coupled to the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and to the body <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, such as in a twin-well process, the body <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> represents the connection to one or more p-type metal-oxide semiconductor field-effect transistor body terminals in the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. In an alternative embodiment, such as in a triple-well process, there are two body connections: one for the p-type metal-oxide semiconductor transistor body terminals and one for the n-type metal-oxide semiconductor transistor body terminals. In some embodiments of the triple-well process, a first voltage source provides a first bias voltage for the p-type metal-oxide semiconductor field-effect transistors, and a second voltage source provides a second bias voltage for the n-type metal-oxide semiconductor field-effect transistors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The logic unit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is formed on a substrate (not shown). The substrate is not limited to being fabricated from a particular material. Any material suitable for use as a substrate in the fabrication of integrated circuits is suitable for use in the fabrication of the substrate on which the logic unit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is formed. Exemplary substrate materials include silicon, germanium, gallium arsenide, and silicon carbide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> performs one or more information processing tasks in an electronic system. The functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> comprises logic gates and information storage devices, such as flip-flops. Some exemplary electronic systems that utilize functional unit blocks include radar systems, telecommunications systems, wide area networks, local area networks, satellite control systems, automobile brake control systems, and computer systems. Exemplary information processing tasks performed by the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> include target tracking in a radar system, storing and forwarding packets in a packet-switching system, and arithmetic and logic computations in a computer system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of serially connected information storage devices (not shown), however the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is not limited to being formed from a particular type of information storage device. Any information storage devices that are capable of being serially connected are suitable for use in forming the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Exemplary information storage devices capable of being serially connected include flip-flops and memory cells. Exemplary flip-flops include J-K flip-flips and D flip-flops. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> includes an input device (not shown), which is the first information storage device in the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and an output device (not shown), which is the last information storage device in the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, information is loaded into the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> by staging the information at the input port of the input device and delivering a clock signal to each of the plurality of serially connected information storage devices in the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The clock signal causes information to be transferred into the input device and through each of the plurality of serially connected information storage devices in the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Information is read from the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> by detecting information at the output device of the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> as the clock signal is being delivered to each of the plurality of serially connected information storage devices in the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. In an alternative embodiment, information is loaded into the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> by writing the information in parallel to each of the plurality of serially connected information storage devices in the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and information is read from the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> by reading the information in parallel from each of the plurality of serially connected information storage devices in the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The body <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> provides a site for applying a bias voltage to the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, which can include p-type metal-oxide semiconductor (PMOS) transistors (not shown), and changing the bias voltage can alter the performance of the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. For example, decreasing the bias voltage applied to the PMOS field-effect transistors increases the speed of the switching elements, such as logic gates and information storage elements formed from the PMOS field-effect transistors, and increasing the bias voltage applied to the PMOS field-effect transistors decreases the speed of the switching elements. Increasing or decreasing the speed of the switching elements in the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can increase or decrease the speed of the function performed by the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The variable voltage source <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> receives the control signal <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> from the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, generates the bias voltage <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> from the control signal <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and provides the bias voltage <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> to the body <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The control signal <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> includes one or more input control signals. In one embodiment, the control signal <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> includes three input control signals. However, the variable voltage source <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is not limited to a particular number of input control signals and can be designed to receive any number of input control signals. The variable voltage source <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> generates the bias voltage <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> having an amplitude controlled by the control signal <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the variable voltage source <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is a digital-to-analog converter. The bias voltage <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> preferably has a voltage swing sufficient to move the operating frequency of the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> to the target frequency of the logic unit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. If bias is applied to PMOS field-effect transistors, in some embodiments, the PMOS field-effect transistor bias voltage has a voltage swing of between about 500 millivolts lower than V<highlight><subscript>CC </subscript></highlight>(the supply voltage) and about 500 millivolts higher than V<highlight><subscript>CC</subscript></highlight>. If bias is applied to NMOS field-effect transistors (such as in a triple-well process), in some embodiments, the bias voltage has a voltage swing of between about &minus;500 millivolts and about &plus;500 millivolts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The bias voltage <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> has a preferred value. To determine the preferred value of the bias voltage <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, a test vector is chosen to exercise the worst-case critical path in the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the test vector is loaded into the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, a zero bias voltage is applied by the variable voltage source <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to the body <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, a clock signal (not shown) having a frequency about equal to the target frequency of the logic unit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is applied to the logic unit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and a result or output vector is read out of the scan chain <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The result or output vector is compared to an expected result vector to determine whether the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is operational. A functional unit block is operational when it operates correctly at its target frequency. If the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is operational at a zero bias voltage, then the bias voltage is increased incrementally until the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is not operational. A functional unit block is not operational when it does not operate correctly at its target frequency. The bias voltage which is one voltage increment less than the bias voltage at which the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> fails or is not operational is the preferred bias voltage. If the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is not operational at a zero bias voltage, then the bias voltage is decreased incrementally until the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is operational. The bias voltage at which the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> becomes operational is the preferred bias voltage. After identifying the preferred bias voltage for the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the configuration bits (not shown) for the functional unit block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can be permanently programmed by performing an information recording operation, such as burning fuses or writing flash memory bits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a detailed block diagram of some embodiments of one of the plurality of logic units shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> according to the teachings of the present invention. The logic unit <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> includes the arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and the digital-to-analog converter <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. The arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and a body <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> includes combinational logic and information storage units arranged to perform arithmetic and logic functions. Exemplary arithmetic functions include addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division. Exemplary logic functions include AND, OR, NAND, NOR and XOR. Arithmetic logic units are commonly used in information processing systems, such as microprocessors, digital signal processors, reduced instruction set processors, complex instruction set processors and very long instruction word processors. The plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> included in the arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> are serially connected in order to permit serial reading and writing. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C, the plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes three information storage devices <highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight> dedicated to providing control signals to the digital-to-analog converter <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. The plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is not limited to a particular type of information storage device. In one embodiment, the plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes J-K flip-flops. In an alternative embodiment, the plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes D flip-flops. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The body <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> in the arithmetic logic unit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> functions the same as the body <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of the logic unit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B and described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The digital-to-analog converter receives the three control signals <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> from the plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, generates the bias voltage <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, and provides the bias voltage <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> to the body <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. If the body <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> includes PMOS field-effect transistors, in some embodiments, the bias voltage <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> has a voltage swing of between about 500 millivolts lower than V<highlight><subscript>CC </subscript></highlight>(the supply voltage) and about 500 millivolts higher than V<highlight><subscript>CC</subscript></highlight>. If the body <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> includes NMOS field-effect transistors (such as in a triple-well process), in some embodiments, the bias voltage <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> has a voltage swing of between about &minus;500 millivolts and about &plus;500 millivolts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is fabricated on a die (not shown) and includes a clock input (not shown). After fabrication, the arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is tested. To test the arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, information is serially read into the plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> from an input port (not shown). The information defines an initial state for the arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. After the information has been serially read into the plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, the arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is clocked for a predetermined number of clock periods. After being clocked, the plurality of serially connected information storage devices <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is scanned or read at an output port (not shown), and the information scanned or read is compared to a predetermined result vector. If the scanned or read information equals the predetermined result vector, then the arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is operational. If the scanned out information is not equal to the predetermined result vector, then the arithmetic logic unit <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is not operational. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> is an illustration of a cross-sectional view of some embodiments of some of the plurality of logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A and formed on die <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> according to the teachings of the present invention. The die <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> includes a p-type substrate <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> that includes an n-well <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, a variable voltage source <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, and n-type metal-oxide semiconductor (NMOS) field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The n-well <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> includes p-type metal-oxide semiconductor (PMOS) field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> and a bias tap <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. A functional unit block <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> includes the NMOS field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and the PMOS field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. The variable voltage source <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> is coupled to the functional unit block <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and to the bias tap <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. The variable voltage source <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> receives control signals <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> from the functional unit block <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and provides a bias voltage <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to the bias tap <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1E</cross-reference> is an illustration of a cross-sectional view of some alternative embodiments of some of the plurality of logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A and formed on die <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> according to the teachings of the present invention. The die <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> includes a p-type substrate <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> that includes an n-well <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, a variable voltage source <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>, an isolated p-well <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, and a variable voltage source <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The n-well <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> includes p-type metal-oxide semiconductor (PMOS) field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> and a bias tap <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. The p-type metal-oxide semiconductor (PMOS) field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> and the bias tap <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> are formed in the n-well <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The isolated p-well <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> includes an n-well <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight>, a p-well <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> formed in the n-well <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight>, and a bias tap <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> formed in the p-well <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and n-type metal-oxide semiconductor (NMOS) field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> formed in the p-well <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The PMOS field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> and the NMOS field-effect transistors <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> form a functional unit block <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. The variable voltage source <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> is coupled to the bias tap <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> and the functional unit block <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. The variable voltage source <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> provides a control voltage <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> to the bias tap <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> and receives control signals <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> from the functional unit block <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. The variable voltage source <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> provides a control voltage <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> to the bias tap <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and receives control signals <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> from the functional unit block <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow diagram of some embodiments of a method <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for generating a body bias voltage according to the teachings of the present invention. The method <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> includes two operations. In one operation shown in block <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, a preferred body bias voltage for a functional unit block having a body is identified. In another operation shown in block <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, a plurality of control signals, which are coupled to a variable voltage source that provides the preferred body bias voltage to the body, is permanently programmed. In an alternative embodiment, identifying a preferred body bias voltage for a functional unit block having a body comprises identifying a body bias voltage for which the functional unit block is operational and for which leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized. In another alternative embodiment, permanently programming a plurality of control signals, which are coupled to a variable voltage source that provides a preferred body bias voltage to the body, includes burning fuses coupled to the variable voltage source. In still another alternative embodiment, permanently programming a plurality of control signals, which are coupled to a variable voltage source that provides the preferred body bias voltage to the body, includes writing flash memory bits coupled to the variable voltage source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flow diagram of some alternative embodiments of a method <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> for generating a body bias voltage according to the teachings of the present invention. The method <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes scanning a test vector into a scan chain of a functional unit block, the scan chain including a plurality of control signals for controlling a variable voltage source (block <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>), applying a clock signal to the functional unit block (block <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>), scanning a result vector out of the functional unit block (block <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>), comparing the result vector to an expected result vector to determine whether the functional unit block is operational (block <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight>), and generating a new test vector that changes the plurality of control signals (block <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight>), if the functional unit block is not operational. In an alternative embodiment, the method <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> further includes adjusting the plurality of control signals to substantially minimize the leakage current in the functional unit block, if the functional unit block is operational. In another alternative embodiment, the method described further includes storing the plurality of control signals, if the functional unit block is operational and the leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized. In another alternative embodiment, the method <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> further includes permanently storing the plurality of control signals, if the functional unit block is operational and the leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized. In still another alternative embodiment, permanently storing the plurality of control signals, if the functional unit block is operational and the leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized, includes burning fuses. In still another alternative embodiment, permanently storing the plurality of control signals, if the functional unit block is operational and the leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized, includes writing flash memory bits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram of some embodiments of a processor <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> connected to a memory unit <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and a storage unit <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> according to the teachings of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The processor <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> includes the plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Each of the plurality of interconnected logic units <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> performs one or more logical functions required by the processor <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. The processor <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is not limited to a particular type of processor. Exemplary processors suitable for use in connection with the present invention include reduced instruction set processors, complex instruction set processors, digital signal processors, and very long instruction word processors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The memory unit <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> is not limited to a particular type of memory unit. Exemplary memory units include semiconductor memory units and core memory units. Exemplary semiconductor memory units include dynamic random access memory units, static random access memory units, erasable program random access memory units and electrically erasable programmable read-only memory units. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The storage unit <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> is not limited to a particular type of storage unit. In one embodiment, the storage unit <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> is a direct access storage device. In an alternative embodiment, the storage unit <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> is a tape drive. In still another embodiment, the storage unit <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> is a solid state memory. In still another alternative embodiment, the storage unit <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> is a magnetic core storage unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Although specific embodiments have been described and illustrated herein, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art, having the benefit of the present disclosure, that any arrangement which is intended to achieve the same purpose may be substituted for a specific embodiment shown. This application is intended to cover any adaptations or variations of the present invention. Therefore, it is intended that this invention be limited only by the claims and the equivalents thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A logic unit comprising: 
<claim-text>a functional unit block including a body and a scan chain; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a variable voltage source coupled to the scan chain to receive control signals from the scan chain and coupled to the body to provide a bias voltage to the body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the functional unit block comprises an arithmetic logic unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the scan chain comprises a plurality of serially connected information storage devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the variable voltage source comprises a digital-to-analog converter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bias voltage comprises a voltage between about 500 millivolts less than V<highlight><subscript>CC </subscript></highlight>and about 500 millivolts more than V<highlight><subscript>CC </subscript></highlight>for the functional unit block including one or more p-type metal-oxide semiconductor field-effect transistors formed in an n-well. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the digital-to-analog converter receives about three control signal inputs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the body comprises an n-well formed in a p-type substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the body comprises a p-well formed in an n-well formed in a p-type substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A logic unit comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of interconnected functional unit blocks, each of the plurality of interconnected functional unit blocks having a body, and at least one of the plurality of interconnected functional unit blocks including a scan chain; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a variable voltage source coupled to the scan chain to receive control signals from the scan chain and coupled to the body of at least one of the plurality of interconnected functional unit blocks to provide a bias voltage to the body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of interconnected functional unit blocks comprises a processor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the processor comprises a digital signal processor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each scan chain comprises a plurality of serially connected information storage devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the processor comprises a reduced instruction set processor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each variable voltage source comprises a digital-to-analog converter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a memory unit connected to the processor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The logic unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a magnetic storage unit connected to the processor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>identifying a preferred body bias voltage for a functional unit block having a body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>permanently programming a plurality of control signals coupled to a variable voltage source that provides the preferred body bias voltage to the body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein identifying a preferred body bias voltage for a functional unit block having a body comprises: 
<claim-text>identifying a body bias voltage for which the functional unit block is operational and for which leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein permanently programming a plurality of control signals coupled to a variable voltage source that provides the preferred body bias voltage to the body comprises: 
<claim-text>burning fuses coupled to the variable voltage source. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein permanently programming a plurality of control signals coupled to a variable voltage source that provides the preferred body bias voltage to the body comprises: 
<claim-text>writing flash memory bits coupled to the variable voltage source. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>scanning a test vector into a scan chain of a functional unit block, the scan chain including a plurality of control signals for controlling a variable voltage source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a clock signal to the functional unit block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>scanning a result vector out of the functional unit block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing the result vector to an expected result vector to determine whether the functional unit block is operational; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a new test vector that changes the plurality of control signals, if the functional unit block is not operational. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising adjusting the plurality of control signals to substantially minimize the leakage current in the functional unit block, if the functional unit block is operational. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>storing the plurality of control signals, if the functional unit block is operational and the leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>permanently storing the plurality of control signals, if the functional unit block is operational and the leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein permanently storing the plurality of control signal, if the functional unit block is operational and the leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized, comprises: 
<claim-text>burning fuses. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein permanently storing the plurality of control signals, if the functional unit block is operational and the leakage current in the functional unit block is substantially minimized, comprises: 
<claim-text>writing flash memory bits.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005378A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005378A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005378A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005378A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005378A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005378A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030005378A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
