<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001774A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001774A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001774A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001774A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001774A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001774A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001774</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10065120</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020918</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01S005/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>342</class>
<subclass>357100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Position privacy in an electronic device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10065120</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020918</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09690001</doc-number>
<document-date>20001016</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6473031</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Scott</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Harris</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Rancho Santa Fe</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SCOTT C HARRIS</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P O BOX 927649</address-1>
<city>SAN DIEGO</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>92192</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A privacy enhancement device for electronic device such as a cellular telephone. In one mode, the cellular telephone operates in its normal mode, whereby its position can be detected by either wap techniques or by GPS techniques. In a second mode of operation, the wap/GPS operation is overridden, so that the position cannot be detected. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/690,001 filed Oct. 16, 2000.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention defines a system for enhancing a privacy in enhancement in an electronic device with automatic position location detection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Modern electronic devices often include automatic position location detection technology. For example, the modern cellular phone may include a satellite positioning system such as a GPS device. Other cellular phones, referred to as a WAP phones, also automatically keep track of the users position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows an electronic device, which can be a wap phone, regular cellular phone, or any other electronic device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The device is shown with electronic circuitry including electronic processor <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> which processes signals from both GPS device <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>, and from a codec <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The processor also controls an RF device <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The electronic device automatically determines its position. In this embodiment, it does so by communicating with a constellation of global position detecting satellites <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, for automatic determination of position. The electronic device may also communicate with the server <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, such as to a base station. The electronic device may communicate its determined position to the server. This may be done, for example, for emergency purposes. In the case of a WAP device, this may be done simply to monitor the position of the cellular phone. The server may output the position, shown as <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present application defines a device which enhances privacy in such a system. Specifically, the present application teaches a device which selectively prevents the electronic device from transmitting its position. This hence allows selection of an enhanced privacy mode.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> These and other aspects of the invention will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows are block diagram of an electronic device with a built-in automatic position location detection system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a first embodiment of a privacy enhancing device for an electronic element; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference> show a passive version of the privacy enhancing device using an RF blocking technique; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows an active jammer device which actively produces a signal to prevent the reporting of position.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The first embodiment is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In this embodiment, the electronic device is a portable telephone such as a cellular phone. However, it should be understood that other electronic devices, such as computers, personal digital assistants, or any other device which is capable of communicating in any way, may use similar techniques to those disclosed herein. A portable phone <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> has a normal user interface <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>, and other structure such as display, etc. The device also includes a positioning device <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, a position detection block control <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is provided. This is an actuation mechanism, such as a button which can be pressed to deactivate the function of the positioning device <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. The unit&apos;s normal position forms an enable signal <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> which enables the position detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, allowing the position detector to determine its position, and report that position to a remote source, such as a base station. When the button is in its override position, an indicator <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> is illuminated, indicating the privacy mode has been entered. In this privacy-enhanced state, the enable signal is removed, thereby preventing position detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> from reporting its position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A concern, however, is that some users, either hackers or others with more aura of authority, may use this system in a way which determines position surreptitiously, e.g., even when the button is placed on override. For example, law-enforcement officials might use this system to keep track of someone without their knowledge. One way to do this might be to fake an emergency call or the like. Doing this, however, may have serious privacy implications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> If a manufacturer includes a back door into the system, that back door might be used to determine the position of a person, without their authority or knowledge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A test module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> can be used to test the degree of privacy associated with the electronic device. This test module is connectable to the server <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. It also runs a software layer <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> which can be updated via channel <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>, e.g., over the Internet. The test module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, in operation, communicates with a service over the internet. The service employs experts to research and store the latest and most up-to-date way of improperly obtaining position in such a system. This is available via update <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> from the Internet. This may be carried out as a subscription service, in a similar way to the operations currently done to update virus definitions. The Internet returns ways of hacking the position detection prevention, which can hence be used by the test module to evaluate the privacy provided by the actuation <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The test module sends a request for position location to the phone <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, using the best available techniques. The phone returns information, and this information is evaluated by the server <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. Server <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> returns an evaluation of the operation to the test module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. This can provide a user with an indication of the level of privacy they have obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference>. This embodiment may be most usable with a satellite positioning system in a telephone. In this kind of phone, both sets of electronics&mdash;the GPS and the codec&mdash;may use a common processor. However, a GPS system often requires a separate antenna shown as <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The separate antenna may be very sensitive to reception. For example, while cellular telephones can often be used indoors, corresponding GPS devices may not be usable in the same situations. Moreover, each separate telephone type will have a GPS antenna <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> placed in a specified location. There are relatively few telephone types in common use, usually less than 50 types. This system finds, for each telephone type, where the GPS antenna will be placed. The device <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> is made of an RF absorbing or reflecting material such as metal. The device is also made in way which allows it to be temporarily attached to the telephone, e.g., by clipping on to the phone. For example, the device may fit on both sides of the telephone <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> and wrap around the telephone to cover areas adjacent the antenna on both of the surfaces. The cover <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> covers both sides of the antenna <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, and therefore prevents GPS operation while the cover is clamped into place. In this way, privacy can be effectively temporarily enhanced. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference> show two different places where the shield could be attached; but it should be understood that the shield could be attached in many different places. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> One of the stated uses of GPS in a portable phone is for use in an emergency. When the user dials 911, the GPS device allows the emergency authorities to determine the user&apos;s precise location. In order to allow this, the cover can be maintained in place during all operations other than emergencies. During emergencies, the cover can be removed. But once the cover is removed, the position of the electronic device can be automatically detected, as usual. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference> may not work with certain phones. An alternative system is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In this phone, an active jammer module <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is provided. The jammer module either supplants or fools the system into obtaining false position information. For example, the jammer module may provide false satellite information, e.g., indicating a false satellite position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Satellite positioning system information is often provided in broad spectrum noise. The jammer <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may produce broad spectrum noise, which includes information indicative of three satellites, but which is transmitted at a sufficiently low power to be receivable only at a very short range. In the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the jammer can also be attached using attachment clips <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>. The attachment can place the transmitter of the jammer in close proximity with the satellite positioning system antenna. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The jammer information can produce outputs that indicate a false location, for example. Similar operations can be carried out with WAP phones. In a WAP phone, for example, the system may override the carrier, or tell the carrier false information about where the phone is located. This may include providing false triangulation information into the system or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Other modifications are possible and are within the disclosed invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-001.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>.An apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>an electronic device having a position detection module therein which determines a position of said electronic device and reports information indicative of said position of said electronic device to a remote object; and an override control, which includes a manual actuating mechanism and which, in response to manual actuation of said actuating mechanism produces a signal state that prevents said position detection module from determining its position, but which allows other parts of said electronic device to operate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-002.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, wherein said position detection module is a satellite positioning system receiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>.A method, comprising: 
<claim-text>operating a cellular phone in a first mode in which its position can be detected by an automatic position sensing device and automatically reported to a remote location; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to an action by a user of a specific type, operating said cellular phone in a second, privacy enhanced mode, in which cellular phone functions can be used to place and/or receive calls, but its position can not be automatically detected by said automatic position sensing device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising testing said cellular phone while operating in said second, privacy enhanced mode, to determine whether privacy is actually enhanced. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing comprises using a network based service to test whether privacy is enhanced. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said network based service updates software that carries out said testing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said action by said user of the specified type comprises actuating an actuation element on the cellular telephone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising, responsive to actuating said actuating element, interfering with said position being reported to said remote location. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-009.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>.An apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>an electronic device having a position detection module therein which determines a position of said electronic device and reports information indicative of said position of said electronic device to a remote object; and an override control, which includes a manual actuating mechanism and which, in response to manual actuation of said actuating mechanism produces a signal state that prevents said position detection module from reporting said information about its position, but which allows other parts of said electronic device to operate, wherein said override control operates in response to said manual actuation to produce a signal that prevents said position detection module from reporting any information, in any mode of said electronic device, until said manually deactuated. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-010.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>.An apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a portable telephone, including: 
<claim-text>(1)telephone electronics enabling telephone communication; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(2) a position detection module therein which enables determining a position of said portable telephone as a determined position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(3) a reporting device which reports information indicative of said determined position of said portable telephone to a remote object; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a manually operable override control, associated with said portable telephone, operating in response to a manual operation, to prevent said reporting device from reporting any information indicative of the determined position, but allowing said telephone electronics to continue to operate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-011.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein said override control prevents said position detection module from determining said determined position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-012.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, wherein said operating said override control allows said position detection module to determine said determined position, but prevents said reporting device from reporting said information indicative of said determined position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-013.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein said position detection module includes a satellite positioning system device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-014.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein said override control includes a button. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-015.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, wherein said override control produces an enable signal state which enables the position detector to determine its position and report that position to said remote object. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-016.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said remote object includes a base station associated with a telephone system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-017.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, further comprising an indicator which indicates whether the override control is in a state which prevents said reporting device from reporting. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-018.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, wherein said indicator includes an optical indicator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-019.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, wherein said optical indicator includes an indicator which can be selectively illuminated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-020.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>.An apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>an electronic device having a first electronics module, and a position detection module therein which determines a position of said electronic device and produces a signal for reporting information indicative of said position of said electronic device to a remote object; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a position reporting control, which includes a manual control, which is manually actuatable by a user, and which, in response to a first specified actuation by a user, prevents any reporting of said information about position until a second specified actuation by a user, but which allows said first electronics module to continue to operate after said first specified actuation and before said second specified actuation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-021.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, wherein said manual control includes a button which commands circuitry in said telephone to stop performing certain operations when in a first state produced by said first specified actuation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-022.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, wherein said first specified actuation prevents said position detection module from determining said determined position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-023.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, wherein said first specified actuation prevents said position reporting device from reporting information indicative of the determined position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-024.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, wherein said first electronics module includes communication circuitry, which continues to operate after said first specified actuation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-025.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, wherein said apparatus includes a portable telephone, and said first electronics module includes circuitry associated with said portable telephone, including circuitry for communicating with a base station associated with the telephone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-026.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, further comprising an indicator, which indicates a state of said first specified actuation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-027.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, wherein said indicator is an optical indicator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-028.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>.An apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cellular telephone, having a cellular electronics module, and a position detection module which determines a position of said cellular telephone and produces a signal for reporting information indicative of said position of said cellular telephone to a remote object; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a position reporting control, which includes a manual control, which is manually actuable by a user, and which, in response to a first specified actuation by a user, prevents any reporting of said information about position until a second specified actuation by a user, but which allows said cellular electronics module to continue to operate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical indicator, which produces an optical indication which indicates that said first specified actuation has been carried out, and that a privacy enhanced mode has been entered. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-029.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, wherein said first specified actuation prevents said position detection module from determining said determined position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-030.n">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>.An apparatus as in claim <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, wherein said first specified actuation prevents a reporting device from reporting information indicative of the determined position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>.A method of operating a cellular telephone, comprising: 
<claim-text>allowing, in a first mode of operation, automatic reporting of a position of said cellular telephone, and allowing communication between said cellular telephone and a cellular telephone base station; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to a manual actuation, allowing a second mode of operation which prevents any automatic reporting of said position of said cellular telephone, but which still allows communications between said cellular telephone and said cellular telephone base station. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said automatic reporting in said first mode of operation comprises automatic detection of a position of said electronic device via satellite positioning. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second mode of operation prevents said position module from detecting the position via satellite positioning. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second mode of operation allows said position module to detect a position via satellite positioning, but prevents reporting of the detected position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising indicating that said reporting is blocked, using an optical indicator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>.A method, comprising: 
<claim-text>operating a cellular phone in a first mode in which its position can be automatically reported to a remote location; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to an action by a user of a specific type, operating said cellular phone in a second, privacy enhanced mode, in which cellular phone functions can be used to place and/or receive calls, but its position can not be automatically reported to said remote location; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said action by said user comprises attaching an external blocking device to said cellular phone. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>.A system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a test module, associated with an electronic device, and operable to test an amount of privacy for the electronic device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said tested module tests whether said electronic device is currently reporting a position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electronic device includes a wireless communication element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electronic device includes a cellular telephone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>.A system as in claims <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, wherein said electronic device communicates using said wireless communication element to obtain updates to test said amount of privacy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said updates include information about latest ways to improperly obtain a position of the wireless communication element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said test module attempts to obtain certain information, and evaluates a success at obtaining said information to test said amount of privacy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said certain information includes position information of the electronic device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>.A method, comprising: 
<claim-text>testing an electronic device to determine its privacy, and reporting a result of said testing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>.A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said determine privacy comprises determining if said electronic device is automatically reporting its position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising using said electronic device for wireless communication. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, who further comprising updating a way that testing is carried out using said wireless communication medium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing is carried out using requests that attempt to violates the users privacy, and evaluating whether the electronic device responds to said requests. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>.A system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said updating comprises updating new attempts to violate the users privacy.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001774A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001774A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001774A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
