<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00019.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00020.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00021.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00022.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00023.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00024.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00025.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005126A1-20030102-D00026.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005126A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005126</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09866373</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010525</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F015/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>709</class>
<subclass>227000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>709</class>
<subclass>204000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and system for facilitating interactive communication</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Schwartz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stuart</given-name>
<family-name>Evans</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>RushBury</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Wei-Meng</given-name>
<family-name>Chee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>SoloMio Corp.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BAKER BOTTS L.L.P.</name-1>
<name-2>PATENT DEPARTMENT</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>98 SAN JACINTO BLVD., SUITE 1500</address-1>
<city>AUSTIN</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>78701-4039</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An embodiment of a method for facilitating interactive communication is disclosed herein. A mediated communication session is facilitated between a first communication device and a second communication device. Facilitating the mediated communication session includes receiving a request for implementing an interactive communication session. After receiving the request for implementing the interactive communication session, a reply for accepting the request for implementing the interactive communication session is received. The interactive communication session between the first communication device and a third communication device is implemented in response to receiving the reply for accepting the request for implementing the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The disclosures herein relate generally to communication systems and more particularly to methods, systems and apparatus for facilitating interactive communication. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Mobile communication devices, such as cellular telephones, two-way pagers, and wireless enabled personal digital assistants, have become mainstream. Through the use of one of these mobile communication devices, a person is accessible for participating in interactive communication as they engage in their daily activities. As a result, people are now more accessible than ever. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> However, as a result of being more accessible, people are also now more unavailable for participating personally in interactive communication. In many instances, even though a person is accessible for communication, it is often inconvenient or inappropriate for the person to personally engage in interactive communication. For example, while in a meeting, a person may be accessible via their mobile communication device. However, during the meeting and for any number of reasons, it may be inappropriate or inconvenient for the person to attend personally and interactively to an inbound communication. This may be the case even though it is a telephone call or text message that the person needs to or would like to respond personally and immediately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Call waiting, call return, voice mail, electronic assistants and unified messaging systems illustrate examples of conventional communication solutions. Such conventional communication solutions are limited in their ability to facilitate an interactive communication activity in a personalized, time-sensitive and dynamic manner when one or more participants associated with the interactive communication activity are precluded from attending personally to the interactive communication activity. Specifically, conventional solutions help with call filtering (e.g., via caller id or electronic communication assistants). These conventional solutions do not address the process of actually communicating with another party beyond facilitating manual intervention on the subscriber&apos;s part or call redirection (e.g., call forwarding or divert, follow-me). That is, they may result in a communication being redirected to another device, but do not interactively and dynamically assist with the actual communication dialog. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Therefore, a method for enabling communication to be facilitated in a manner that overcomes the limitations of such conventional communication solutions is useful.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram depicting an embodiment of a communication system including a mediation system capable of mediating in an environment including voice-based and data-based communication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram depicting an embodiment of an apparatus capable of facilitating mediated follow-through operations via voice-based and data-based communication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view depicting an embodiment of a menu for specifying an availability status. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view depicting an embodiment of a mediation subscriber policy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart view depicting an embodiment of a method for facilitating a mediation session initiated by an inbound communication request. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view depicting an embodiment of a sequence of events associated with deferring an inbound call from a mobile telephone to a mediation system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a block diagram view depicting an embodiment of a mediation subscriber profile including a plurality of information data sets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view depicting an embodiment of steps for performing an operation of updating the subscriber profile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view depicting an embodiment of steps for determining context and behavior to facilitate the preparation of follow-through actions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a flow chart view depicting an embodiment of a method for facilitating a mediated follow-through operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a flow chart view depicting an embodiment of a method for facilitating an interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a flow chart view depicting another embodiment of a method for facilitating an interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are diagrammatic views depicting an embodiment of a sequence of events associated with requesting and implementing an interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are diagrammatic views depicting an embodiment of a sequence of events associated with facilitating an interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a flow chart view depicting an embodiment of a method for facilitating a mediation session initiated by an outbound communication request. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view depicting an embodiment of a sequence of events associated with requesting mediation of an outbound communication using a mobile telephone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a flow chart view depicting an embodiment of a method for performing a mediated follow-through operation to alter a pending mediated commitment in response to one or more context components being altered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view depicting an embodiment of a sequence of events for altering an availability status using a mobile telephone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a flow chart view depicting an embodiment of a method for facilitation a mediation session for making a mediated service commitment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is a flow chart view depicting an embodiment of a method of facilitating a mediated follow-through operation with a service management system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view depicting an embodiment of a sequence of events for requesting a mediated service commitment using a mobile telephone.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> facilitates mediation between a mediation subscriber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a mediated party <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The mediation subscriber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> communicates with the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through a mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The mediated party <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> communicates with the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through a first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, communication associated with the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is facilitated in a data-based manner and communication associated with the first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is at least partially facilitated in a voice-based format. Accordingly, the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are devices capable of receiving and transmitting information in a data packet format and a voice-based format, respectively. It is contemplated herein that the mediated party may be a different mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> One aspect of the disclosure herein is that data-based communication is advantageous relative to the mediation subscriber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> engaging in mediation activities. Specifically, data-based communication permits the mediation subscriber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to manage mediation activities in a time-sensitive, concise and interactive manner. Data-based communication permits the mediation party <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to engage in mediation activities in situations where voice-based communication would be inconvenient, inappropriate or both. For example, voice-based communication proves to be a less than desirable and effective in situations such as meetings or public spaces where audibly responding to communication activities is often inconvenient and inappropriate. Through the use of data-based communication, the mediation party <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may engage in mediation activities in a non-disruptive manner by responding in a data-based format to information presented in a data-based format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The use of data-based communication provides a quick, less disruptive interrupt for the mediation subscriber. Responding to communications in a data-based manner rather than a voice-based manner only requires glancing down and the pushing of buttons. This type of an interruption can typically be tolerated without significantly disrupting the surrounding activities. There is no such voice-based communication equivalent for inaudibly and time-effectively responding to a communication in a voice-based manner. For example, it is time consuming to answer a call, engage the other party, explain that you are unavailable, and (for example) find out from the mediated party if you can call back when your meeting is over. In a voice-based format, this type of communication can be significant. Furthermore, call screening or other filtering systems offer little relief in this regard because they do not promote a communication with the mediated party. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> One method for accomplishing data-based communication includes communicating information via data packets. General Packet Radio Service (also referred to as GPRS) is a packet-based service that allows information to be sent and received, as data packets, across networks, such as digital cellular networks that supports GPRS. For example, a Global System for Mobile Communications (also referred to as GSM) network is one example of a digital mobile telephone network that can be configured to support GPRS. GPRS facilitates transmission of data packets between mobile communications networks and the Internet. As a result, GPRS is considered to be a sub-network of the Internet with GPRS capable mobile phones being viewed as an access device. Accordingly, access to the Internet is available to mobile users via GPRS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Data packet network services, such as GPRS, bring together high-speed radio access and Internet Protocol (IP) based services into one, powerful environment. IP is a packet-based protocol associated with the Internet that allows active communication devices to be &ldquo;on line&rdquo; at all times and only pay for data that is actually sent or received. In this manner, a connection between an active communication device and the network is always present. As a result, data is sent and received more efficiently than commercially implemented switched-based protocol because a network connection does not first need to be established. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> GPRS is designed for digital cellular networks (GSM, DCS, PCS, TDMA). For example, with respect to GSM networks, GPRS can be viewed as an overlay network onto second-generation GSM networks. It utilizes a packet radio principle and can be used for carrying subscriber packet data protocol information between GPRS enabled devices on GPRS compatible networks and other types of packet data networks such as the Internet. GPRS is standardized by the ETSI (European Telecommunications Standards Institute), and allows voice and data communication to share a common connection. That is, unlike current circuit-switched technology, data packets can arrive/be sent even while voice communication is active and vice versa. Accordingly a voice-based communication can be in progress while receiving and sending data and vise-versa. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Networks supporting GPSR provide an &lsquo;always-on&rsquo; connection with a client device such as a smart phone. Information can be retrieved rapidly because the client device is &lsquo;always-on&rsquo; in the network. Accordingly, the visual display of a GPRS enable device is sometimes referred to as an &lsquo;always-on&rsquo; display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> GPRS network resources are used only when a subscriber is actually sending or receiving data. Rather than dedicating a radio channel to a GPRS subscriber for a fixed period of time, available GPRS resources can be concurrently shared between several subscribers. As GPRS is a radio resource, this efficient use of scarce radio, i.e. frequency, resources means that large numbers of GPRS subscribers can potentially share the same bandwidth and be served from a single cell. The actual number of subscribers supported depends on the application being used and how much data is being transferred. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> GPRS enables mobile Internet functionality by allowing compatibility between existing Internet and GPRS compatible networks. Any service that is used over the fixed Internet today, such as File Transfer Protocol (FTP), chat, email, HTTP, and fax, are also available over GPRS compatible networks. Furthermore, because GPRS enables mobile device users to access the Internet effectively and efficiently, web browsing is a very important application for GPRS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of an apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for enabling mediation activities to be facilitated by the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is further capable of enabling communication between the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a third mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in a manner as disclosed herein. As depicted, the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the second mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, the mediated party computer system <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and service management system <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> are capable of communicating therebetween via the apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In practice, the apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> facilitates mediated communication for a plurality of mediation subscriber communication devices, mediated party communication devices and service management systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (also referred to herein as a communication apparatus) includes the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a data packet network <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a voice network <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a computer data network <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and an interactive communication session (ICS) system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the ICS system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are examples of communication systems. The mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is connected to the data packet network <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, to the voice network <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and to the computer data network <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, thus enabling communication therebetween. The computer network <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is connected to a mediation subscriber computer system <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, to the mediation manager <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and to a service management system <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of a service provider, thus enabling communication therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The voice network <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> includes a computer telephone interface (CTI) server <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and an interactive voice response (IVR) system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The CTI server <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is connected to the IVR system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The IVR system enables interactive voice response from the mediated party to be received by the mediation system and transformed into a computer-based communication format. Commercially available IVR systems for providing speech and call automation functionality are commercially available from Intervoice-Bright Incorporated, IBM Corporation and from Periphonics Corporation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In many situations, it is desirable and advantageous for the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to communicate directly with the first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. In such situations, the mediation subscriber communication device communicates with the mediated party communication device without intervention by the mediation system. To facilitate data-based communication between the mediation subscriber communication system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is connected to the mediated party communication device through the data packet network <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. To facilitate voice-based communication between the mediation subscriber communication system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is connected to the mediated party communication device through the voice network <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, both voice and data can be passed through the mediation system without intervention, or the communication can be re-routed so that the mediation system is not in the communication path. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a mediation manager <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> with a data packet client <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, a computer telephone interface (CTI) client <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, a computer network interface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and an information storage device <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> connected thereto. A Dell PowerVault (TM) series storage device is one example of the information storage device <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The data packet network <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a data packet server <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that enables communication between the data packet network <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the data manager <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> via the data packet client <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The voice network <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> includes a computer telephone interface (CTI) server <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that enables communication between the data packet network <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the mediation manager <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> via the CTI client <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The mediation manager <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes a data processor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, such as a network server, a workstation or other suitable type of data processing device. The computer interface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is connected between the data processor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the computer network <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for enabling communication therebetween. A Dell PowerEdge&trade; series server is one example of a suitable commercially available network server. A Dell Precision&trade; series workstation is one example of a suitable commercially available workstation. The information storage device <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is connected to the data processor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for storing information in non-volatile memory and retrieving information therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A first data processor program product <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> includes a first data processor program that is processable by the data processor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the mediation manager <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The first data processor program enables facilitation of at least a portion of the operations performed by the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for accomplishing the methods disclosed herein. The first data processor program is accessible by the data processor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the mediation manager <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from an apparatus such as a diskette, a compact disk, a network storage device or other suitable apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The service management system <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> includes a data processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, computer network interface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a voice network interface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The computer network interface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is connected to the computer network <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for enabling data-based communication between the service manager <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via the computer network <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The voice network interface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is connected to the voice network <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for enabling voice-based communication between the service manager <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via the voice network <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The mediation subscriber computer system <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> includes a data processor <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a computer network interface <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The computer interface <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is connected between the data processor <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the mediation subscriber computer system <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the computer network <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for enabling communication therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> A mobile telephone capable of transmitting and receiving data packets via the General Packet Radio Service (GPRS) is one example of the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. GPRS enabled mobile telephones, also referred to as &ldquo;Smart Phones&rdquo;, are offered by manufacturers such as Ericsson Incorporated and Nokia Incorporated. Smart phones are mobile phones with built-in voice, data, and Web-browsing services. Smart phones integrate mobile computing and mobile communications into a single terminal. Smart phones, importantly, can execute Java programs within the device. Java programs can be used to control presentation and interaction with the user, as well as send and receive data packets. The Ericsson models R380 and R520 telephones and the Nokia 9000 series telephone represent specific examples of GPRS enable mobile telephones. All GPRS phones provide WAP User Agents as an application environment and presentation using WML with programming using WMLScript. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The ICS system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes an interactive session manager <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> with a data packet client <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, a computer network interface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and an information storage device <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> connected thereto. The interactive session manager <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> includes a data processor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, such as a network server, a workstation or other suitable type of data processing device. The computer interface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is connected between the data processor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the computer network <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for enabling communication therebetween. The information storage device <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is connected to the data processor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for storing in non-volatile memory and retrieving information therefrom information associated with implementing and facilitating an interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> A second data processor program product <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> includes a second data processor program that is processable by the data processor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the mediation manager <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The second data processor program enables facilitation of at least a portion of the operations performed by the ICS system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> for accomplishing the methods disclosed herein. The second data processor program is accessible by the data processor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the interactive session manager <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> from an apparatus such as a diskette, a compact disk, a network storage device or other suitable apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated herein that in another embodiment (not shown) of the apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, an integrated communication management system may include a mediated communication portion for supporting functionality associated with the mediated communication session and an interactive communication portion for supporting functionality associated with the interactive communication session. The mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is one embodiment of the mediated communication portion. The ICS system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is one example of the interactive communication portion. The mediation portion and the interactive communication portion may share a common data processor, a common information storage device, a common data packet client and a common computer network interface. In this manner, the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the ICS system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are effectively integrated into a single system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> It is further contemplated herein that a third data processor product supports functionality associated with the mediated communication session and the interactive communication session. In at least one embodiment of the third data processor program product, the third data processor program product provides the functionality associated with the first and the second data processor programs disclosed above. The third data processor program product is capable of being accessible by both the data processor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the mediation manager <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the data processor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the interactive session manager <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, or by the common data processor of the integrated communication management system disclosed above. In this manner, the first data processor program and the second data processor program are effectively integrated into a single data processor program product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, such as a smart phone, include a user interface. The user interface of the device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes a data interface portion and a voice interface portion. In the embodiment of the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the user interface includes a visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a plurality of alphanumeric keys <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, a plurality of control keys <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and a scroll key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. The voice interface portion of the user interface includes a speaker <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>and a microphone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The data interface portion of the user interface permits information to be visually displayed and permits the mediation subscriber to interactively manipulate information associated with data-based communications between the device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>permits information to be visually displayed. The plurality of alphanumeric keys <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>permits alphanumeric information to be inputted. The plurality of control keys <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>permit associated functionality to be selected. For example, functional operations, such as accept and cancel, displayed on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be associated with respective control keys <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The scroll key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>permits menu information such as availability specifiers AS to be highlighted and manipulated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> It should be understood that other types of devices also represent suitable examples of the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Personal digital assistants (PDAs) such as those offered by Palm Computing and Handspring are data-centric devices that are capable of providing mobile wireless access. These devices can utilize GPRS through a GPRS-capable mobile phone via a serial cable or directly if they have built-in GPRS capability. Similarly, suitably equipped mobile computers are also capable of communicating data packets over a GPRS compatible network. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The apparatus, systems and devices discussed and disclosed herein permit mediation of an inbound or outbound communication to be facilitated electronically, yet in a dynamic, personalized and time-sensitive manner. In one embodiment, the methods disclosed herein are not governed exclusively by user-defined rules and designations. In these embodiments, it is advantageous for these methods to be facilitated in large degree by system-defined information. System defined information is information garnished by the mediation system in response to facilitating mediation operations. Furthermore, it is desirable to require the mediation subscriber to define and maintain only a minimal amount of designated information (also referred to herein as user-defined information). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> One example of user-defined information is an availability status of the mediation subscriber. The availability status defines qualitative aspects of the mediation subscriber&apos;s availability and, in some cases, also defines quantitative aspects of the mediation subscriber&apos;s availability. As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, an availability status menu ASM is displayable on a visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The availability status menu ASM includes a plurality of availability specifiers AS. For a first type of availability specifier AS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a time indicating availability is specified in a time field TF. For example, the mediation subscriber may specify that he will be in a meeting until a designated time, such as 10:15 AM. For a second type of availability specifier AS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a duration quantitatively indicating availability is specified in a duration field DF. For example, the mediation subscriber specifies availability in a designated amount of time, such as 10 minutes. For a third type of availability specifier AS<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the selected availability status itself defines a relative (qualitative) time designating the availability of the mediation subscriber. For example, the mediation subscriber may designate that he is available now. For a fourth type of availability specifier AS<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the fourth type of availability specifier AS<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> that queries a priority of the communication request by the mediated party. For example, the mediation subscriber may select an availability specifier that results in the urgency of the communication request being mediated by the mediation system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Another technique for providing subscriber specified preferences and information includes the preparation of one or more policies. An embodiment of a policy <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, as viewed via visual display <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; of the mediation subscriber computer system <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Information included in the policy <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be provided via the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, via the mediation subscriber computer system <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, or both. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The policy <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a tab <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> that may be used to specify a name for a particular group of individuals associated with the policy <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. At a group field <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, the mediation subscriber may specify one of more specific individuals that apply to the policy <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Information such as the name and one or more telephone numbers associated with each individual is specified at the group field <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. At a greeting field <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, the mediation subscriber may designate and set-up a desired greeting. For example, the mediation subscriber may designate a standard greeting or a custom greeting. The standard greeting is a greeting that would be applied to any policy that does not specify a custom greeting. At a co-mediator field <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, the mediation subscriber may designate one or more co-mediators associated with the policy <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Each designated co-mediator is thus authorized by the mediation subscriber to engage in mediation of a communication request received by the mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Still referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the mediation subscriber may designate a default action to be performed by the mediation system in instances when a follow-up action for a particular communication is not provided by the mediation subscriber in response to being prompted for one by the mediation system. A first set of default actions D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> define actions that are taken in instances where a follow-up action by the mediation subscriber is not provided in response to the mediation system prompting the mediation subscriber for a follow-up action. For example, the mediation subscriber may designate a default action from the first set of default actions D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for instructing the mediation system to forward applicable communications to the mediation subscriber&apos;s administrative assistant. A second set of default actions D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> defines a plurality of follow-up actions that designate an initial action associated with applicable communications. For example, the mediation subscriber may designate a default action from the second set of default actions D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> for instructing the mediation system to &lsquo;Schedule A Time To Talk&rsquo; with the mediated party (team member) if a particular criteria C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is met, such as a communication being designated as urgent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of a method for facilitating a mediation session initiated by an inbound communication request is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, illustrates an example of an apparatus capable of carrying out the method depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. At a block <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, an inbound communication request from the first mediated party communication device <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is received by the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Information may be communicated between the mediation subscriber communication device and the mediation system via data packets over a suitable network. An inbound telephone call illustrates one example of the inbound communication request. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In response to receiving the inbound communication request, an applicable context and behavior information are determined at a block <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>. In response to determining that a policy does not apply to the inbound communication request at a box <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, a contextual communication summary is prepared and the contextual communication summary is communicated to the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> at, a block <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and a block <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, respectively. Information provided by a carrier caller identification service, such as a caller&apos;s name and phone number and information relating to acts initiating the communication from the mediated party, such as returning a call from the mediation subscriber, may comprise a portion of the information included in the contextual communication summary. Behavior information is discussed in greater detail below. At a block <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, a plurality of follow-through actions is prepared. In other embodiments, only one follow-through action is prepared. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> At a block <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, the mediation subscriber may choose to accept the inbound communication or defer the inbound communication to a mediation operation. In the case where the mediation subscriber chooses to accept the inbound communication, a connection is facilitated (block <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>) between the mediation subscriber communication device and the mediated party communication device a suitable voice network, such as the voice network <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In the case where the mediation subscriber chooses to defer the associated inbound communication, at the block <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, the plurality of follow-through actions is communicated to the mediation subscriber communication device at a block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> It should be noted that a plurality of operations, such as communicating the contextual communication summary to the mediation subscriber and preparing the plurality of follow-through actions, may be performed concurrently. For example, mediation operations between the mediation system and the mediation subscriber may be performed while telephone is ringing. In this manner, time may be used efficiently, thus reducing the time which the mediated party is awaiting either a personal or mediated response. It should also be noted that the contextual communication summary and the follow-through actions may be communicated essentially simultaneously such that the mediation subscriber nearly immediately has all the information necessary to address the inbound communication request. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In response to the mediation subscriber selecting one of the follow-through actions, a selected follow-through action is received by the mediation system from the mediation subscriber communication device at a block <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. In response to receiving the selected follow-through at the block <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, an operation for determining if the selected follow-through operation requests an interactive communication session between the mediated party and the mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> An interactive communication session is defined herein as a communication session in which communication between two parties is capable of being conducted in essentially a non-mediated manner. A mediated communication session is defined herein as a communication session in which communication between two parties is at least partially mediated by a mediation system. A text-based interactive communication session is defined herein as an interactive communication session in which communication between the mediated party and the mediation subscriber is facilitated using text-based communication techniques. The text-based interactive communication session is also referred to herein as a text session. A voice-data mediated communication session is defined herein as a mediated communication session in which voice-based communication techniques are used for communication between the mediation system and the mediated party and text-based data communication techniques are used for communication between the mediation system and the mediation subscriber. The voice based mediated communication session is also referred to herein as a mixed-mode session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In response to the received follow-through action not requesting an interactive communication session between the mediated party and the mediation subscriber, a mediation follow-through operation according to the selected mediated follow-through action is facilitated at a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. In response to facilitating the mediation follow-through operation, a mediation subscriber profile is updated at a block <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. As discussed below, updating the mediation subscriber profile includes updating at least one data set, such as a mediation activity data set, in a mediation subscriber profile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In response to the received follow-through action requesting an interactive communication session between the mediated party and the mediation subscriber, the interactive communication session is facilitated at the block <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight>. Embodiments of methods for facilitating the interactive communication session are disclosed below in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The interactive communication session permits the mediation subscriber, the mediated party or both to communicate using free-forrn text strings, pre-defined dialog responses, action-based dialog responses, user-defined dialog responses and contextually-generated dynamic dialog responses. In this manner, the interactive communication session provides a more information-rich communication environment than does a mediated communication session. It should be understood that mediated communication as disclosed is not precluded in the interactive communication system. Rather, mediated communication as disclosed herein may be used in a manner for enhancing the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> It should also be understood that the advantages afforded to the mediation subscriber by the mediated communication session are also afforded to the mediation subscriber by the interactive communication session as disclosed herein. For example, in the interactive communication session, the mediation subscriber can communicate in a manner that is not disruptive or inappropriate in a meeting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In response to determining at the box <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> that a policy, such as the policy depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, does apply to the inbound communication request and determining at a block <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> that that the policy requires always ringing the mediation subscriber, the method continues at the block <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. In response to determining at the block <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> that policy-driven mediated follow-through is required, the method continues at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. In the case of policy-driven mediated follow-through, facilitating mediated follow-through at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> is performed, at least in part, according to the follow-through action designated in the policy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The mediated follow-through operation performed at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> depicts an example of a virtual mediation operation. By virtual mediation operation, it is meant that the mediation operation is performed by the mediation system on behalf of the mediation subscriber. For example, the mediation can be performed in an automated manner by data processing device as described herein. Virtual mediation adds a high degree of personalization to acting on behalf of the mediation subscriber. To this end, the virtual mediation operation is performed based on contextual and behavioral information associated with the mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> It should be understood that rather than choose to accept the inbound communication or select one of the follow-through actions, the mediation subscriber may choose to do nothing (neither accept nor defer the inbound communication). By the mediation subscriber choosing to not accept the call nor to select one of the follow-through actions (block <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>), a system-imposed follow-through action, such as the default action discussed above in reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, is identified by the mediation system at a block <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, when the mediation subscriber chooses to neither accept nor defer the inbound communication, the mediation follow-through operation is facilitated according to the system imposed follow-through action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> It is also contemplated that a system-defined action based on contextual information, historical information, and behavioral information may be imposed rather than default actions associated with user-defined information. For example, the mediation subscriber is in a meeting and has received three calls from unknown parties. In all three cases, the mediation subscriber has selected a follow-through action requesting that the mediated (unknown) party schedule a time to talk. Accordingly, for all subsequent unknown callers while the mediation subscriber is in the meeting, the mediation system automatically initiates a mediated follow-through operation for scheduling a time to talk. A pre-defined number of occurrences may need to occur first, such as three attempts from unknown callers, prior to mediation system imposing such as system-defined follow-through action. In this example, the follow-through action imposed by the mediation system is a system-defined behavior-based follow-through action. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Inbound Call Mediation </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> David is in an important meeting in which it would be seen as disruptive to verbally respond to incoming communications received on his wireless telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, at a first mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, David visually reviews a caller summary CS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The caller summary includes contextual information associated with prior incoming calls that he has not accepted. At some prior point in time, David has communicated his availability status to the mediation system. Accordingly the mediation system knows that David is planning on being in this meeting until 14:30 hours. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> After reviewing the caller summary CS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a second mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, David receives an incoming call from Richard S. In response to receiving the incoming call, a communication summary CS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is displayed on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of his wireless telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. By reviewing the communication summary CS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, David is able to quickly and non-disruptively ascertain that the incoming call is from Richard S and that Richard S has made repeated attempts to return a call from David. Because David is still in the meeting, he chooses to defer the call for virtual mediation by selecting the control key <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with a defer action DA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> In response to choosing the defer action DA, a follow-through action menu FAM is displayed on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; at a third mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The follow-through action menu includes a plurality of follow-through actions FA. David uses the scroll key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to highlight the follow-through action &lsquo;Will call when free&rsquo; and confirms the selection by depressing the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with an accept action AA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Because David responded to the inbound communication using a data-based communication format, he was able to review the available contextual information and implement a desired follow-through action without disrupting the meeting. Furthermore, it only took David a short period or time (e.g. about 10 seconds) to review the available contextual information and implement the desired follow-through action. While David is still participating in the meeting, the mediation system has engaged in a virtual mediation operation for notifying Richard (the mediated party) that David will call him after the meeting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> As a result of David having provided his availability status to the mediation system, the mediation system uses the availability status in performing the mediation operation. The mediation system lets Richard know that David is in a meeting until 14:30 hours and will return his call after this time. In this manner, a more personalized and efficient communication is facilitated between the mediation system and Richard.</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> The &lsquo;schedule a time&rsquo; follow-through action depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is one embodiment of a follow-through action for mediating a coordinated arrangement for person-to-person communication to be facilitated. In such an embodiment, the mediation system mediates an agreed upon time and/or day for the mediation subscriber and the mediated party to communicate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Context and contextual, as referred to herein, relate to experiences, actions, and information associated with a communication. For example, the contextual communication summary CS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, includes a plurality of context components. A first context component CC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is associated with a name of the mediated party. A second context component CC<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is associated with a phone number of the mediated party. A third context component CC<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is associated with the reason for the communication. A fourth context component CC<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is associated with prior attempts by the mediated party to contact the mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Together, these context components CC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-CC<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> provide the mediation subscriber with a brief yet insightful summary of the inbound communication. In other embodiments, the contextual communication summary includes only one context component, such as the phone number of the mediated party. The actions of the mediation subscriber and the mediated party result in an abundance of contextual information associated with the inbound communication being generated. Furthermore, completed and on-going mediation operations generate information associated with such mediation operations. Such information is useful in determining system-defined information, such as system-defined default actions mentioned above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that, in addition to the contexts previously discussed, there are many other types of contextual data that may be used to control communication between parties. Table 1 lists specific context types and embodiments. Accordingly, mediation steps can be based upon the various contexts described herein, including those of Table 1.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="161PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Presence</entry>
<entry>Presence of one or more parties to a mediation</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>communication. The Presence of a party</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>defines their availability for communication</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>via various channels (eg phone or instant</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Messaging (chat). Presence may be set by</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>the party (ie they choose NOT to be available, or</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>by physical limitations (out of range).</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Presence identifies what channels a user can be</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>reached via at any given time</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Location</entry>
<entry>The location of one or more parties to a mediated</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>communication. The location will generally be the</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>location of the mediation device, and in one embodi-</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ment, can be determined automatically based data</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>available to the wireless communications system, or</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>other positioning system such as a Global Positioning</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>System. In another</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>implementation, a party can manually specify their</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>location or an alternate location.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Time</entry>
<entry>Time that the party is in. For the subscriber, this could</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>be with respect to Mediation policies</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(&ldquo;deny all business calls after 7 pm&rdquo; or</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&ldquo;Deny all calls when I am busy&rdquo;) and also for</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>managing or warning about scheduled meetings</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(&ldquo;Incoming call from Sally, but you have a</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>meeting in 5 minutes&rdquo;)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Identity</entry>
<entry>Identity and number/address that Mediated party</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>is using. For the subscriber, this could be</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>with respect to Mediation policies</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(&ldquo;deny all calls unless it&apos;s Sally&rdquo;)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Communication</entry>
<entry>The history of communication interactions</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>History</entry>
<entry>and follow through actions between caller and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>subscriber may influence the options</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(or priority) of options to be taken</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Membership</entry>
<entry>The membership of a caller, as organized</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>in the subscribers address book may influence</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>which policies of mediation apply.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>E.g. &ldquo;Deny all business calls after 7 pm&rdquo; means if</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>caller has been assigned as a &ldquo;business&rdquo; caller then</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>deny their call after 7 pm.</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> It will be further appreciated that, in addition to those mediation actions and follow-through mediation actions described, there are many other types of actions that may be used to control communication between parties. Table 2 indicates specific action types and embodiments.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="154PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Forward Call</entry>
<entry>A party to a mediated communication can request</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>the call be forwarded to a different party,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>such as an assistant.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Leave Message</entry>
<entry>A party to a mediated communication can request</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>that caller be asked to leave a message.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Request call back or</entry>
<entry>Subscriber may, via the mediation service,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>message</entry>
<entry>request the</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(VM/SMS/Email)</entry>
<entry>caller calls later (e.g. when both a</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>free) or send a simple message via certain channels.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Promise to call back</entry>
<entry>Subscriber may, via the mediation service,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>tell the caller that they will return the call in due</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>course</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Schedule a meeting</entry>
<entry>Subscriber may, via the mediation service,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(conf call or other)</entry>
<entry>request that the caller arrange a time (when both</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>a free) to talk</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Use Internet Chat</entry>
<entry>Subscriber may, via the mediation service,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(Instant Messaging)</entry>
<entry>suggest transferring the form of communication</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>to on-line chat (when they are in a conference</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>for example)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Deny call, side</entry>
<entry>Deny the call to the user, but at the same</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>effecting policy</entry>
<entry>time defining a policy or rule that will affect</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>change</entry>
<entry>subsequent calls from that caller (e.g. &ldquo;No more</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>calls from him today&rdquo;)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Deny call and send</entry>
<entry>Deny the call to the user (e.g. in a meeting),</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>message</entry>
<entry>but opt to send them a text message.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Deny call and send</entry>
<entry>Deny the call to the user but select a</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&ldquo;canned&rdquo; message</entry>
<entry>&ldquo;canned/pre-recorded&rdquo;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>message to be displayed or</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&ldquo;read&rdquo; to the call</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ask a question</entry>
<entry>Defer taking the call, but via the mediation</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>service ask a question to the caller. E.g. &ldquo;Is it</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>important&quest;&rdquo;.</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the mediation subscriber profile <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The mediation subscriber profile <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is stored on the data storage device <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The mediation subscriber profile <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> includes one or more data sets. A communication history data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>includes communication history information, such as the name and telephone number of the party associated with the communication. An availability history data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>includes availability history information of the mediation subscriber. An action history data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>includes follow-through action history information. A mediation activity data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>includes information relating to completed or in-progress mediated activities. A policies data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>includes the policies discussed above. A service provider data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>includes information such as preferences (i.e. type of room, type of food, etc) relating to mediated service that can be requested by the mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Each one of the profile data sets <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>can be associated with at least one other profile data set such that related information can be associated. For example, in one embodiment, it is desirable and advantageous to relate a particular communication from a mediated party with a corresponding follow-through action and availability. Relating such information supports determining context, history and mediation status associated with a particular communication. It should also be understood that the data sets might be each maintained in separate databases or in a common database along the system depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In addition, the data sets can have information specific to either the mediation subscriber or the mediated party being mediated, i.e. the caller. For example, the action history data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>can have a history of actions taken by either the mediated party or the mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> It is one aspect of the apparatus, methods and systems disclosed herein that the information archived in the mediation subscriber profile <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> may be used to gain insight into behaviors and preferences of the mediation subscriber with respect to handling inbound and outbound communications. Determining such behaviors and preferences is desirable and advantageous. In this manner, mediation operations may be carried-out dynamically and time-efficiently. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, an embodiment of steps for performing the operation of updating the mediation subscriber profile <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> at the block <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is depicted. The steps for performing the operation of updating the mediation subscriber profile <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> include archiving inbound communication information (block <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), archiving the availability status of the mediation subscriber at the time of receiving the inbound communication (block <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), and archiving any corresponding follow-up action (block <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>). Examples of the inbound communication information includes a time of receipt of the inbound communication, a name of the mediated party, a telephone number associated with the inbound communication. Archiving is defined herein to include forming relationships between information as discussed above in reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> depicts an embodiment of a method for accomplishing the operation of determining applicable context and behavior by the mediated party, as depicted at the block <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. One example of determining the context associated with the inbound communication includes determining a present availability of the mediation subscriber (block <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), analyzing present information associated with the inbound communication (block <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), and analyzing historical information, such as from the mediation subscriber profile, that is associated with the inbound communication (block <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>). One example of determining a related behavior includes analyzing mediation subscriber policies (block <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>), analyzing follow-through actions associated with historical inbound communication information (block <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>) and analyzing availability history of the mediation subscriber (block <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>). All of the information analyzed at the block <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is archived in the mediation subscriber profile discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> depicts an embodiment of a method for accomplishing the operation of facilitating a mediated follow-through operation, as depicted at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. At a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a follow-through action communication is prepared. In one embodiment, the follow-through action communication is voice based. The follow-through action communication is communicated to the mediated party communication device at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In response to the selected follow-through action being accepted by the mediated party at a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>&prime;, completion of the selected follow-through action is facilitated by the mediation system at a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. In response to the selected follow-through action being unaccepted able or non-actionable by the mediated party, at a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>&Prime;, the mediated party may choose to terminate the communication, such as by hanging-up, or to suggest a revised follow-through action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> In response to suggesting an alternate follow-through action at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>&Prime;, an availability request is communicated to the mediated party at a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. Prompting the mediated party to reply with how long they will be available, when they will be available, or the like are examples of communicating the availability request to the mediated party communication device. At a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>, a present availability is received from the mediated party. The present availability may be received from the mediated party in a voice-based format or as data entered using a device, such as a telephone keypad. At a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>, a plurality of alternate follow-through actions is prepared. In other embodiments, only one alternate follow-through action is prepared. Preparing the alternate follow-through actions includes assessing information such as the present availability of the mediated party, the present availability of the mediation subscriber, communication history, policies, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated that these alternate follow-through actions may include all or some of the non-selected follow-through actions previously sent to the mediation subscriber at the block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Additionally, it is contemplated that all or some of the alternate follow-through actions may be availability-defined follow-through actions. By availability-defined follow-through actions, it is meant that the availability of the mediation subscriber and/or the availability of the mediated party define a specific follow-through action. A call-back time based on joint availability of the mediation subscriber and the mediated party illustrates an example of the availability-defined follow-through actions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> At a block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>g</italic></highlight>, the plurality of alternate follow-through actions is communicated to the mediation subscriber communication device and the method continues at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>&prime;. In response to the mediated party accepting one of the alternate follow-through actions at the block <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>&prime;, the method continued at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. In response to the mediated party not accepting one of the alternate follow-through actions at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>&prime;, the method continues at the block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>&Prime;. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 2 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Performing Mediated Follow-Through Operation </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> In response to David selecting the &lsquo;Will call when free&rsquo; follow-through action (see Example 1), the mediation system engages in the following voice based communication with the Richard, via the IVR system. &ldquo;Richard, I am unavailable to talk with you right now, but will call you as soon as I am out of my meeting. I expect to be out of me meeting at 14:30 hours. If you will be available at around this time, please press 1. If you will not be available at about this time, please press 2&rdquo;. The communication with the mediated party may be in David&apos;s actual voice, a synthesized voice or other type of voice format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In the instance in which Richard S. is available at this time, he responds accordingly by pressing 1. In response to Richard S. responding that he is available at this time, the mediation system communicates the following confirmation message to Richard S and then terminated the call. &ldquo;Richard, I&apos;ll be call you shortly after 14:30 hours. I look forward to talking with you then. Good-bye.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> In the instance in which Richard is not available at this time, he responds accordingly by depressing 2. The mediation system then engages in the following voice-based communication with the Richard, via the IVR system, in an attempt to proceed according to an alternate and mutually acceptable follow-through action. &ldquo;Richard, I would like to connect with you. After the tone, please key in a time that you are available to talk so that I can attempt to accommodate your schedule.&rdquo; After the tone, Richard uses the telephone keypad to enter a time, such as 15:45 hours. In some instances, it may be desirable to use voice recognition for receiving contextual information and responses from Richard. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> In response to receiving the time specified by Richard, the mediation system communicates a data-based communication to David. The data-based communication is a single follow-through action prompting David with &ldquo;Are you available to talk with Richard at this time&quest;&rdquo; In the instance in which David is available to talk with Richard at the time specified by Richard, he confirms that he is available by depressing the control key corresponding to the accept action. In response to David confirming that he is available at the time specified by Richard, the mediation system communicates the following voice-based communication to Richard and terminates the call. &ldquo;Richard, I am available to talk with you at this time. I will call you at around 15:45 hours. Thanks and I&apos;ll talk to you soon. Good-bye.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> In the instance in which David is not available to talk with Richard at the time specified by Richard, he indicates that he is not available by depressing the control key corresponding to a decline action. In response to David indicating that he is not available at the time specified by Richard, the mediation system communicates the following voice-based communication to Richard and terminates the call. &ldquo;Richard, I am not available to talk with you at this time. I&apos;ll follow-up with you later to try and find a convenient time to talk. Thanks for calling. Good-bye.&rdquo; In some instances, the mediation system may allow Richard to be transferred to David&apos;s assistant, such that mediation can be continued via David&apos;s assistant.</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of a method <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> for facilitating the interactive communication session, as depicted at the block <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. The method <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> includes an operation <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> for transmitting a request for implementing an interactive communication session and an operation <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> for transmitting a reply for accepting the request. The operation <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> includes transmitting the request for implementing from a first communication device, such as a wireless mediation subscriber communication device, for being received by the mediation system. The operation <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> includes transmitting the reply for accepting the request from a second communication device, such as a voice-based mediated party communication device, for being received by t he mediation system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> In response to the mediation system performing an operation <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> for receiving the request for implementing and an operation <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> for receiving the reply for accepting the request, an operation <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> is performed by the mediation system for preparing log-in information for implementing the interactive communication session. In response to performing the operation <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, an operation <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> is performed by the mediation system for transmitting the log-in information from the mediation system for being received by the second communication device and by an interactive communication session system. An Internet service provider (ISP) system is one example of the interactive communication session system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> After the operation <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> is performed for transmitting the log-in information, an operation <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> is performed by the interactive communication session system for receiving the log-in information. Furthermore, after an operation <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> is performed by the second communication device for receiving the log-in information, an operation <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> is performed for transmitting the log-in information from a third communication device, such as a text-based meditated party communication device, for being received by the mediation system. In at least one embodiment of the log-in information, the log-in information includes a passcode and an address for an Internet website. Broadly speaking, the log-in information includes sufficient information for enabling the mediation subscriber and/or the mediated party to initiate implementation of the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> In at least one embodiment of the third communication device, the third communication device is computer system capable of communicating with the mediation system and the first communication device via a data communication network such as the Internet. Other examples of the third communication device include a personal digital assistant, a smart phone and a mobile text-messaging device such as a 2-way text pager. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> In response to an operation <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> being performed by the mediation system for receiving the log-in information, an operation <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> is performed by the mediation system for authenticating the log-in information. Authentication of the log-in information ensures that the log-in information is valid. In at least one embodiment of the log-in information, the log-in information includes a time-stamped passcode that is readable by the mediation system and is valid for only a prescribed validation period. A time-stamped passcode is an example of chronologically referenced log-in information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> In at least one embodiment of the operation <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> for authenticating the log-in information, the operation <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> includes determining an elapsed period of time from when the time-stamped passcode was generated and verifying that the elapsed period of time is less than the prescribed validation period of the passcode. Accordingly, if the elapsed period of time is greater than the prescribed validation period, the authentication operation would reveal that the log-in information is invalid. In such a situation, the mediation system would return a message to this effect to the party attempting to initiate implementation of the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated herein that generating the passcode may include receiving a specified passcode from one of the communication devices. In one embodiment of receiving a specified passcode, the specified passcode is a mediation subscriber specified passcode received from a mediation subscriber communication device. In another embodiment of receiving a specified passcode, the specified passcode is a mediated party specified passcode received from a mediated party communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> In response to performing an operation <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> for transmitting a session authorization notification from the mediation system for being received by the interactive communication session system, an operation <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> is performed by the interactive communication session system for receiving the session authorization notification. The operations <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> illustrate an example of implementing the interactive communication session. After performing the operation <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> for receiving the session authorization notification, an operation <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> is performed by the interactive communication session system for managing the interactive communication session between the first communication device and the third communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> Upon the interactive communication session being ended, an operation <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> is performed by the interactive communication session system for transmitting a session termination notification for being received by the mediation system. In response to the mediation system performing an operation <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> for receiving the session termination notification, an operation <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> is performed by the mediation system for invalidating the log-in information. It is contemplated that the operations <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> are omitted in a case where the passcode is invalidated after the prescribed validation period of the log-in information discussed above elapses, even though the text-session has already been implemented. In such a case, so long as the parties are engaged in the interactive communication session, the interactive communication session is active even though the log-in information has been invalidated as a result of the prescribed validation period of the log-in information having elapsed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of a method <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>&prime; for facilitating the interactive communication session, as depicted at the block <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. The method <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>&prime; depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> differs from the method <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> that depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> in that the interactive communication session system, rather than the mediation system, facilitates all of the operations associated with implementing the interactive communication session. The method <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>&prime; includes an operation <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>&prime; for transmitting a request for implementing the interactive communication session and an operation <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>&prime; for transmitting a reply for accepting the request. The operation <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>&prime; includes transmitting the request for implementing from a second communication device, such as a voice-based mediated party communication device, for being received by the mediation system. The operation <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>&prime; includes transmitting the reply for accepting the request from the first communication device, such as a wireless mediation subscriber communication device for being received by the mediation system. It is contemplated herein that the both the mediation subscriber and the mediated party both are provided with the capability for proposing a request for implementing the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> In response to the mediation system performing an operation <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>&prime; for receiving the request for implementing and an operation <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>&prime; for receiving the reply for accepting the request, an operation <highlight><bold>259</bold></highlight>&prime; is performed by the mediation system for transmitting a session request notification for being received by the interactive communication session system. In response to the interactive communication session system performing an operation <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>&prime; for receiving the session request notification, an operation <highlight><bold>261</bold></highlight>&prime; is performed by the interactive communication session system for preparing log-in information for implementing the interactive communication session. In response to performing the operation <highlight><bold>261</bold></highlight>&prime; for preparing the log-in information, an operation <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>&prime; is performed by the interactive communication session system for transmitting the log-in information for being received by the second communication device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> After an operation <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight>&prime; is performed by the second communication device for receiving the log-in information, an operation <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight>&prime; is performed for transmitting the log-in information from a third communication device, such as a text-based meditated party communication device, for being received by the interactive communication session system. In response to an operation <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>&prime; being performed by the interactive communication session system for receiving the log-in information, an operation <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>&prime; is performed by the interactive communication session system for authenticating the log-in information. In response to the interactive communication session system performing the operation <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>&prime; for authenticating the log-in information, an operation <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight>&prime; is performed by the interactive communication session system for managing the interactive communication session between the first communication device and the third communication device. The operations <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>&prime; to <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>&prime; illustrate another example of implementing the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> Upon the interactive communication session being ended, an operation <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight>&prime; is performed by the interactive communication session system for invalidating the log-in information. It is contemplated that the operation <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight>&prime; is omitted in the case where the passcode is invalidated after the prescribed validation period of the log-in information discussed above elapses, even though the interactive communication session has already been implemented. In such a case, so long as the parties are engaged in the interactive communication session, the interactive communication session remains active even though the log-in information has been invalidated as a result of the prescribed validation period of the log-in information having elapsed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> As disclosed above, the mediated party transfers from the second communication device to the third communication device for engaging in the interactive communication session. It is also contemplated herein that the mediation subscriber may transfer from the first communication device to a fourth communication device. In this manner, the mediation subscriber is provided with the ability to move to a different communication device that may provide more efficient and/or effective communication. A computer system capable of communicating with the mediation system and the third communication device via a data communication network such as the Internet is an example of the fourth communication device. Other examples of the fourth communication device include a personal digital assistant, a smart phone and a mobile text-messaging device such as a 2-way text pager. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> In a first embodiment of a method wherein the mediation subscriber transfers from the first communication device to the fourth communication device for communicating with the mediated party, log-in information is transmitted to the first communication device for enabling implementation of the interactive communication session between the third and the fourth communication devices. The log-in information transmitted to the first communication device is used in a similar manner as that transmitted to the second communication device for implementing the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> In a second embodiment of a method wherein the mediation subscriber transfers from the first communication device to the fourth communication device for communicating with the mediated party, implementation of the interactive communication session is performed in an automated manner using system-accessible information associated with the mediation subscriber. For example, an automated log-in link could be transmitted to a known e-mail address of the mediation subscriber. In response to the mediation subscriber selecting the link via the fourth communication device, the interactive communication session is automatically implemented between the third and fourth communication devices. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 3 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Implementing An Interactive Communication Session. </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> David is still in the meeting, Example 1, when he gets a call from Steffen on his wireless telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. David knows it would not be appropriate to take a voice call in the meeting so he chooses to defer the call as discussed above in reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Because Steffen is a key member of David&apos;s team, he would like to communicate with Steffen via an interactive communication session so that they can exchange information in a more detailed manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, at an interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, David selects a &lsquo;text me back&rsquo; follow-through action from the plurality of follow-through actions FA on the follow-through action menu FAM. The &lsquo;Text me back&rsquo; follow-through action is a follow-through action for initiating the interactive communication session. In response to selecting the &lsquo;Text me back&rsquo; follow-through action FA, at a second interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the mediation system implements an Interactive Voice Response (IVR) operation for enabling Steffen to respond to David&apos;s request for the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> The IVR operation for enabling Steffen to respond to David&apos;s request for the interactive communication session includes transmitting a query message QM to Steffen for determining his availability and/or interest in participating in the interactive communication session. An example of the query message QM associated with initiating the interactive communication session is &ldquo;I can&apos;t talk now, can we communicate via text&quest;&rdquo; After communicating the query message QM, an IVR operation is performed for transmitting one or more query responses (QR) to Steffen for enabling him to respond to the query message QM. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> In addition to allowing Steffen to accept the request for implementing the interactive communication session, the query messages QM provide Steffen with alternatives for allowing Steffen to not accept the request for implementing the interactive communication session. The text me back follow-through action and associated IVR operation represent a proposal to engage in an interactive communication session, not a mandated requirement. In this manner, the mediation subscriber cannot force implementing the interactive communication session on the mediated party, and vise versa, in instances where the mediated party is requesting implementation of the interactive communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> Examples of the query responses QR are depicted below in Table 3.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="140PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Press 1 for:</entry>
<entry>Yes, but I will have to e-mail you later.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Press 2 for:</entry>
<entry>It&apos;s quick, can you take my call&quest;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Press 3 for:</entry>
<entry>No, I will leave a voice message instead.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Press 4 for:</entry>
<entry>Yes, I&apos;m transferring to a text device now.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> In response to Steffen pressing the &num;4 key on the keypad of his telephone for initiating the interactive communication session at the second interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a dialog thread field <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is displayed on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; at a third interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The dialog associated with the first and the second interactive session interaction events T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are displayed in the dialog thread field <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. Displaying of the dialog thread field <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; is an example of the mediated subscriber communication device reflecting a change from the voice session to the text session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Also in response to Steffen pressing the &num;4 key on the keypad of his telephone for initiating the text session, an IVR operation is performed at a fourth interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for transmitting a text session log-in information message LIM to Steffen. An example of the text session log-in message is &ldquo;Go to the website address: www.davids01.portal.com and type in the passcode &lsquo;davids422&rsquo; where prompted&rdquo;. It is contemplated that a user-provided passcode may be requested rather than a system-defined passcode being provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> After transmitting the text session log-in information message LIM, an IVR operation is performed for transmitting one or more log-in message responses (LMR) to Steffen for enabling him to respond to the text session log-in information message LIM. Examples of the log-in message responses LMR are depicted below in Table 4.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00004">
<number>4</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="21PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="133PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Press 1 for:</entry>
<entry>OK, continue with log-in.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Press 2 for:</entry>
<entry>I will talk later instead.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Press 3 for:</entry>
<entry>I need more instructions.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Press 4 for:</entry>
<entry>Repeat text session log-in information</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> Steffen moves to his computer and selects &num;4 key on the keypad of his telephone. Accordingly, the text session log-in information message LIM is repeated. At an interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, Steffen accesses the website corresponding to a website address WA in the text session log-in information message LIM and enters a passcode PC provided in the text session log-in information message. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> In response to implementing the interactive communication session via the first through fifth interactive session interaction events T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, a textual dialog interface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is displayed via a web browser <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> at a sixth interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15A</cross-reference>. The textual dialog interface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> includes a text message entry field <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, a user-defined dialog response button <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, a dialog thread field <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, a message send button <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and an end session button <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. Steffen enters a first textual message in the text entry field <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and selects the message user-defined dialog response button <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. In response to selecting the user-defined dialog response button <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, a user-defined dialog response dialog field <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> is displayed, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>B, at a seventh interactive session event T<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Steffen enters one or more user-defined dialog responses in the user-defined dialog response field <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> In response to selecting the message send button <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, the first textual message, including any user-defined dialog responses, is transmitted for being received by the telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. Also in response to selecting the message send button <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, the first textual message is displayed in the dialog thread field <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the textual dialog interface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. It is contemplated that the first textual message may be displayed with or without the user-defined dialog responses being displayed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> At a seventh interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the first textual message is displayed in the dialog thread field <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. A plurality of dialog responses DR, including any user-defined dialog responses, are displayed on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. The dialog responses DR include pre-defined dialog responses, contextual dialog responses, action-based dialog responses, and user-defined dialog responses. Examples of the dialog responses are depicted below in table 5.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00005">
<number>5</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="168PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 5</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Pre-Defined</entry>
<entry>Responses that are routinely provided, such as Yes,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>No, Hold On, Hang Up.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Contextual</entry>
<entry>Textual messages are analyzed and answers/option that</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>MAY be appropriate are presented.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>For example, if a questions starts &ldquo;what time . . . &rdquo;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>a menu option</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&ldquo;pick time&rdquo; could be offered.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Action-Based</entry>
<entry>Responses that result in a system implemented action.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>For example, a dialog response</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&ldquo;Transfer To Voice&rdquo; results in a system</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>implemented action for terminating the</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>text session</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>and placing a call to the mediated party using a</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>system-accessible phone number, or a</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>phone number provided by the mediation subscriber</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>or mediated party. In this manner, a</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>telephonic communication session is implemented.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>User-Defined</entry>
<entry>Responses that are directly supplied by the mediated</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>party. For example, the textual dialog</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>interface includes several rows of small text boxes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>into which the mediated party types</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>likely/desired &ldquo;answers&rdquo; to a question or</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>situation presented in the textual message. In this</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>manner the mediated party makes it easier for</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>the mediation subscriber to respond in a</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>direct manner.</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> In response to David selecting the dialog response &ldquo;YES&rdquo;, the dialog response &ldquo;YES&rdquo; is displayed in the dialog thread field <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the textual dialog interface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> at an eighth interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>. Steffen enters a second textual message in the text entry field <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> that he will be ending the text session and contacting David via an umnediated voice-based communication session (i.e. a telephone call). In response to selecting the send button <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, the second textual message is displayed in the dialog thread field <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. Steffen then selects the end button <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and the interactive communication session between David and Steffen is terminated after transmitting the second textual message to the telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. The operations and associated information/responses of the sixth through eighth interactive session interaction events T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-T<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> depict an embodiment of managing the interactive communication session.</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> The text-session interaction events T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-T<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> depicted in Example 3 above are based on the mediation subscriber making the request for implementing the interactive communication session. It is also contemplated herein that the mediated party may be provided with the ability for making the request for implementing the interactive communication session. In an example where the mediated party proposes makes the request for implementing the interactive communication session, an option for making the request for implementing the interactive communication session is presented to the mediated party in the mediation communication session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of presenting the mediated party with an option for requesting the interactive communication session, the option is present to the mediated party via one or more IVR system operations. In response to the mediated party requesting the interactive communication session, a follow-through action for allowing the mediation subscriber to accept the request for implementing the interactive communication session is displayed on the visual display of the mediation subscriber communication device. In response to the mediation subscriber selecting the follow-through action for accepting implementation of the interactive communication session (i.e. a reply for accepting the implementation request), implementation and facilitation of the interactive communication session is commenced according to the forth through eighth interactive session interaction event T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-T<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> Referring back to mediated communication sessions, another type of mediation session is one initiated by an outbound communication request. An embodiment of a method for facilitating a mediation session initiated by an outbound communication request is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>. The apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, illustrates an example of an apparatus capable of carrying out the method depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>. At a block <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, an outbound communication request is received by the mediation system from the mediation subscriber communication device, via one or more data packets or via a voice-based communication. The outbound communication request includes contact information such as a name, a telephone number, etc. for identifying an/or contacting the mediated party. In response to receiving the outbound communication request, a plurality of follow-through actions is prepared at a block <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight>. In other embodiments, depending on the outbound request, only one follow-through action or no follow-through action is prepared. Preparing the follow-through actions includes assessing related contextual information such as the present availability of the mediation subscriber, mediation behavior and preferences of the mediation subscriber, information in policies of the mediation subscriber, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> At a block <highlight><bold>354</bold></highlight>, the plurality of follow-through actions is communicated to the mediation subscriber from the mediations system. At a block <highlight><bold>356</bold></highlight>, a selected follow-through action is received by the mediation system from the mediation subscriber. In response to receiving the selected follow-through action, the mediated party communication device is contacted at the block <highlight><bold>358</bold></highlight>. It should be understood that the mediation system contacts the mediated party communication device. Accordingly, the mediation system engages in communication with the mediated party to determine if the mediated party is available to engage in communication with the mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> In response to the availability of the mediated party and the mediation subscriber permitting immediate communication (block <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>&prime;), the mediation system facilitates connection of the mediation subscriber communication device with that of the mediated party communication device at a block <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight>. In response to the availability of mediated party or the mediation subscriber not permitting communication immediately therebetween (block <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>&prime;), the mediation continues to a block <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> At the block <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>&Prime;, in response to the mediated party not selecting a follow-through option, the mediation system terminates its communication with the mediated party at a block <highlight><bold>362</bold></highlight>. In response to the mediated party selecting a follow-through option at the block <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>&Prime; the mediation system facilitates, block <highlight><bold>364</bold></highlight>, a mediated follow-through operation with the mediated party according to the follow-through option selected at the block <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>&Prime;. Scheduling time to talk, call forwarding, entering voice mail and the like are examples of follow-through options that may be selected at the block <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>&Prime;. At a block <highlight><bold>366</bold></highlight>, the mediation activity data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, is updated with information associated with the communication appointment. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 4 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Outbound Call Mediation </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> At a fourth mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>, David recognizes that his meeting is about to end. In reviewing the caller summary CS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, David decides that he would like for the mediation system to facilitate a return call to Sally E. To initiate such an operation, David depresses the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with an options action OA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> In response to depressing the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with the options action, an options menu OM is displayed on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at a fifth mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The options menu OM includes a plurality of option selections OS. Examples of option selections OS include make a call, return a call, make a reservation, change my availability, change my policies and change my service preferences. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> In response to choosing the &lsquo;return a call&rsquo; option selection, an attempt is made at contacting Sally via her communication device. In the event that Sally answers, the mediation system connects David with Sally. In the event that Sally is not available, a plurality of call resolutions CR is displayed on the visual display at a sixth mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The call resolutions CR provide various options when the caller is not available. Examples of call resolutions CR include schedule a call, continue to try, and quit call attempt. David uses the scroll key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to select the &lsquo;Continue to try&rsquo; call resolution and confirms this selection by depressing the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with the accept action AA. The mediation continues to contact Sally.</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> It is desirable and advantageous for a mediated follow-through operation or pending mediated commitment to be modified according to an updated context component. For example, in the case where the availability status of the mediation subscriber changes, it is desirable and advantages for in-progress mediation operations and pending mediated commitments to be dynamically adjusted as necessary. The apparatus, methods and systems disclosed herein are capable of supporting such dynamic adjustment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> The &lsquo;schedule a call&rsquo; call resolution depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is one embodiment of a call resolution for mediating a coordinated arrangement for person-to-person communication to be facilitated. In such an embodiment, the mediation system mediates an agreed upon time and/or day for the mediation subscriber and the mediated party to communicate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> depicts an embodiment of a method for facilitating a mediation session to alter a pending mediated commitment in response to one or more context components being altered. The apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, illustrates an example of an apparatus capable of carrying out the method depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>. Information may be communicated between the mediation subscriber communication device and the mediation system via data packets over a suitable network. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> At a block <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, an altered context component is received by the mediation system. The altered context component may be received from the mediation subscriber or the mediated party. At a block, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> an affected mediated commitment is identified. A revised availability status illustrates an example of the altered context component capable of affecting a mediated commitment. A revised follow-through action is determined and a follow-through communication is prepared at a block <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> and at a block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>, respectively. At a block <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>, an attempt is made at contacting the mediated party via the mediated party communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> It should be understood that one or more context components and/or mediated commitments could be affected simultaneously. Therefore, at the block <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, more than one altered context component may be received. Also, the particular revised follow-through actions included in the follow-through action summary may vary depending on the specific context components and/or mediated commitments affected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> In response to the mediated party not being contacted, a postponement message is communicated to a mediated party messaging service at a block <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, if available. Voice mail and an answering machine illustrate suitable examples of the mediated party messaging service. At a block <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> the mediation activity data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, is updated to reflect that the mediated commitment has been postponed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> In response to the mediated party being contacted, the revised follow-through communication is communicated to the mediated party communication device at a block <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight>. In response to the revised follow-through action being unacceptable to the mediated party, the method would proceed from the block <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> to the block <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, thus resulting in the mediated commitment being postponed. The method then proceeds to the block <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> where the mediation activity data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, is updated to reflect that the mediated commitment has been changed. In response to the revised follow-through action being acceptable to the mediated party, at a block <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight>, the mediated follow-through operation is performed according to the altered context component is facilitated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> In response to the mediated follow-through operation successfully producing an altered mediated commitment, the method proceeds to the block <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> where the mediation activity data set <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, is updated to reflect that the mediated commitment has been changed. In response to the mediated follow-through operation being unsuccessful at producing an altered mediated commitment, a postponement message is communicated to a mediated party at a block <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. The method then proceeds to the block <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>. The mediated party being unable to commit to a mutually acceptable time to talk illustrates an example of the mediated follow-through operation being unsuccessful. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 4 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Mediated Commitment Dynamic Updating </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> At a seventh mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>, David is still in his meeting, reviewing a pending commitment summary POS displayed on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of his wireless telephone, when he notices that his meeting has run longer than expected. The pending commitment summary PCS indicates that David has a number of pending mediated commitments that are based on his meeting being over by about 14:30 hours. David also notices that the meeting has run longer than the time specified according to his availability status, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Accordingly, David selects the control key associated with the options action OA such that the options menu OM is displayed at an eighth mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. David then uses the scroll key <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> to highlight the &lsquo;Change my availability&rsquo; options selection and confirms the selection by depressing the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with the accept action AA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> In response to selecting the choosing the &lsquo;Change my availability&rsquo; options selection OS, the availability status menu ASM is displayed on the visual display at a ninth mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. David uses the scroll key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to select the &lsquo;In meeting until . . . &rsquo; availability specifier, enters a new time for when he will be out of the meeting, and confirms the new availability status by depressing the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with the accept action AA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> In response to altering his availability status, the mediation system identifies the pending mediated commitments associated with the availability status. The mediation system then acts on behalf of David to contact the appropriate mediated parties to revise the mediated commitments according to the altered availability status. As revised mediated commitments are established, David is able to review them via the pending commitment summary PCs.</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> depicts an embodiment of a method for performing a mediation session to set-up a mediated service commitment. The apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, illustrates an example of an apparatus capable of carrying out the method depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>. Information may be communicated between the mediation subscriber communication device and the mediation system via data packets over a suitable network. At a block <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, a service mediation request is received by the mediation system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In response to receiving the service mediation request, a context is determined and a plurality of service actions is prepared at a block <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> and a block <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, respectively. In other embodiments, one or no service actions are prepared. At a block <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>, the plurality of service actions is communicated to the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> In response to receiving, at a block <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>, a selected one of the service actions from the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a mediated follow-through operation is facilitated with the service provider at a block <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>. At a block <highlight><bold>509</bold></highlight>, confirmation information, such as a confirmation code, associated with the service reservation is received from the service provider reservation system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> At a block <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, in response to completing the mediated follow-through operation, the mediated activity data set, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, is updated. Updating the mediated activity data set includes adding information associated with the mediated service request, such as a confirmation number and a telephone number of the service provider, to the data set. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> depicts an embodiment of a method for accomplishing the operation of facilitating the mediated follow-through operation, as depicted at the block <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>. At a block <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a plurality of service providers capable of providing the requested service is identified. In other embodiments, only one service provider is identified. At a block <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the identified service providers are communicated to the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. After communicating the plurality of service providers to the mediation subscriber communication device, confirmation of a selected service provider is received, at a block <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, from the mediation subscriber communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> At a block <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, a network connection is established between the service provider reservation system and the mediation system through the computer network. At a block <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>, the mediated follow-through operation is performed, thus establishing a mediated service commitment. The mediated service commitment illustrates an example of a mediated commitment, as discussed above. It is contemplated that communication between the mediation system and the service management system may be facilitated via the computer network and the voice network. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, data-based communication and voice-based communication may be used for facilitating the mediated service operation at the block <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. For example, the mediation system may complete a first portion of the mediated follow-through operation via data-based communication through the computer network and a second portion of the mediated follow-through operation via voice-based communication the through the voice network. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 5 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Service Mediation </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> David decides to make a reservation at his favorite restaurant to be sure he gets seated for dinner without too long of a wait. He was expecting to get there before the dinner crowd. However, because his meeting ran over, he thinks he may now have a hard time getting a seat. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, at a tenth mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>, David brings up the options menu OM on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of his wireless telephone <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. David uses the scroll key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to choose the &lsquo;Make a reservation&rsquo; option selection and confirms his selection by depressing the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with the accept action AA. In response to choosing the &lsquo;Make a reservation&rsquo; option selection, a service menu is on the visual display <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at an eleventh mediated session interaction event Eli. The service menu SM includes a plurality of service selections. Examples of service selections SS include arrange a taxi, arrange a hotel reservation, arrange a restaurant reservation and book a flight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> David uses the scroll key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to select the &lsquo;Arrange a restaurant reservation&rsquo; service selection and confirms the selection by depressing the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with the accept action AA. In response to choosing the &lsquo;Arrange a restaurant reservation&rsquo; service selection, an arrangement option menu AOM is displayed on the visual display at a twelfth mediated session interaction event E<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The arrangement option menu AOM includes a plurality of arrangement options AO. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> Each service selection SS has one or more corresponding context-specific arrangement options. Accordingly, the arrangement options AO displayed in response to choosing the &lsquo;arrange a restaurant reservation&rsquo; service action are specific to arranging the taxi and are based on the present availability of the mediation subscriber. Because the mediation system knows that the mediation subscriber is in a meeting, the context derived from being in a meeting until a specified time is used to add a contextual aspect to some of the arrangement options AO. In this example, in which David is in a meeting until 15:15 hours, context-specific service actions include arranging a taxi for immediately after the meeting, arrange a taxi for X minutes after the meeting arranging a restaurant reservation Y minutes after the meeting and booking a flight Z hours after the meeting. In this manner, a mediated service commitment may be acted on in a more specific fashion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> David uses the scroll key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to select the &lsquo; . . . min after meeting&rsquo; arrangement option, enters 45 minutes in the corresponding time field and confirms this selection and entry by depressing the control key <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>associated with the accept action AA. In response to confirming this selection and entry, the mediation system identifies the restaurant, contacts a service management system of the restaurant and mediates the requested reservation on David&apos;s behalf according to the arrangement option specified by David. The mediation system contacts the service management system of the restaurant, such as via the Internet or via an automated or actual voice communication, for facilitating mediation of the reservation. Information associated with the restaurant are provided manually by David, garnished from the service provider preference data set in David&apos;s profile (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) or a combination of such information input techniques. Once the reservation is confirmed by the mediation system, David is able to review it via the pending commitment summary PCS discussed in reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the systems, apparatus and methods disclosed herein provide advantageous and beneficial results relative to conventional mediation solutions. Such embodiments use all appropriate and available resources to interact with a mediated party. It does not depend on the mediated party being a mediation subscriber or having a smart phone. The device independent nature, with respect to the mediate party, places few restrictions on the breadth of communication. Furthermore, mediation is carried out in a very similar manner, as would mediation done personally by the mediation subscriber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> The methods disclosed herein negotiate with mediated parties with the ultimate goal of connecting the two parties. Connecting the two parties may be via a scheduled telephone call or a mediated service commitment such as a taxi reservation. The objective of the mediation system is to continually and dynamically act on the behalf of the mediation subscriber when the mediation subscriber cannot personally participate in a dynamic, personal and time-consuming manner. To this end, one aspect is the ability to identify and analyze contextual information associated with the mediation subscriber and the mediated party. Accordingly, advantageous and beneficial results are achieved as a result of separating the availability individuals from the availability of their respective communication devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> Some types of the mediation subscriber communications devices, such as smart phones, include data processing capabilities. For example, some smart phones are capable of running JAVA-based programs. It is contemplated that such data processing capabilities will permit at least a portion of the operations and steps of the methods disclosed herein to be performed by the mediation subscriber communication device acting as the mediation system rather than solely by a separate mediation system. For example, in some instances, it may be desirable and advantageous for all or some menu follow-through actions to be prepared by the mediation subscriber communication device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> The various functions and components in the present application may be implemented using an information handling machine such as a data processor, or a plurality of data processing devices. Such a data processor may be a microprocessor, microcontroller, microcomputer, digital signal processor, state machine, logic circuitry, and/or any device that manipulates digital information based on operational instruction, or in a predefined manner. Generally, the various functions, and systems represented by block diagrams herein are readily implemented by one of ordinary skill in the art using one or more of the implementation techniques listed herein. When a data processor for issuing instructions is used, the instructions may be stored in memory. Such a memory may be a single memory device or a plurality of memory devices. Such a memory device may be read-only memory device, random access memory device, magnetic tape memory, floppy disk memory, hard drive memory, external tape, and/or any device that stores digital information. Note that when the data processor implements one or more of its functions via a state machine or logic circuitry, the memory storing the corresponding instructions may be embedded within the circuitry that includes a state machine and/or logic circuitry, or it may be unnecessary because the function is performed using combinational logic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> Such an information handling machine may be a system, or part of a system, such as a computer, a personal digital assistant (PDA), a hand held computing device, a cable set-top box, an Internet capable device, such as a cellular phone, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> In the preceding detailed description, reference has been made to the accompanying drawings that form a part hereof, and in which are shown by way of illustration specific embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. These embodiments and certain variants thereof, have been described in sufficient detail to enable those skilled in the art to practice the invention. It is to be understood that other suitable embodiments may be utilized and that logical, mechanical, chemical and electrical changes may be made without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention. For example, functional blocks shown in the figures could be further combined or divided in any manner without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention. To avoid unnecessary detail, the description may omit certain information known to those skilled in the art. The preceding detailed description is, therefore, not intended to be limited to the specific forms set forth herein, but on the contrary, it is intended to cover such alternatives, modifications, and equivalents, as can be reasonably included within the spirit and scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method, comprising: 
<claim-text>facilitating a mediated communication session between a first communication device and a second communication device, wherein facilitating the mediated communication session includes receiving a request for implementing an interactive communication session; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>implementing the interactive communication session between the first communication device and a third communication device in response to receiving the reply for accepting the request. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>receiving the request for implementing includes receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the reply for accepting the request includes receiving the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device includes receiving the request for implementing from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein receiving the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device includes receiving the reply for accepting the request from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>facilitating the mediated communication session includes facilitating a voice-based mediated communication session; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>implementing the interactive communication session includes implementing a text-based interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein facilitating the voice-based mediated communication session includes: 
<claim-text>facilitating text-based communication between a mediation system and the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>facilitating voice-based communication between the mediation system and the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>receiving the request for implementing includes receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the reply for accepting the request includes receiving the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>receiving the request for implementing includes receiving the request for implementing from the second communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the reply for accepting the request includes receiving the reply for accepting the request from the first communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein implementing the interactive communication session includes: 
<claim-text>preparing log-in information for the interactive communication session; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting said log-in information to the second communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving said log-in information from the third communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>authenticating said log-in information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein preparing said log-in information includes generating a passcode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>preparing generating said passcode includes generating a chronologically referenced passcode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>authenticating said log-in information includes determining an elapsed period of time from when the chronologically referenced passcode was generated and verifying that the elapsed period of time is less than a prescribed validation period for which the passcode is valid. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein generating a chronologically referenced passcode includes generating a time-stamped passcode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>receiving the request for implementing includes receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device wherein the first communication device is a mediated party communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>preparing said log-in information includes receiving a mediated party-specified passcode from the first communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>receiving the request for implementing includes receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device wherein the first communication device is a mediation subscriber communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>preparing said log-in information includes receiving a mediation subscriber-specified passcode from the first communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein preparing said log-in information further includes generating an interactive communication session log-in address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein generating the interactive communication session log-in address includes generating a unique communication network log-in address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein generating the unique communication network log-in address includes generating a mediation subscriber specific Internet website address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein implementing the interactive communication session further includes transmitting a text session authorization notification to an interactive communication session system after authenticating said log-in information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>invalidating the passcode after a prescribed validation period elapses. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>invalidating the passcode after implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>managing the interactive communication session between the first communication device and the third communication device after performing an operation for implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>receiving an interactive communication session authorization notification in response to implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein managing the interactive communication session includes: 
<claim-text>displaying a textual dialog interface on a visual display of the third communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a dialog response on a visual display of the first communication device </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the textual dialog interface includes displaying a text entry field for enabling a text message to be composed and a dialog thread field for displaying textual dialog between the first and the third communication devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the dialog response includes displaying a pre-defined dialog response. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the predefined dialog response includes displaying a dialog response for responding in the affirmative manner to a textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the predefined dialog response includes displaying a dialog response for responding in a negative manner to a textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the predefined dialog response includes displaying a dialog response for responding that a response to the textual message will be momentarily delayed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the dialog response includes displaying a contextual response message associated with a context of a textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the contextual response message includes analyzing at least a portion of the textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the dialog response includes displaying an action-based response for initiating a system-implemented action. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the action-based response includes displaying a response for initiating a transfer from the interactive communication session to a telephonic communication session. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A method, comprising: 
<claim-text>facilitating a voice-based mediated communication session between a first communication device and a second communication device, wherein facilitating the mediated communication session includes receiving a request for implementing a text-based interactive communication session from the first communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a reply for accepting the request from the second communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>implementing the text-based interactive communication session between the first communication device and a third communication device in response to receiving the reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>managing the interactive communication session between the first communication device and the third communication device after performing an operation for implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device includes receiving the request for implementing from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein receiving the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device includes receiving the reply for accepting the request from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein facilitating the voice-based mediated communication session includes: 
<claim-text>facilitating text-based communication between a mediation system and the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>facilitating voice-based communication between the mediation system and the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein implementing the interactive communication session includes: 
<claim-text>generating a passcode and an interactive communication session log-in address for the interactive communication session; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the passcode and the interactive communication session log-in address to the second communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving said passcode from the third communication device; and authenticating said passcode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>preparing generating said passcode includes generating a time-stamped passcode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>authenticating said passcode includes determining an elapsed period of time from when the time-stamped passcode was generated and verifying that the elapsed period of time is less than a prescribed validation period for which the time-stamped passcode is valid. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein generating the interactive communication session log-in address includes generating a unique communication network log-in address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein generating the unique communication network log-in address includes generating a mediation subscriber specific Internet website address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein managing the interactive communication session includes: 
<claim-text>displaying a textual dialog interface on a visual display of the third communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying a dialog response on a visual display of the first communication device </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the textual dialog interface includes displaying a text entry field for enabling a text message to be composed and a dialog thread field for displaying textual dialog between the first and the third communication devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the dialog response includes displaying a pre-defined dialog response. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the predefined dialog response includes selecting the predefined dialog response from a group of predefined dialog responses including a dialog response for responding in the affirmative manner to a textual message, a dialog response for responding in a negative manner to a textual message, and a dialog response for responding that a response to the textual message will be momentarily delayed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the dialog response includes analyzing at least a portion of a textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> wherein displaying the dialog response includes displaying a response for initiating a transfer from the interactive communication session to a telephonic communication session. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. A data processor program product, comprising: 
<claim-text>a data processor program processable by at lease one data processor of a communication apparatus; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an apparatus from which the data processor program is accessible by said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the data processor program being capable of enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to: 
<claim-text>facilitate a mediated communication session between a first communication device and a second communication device, wherein facilitating the mediated communication session includes receiving a request for implementing an interactive communication session; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receive a reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>implement the interactive communication session between the first communication device and a third communication device in response to receiving the reply for accepting the request. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing from the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing from the first communication device includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to facilitate the mediated communication session includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to facilitate a voice-based mediated communication session; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to implement the interactive communication session includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to implement a text-based interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to facilitate the voice-based mediated communication session includes: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to facilitate text-based communication between a mediation system and the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to facilitate voice-based communication between the mediation system and the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing includes receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request includes receiving the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing from the second communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request from the first communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to implement the interactive communication session includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to: 
<claim-text>prepare log-in information for the interactive communication session; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmit said log-in information to the second communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receive said log-in information from the third communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>authenticate said log-in information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to prepare said log-in information includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a passcode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to prepare generating said passcode includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a chronologically referenced passcode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to authenticate said log-in information includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to determine an elapsed period of time from when the chronologically referenced passcode was generated and to verify that the elapsed period of time is less than a prescribed validation period for which the passcode is valid. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 57</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a chronologically referenced passcode includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a time-stamped passcode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing from the first communication device wherein the first communication device is a mediated party communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to prepare said log-in information includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive a mediated party-specified passcode from the first communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing from the first communication device wherein the first communication device is a mediation subscriber communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to prepare said log-in information includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive a mediation subscriber-specified passcode from the first communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one data processor is further capable of enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate an interactive communication session log-in address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 61</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate the interactive communication session log-in address includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a unique communication network log-in address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate the unique communication network log-in address includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a mediation subscriber specific Internet website address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to implement the interactive communication session further includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to transmit a text session authorization notification to an interactive communication session system after authenticating said log-in information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one data processor program is further capable of enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to: 
<claim-text>invalidate the passcode after a prescribed validation period elapses. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one data processor program is further capable of enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to: 
<claim-text>invalidate the passcode after implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00067">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one data processor program is further capable of enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to: 
<claim-text>manage the interactive communication session between the first communication device and the third communication device after performing an operation for implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00068">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 67</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one data processor program is further capable of enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to: 
<claim-text>receive an interactive communication session authorization notification in response to implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00069">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 67</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to manage the interactive communication session includes: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a textual dialog interface on a visual display of the third communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a dialog response on a visual display of the first communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00070">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 69</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the textual dialog interface includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a text entry field for enabling a text message to be composed and a dialog thread field for displaying textual dialog between the first and the third communication devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00071">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 69</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a pre-defined dialog response. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00072">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 71</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the predefined dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a dialog response for responding in the affirmative manner to a textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00073">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 71</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the predefined dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a dialog response for responding in a negative manner to a textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00074">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 71</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the predefined dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a dialog response for responding that a response to the textual message will be momentarily delayed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00075">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 69</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a contextual response message associated with a context of a textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00076">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 75</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the contextual response message includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to analyze at least a portion of the textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00077">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 69</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display an action-based response for initiating a system-implemented action. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00078">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 77</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the action-based response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a response for initiating a transfer from the interactive communication session to a telephonic communication session. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00079">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight>. A data processor program product, comprising: 
<claim-text>facilitating a voice-based mediated communication session between a first communication device and a second communication device, wherein facilitating the mediated communication session includes receiving a request for implementing a text-based interactive communication session from the first communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a reply for accepting the request from the second communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>implementing the text-based interactive communication session between the first communication device and a third communication device in response to receiving the reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>managing the interactive communication session between the first communication device and the third communication device after performing an operation for implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00080">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing from the first communication device includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the request for implementing from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00081">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to receive the reply for accepting the request from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00082">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to facilitate the voice-based mediated communication session includes: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to facilitate text-based communication between a mediation system and the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to facilitate voice-based communication between the mediation system and the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00083">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to implement the interactive communication session includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to: 
<claim-text>generate a passcode and an interactive communication session log-in address for the interactive communication session; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmit the passcode and the interactive communication session log-in address to the second communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receive said passcode from the third communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>authenticate said passcode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00084">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 83</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate said passcode includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a time-stamped passcode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to authenticate said passcode includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to determine an elapsed period of time from when the time-stamped passcode was generated and to verify that the elapsed period of time is less than a prescribed validation period for which the time-stamped passcode is valid. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00085">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 83</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate the interactive communication session log-in address includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a unique communication network log-in address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00086">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 85</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate the unique communication network log-in address includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to generate a mediation subscriber specific Internet website address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00087">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to manage the interactive communication session includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to: 
<claim-text>display a textual dialog interface on a visual display of the third communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>display a dialog response on a visual display of the first communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00088">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 87</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the textual dialog interface includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a text entry field for enabling a text message to be composed and a dialog thread field for displaying textual dialog between the first and the third communication devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00089">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 97</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a pre-defined dialog response. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00090">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 89</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the predefined dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to select the predefined dialog response from a group of predefined dialog responses including a dialog response for responding in the affirmative manner to a textual message, a dialog response for responding in a negative manner to a textual message, and a dialog response for responding that a response to the textual message will be momentarily delayed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00091">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 87</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to analyze at least a portion of a textual message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00092">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. The data processor program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 87</dependent-claim-reference> wherein enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display the dialog response includes enabling said at least one data processor of the communication apparatus to display a response for initiating a transfer from the interactive communication session to a telephonic communication session. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00093">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight>. A communication apparatus including at least one communication session system, said at least one communication system capable of: 
<claim-text>facilitating a mediated communication session between a first communication device and a second communication device, wherein facilitating the mediated communication session includes receiving a request for implementing an interactive communication session between the first communication device and a third communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>implementing the interactive communication session in response to receiving the reply for accepting the request. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00094">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. The communication apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 93</dependent-claim-reference> comprising a mediation system capable of: 
<claim-text>facilitating the mediated communication session; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>implementing the interactive communication system. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00095">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>. The communication apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 93</dependent-claim-reference> comprising a mediation system and an interactive communication session system: 
<claim-text>wherein the mediation system is capable of: 
<claim-text>facilitating the mediated communication session; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the interactive communication session system is capable of: 
<claim-text>implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00096">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. The communication apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 93</dependent-claim-reference> comprising an integrated communication management system, wherein the integrated communication management system is capable of: 
<claim-text>facilitating the mediated communication session; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00097">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>. The communication apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 96</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the integrated communication management system includes: 
<claim-text>a mediated communication portion capable of: 
<claim-text>facilitating the mediated communication session; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the reply for accepting the request; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interactive communication portion capable of: 
<claim-text>implementing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00098">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. The communication apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 97</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the integrated communication management system is further capable of: 
<claim-text>managing the interactive communication session. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00099">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. The communication apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 93</dependent-claim-reference> comprising a mediation system, wherein the mediation system is capable of: 
<claim-text>receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00100">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The communication apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 99</dependent-claim-reference> wherein receiving the request for implementing from the first communication device includes receiving the request for implementing from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00101">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The communication apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 99</dependent-claim-reference> wherein receiving the reply for accepting the request from the second communication device includes receiving the reply for accepting the request from a wireless communication device capable of transmitting and receiving data packets.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00019">
<image id="EMI-D00019" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00020">
<image id="EMI-D00020" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00021">
<image id="EMI-D00021" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00022">
<image id="EMI-D00022" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00023">
<image id="EMI-D00023" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00024">
<image id="EMI-D00024" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00025">
<image id="EMI-D00025" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00026">
<image id="EMI-D00026" file="US20030005126A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
