<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004538A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004538A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004538A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004538A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004538A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004538A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004538A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004538A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004538</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10146273</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020515</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61M029/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>606</class>
<subclass>200000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Retrieval device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60292168</doc-number>
<document-date>20010518</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dean</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Secrest</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Concord</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Marlin</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Younker</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>West Palm Beach</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>WATTS, HOFFMANN,</name-1>
<name-2>FISHER &amp; HEINKE CO., L.P.A.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Ste. 1750</address-1>
<address-2>1100 Superior Ave.</address-2>
<city>Cleveland</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>44114</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An endoscopic surgical device for retrieving severed tissue or foreign bodies from within a subject is disclosed. The device comprises a support unit and a tissue retrieving net system. The net system is carried by the support unit and may be inserted into the subject through an orifice or small incision and operated to retrieve tissue that has been severed by a conventional method. The net system comprises a net, a net actuator, a net deployment and retrieval assembly for transmitting motion between the net and its actuator. The net system further comprises at least one net connector disposed such that only one connector is within an articulation zone, defined by locations of severe bending of the device during operation. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This non-provisional application claims benefit of U.S. Patent Provisional Application Serial No. 60/292,168, entitled &ldquo;Retrieval Device,&rdquo; filed on May 18, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to surgical devices and more particularly to endoscopic retrieval devices constructed for retrieving relatively small pieces of sample tissue or foreign bodies from a human subject through orifices or small incisions. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Snares, baskets, and graspers are in widespread use for severing capturing and retrieving tissue specimens and foreign bodies from within subjects. The devices are used in human and animal subjects, in laparoscopic surgeries and other procedures where access within a subject is only possible via a small opening. One exemplary use is for cutting off and retrieving intestinal polyps where a wire snare, passed through an colonoscope instrument channel, encircles and is tightened about an intestinal polyp to sever the polyp. The severed polyp is retrieved in a net inserted through the instrument channel. The net is manipulated to enclose the polyp and then withdrawn with the instrument so that the tissue architecture remains undisturbed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In this procedure, as well as others, the net and snare must be quite compact in order to pass into the subject through the instrument channel, or other passage. Prior art proposals have employed snares supported within plastic tubes that were snaked into the subject to locate the snare where desired. The snare was then deployed from its tube, manipulated to cut off the polyp and retrieved into the tube for removal from the subject. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A net, collapsed within another tube, was introduced through the instrument channel, etc., for removing the polyp. When near a target polyp, the net was deployed, like the snare, and manipulated to net the polyp. The net was then closed sufficiently to secure the polyp and withdrawn from the subject. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,643,283 to Younker, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety, discloses a device for retrieving an object from within a subject. The device comprises a shaft and a compressible pouch for receiving the object positioned adjacent a distal end of the shaft. The pouch includes a mouth which can be opened and closed. The pouch is retained, in proximity to the distal end of the shaft, on a cable loop by a slidable tether. The net is free to slide on the cable loop to form a pouch at the distal end of the shaft. The tether is fixed at a second location near the proximal end of the shaft, and in one embodiment, is tied off to a ring and secured with heat shrink tubing. When the targeted foreign object is within the pouch, a clinician disengages the ring portion of the handle to close the net around the object. The clinician then removes the device from the patient and unloads the object from the net. The clinician then places the ring on a post, in order to pack the pouch into the distal end of the shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In operation of a commercial embodiment of U.S. Pat. No. 5,643,283, several problematic issues have surfaced. Clinicians have experienced difficulty in understanding the operation of the tether, in particular, the interaction of the ring and post. The ring is to be used to pull the net inside the shaft only when an object is not within the net. In preparation to capture an object, the ring should be disengaged to release the net. The net is then slid over the targeted object and the net is closed. At this point, proper operation would involve merely removing the device from the patient. However, some clinicians when operating the device try to further pull the net inside the shaft when the net is bundled up at distal end of cable loop. This will cause the net to jam, or in some cases, damages the tubing. The occasional improper operation of the device sometimes causes permanent malfunction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The commercial embodiment discussed above also adds undesirable expense to the product. Specifically, the full length tether and heat shrink operation add material cost and labor assembly cost to the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a new and improved retrieval device that is so constructed and arranged that net movement during deployment and retrieval is not prohibitively restricted. Secure net attachment is assured and that provides for convenient net packing in the introducer passage. The device provides a convenient and economical method of sample retrieval during endoscopic procedures. The new retrieval device is easy assemble, manufactured at a reduced cost, and easier to use by the end consumer. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one illustrated embodiment of the present invention an endoscopic surgical device for retrieving severed tissue from within a human subject is provided. The device includes a support unit and a tissue retrieving net system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The support unit includes a body and an elongated introducer member. The body defines a first passage therethrough. The introducer has a first end section proximal and fixed with respect to the body and a second end section remote from the body. The introducer member further defines a second passage aligned with the first passage and opening at the second end section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The tissue retrieving net system includes a net, a net deployment and retrieval assembly and a net actuator system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The net includes a wire-like resilient loop and a net element having a mouth section slidably disposed on the loop and a tissue receiving pouch section. The loop terminates with two relatively parallel loop cables. The net is disposed adjacent the second end for deployment and retraction through the second passage opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The net deployment and retrieval assembly extends substantially through the first and second passages and connects to the net. The assembly further includes a motion transmitting member extending in the second passage to the loop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The net actuator unit includes a first handle fixed with respect to the body and a second handle fixed with respect to the motion transmitting member and movable relative to the first handle. The act of shifting the second handle relative to the first handle shifts the net into and out of the second passage opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The introducer member second passage has a diameter substantially smaller than the width of the loop as deployed. The member engages the loop at the second end section opening and resiliently collapses and elongates the loop as the net is retracted and moves into the introducer member passage. The loop resiliently returns to its uncollapsed configuration as it is deployed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the net system includes at least one connector adapted to fasten each loop cable. The ends of the net element are secured to the motion transmitting member on the proximal side of the at least one connector with respect to the support unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In a second embodiment, the net system further includes a first connector, a second net connector proximal to the second passage opening, and an intermediate portion defined by an axial space on the loop cables between the first connector and the second connector. The first connector and the second connector are adapted to fasten each loop cable. Ends of the net element are secured to the loop within the intermediate loop portion between the first connector and the second connector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The deployment and retrieval assembly may include a thin, flexible wire-like motion transmitting member between the net actuator unit and the loop. The motion transmitting member extends within an introducer guide passage which closely surrounds the motion transmitting member and constrains the member for translational longitudinal motion within the passage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The first connector may be disposed at least 6 inches from the second connector, such that only one connector is within an articulation zone during deployment of the net element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The ends of the net element may be secured to the motion transmitting member adjacent a proximal shoulder of the connector with respect to the support unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The present invention offers advantages over devices available in the prior art. In a second embodiment, the net is fixed distally and proximally by the use of a first and second connector. The connectors are sufficiently spaced apart to provide secure net attachment without the use of additional tether mechanisms. The connectors are positioned such that only one may be within an articulation zone of the endoscope at a time, permitting ease of net deployment in a variety of geometric operating configurations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In a first embodiment, only one connector is used to secure the proximal side of the net. This technique decreases the amount of cable loop length within the articulation zone. The reduction in cable loop length effectively reduces the amount of rigid material within the articulation zone of the endoscope at a time, further permitting ease of net deployment in a variety of geometric operating configurations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The device is also easier to assemble and less expensive to manufacture than certain conventional designs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Further features and advantages of the invention will become apparent from the following detailed description made with reference to the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an elevational view of a surgical device constructed according to one embodiment of the present invention, illustrated with the net element deployed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, illustrated with the net element retracted; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an enlarged fragmentary view of a part of the device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, showing detail of the introducer member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a enlarged fragmentary view of part of the device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, with the device show as positioned in a sample configuration within a subject; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an enlarged fragmentary view of part of a surgical device constructed according to a second embodiment of the present invention, showing detail of the introducer member; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a enlarged fragmentary view of part of the device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, with the device show as positioned in a sample configuration within a subject.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BEST MODE CONTEMPLATED FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> An endoscopic surgical device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for retrieving severed tissue and or foreign bodies from within a subject is illustrated by the drawings. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, in one embodiment, the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a support unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a tissue retrieving net system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The net system is carried by the unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and is so constructed and arranged that it may be inserted into the subject through an orifice or small incision and operated to retrieve a tissue sample previously detached from the subject by a conventional method, e.g., a snare/cautery system. Accordingly, the net system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> comprises a net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a net actuator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and a net deployment and retrieval assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> for transmitting motion between the net and its actuator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comprises a net element <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and a net loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and a distal <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and proximal <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> tie off suture that secures the net. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be used with any suitable or conventional endoscopic or laparascopic surgical equipment. For purposes of this disclosure the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is described in the context of use with an endoscope/colonoscope/sigmoidoscope type apparatus (not illustrated), of conventional or suitable construction. The scope is provided with an elongated body having a controllably flexible projecting end re-ion. Surgical instruments, such as the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, may be introduced through an instrument channel, which extends through the scope body, for retrieving tissue targeted by the surgeon manipulating the scope. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The support unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> supports the net system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> so that the net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be inserted through the scope instrument channel by a surgeon. The support unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprises a body <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> defining a passage and an elongated introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> having a first end section <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> proximal and fixed with respect to the body <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a second end section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> remote from the body. The introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is tubular and aligned with the body passage for receiving the net system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The illustrated introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is a smooth, supple member capable of being snaked through the scope instrument channel into the subject and readily flexed into any shape required as the scope body is flexed by the surgeon. In the illustrated embodiment, the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is a generally cylindrical, small diameter tube formed of non-reactive low friction plastic material, such as polytetrafluouroethylene. The first end section <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is fixed to the body <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> while the second end section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> houses the net for individual deployment and retrieval. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The net actuator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is adapted for reciprocating the deployment and retrieval assembly in the body and introducer to operate the net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The actuator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> comprises a first handle <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> fixed with respect to the body <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and a second handle <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> attached to the deployment and retrieval assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and movable with respect to the handle <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The second handle <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is fixed to the assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and mounted on the handle <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> between its ends for longitudinal sliding movement. The second handle comprises a dual finger ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> slidable on the handle <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The handles <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> as illustrated are formed from molded plastic materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The deployment and retrieval assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is constructed and arranged to transmit considerable deployment and retractive forces to the net while enabling the scope body to be freely manipulated and flexed to position the net where desired. The assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> comprises a link comprises a first link section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and a second link section <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> connected to the actuator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for transmitting compressive and tensile forces between the handle <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and a bore <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The bore <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is disposed within the center of the body <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The link <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> transmits relatively substantial compressive forces without bending or breaking. The illustrated first link section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is formed from hypodermic needle stock, i.e., it is a cylindrical stainless steel tube. The second link section <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> as illustrated is a multi-strand cable. The first link section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> joins the second link section <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> as the link exits the body <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> extends from the body <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and within the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> so that it must flex with the introducer yet transmit compressive and tensile forces. The illustrated link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is closely surrounded by the body passage of the introducer passage <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is relatively stiff compared to the supple introducer. When transmitting compressive forces, the link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is resiliently deformed to bow against the introducer wall. The link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> has good compressive and tensile strength and is somewhat resiliently bendable. The link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> will bend appreciably without yielding and kinking. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> A first connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and a second connector <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> fix the loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in two locations with respect to the net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The proximal side of the net is tied off at a location <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> between the loop cables. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> tether <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is used to tie off the proximal side of the net. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> This tether is shorter than conventional tethers that travel the full length of the introducer. No further tethering system is required, although additional net mounting techniques may be employed in the practice of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the first connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> joins the link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and the loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> together structurally. The illustrated connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is a short tube crimped to both ends of the loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and to the second link section <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The illustrated connector tube is crimped about the loop and link to form a cross sectional shape, which is capable of rotating within the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The illustrated connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is formed from hypodermic needle stock, like the first link section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The second connector <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> further joins opposing portions on the net loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> at a location proximal to the net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with respect to the first connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment, the space between the two loop cables is utilized to fix the net element <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> with respect to the link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. An intermediate region R, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, axially between the first connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and the second connector <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> within the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may be used. In an exemplary embodiment, the proximal side of the net element <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> with respect to the support system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is fixed to the net loops <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> at a convenient location <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. Suture material, or another known suitable method, may be used to tie the net to the loop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is deployed from the introducer second end <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and manipulated by the surgeon to net severed tissue and secure the tissue for retrieval from the subject. The net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be deployed after a snare or similar technique has severed the target tissue. The net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comprises a pouch-like net element <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> slidably supported on the loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The illustrated net loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is formed from a loop of fine wire constructed and arranged to cooperate with the introducer to deploy and retract the net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The illustrated loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a stiff, resilient flexible wire having its respective ends crimped in place in two locations by the first and second connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. When the net is deployed from the end of the introducer, the loop resiliently expands to a relaxed condition where the loop width is substantially greater than the introducer diameter. The deployed snare is guided to a position where it receives a target polyp or other tissue. The net is retracted by the surgeon. As the net is retracted into the introducer second end <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> the loop resiliently bears against the introducer wall so the loop resiliently collapses, narrowing the loop portion projecting from the introducer. Tissue or another object captured within the net element <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is progressively constricted by the elastic nature of the net, allowing for a wide range of sized objects to fit inside the net without compromising the architecture preservation or the security of the object, as the net is being drawn toward the distal end of the introducer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The net element <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is an extremely light pouch-like structure having the net loop wire extending through the mesh about its periphery to form a net mouth slidably supported on the loop and a depending pouch. The net fibers are quite fine, yet sufficiently strong that the net element may slide along the loop wire in the direction away from the connectors <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to enclose tissue within the pouch as the net is retrieved and/or to gather the entire net at the distal net loop end when the net loop has been retrieved. The net has minimal bulk so that when an empty net is retrieved, it easily moves completely into the introducer passage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The illustrated net is formed from 100% nylon fibers having strand diameters of from about 0.0125 mm-0.04 mm. The fibers are woven in a diamond mesh pattern with the mesh strands spaced from 1 mm-3 mm and their intersections fixedly secured together. The illustrated netting material is substantially like that of a fine mesh hair net. The net is formed by cutting about a square, circular or elliptical section of the net, trimming or otherwise finishing the edges and threading the loop wire through the peripheral mesh elements. The cut net section size is selected sufficiently larger than the net loop area to assure that a pouch-like, tissue receiving portion suspends from the net mouth, but not too large to create undesirable bulk and difficulty packing the net when pulling it inside the shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Attempting to fully retrieve a tissue containing net into the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can result in tissue loss by forcing the tissue through the net. The net fibers are fine and strong so they may cut the tissue or they may be broken, either of which alternative is undesirable. A net actuator thumb ring may be provided with a tag (not illustrated) warning the surgeon not to continue retrieving the net against unusual resistance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The present invention resolves problems faced by surgeons and nurses working with some prior art designs. Nurses and doctors have experienced difficulty in understanding the operation of the tether, specifically the interaction of the ring and post. Therefore, occasionally the device is operated incorrectly causing malfunction. The present design allows a nurse to pull back on the handle to conveniently pack the net inside the introducer passage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Further, often a surgeon is required to manipulate the endoscope into difficult to access internal areas. Certain procedures require bending or twisting the endoscope. The area of the endoscope that is twisted or bent is called the articulation zone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Some net devices have featured multiple connector designs in which the connectors are spaced somewhat adjacently with the second end section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. In these designs, the multiple connectors on the net devices have resisted bending of the scope. Moreover, the friction created has made deployment of the net difficult once the scope has been desirably positioned by the surgeon. One advantage of the present invention is increased freedom of movement, and ease of net deployment, within the articulation zone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> During operation of the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the surgeon experiences an increased ease of use over prior art designs. In the illustrated embodiment, the first connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is axially disposed a distance from the second connector <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, such that only one connector is within the articulation zone (bounded by A<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>,A<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), defined along the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> longitudinal axis, during deployment of the net element. In the illustrated system, the first connector <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is disposed at least six inches from the second connector <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The articulation zone defines the axial portion of the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> within a substantially non-linear position. The articulation zone typically includes bends of greater than 30&deg; and can exceed 200&deg; at a radius of 0.75 inches or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> portion of the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated as positioned in a probable configuration within a subject. During operation of the scope, a surgeon may manipulate the second end section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the introducer into a severe articulated position. At times, the second end section may be bent up to 180&deg;, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Deployment of the net <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in this and similar positions is difficult when the connectors <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> are both within the articulation zone. The combined kinetic frictional force of each connector against the inside of the introducer passage would otherwise make deployment of the net difficult. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the surgeon more easily deploys the net in a variety of positions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> A second embodiment of the present invention is illustrated by the drawings. A part of an endoscopic surgical device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for retrieving severed tissue and or foreign bodies from within a subject is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. In this illustrated design, the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a support unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and net actuator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> as previously described. However, an alternative construction of a net deployment and retrieval assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is utilized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated design, the net deployment and retrieval assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> uses a single connector. Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the connector <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> joins the link <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and the loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> together structurally. The illustrated connector <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> is a short tube crimped to both ends of the loop <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and to the second link section <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The illustrated connector tube is crimped about the loop and link to form a cross sectional shape, which is capable of rotating within the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The illustrated connector <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> is formed from hypodermic needle stock, like the first link section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> One goal of the design is to reduce the amount of rigid material within the articulation zone. During operation of the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the surgeon experiences an increased ease of use over prior art designs. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the length of rigid material within the articulation zone (bounded by A<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>,A<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), defined along the introducer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> longitudinal axis, is minimized during operation of the net element. The reduction in rigid material results from reducing the length of loop cable <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> within the articulation zone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the proximal side of the net element <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> with respect to the support system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is fixed to the net loops <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> at a convenient location <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight>. Suture material, or another known suitable method, may be used to tie the net to the loop. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> tether <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is used to tie off the proximal side of the net. This tether is shorter than conventional tethers that travel the full length of the introducer. The tether <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be tied off adjacent the shoulder of the connector <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>. As shown, the tether has a diameter not greater than the thickness of the connector shoulder. No further tethering system is required, although additional net mounting techniques may be employed in the practice of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> While two embodiments of the invention has been illustrated and described in considerable detail, the present invention is not to be considered limited to the precise constructions disclosed. Various adaptations, modifications and uses of the invention may occur to those skilled in the arts to which the invention relates. It is the intention to cover all such adaptations, modifications and uses falling within the scope or spirit of the annexed claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">Having described my invention I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An endoscopic surgical device for retrieving severed tissue or foreign bodies from within a human body, the device comprising: 
<claim-text>a. a support unit comprising: 
<claim-text>i. a body defining a first passage therethrough; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. an elongated introducer member having a first end section proximal and fixed with respect to said body and a second end section remote from the body, the introducer member defining a second passage aligned with the first passage and opening at said second end section; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>b. a tissue retrieving net system comprising: 
<claim-text>i. a net comprising a wire-like resilient loop and a net element having a mouth section slidably disposed on the loop and a tissue receiving pouch section, said loop terminating with two relatively parallel loop cables, said net disposed adjacent said second end for deployment and retraction through said second passage opening; </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. a net deployment and retrieval assembly extending substantially through said first and second passages and connected to the net, said assembly comprising a motion transmitting member extending in said second passage to said loop; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>iii. a net actuator unit comprising a first handle fixed with respect to said body and a second handle fixed with respect to said motion transmitting member and movable relative to said first handle so that shifting the second handle relative to said first handle shifts said net into and out of said second passage opening; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>c. said introducer member second passage having a diametrical extent substantially smaller than the width of said loop as deployed, said member engaging said loop at said second end section opening and resiliently collapsing and elongating said loop as said net is retracted and moves into said introducer member passage, said loop resiliently returning to its uncollapsed configuration as it is deployed; </claim-text>
<claim-text>d. said net system further comprising a first connector, a second net connector proximal to second passage opening, and an intermediate portion defined by an axial space on the loop cables between the first connector and the second connector, wherein the first connector and the second connector are adapted to fasten each loop cable, and ends of said net element are secured to the loop within the intermediate loop portion between the first connector and the second connector. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The device claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said deployment and retrieval assembly comprises a thin, flexible wire-like motion transmitting member between the net actuator unit and the loop, said motion transmitting member extending within an introducer guide passage, said introducer guide passage closely surrounding said motion transmitting member and constraining said member for translational longitudinal motion within said passage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The device claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first connector is disposed at least 6 inches from said second connector, such that only one connector is within an articulation zone during deployment of the net element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An endoscopic surgical device for retrieving severed tissue or foreign bodies from within a human body, the device comprising: 
<claim-text>a. a support unit comprising: 
<claim-text>i. a body defining a first passage therethrough; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. an elongated introducer member having a first end section proximal and fixed with respect to said body and a second end section remote from the body, the introducer member defining a second passage aligned with the first passage and opening at said second end section; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>b. a tissue retrieving net system comprising: 
<claim-text>i. a net comprising a wire-like resilient loop and a net element having a mouth section slidably disposed on the loop and a tissue receiving pouch section, said loop terminating with two relatively parallel loop cables, said net disposed adjacent said second end for deployment and retraction through said second passage opening; </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. a net deployment and retrieval assembly extending substantially through said first and second passages and connected to the net, said assembly comprising a motion transmitting member extending in said second passage to said loop; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>iii. a net actuator unit comprising a first handle fixed with respect to said body and a second handle fixed with respect to said motion transmitting member and movable relative to said first handle so that shifting the second handle relative to said first handle shifts said net into and out of said second passage opening; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>c. said introducer member second passage having a diametrical extent substantially smaller than the width of said loop as deployed, said member engaging said loop at said second end section opening and resiliently collapsing and elongating said loop as said net is retracted and moves into said introducer member passage, said loop resiliently returning to its uncollapsed configuration as it is deployed; </claim-text>
<claim-text>d. said net system further comprising a connector, wherein the connector is adapted to fasten each loop cable, and ends of said net element are secured to the motion transmitting member on the proximal side of the connector with respect to said support unit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The device claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said deployment and retrieval assembly comprises a thin, flexible wire-like motion transmitting member between the net actuator unit and the loop, said motion transmitting member extending within an introducer guide passage, said introducer guide passage closely surrounding said motion transmitting member and constraining said member for translational longitudinal motion within said passage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The device claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ends of said net element are secured to the motion transmitting member adjacent a proximal shoulder of said connector with respect to said support unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004538A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004538A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004538A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004538A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
