<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001281A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001281A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001281</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10157272</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020528</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-38103</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L023/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>777000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>686000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Stacked chip package having upper chip provided with trenches and method of manufacturing the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yong</given-name>
<middle-name>Hwan</middle-name>
<family-name>Kwon</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Suwon-city</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Se</given-name>
<middle-name>Yong</middle-name>
<family-name>Oh</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sa</given-name>
<middle-name>Yoon</middle-name>
<family-name>Kang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>David W. Heid</name-1>
<name-2>SKJERVEN MORRILL MacPHERSON LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>25 Metro Drive, Suite 700</address-1>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95110-1349</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A stacked chip package includes a substrate having an upper surface and a lower surface, a first semiconductor chip having an upper surface and a lower surface, wherein the lower surface of the first semiconductor chip is attached to the upper surface of the substrate and the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip includes a plurality of first electrode pads, and a second semiconductor chip having an upper surface and a lower surface. The lower surface of the second semiconductor chip is attached to the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip, and the lower surface of the second semiconductor chip includes trenches that correspond to the locations of the first electrode pads on the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to stacked chip packaging technology. More particularly, the present invention relates to a stacked chip package that includes an upper chip having trenches and a method of manufacturing the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> As more circuitry is integrated into high performance semiconductor chips, the size of such chips increases and the need for a greater density of chips is needed. Stacked chip packages and stacked packages have been developed to meet this need. Stacked chip packages include multiple chips stacked on one another and embodied in a single package. In contrast, stacked packages includes multiple packages, where each package includes a single chip, stacked on one another. Stacked chip packages and stacked packages have the advantage that chips having several functions can be embodied in a single package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In a stacked package, the thickness of an individual package is at least two times that of the chip embodied within the package. Thus as individual packages are stacked to form a stacked package, the thickness of the resulting stacked package is very thick which is undesirable. Also, to electrically connect the individual packages, the leads which extend from each package must be deformed. This requires additional steps to be performed when fabricating a stacked package which can decrease yield. Such steps can include fitting the external lead of the individual package disposed in the upper portion into the external lead of the individual package disposed in the lower portion, and punching in the external lead of the individual stacked package perpendicularly, and inserting a connecting terminal in the hole or other suitable deformation. Since an external connection terminal must be used in a stacked package, a decrease of the yield of the such packages is inevitable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> When compared to stacked packages, stacked chip package are more advantageous since they can be mounted more easily and effectively. Additionally, stacked chip packages can be designed using different types of internal structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> For example, one conventional stacked chip package includes a lower chip which is attached to a lower surface of a lead frame die pad via an adhesive, and an upper chip which is attached to the upper surface of the die pad via an adhesive. The lower chip is attached to the die pad such that the active surface of the lower chip faces downward, and the upper chip is attached to the die pad such that the active surface of the upper chip faces upward. The upper and lower semiconductor chips respectively are electrically connected to a lead frame via bonding wires. The upper and lower chips and the bonding wires are encapsulated and protected by a package body formed by a mold resin. In this type of conventional stacked chip package, the lower chip and the upper chip can have the same size and be identical to one another. For example, the upper and lower chips can both be edge pad chips, on which electrode pads connected to the bonding wires are formed in the edge portion of the active surface of the chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Another conventional stacked chip package is configured to stack a plurality of chips on a die pad in the same direction. In such a case, a lower chip must be larger than an upper chip. The lower chip is attached to the die pad via an adhesive and the upper chip is attached to the active surface of the lower chip via an adhesive. The upper and lower chips are electrically connected to leads via bonding wires, and are protected by a package molding body. In the stacked package having the above-described structure, the structures of the upper and lower chips must be different from each other (i.e., the lower chip must be larger than the upper chip). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the present invention, a stacked chip package is provided. The stacked chip package includes a substrate having an upper surface and a lower surface, a first semiconductor chip having an upper surface and a lower surface, wherein the lower surface of the first semiconductor chip is attached to the upper surface of the substrate and the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip includes a plurality of first electrode pads, and a second semiconductor chip having an upper surface and a lower surface, wherein the lower surface of the second semiconductor chip is attached to the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip and the lower surface of the second semiconductor chip includes trenches that correspond to the locations of the first electrode pads on the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Other embodiments, aspects, and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following descriptions and the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> For a more complete understanding of the present invention and for further embodiments, aspects, and advantages, reference is now made to the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view of a stacked chip package according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing a method of manufacturing a stacked chip package according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>are used to explain a first method of manufacturing an upper semiconductor chip in a stacked chip package according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>are used to explain a second method of manufacturing an upper semiconductor chip in a stacked chip package according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>are used to explain a third method of manufacturing an upper semiconductor chip in a stacked chip package according to the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view of a stacked chip package <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the present invention. The stacked chip package <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprises a substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a plurality of semiconductor chips <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and a package molding body <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be any suitable substrate material such as a polyimide tape, a printed circuit board (PCB), or a ceramic board. The substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a mounting surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, on which semiconductor chips are mounted, and a lower surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> opposite to the mounting surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A plurality of bonding pads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are formed in the mounting surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The lower semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is attached to the mounting surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via a first adhesive layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An on-chip circuit and a plurality of electrode pads <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are formed in the active surface of the lower semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, that is, the upper surface of the chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The cross-section of the lower semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has a rectangular shape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The upper semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is attached to the active surface of the lower semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> via a second adhesive layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The first adhesive layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the second adhesive layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be any suitable adhesive, such as an Ag-epoxy adhesive or a film type adhesive tape made of an epoxy-based resin. An on-chip circuit and a plurality of electrode pads <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are also formed in the active surface of the upper semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The size and the arrangement of the on-chip circuit and the electrode pads of the upper semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is similar to the arrangement of the on-chip circuit and the electrode pads of the of the lower semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The lower and upper semiconductor chips <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are edge pad chips, in which the electrode pads <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are disposed on the edges of the active surfaces of the chips. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Unlike the cross-section of the lower semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the cross-section of the upper semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> does not have a rectangular shape. Rather, in both edges of the lower surface of the upper semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, trenches <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of a substantially semicircular shape are formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The electrode pads <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the lower semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to the bonding pads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via first bonding wires <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The electrode pads <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the upper semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to the bonding pads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via second bonding wires <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. From the bonding wires <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, balls (not shown) are formed on the electrode pads <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and stitches are formed on the bonding pads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A wire loop of a certain height is provided above the balls formed on the electrode pad <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, trenches <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> are formed in both edges of the lower surface of the upper semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The trenches <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> provide a necessary space for the wire loop of the first bonding wires <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> that connect to the lower semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. By providing the trenches <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> in upper semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, it is possible to stack chips <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which can perform identical functions and can have identical physical sizes, in the same direction on the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Because the chips are stacked on only one surface (i.e., mounting surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the lower surface of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be utilized as a space for electrically connecting the stacked chip package <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to an external device, such as a motherboard. In particular, a plurality of ball lands <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can be formed on the lower surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Solder resist <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can be applied around the ball lands <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Next, solder balls <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> can be arranged on the ball lands <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and reflowed so that an external electrical connection can be formed using a surface arrangement technique. Since the ball lands <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to bonding pads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> through the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the upper and lower semiconductor chips <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be electrically connected to an external device, such as a motherboard through the electrode pads <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the bonding wires <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the bonding pads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the ball lands <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and the solder balls <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing a method of manufacturing a stacked chip package, such as stacked chip package <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> First, a first wafer to be formed into a plurality of lower chips (e.g., chip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) is prepared (step <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>). The first wafer is fabricated to have an on-chip circuit and electrode pads using a wafer-batch fabrication process. Tape is affixed to the lower surface of the first wafer (step <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>) and then the first wafer is sawed using a cutting blade (e.g., a diamond wheel) rotating at a high speed (step <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>). The wafer is sawed along a scribe line formed in the upper surface (i.e., the active surface) of the wafer. By separating the individual semiconductor chips from the sawed wafer, the lower semiconductor chips are prepared (step <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Next, a second wafer to be formed into a plurality of upper chips (e.g., chip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) is prepared (step <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>). The second wafer is fabricated to have an on-chip circuit and electrode pads that are similar to or identical to the on-chip circuit and electrode pads of the first wafer using the wafer-batch fabrication process. A plurality of backside trenches are formed in the lower surface of the second wafer (step <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>) and then the second wafer is sawed (step <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>). By separating the individual semiconductor chips from the sawed wafer, the upper chips are prepared (step <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>). The step of forming the backside trenches is described in detail below with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The prepared lower semiconductor chips are attached to the substrate using a first die bonding step <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight>. Then the adhesive layer used in the die bonding step is hardened and thereafter the surface of the adhesive layer is cleaned by, for example, a plasma (step <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>). The die bonded lower semiconductor chip is electrically connected to the substrate using a first wire-bonding step <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Next, the upper semiconductor chips are attached to the active surfaces of the lower semiconductor chips using a second die bonding step <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. Then the adhesive layer is hardened and thereafter the surface of the adhesive layer is cleaned by the plasma (step <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>). The upper semiconductor chip is electrically connected to the substrate using a second wire-bonding step <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Finally, a package body is formed after a molding step <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The step of forming the backside trenches in the second wafer (step <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>) can be carried out by various methods as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>are cross-sectional side views used to explain a first exemplary method of manufacturing the upper semiconductor chip having backside trenches according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As shown in the plan view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, in which the plurality of semiconductor chips are formed using the wafer fabrication process, is prepared and alignment keys <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are formed on the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, that is, the surface of the wafer that is opposite to active surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As shown in the cross-sectional side view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, groves or trenches <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of predetermined depths and widths are formed on the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The locations of the trenches <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are determined based on the alignment keys <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and correspond to the locations of scribe line on the active surface of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. A passivation layer <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is deposited on the active surface <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The trenches <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are formed by sawing the wafer, for example, using a cutting blade rotating at a high speed. The depths and widths of the trenches <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, as explained referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, are large enough such that there is sufficient space for the wire loop which extends above the electrode pads of the lower chips in the stacked chip package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, a metal layer <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is deposited on the entire surface of the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> including the surface of the trenches <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The metal layer <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> prevents the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> from breaking or generating chip cracks in the process of applying the adhesive to the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer and sawing the active surface of the wafer along the scribe line, thereby separating the individual chips from the wafer. In other words, the metal layer <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> increases the mechanical strength of the wafer having trenches <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The metal layer <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> can be deposited on the entire surface of the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer using any suitable technique, such as by electroplating, sputtering, evaporation, or electroless plating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> After an adhesive tape <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is attached to the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, in which the trenches <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are formed and the metal layer <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is deposited thereon (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>), the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is sawed along the scribe line so that the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is separated into the individual chips <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can be separated into the individual chips <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>using the general wafer sawing process. Although the individual chips are separated by separation regions <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, the lower surfaces thereof remain fixed to the adhesive tape <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>are cross-sectional side views used to explain a second exemplary method of manufacturing the upper semiconductor chip having backside trenches according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, alignment keys <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> are formed after depositing a first metal layer <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> on the entire surface of the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Then, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, small groves <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> are formed in predetermined locations on the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The small groves <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> may be formed using a cutting blade having a width narrower than that used in the wafer sawing process. Next, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, trenches <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> of desired sizes are formed by wet-etching the small groves <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> using the first metal layer <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> as a mask. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The first metal layer <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is then removed, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, and a second metal layer <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> is deposited on the entire surface of the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> including the trenches <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. The second metal layer <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> prevents the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> from breaking or generating chip cracks in the wafer sawing process, as does the metal layer <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>are cross-sectional side views used to explain a third exemplary method of manufacturing the upper semiconductor chip having backside trenches according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, an etching mask layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is deposited on the entire surface of the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. A photo-resist pattern layer <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, is formed on the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> by applying a photo-resist over the etching mask layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and the patterning the photo-resist. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Next, an etching mask pattern layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, is formed by removing the exposed etching mask layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> not covered by the photo-resist pattern layer <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> and removing the photo-resist pattern layer <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, trenches <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> are then formed by etching the backside of the wafer using the etching mask pattern layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as a mask. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The etching mask pattern layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is removed, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>, and a metal layer <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> is deposited on the entire surface of the backside <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> including the trenches <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>. The metal layer <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> prevents the wafer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> from breaking or generating chip cracks in the wafer sawing process, as do the metal layers <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> One advantage of the present invention is that it allows chips having the same sizes to be stacked upon one another in a stacked chip package. Another advantage of the present invention is that it allows conventional wire-bonding technology/equipment to be used to electrically connect stacked chips having the same size to a substrate since the upper chip includes trenches. As a result, stacked chip packages can be manufactured using conventional equipment and thus at a lower cost. Yet another advantage of the present invention is that because the chips are stacked on only one surface of the substrate, sufficient space remains for external electrical connections on the bottom of the package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> While particular embodiments of the present invention have been shown and described, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that changes and modifications may be made without departing from this invention in its broader aspect and, therefore, the appended claims are to encompass within their scope all such changes and modifications as fall within the true spirit of this invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A stacked chip package comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate having a mounting surface which includes a plurality of bonding pads; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first semiconductor chip disposed over the mounting surface of the substrate, the first semiconductor chip having an active surface that includes a plurality of first electrode pads; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second semiconductor chip disposed over the active surface of the first semiconductor chip, the second semiconductor chip having an active surface that includes a plurality of second electrode pads; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of first bonding wires that electrically connect the first electrode pads of the first semiconductor chip to the bonding pads of the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of second bonding wires that electrically connect the second electrode pads of the second semiconductor chip to the bonding pads of the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second semiconductor chip includes trenches formed on a lower surface opposite to the active surface of the second semiconductor chip, wherein the trenches provide a space that allows the plurality of first bonding wires to be electrically connected to the first electrode pads of the first semiconductor chip. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first semiconductor chip and the second semiconductor chip are of the same physical size. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a lower surface of the second semiconductor chip is attached to the active surface of the first semiconductor chip via an adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a package body encapsulating the first and second semiconductor chips, the first bonding wires, the second bonding wires, and the bonding pads of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a plurality of solder balls are formed on a lower surface of the substrate and the solder balls are electrically connected to the bonding pads. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a metal layer is deposited on the entire lower surface of the second semiconductor chip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the substrate is selected from a group consisting of a polyimide tape, a printed circuit board (PCB), and a ceramic substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A stacked chip package comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate having an upper surface and a lower surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first semiconductor chip having an upper surface and a lower surface, wherein the lower surface of the first semiconductor chip is attached to the upper surface of the substrate and the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip includes a plurality of first electrode pads; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second semiconductor chip having an upper surface and a lower surface, wherein the lower surface of the second semiconductor chip is attached to the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip and the lower surface of the second semiconductor chip includes trenches that correspond to the locations of the first electrode pads on the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first semiconductor chip and the second semiconductor chip are of the same physical size. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the upper surface of the substrate includes a plurality of bonding pads that are electrically connected to the plurality of first electrode pads on the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip via a plurality of first bonding wires. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the upper surface of the substrate includes a plurality of bonding pads that are electrically connected to a plurality of second electrode pads on the upper surface of the second semiconductor chip via a plurality of second bonding wires. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the upper surface of the substrate includes a plurality of bonding pads that are electrically connected to the plurality of first electrode pads on the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip via a plurality of first bonding wires and are electrically connected to a plurality of second electrode pads on the upper surface of the second semiconductor chip via a plurality of second bonding wires. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The stacked chip package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the trenches enable the plurality of first electrode pads on the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip to be electrically coupled to the upper surface of the substrate via a plurality of first bonding wires. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method for manufacturing a stacked chip package, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>attaching a lower surface of a first chip to an upper surface of a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching a lower surface of a second chip to an upper surface the first chip, wherein the lower surface of the second chip includes trenches that correspond to a plurality of first electrode pads on an upper surface of the first chip; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wirebonding the plurality of first electrode pads on the upper surface of the first chip to corresponding bonding pads on the upper surface of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>wirebonding a plurality of second electrode pads on an upper surface of the second chip to corresponding bonding pads on the upper surface of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein attaching a lower surface of a first chip to an upper surface of a substrate comprises affixing the lower surface of the first semiconductor chip to the upper surface of the substrate using an adhesive, and wherein attaching a lower surface of a second chip to an upper surface the first chip comprises affixing the lower surface of the second semiconductor chip to the upper surface of the first semiconductor chip using an adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>forming trenches on a lower surface of a second wafer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sawing the second wafer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>singulating the second wafer into a plurality of chips which include the second chip. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>forming alignment keys on the lower surface of a second wafer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming groves in predetermined locations based on the alignment keys; </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a metal layer to the lower surface of the second wafer including the surfaces of the groves; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>singulating the second wafer into a plurality of chips which include the second chip. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>applying a first metal layer to a lower surface of a second wafer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming alignment keys; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming groves on the predetermined locations of the lower surface of the second wafer based on the alignment keys; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming trenches by etching the groves using the first metal layer as a mask; </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a second metal layer to the lower surface of the second wafer including the surfaces of the trenches; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>singulating the second wafer into a plurality of chips which include the second chip. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>depositing an etching mask layer on a lower surface of a second wafer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a photo-resist pattern layer on the etching mask layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>defining an etching mask pattern layer by partially removing the etching mask layer based on the photo-resist pattern layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the photo-resist pattern layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming trenches by etching the lower surface of the second wafer using the etching mask pattern layer as a mask; </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the etching mask pattern layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a metal layer on the lower surface of the second wafer including the surfaces of the trenches; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>singulating the second wafer into a plurality of chips which include the second chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001281A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
