<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000386A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000386A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000386A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000386A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000386A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000386A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000386</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09880559</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010613</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B01D045/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>095</class>
<subclass>269000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>055</class>
<subclass>452000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>055</class>
<subclass>455000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>SYSTEM FOR SEPARATING AN ENTRAINED IMMISCIBLE LIQUID COMPONENT FROM A WET GAS STREAM</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hugh</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>West</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>St. Albert</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>GABLE &amp; GOTWALS</name-1>
<name-2>Attn. PAUL H. JOHNSON</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>100 W. FIFTH ST.</address-1>
<address-2>10TH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>TULSA</city>
<state>OK</state>
<postalcode>74103</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream, the system including a vessel having an interior in communication with a wet gas inlet, a gas outlet and a liquid outlet, at least one vortex tube supported within the vessel interior, the vortex tube having an inlet end and an outlet end and a tubular wall having an internal wall surface through which fluids pass as the gas flows between the vessel wet gas inlet and gas outlet, a vortex generator supported within the vortex tube near the inlet end, the vortex generator causing gas within the vortex tube to rotate to thereby cause at least some of the liquid component to be forced against the interior wall surface of the vortex tube by centrifugal action, a circumferentially positioned liquid outlet in the vortex tube downstream of the vortex generator configured to strip liquid and bypass gas from the stream flowing through said vortex tube, stripped liquid and bypass gas entering a central chamber of the vessel and a recycle port in the vortex tube upstream of the vortex generator through which bypass gas flows. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">REFERENCE TO PENDING APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is not related to any pending United States or international patent application. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">REFERENCE TO MICROFICHE APPENDIX </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This application is not referenced in any Microfiche Appendix. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The disclosure herein is for a system, and a method of operating a system, for separating a liquid component from a gas stream in which the liquid component is immiscible&mdash;that is, it is not absorbed in the gas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The invention generally relates to gas/liquid separators which are typically process vessels that are commonly pressurized. The function of the separator system is to segregate immiscible phases of the process stream. Where the process stream is in the form of a gas stream that carries with it immiscible liquid components, the function of the separator is to separate out the liquid components to provide, at the output of the separator, a gas stream which has relatively less entrained liquid. Separators for separating liquid and gas components of the stream are commonly utilized in the oil and gas industry, specifically in oil and gas production, oil refining and gas processing. In addition, gas/liquid separator&apos;s are utilized in the mining industry, chemical plants, wastewater treatment, pulp and paper plants and pharmaceutical plants. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Separators can be designed to separate: (1) two-phase streams&mdash;that is, vapor/liquid streams; (2) three-phase streams&mdash;that is, vapor/organic liquid/aqueous streams; or (3) four-phase streams&mdash;that is, vapor/organic liquid/aqueous-liquid/solids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Industry has developed many types of separators. Most separation depends ultimately on the force of gravity, either natural gravity or created gravity forces such as represented by cyclone separators. Natural gravity is usually accomplished by flowing a stream having immiscible components into a vessel which provides a relatively quiescent environment that allows gravity to act on heavier components of the stream and move them into a downward part of the vessel and accordingly, forcing the lighter components into an upper part of the vessel. Artificial high gravity fields are provided by cyclone separators wherein the stream is subjected to rapid rotation. One type of artificial gravity separators is called a &ldquo;mono-tube cyclone separator&rdquo; which utilizes an elongated tube as a rotation chamber, rotation of the stream being accomplished by means of a vortex generator, sometimes referred to as a &ldquo;spin generator&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A separation system wherein artificially induced gravity is used for augmenting separation in a single tube is commonly referred to as a &ldquo;mono-tube&rdquo; cyclone separator. Separators that have one or more of the mono-tube cyclone separators enclosed within a vessel are commonly referred to as &ldquo;cyclone-tube separators&rdquo;. The disclosure herein relates to a cyclone-tube separator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> For background information relating to the general subject matter of this invention reference may be had to the following previously issued United States patents:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="112PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>U.S. Pat. No.</entry>
<entry>INVENTOR</entry>
<entry>TITLE</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>1,836,004</entry>
<entry>Becker</entry>
<entry>Apparatus for Treating Gas</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2,808,897</entry>
<entry>Reinsch et al</entry>
<entry>Apparatus for Contacting Liquid</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>and Vaporous Materials</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3,296,774</entry>
<entry>Hoogendorn et al</entry>
<entry>Gas-Liquid Contactor with Wall</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Obstructions and Contacting Method</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3,498,028</entry>
<entry>Trouw</entry>
<entry>Apparatus for Contacting Liquid</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>and Gases</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3,581,467</entry>
<entry>Donnelly</entry>
<entry>Method and Apparatus for Vortical</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Liquid-Gas Movement</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3,605,388</entry>
<entry>Zuiderweg et al</entry>
<entry>Apparatus for Contacting Liquids</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>and Gases</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3,662,521</entry>
<entry>Behar et al</entry>
<entry>Device for Reaction Between</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Liquid Phase and Gaseous Phase</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3,930,816</entry>
<entry>Miczek</entry>
<entry>Structure for a Gas and Liquid</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Contacting Chamber in a Gas</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Effluent Processing System</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4,128,406</entry>
<entry>Spevack</entry>
<entry>Contact Apparatus for Multiphase</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Processing</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4,486,203</entry>
<entry>Rooker</entry>
<entry>Inlet Momentum Absorber for</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Fluid Separation</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4,838,906</entry>
<entry>Kiselev</entry>
<entry>Contact-and-Separating Element</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4,880,451</entry>
<entry>Konijn</entry>
<entry>Gas/Liquid Contacting Apparatus</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5,145,612</entry>
<entry>Reay et al</entry>
<entry>Apparatus for Mixing Vapor in a</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Countercurrent Column</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5,683,629</entry>
<entry>Konijn</entry>
<entry>Horizontal Tray and Column for</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Contacting Gas and Liquid</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5,714,068</entry>
<entry>Brown</entry>
<entry>Inlet Device for Large Oil Field</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Separator</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A system is provided for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a gas stream. The system employs a vessel. The interior of the vessel is in communication with a wet gas inlet, a gas outlet and a liquid outlet. The term, &ldquo;wet gas&rdquo; means the inlet gas stream having a liquid component or components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> At least one vortex tube is supported within the vessel interior. The vortex tube has an inlet end and an outlet end and a tubular wall having an internal surface through which gas passes. The vortex tube(s) are arranged within the vessel so that the wet gas entering the vessel flows through the vortex tube as the gas passes between the vessel wet gas inlet and the gas outlet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A vortex generator (sometimes referred to as a &ldquo;spin generator&rdquo;) is supported within the vortex tube near the tube inlet end. The vortex generator causes gas flowing within the vortex tube to rotate rapidly to thereby impart artificial gravity to the stream. This rapid rotation of the gas stream causes the liquid component to be forced against the interior wall of the vortex tube by centrifugal action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A circumferentially positioned liquid outlet is provided in the vortex tube downstream of the vortex generator. This centrifugal outlet may be in the form of a circumferential slot formed in the vortex tube that can, in one practical embodiment, be achieved by forming the vortex tube of two axially aligned pipe sections wherein the section adjacent the outlet end of the vortex tube is of smaller internal diameter. As the gas stream flows within the vortex tube the liquid component is moved axially along the interior wall of the tube until the liquid encounters the circumferential liquid outlet. The liquid component is passed through the outlet while a substantial portion of the gas in the stream continues within the vortex tube to the tube outlet end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> As entrained liquid that has been forced against the interior wall of the vortex tube passes out through the circumferential liquid outlet a portion of the gas making up the stream also passes through the outlet, the discharged liquid and by-pass gas passing into the interspacial volume interior of the vessel, surrounding the tube. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A recycle port is provided in the vortex tube upstream of the vortex generator. The by-pass gas flowing into the interior of the vessel through the circumferential liquid outlet is drawn back into the interior of the vortex tube through the recycle port to co-mix with the gas stream entering the inlet end of the vortex tube. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the invention the interior of the separator vessel is compartmented to provide an inlet chamber, an outlet chamber and a middle chamber. Gas flowing out the outlet end of the vortex tube flows into the outlet chamber. This gas is relatively liquid-free compared to the wet gas that flows into the vessel inlet section. Liquid separated from the gas stream that flows out of the vortex tube through the circumferential liquid outlet passes into the middle chamber of the vessel and, by gravitational force, accumulates in a lower portion of the vessel and is withdrawn through the vessel liquid outlet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In order to induce recirculation of the by-pass gas to flow back into the vortex tube a venturi effect is created in the vortex generator, creating a low static pressure. The venturi is preferably combined with the vortex generator. In the preferred embodiment the venturi/vortex generator is formed using a nosecone member having an external diameter less than the internal diameter of the vortex tube, and an aerodynamic forward end. The vortex generator or spin generator is accomplished by a plurality of spaced apart circumferentially arranged curved blades that extend between the exterior of the nosecone and the interior of the vortex tube. These curved blades are configured to impart a high rate of spin to gas passing through the vortex tube while, as above indicated, the nosecone member achieves venturi action. In the preferred arrangement the nosecone rearward portion is hollow, the hollow area communicating via an open rearward end of the nosecone with the fluid stream passing through the tube. A duct is provided between the by-pass return opening in the vortex tube so that recycled gas passes through the opening in the tube, through the duct and into the interior of the nosecone where it is discharged out the rearward end thereof back into the gas stream. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A better understanding of the invention will be obtained from the following description of the preferred embodiments taken in conjunction with the attached claims and with the attached drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an elevational view of a separator vessel that employs the principles of this invention. The separator vessel has a wet gas inlet, a gas outlet and a liquid outlet. Shown in dotted outline within the vessel is a single vortex tube positioned between two tubesheets. Multiple such tubes may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is enlarged cross-sectional view of a portion of the vortex tube. The cross-sectional shows a portion of the vortex tube adjacent its outlet end and illustrates a circumferential liquid outlet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a fragmentary cross-sectional view of a portion of the vortex tube. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a nosecone positioned within a forward portion of the vortex tube&mdash;that is, near the inlet end of the vortex tube. This figure shows the nosecone in an elevational exterior view and shows a duct communicating with a by-pass opening in the vortex tube by which by-pass gas can enter into the hollow nosecone. Further, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows circumferentially arranged, spaced apart, curved blades position in the annular area between the exterior of the nosecone and the interior wall of the vortex tube. These blades impart rapid spinning action to the gas stream to cause the entrained liquids to be expelled towards the interior wall of the vortex tube. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is enlarged relative to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and shows the duct by which by-pass gas is conveyed from the exterior of the vortex into the interior of the nosecone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> of a single curved blade that is positioned between the exterior wall of the nosecone and the interior wall of the vortex tube. A plurality of these curved blades are circumferentially arranged to impart a high rate of spinning action to gas flowing through the vortex tube. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> showing one way by which a circumferential liquid outlet can be provided in the vortex tube. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF A PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring to the drawings and first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a gas stream is illustrated. The system employs a vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that, in the illustrated embodiment, is horizontal but that could be vertical. Vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has an interior wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Communicating with the vessel interior defined by wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, is a wet gas inlet <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a gas outlet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Inlet <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is described as a &ldquo;wet gas&rdquo; inlet to designate that it is the inlet wherein gas having a liquid component entrained therewith enters the vessel. The gas outlet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has at least a portion of the entrained liquid separated therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Extending from the bottom of vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a liquid collection chamber <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> having a liquid outlet <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> through which liquid separated from gas flowing through vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is discharged. In the preferred embodiment of the invention, liquid accumulates to a liquid level <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> that is maintained within chamber <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to serve as a liquid lock to prevent gas from passing from the interior of the vessel through liquid outlet <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In order to maintain liquid level <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, liquid controls can be employed, the liquid level controls being indicated by the numerals <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>A through <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>D. Equipment to provide liquid level control is commonly commercially available and therefore the system for maintaining liquid level <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> within liquid collection chamber <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is not a part of this invention, and not shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Shown in dotted outline in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a first tubesheet <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> that is adjacent wet gas inlet <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and, spaced from it, a second tubesheet <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> that is positioned near gas outlet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Tubesheets <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> divide the vessel into three interior compartments - that is, an inlet chamber <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, an outlet chamber <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and a middle chamber <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Tubesheets <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are impervious to flow. Supported between tubesheets <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is a vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, the vortex tube having an inlet end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and an outlet end <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. There is provided an opening in first tubesheet <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> conforming to vortex tube inlet end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and in like manner, an opening in second tubesheet <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> conforming to the vortex tube outlet <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Wet gas flowing through inlet <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into inlet chamber <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> must flow through vortex tube(s) <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to pass into the gas outlet chamber <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is an elongated metal tubular member, a section of which is seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> has an interior wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows an internal area of vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> that is adjacent tubesheet <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (not seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>)&mdash;that is, an area of vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> that is adjacent the tube inlet end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Positioned within tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is a nosecone member <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, the nosecone member being shown in exterior view. Nosecone member <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> has a forward end <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> that is configured to provide a streamlined shape. The rearward end <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is blunt and is open&mdash;that is, nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is hollow providing an interior surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and an interior cavity <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The interior surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the nosecone is tapered adjacent rearward end <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the tapered section being indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> to provide a sharp circumferential exit edge at rearward end <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The exterior surface <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is less than the interior diameter of the vortex tube interior wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> leaving an annular area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Spaced within this annular area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are a plurality of thin, smooth blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The plurality of blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> are circumferentially spaced apart from each other as supported within annular area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The cross-sectional shape of the blades is indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> the shape of each of the blades provides a long wrap and a high exit angle. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> has a dotted line <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> representing a linear gas flow path as the gas attempts to pass through the annular area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> within the vortex tube. That is, line <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> shows the path that gas would take except for the provision of the plurality of blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The shape of each of the blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is such that the flow path of fluids passing annular area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is directed at an angle such as indicated by dotted line <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. This illustrates the creation of a high exit angle <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> each with a high exit angle provide rapid whirling or spinning action to gas flowing through vortex tube. This whirling action imparted by blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> creates an artificial gravity or centrifical force causing the heavier component of the fluid stream, that is the entrained liquid component and any solids component to be expelled outwardly against the interior wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the vortex tube. The rapidly swirling centrifical gas stream flows down the length of vortex <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> towards the open outlet end <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Positioned slightly upstream from outlet open end <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is a circumferentially oriented liquid outlet generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and illustrated in detail in the cross-sectional view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Liquid outlet <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> provides a circumferential opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> surrounding or at least substantially surrounding vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The function of circumferential opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is to strip liquid flowing on the vortex tube interior wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> as it is moved by gas flow. Circumferential opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> can be provided in a variety of ways. In the illustrated embodiment, opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is achieved by employing a supplemental vortex tube portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A that extends from liquid outlet <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> to the vortex tube outlet end <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Tube portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A may be of slightly decreased external and internal diameters compared to the main vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Further, the forward end <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of vortex tube portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A is shaped on a bevel and in like manner the outlet end of the main vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is shaped in a complimentary bevel <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> so that the circumferential slot <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> has a radial outward bias with respect to the vortex tube. As gas flows down vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and spins at a rapid rate forcing the liquid component against the interior wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> it is stripped off of the wall and passes outwardly through passageway <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> into the middle section <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. This liquid accumulates and is withdrawn through liquid collection chamber <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 6</cross-reference> show one means of supporting vortex tube main portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to the supplemental tube portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A. The front end portion of short length rods <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are welded onto the exterior surface of vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> main portion and extend past circumferential opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Short length spacers, which can also be in the form of short length rods <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, are attached, such as by welding, to the external surface of vortex tube supplement portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A and also to rods <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. This arrangement holds vortex tube main portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and supplemental portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A in axial alignment and yet provides circumferential slot <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> for stripping of liquid from interior wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> as a gas stream passes towards the exit end of the vortex tube. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Circumferential opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is configured to strip off liquid but at the same time a portion of the gas stream is free to pass out through opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The passage of a portion of the gas stream outwardly through opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is necessary to carry with it separated liquid. The gas that passes out through circumferential opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is recycled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Returning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> there is shown a recycle opening <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> in vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. There is a sidewall opening in nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> that is not seen in the drawings, that is in alignment with opening <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> in duct <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. Opening <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is in alignment with opening <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Duct <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is shown in cross-section in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The function of opening <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and opening <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> through duct <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is to provide a passageway for the flow of recycled gas from vessel central chamber <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> into the interior of nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> where it will then flow from the nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> back into the interior of vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the duct <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is preferably streamlined so as to present minimal obstruction to the flow of the gas stream through vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> has two basic functions. First, it provides one means of installing blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. That is, the nosecone provides an annular area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> through which gas flows and provides a space in which to mount blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> so that an effective whirling or spinning is imparted to the gas flowing through the tube. In addition, nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> helps achieve a venturi action. That is, gas flowing in the tube drops in pressure as it passes nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> due to venturi action. This venturi action results in a pressure within the interior <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> that is lower than the pressure within the vessel central chamber <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. This pressure differential, causes gas to flow from central chamber <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> through the passageway created by openings <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> in duct <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> into the interior of nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The gas is drawn by the venturi action of gas flow exterior of the nosecone into the interior of vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> where the recirculating gas mixes with the main gas stream entering the vortex tube to ultimately flow into the outlet chamber <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The drawings herein show only a single vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> within vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the vortex tube extending between tubesheets <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. In actual practice of the invention the normal system may include a plurality of vortex tubes. These tubes can be arranged circumferentially around and spaced from the centrally positioned vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> as shown in the drawing. Further, the vortex tubes can be arranged circumferentially within the interior vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a manner that does not employ a central vortex tube without departing from the spirit and scope of this disclosure. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OPERATION OF THE SEPARATOR SYSTEM </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Gas carrying liquid mist enters the inlet section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, then flows into tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and through a spin-generator achieved by blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Centrifugal force causes liquids to migrate outwardly and collect around the tube interior wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and gas to move toward outlet chamber <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. In this particular design, a circumferential slot <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is used to remove the liquid film from inner tube wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. To induce the liquid to flow through slot <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, a lower pressure is maintained outside the tube. A small portion of the gas flows through slot <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> with the liquid and is recycled. The lower pressure is created in the spin-generator by venturi action. Gas entering the spin-generator accelerates, creating a low throat pressure. The recycled gas flows back toward this low-pressure source via the space outside tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, then through duct <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> in the spin-generator which conducts it to the interior of nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. It is released inside the hollow nosecone and flows toward its open end <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> through which recycled gas joins the mainstream inside tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Several improvements over existing spin-generators are embodied in this disclosure. Functional improvements to spin-generators illustrated and described in this disclosure include: a) the flowing gas stream is intercepted in a manner that minimizes energy loss; b) rotation is imparted to the gas stream in an efficient manner; c) rotation speed is increased to improve separation; and d) recycled gas is conducted back into the mainstream of gas flow in a streamlined manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Some of the unique features of this disclosure are: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> (1) the disclosed spin-generator has a relatively long, tapered nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> with a rounded forward end <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> (2) the discharge angle of spin imparting blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is made steeper to impart a higher tangential component to the gas discharge velocity; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> (3) the wrap of the individual blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is increased, and the number of blades is increased, compared to existing spin-generators, such that there is complete coverage of the flow area by the blades; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> (4) blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> are made as thin and smooth as practical; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> (5) single recirculation duct <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is used, the duct being separate from blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The outer surface contour of recirculation duct <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is streamlined to minimize resistance to the main stream gas flow; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> (6) the bore of the hollow cylindrical nosecone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> flares at the tail end, by means of a high-angle inside bevel <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, to form a sharp exit edge <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Each of these individual design elements and all combinations of them are considered a part of this disclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The effect of these improvements is a device with less pressure drop to the primary flow stream than previously has existed, and a higher exit rotation angle. The lower pressure drop will translate into higher capacity per cyclone tube, and fewer required tubes, and therefore, a smaller diameter vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The higher rotation angle of blades <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> result in increased g-forces applied to the entrained liquid component for faster phase separation, which shortens the required length of vortex tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, and correspondingly a shorter length is required for vessel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The claims and the specification describe the invention presented and the terms that are employed in the claims draw their meaning from the use of such terms in the specification. The same terms employed in the prior art may be broader in meaning than specifically employed herein. Whenever there is a question between the broader definition of such terms used in the prior art and the more specific use of the terms herein, the more specific meaning is meant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described with a certain degree of particularity, it is manifest that many changes may be made in the details of construction and the arrangement of components without departing from the spirit and scope of this disclosure. It is understood that the invention is not limited to the embodiments set forth herein for purposes of exemplification, but is to be limited only by the scope of the attached claim or claims, including the full range of equivalency to which each element thereof is entitled. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream comprising: 
<claim-text>a vessel having an interior in communication with a wet gas inlet, a gas outlet and a liquid outlet; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one vortex tube supported within said vessel interior, the vortex tube having an inlet end and an outlet end and a tubular wall having an internal wall surface through which a gas stream passes as the gas flows between said vessel wet gas inlet and gas outlet; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vortex generator supported within said vortex tube intermediate said inlet and outlet ends, the vortex generator causing gas within said vortex tube to rotate to thereby cause at least some of said liquid component to be forced against said interior wall surface of said vortex tube by centrifugal action; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a circumferentially positioned liquid outlet in said vortex tube tubular wall downstream of said vortex generator configured to strip liquid from said vortex tube interior wall along with bypass gas from said gas stream flowing through said vortex tube, stripped liquid and bypass gas entering said interior of said vessel; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a recycle port in said vortex tube tubular wall upstream of said vortex generator through which bypass gas flows. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> including: 
<claim-text>a venturi element positioned within said vortex tube for creating an area of pressure drop within said vortex tube, said recycle port in said vortex tube having communication with said area of pressure drop by which bypass gas is drawn into said vortex tube. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vortex generator includes a nose cone of external diameter less than an internal diameter of said vortex tube providing an annular area therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> including a duct having an inlet end communicating with an opening in said vortex tube tubular wall and an outlet end communicating with said venturi element through which bypass gas flows from the interior of said vessel to the interior of said vortex tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said nose cone has a closed front, upstream end, an open rear, downstream end and has at least, in part, a hollow interior communicating with said open downstream end and wherein said duct outlet end communicates with said nose cone hollow interior whereby bypass gas flows into the interior of said vortex tube through said duct, through said nose cone interior and out through said nose cone open downstream end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vortex generator is in the form of a plurality of spaced apart, circumferentially arranged, curved blades past which wet gas stream flowing through said vortex tube passes, the blades being configured to impart whirling action to said immiscible liquid component of said gas passing therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vortex generator includes, in addition said nose cone, a plurality of spaced apart, circumferentially arranged, curved blades supported within said annular area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> in which said plurality of spaced apart curved blades at least in part support said nose cone within said vortex tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said nose cone hollow interior is defined by increased internal diameters adjacent said open, rear downstream end providing a sharp, circumferential exit edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vessel is elongated, having an inlet portion with which said wet gas inlet communicates and an outlet portion with which said gas outlet communicates and a central portion between said inlet and outlet portions, and include a first wall separating said inlet portion and said central portion and a spaced apart second wall separating said outlet portion and said central portion, each of said first and second walls having a passageway opening therethrough and wherein said vortex tube inlet end is in communication with said opening in said first wall and said outlet end is in communication with said opening in said second wall, said liquid outlet and said recycle port in said vortex tube communicating with said vessel central portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said duct is, in cross-section perpendicular its length, aerodynamically configured. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each of said curved blades is configured to provide a long wrap and to impart high exit angle to gas passing between said blades. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream comprising: 
<claim-text>a vessel having an interior in communication with a wet gas inlet, a gas outlet and a liquid outlet; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one vortex tube supported within said vessel interior, the vortex tube having an inlet end and an outlet end and a tubular wall having an internal wall surface through which a gas stream passes as the gas flows between said vessel wet gas inlet and gas outlet in said vortex tube having a recycle port in said tubular wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vortex generator supported within said vortex tube intermediate said inlet and outlet ends, the vortex generator causing gas within said vortex tube to rotate to thereby cause at least some of said liquid component to be forced against said interior wall surface of said vortex tube by centrifugal action; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a liquid outlet in said vortex tube tubular wall downstream of said vortex generator configured to strip liquid from said vortex tube interior wall along with bypass gas from said gas stream flowing through said vortex tube, stripped liquid and bypass gas entering said interior of said vessel; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a venturi element positioned within said vortex tube for creating an area of pressure drop therein, said recycle port in said vortex tube having communication with said area of pressure drop by which bypass gas is drawn into said vortex tube. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vortex generator includes a nose cone of external diameter less than an internal diameter of said vortex tube providing an annular area therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> including a duct having an inlet end communicating with an opening in said vortex tube tubular wall and an outlet end communicating with an internal passageway in said venturi element through which bypass gas flows from the interior of said vessel to the interior of said vortex tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said nose cone has a closed upstream end, an open downstream end and wherein said internal passageway communicates with the open downstream end and wherein said duct outlet end communicates with said nose cone interior passageway whereby bypass gas flows into the interior of said vortex tube through said duct, through said nose cone interior passageway and out through said nose cone open downstream end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vortex generator is in the form of a plurality of spaced apart, circumferentially arranged, curved blades past which wet gas stream flowing through said vortex tube passes, the blades being configured to impart whirling action to said entrained immiscible liquid component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vortex generator includes, in addition to said nose cone, a plurality of spaced apart, circumferentially arranged, curved blades supported within said annular area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> in which said plurality of spaced apart curved blades at least in part support said nose cone within said vortex tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said nose cone interior passageway is defined by increased internal diameters adjacent said open downstream end providing a sharp circumferential exit edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vessel is elongated, having an inlet portion with which said wet gas inlet communicates and an outlet portion with which said gas outlet communicates and a central portion between said inlet and outlet portions, and include a first wall separating said inlet portion from said central portion and a spaced apart second wall separating said outlet portion from said central portion, each of said first and second walls having a passageway opening therethrough and wherein said vortex tube inlet end is in communication with said opening in said first wall and said vortex tube outlet end is in communication with said opening in said second wall, said liquid outlet and said recycle port in said vortex tube communicating with said vessel central portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said duct is, in cross-section perpendicular its length, aerodynamically configured. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A system for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each of said curved blades is configured to provide a long wrap and to impart high exit angle to gas passing between said blades. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A method for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream comprising; 
<claim-text>(1) passing said wet gas stream through a vortex tube having an inlet end and an outlet end and tubular wall having an internal wall surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(2) causing gas within said vortex tube to rotate to thereby cause at least some of said liquid component to be forced against said interior wall surface of said vortex tube by centrifugal action; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(3) stripping liquid from said vortex tube interior wall surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(4) diverting liquid stripped from said vortex tube interior wall surface along with bypass gas out through an outlet in said vortex tube tubular wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(5) recycling bypass gas back into said vortex tube; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(6) withdrawing for disposal liquid stripped from said vortex tube interior wall surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A method for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> including the step of; 
<claim-text>creating an area of pressure drop within said vortex tube to augment step (5) of recycling bypass gas back into said vortex tube. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A method for separating an entrained immiscible liquid component from a wet gas stream according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein step (2) of causing gas within said vortex tube to rotate is accomplished by a plurality of spaced apart, circumferentially arranged curved blades past which said wet gas stream flows as it flows through said vortex tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000386A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000386A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000386A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
