<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002706A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002706A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002706A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002706A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002706A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002706A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002706</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09880481</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010613</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04R025/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>381</class>
<subclass>381000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>381</class>
<subclass>374000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Adjustable earphones for personal audio and communication systems
</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09880481</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20010613</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09869470</doc-number>
<document-date>20010628</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shawn</given-name>
<middle-name>P.</middle-name>
<family-name>Keliiliki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Orem</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>J.C. PATENTS INC.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>4 Venture, Suite 250</address-1>
<city>Irvine</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>92618</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An ear mounted earphone includes a speaker housing for positioning a speaker at the entrance to the auditory canal of an ear of a user. An elongate boom extends from the speaker housing and through a sleeve at one end of an earpiece so that the boom may be moved longitudinally and rotationally within the sleeve for adjustment purposes and will be frictionally held in adjusted position by the sleeve during use. A microphone arm with microphone may be rotatably mounted on the speaker housing to provide a microphone when the earphones are used with a communication system. The rotatability of the microphone arm allowing the same earphone and microphone arm to be adjusted for use with either the right or left ear of a user. An earpiece may be conveniently integrally molded as a single piece with a slit formed therein intermediate its length so the wire to the speaker and microphone can be positioned within the earpiece. The speaker may be waterproofed by a thin waterproof material such as mylar. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention is in the field of earphones for use with personal audio systems and communication systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. State of the Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Personal audio systems enabling a user to listen to the radio, cassette tapes, or compact disks while involved in other activities are very popular. Such systems include headphones or earphones which a user wears over or in his or her ears so that the sound from the system is heard only by the user and does not disturb others. The earphones also usually provide better sound transmission to the listener so the listener can hear and understand the sounds better than if merely transmitted into the air, particularly during movement of the user such as in sport or exercise activities or in noisy environments. Such earphones are also sometimes used in communication systems such as telephone and radio communication systems. For use with such communication systems, the earphones will often have a microphone associated therewith extending toward the users&apos;s mouth so the user can easily participate in hands-off two-way communication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> With all systems using earphones, comfort and convenience of the earphones is important. My U.S. Pat. No. 5,412,736 shows earphones designed for comfortable securement to the ear of a user and particularly for secure carriage on the ear of a user during vigorous activity by the user. While the earphones shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,412,736 work satisfactorily to hold the earphones on a user&apos;s ear even during vigorous activity by the user and are generally comfortable, such earphones are not as adjustable as desired for some users and are not designed for use with communication systems in that they are not adapted for carrying a microphone. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, the speaker and speaker housing of an earphone is mounted to an ear mounting means for both rotational and spatial adjustment with respect to the ear mounting means so that a user can adjust the positioning of the speaker housing for maximum comfort. A microphone arm may be mounted to one of the housings so that earphones may be used in communication systems requiring a microphone and in a preferred embodiment, the microphone arm is mounted for approximately 270 degrees of rotation with respect to the housing so that the earphone with microphone arm can be worn on either the left or the right ear and the microphone arm will extend to the area of a user&apos;s mouth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The invention provides an elongate boom extending from the speaker housing through a sleeve in the ear mounting means. The boom is frictionally held in the sleeve and can be rotated in the sleeve and slid longitudinally in the sleeve to adjust the orientation and positioning of the sneaker with respect to the ear mounting means. In this way, the earphone can be adjusted for a comfortable fit by substantially all users. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> While with personal audio systems two earphones, one for each ear Will be provided and used, with communication systems, either a single earphone or two earphones may be used. Where easy two way communication is desired, the single earphone, or one of the two earphones used, will be provided with a microphone arm extending from the speaker housing to hold and position a microphone in operable location near the mouth of a user to enable the microphone to pick up sound emanating from the user&apos;s mouth. It is preferred that the microphone arm be mounted to the speaker housing for about 270 degrees of rotation with respect to the housing so the arm may be rotated and the earphone used on either the right ear or left ear as preferred by the user. The microphone and its mounting may be removable so the earphones may be used either with or without a microphone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A waterproof or water resistant cover may be installed in the speaker housing over the speaker cover to make the earphone water resistant to prevent rusting or other corrosion of metal parts of the speaker and other possible damage to the speaker from perspiration or other moisture that the earphones may encounter during use or storage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The earphones of my cited patent required manufacture of the earpiece by molding two earpiece halves, inserting the wire from the speaker in one half and gluing the halves together. According to the present invention, the earpiece is molded as a single piece with a slit extending into the earpiece along the intermediate portion of the length of the earpiece. The wire can then be inserted through the ends of the earpiece into the ends of the slit with, for example, a needle and positioned within the slit between the ends of the earpiece to enclose the wire in the earpiece.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The best mode presently contemplated for carrying out the invention is illustrated in the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side elevation of an earphone of the invention with a microphone mounted thereon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> front elevation of the earphone of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> taken from the left in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> fragmentary vertical section taken on the line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing the speaker, speaker housing, and microphone arm mounting; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> vertical section taken on the line <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> side elevation of the microphone mounting taken on the line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, but not showing the speaker housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, an exploded view showing the speaker and its mounting to the speaker housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> perspective view of a communication system being worn by a user; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8, a</cross-reference> vertical sect-on through the earpiece taken on the Line <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> or <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9, a</cross-reference> fragmentary vertical section similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, but showing the microphone mounting removed and a cap in its place. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE ILLUSTRATED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The current invention will be illustrated and described in connection with earphones as shown in my U.S. Pat. No. 5,412,736, and the disclosure of such patent is hereby incorporated by reference. While the current inventions were specifically developed to complement the earphones shown in my cited patent, they have application with other earphones as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As shown, particularly in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an earphone of the invention includes an earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> which serves as an ear mounting means designed to fit behind the ear of a user and to support a speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> includes a speaker <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, mounted therein to be comfortably positioned at the entrance to the auditory canal of an ear of the user. A sleeve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is formed at the forward end of the earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with an opening <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> therethrough sized to tightly receive a boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> extending from the speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The fit of boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in sleeve opening <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is such that a user can slide boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> longitudinally back and forth in sleeve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> as indicated generally by arrow <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and can rotate boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in sleeve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, but, when sliding or rotational force is not present, boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> will be frictionally held in place with respect to sleeve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the position and orientation of speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can be adjusted with respect to earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> so that speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can be comfortably positioned at the entrance to the ear&apos;s auditory canal for just about any potential user of the earphones. A stop <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> on the end of boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> prevents the boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> from being removed from sleeve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which extends between the ear and the user&apos;s head with sleeve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> at the forward end of earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> extending over the upper forward portion of the ear as shown at <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, in combination with speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> which fits into the ear and boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> which adjustably connects the speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, cooperate with the user&apos;s ear to comfortably position and hold the speaker <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the user&apos;s ear at the entrance of the auditory canal even during vigorous physical activity by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> A pair of wires <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> extend from speaker <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, through a central bore <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The wires extend from the end of boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> as a single, insulated multiconductor wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to form a loop <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> before entering earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> where the wires extend inside earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to its remote end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> below the ear lobe of a user. The loop <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> provides slack in wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to allow movement of boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in sleeve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A length of the wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> extends from the earpiece remote end <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> for attachment at a remote location to a signal source. This could be a communication device such as a cellular telephone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, worn on the waist of the user, a personal audio system similarly worn by the user, or a combination communication device and personal audio system. The end of wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> away from the earphones well generally include a standard plug or jack for plugging into a socket in the telephone or audio system in standard manner. Where two earphones are used, wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will include a Y-connector, not shown, but located behind the user&apos;s back in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, so that wires extend to both earphones. If desired, wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may also include a built in volume control <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and built in manual communication switch <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> for manually switching a microphone on and off. Depending upon the communication system used, a Y-connector may also be provided at the end of the wire near the communication device to separate wires to the speaker or speakers from wires from the microphone. Each set of wires would have its own plug to be placed into the appropriate socket of the communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Various speakers may be used in the earphones and mounted in speaker housing it. Some high duality speakers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> include a metal protective cover <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. It has been found that use of the earphones during strenuous activity by the user can result in perspiration or other moisture reaching this metal cover and causing it to corrode. Therefore, it is an aspect of the invention to place a waterproof material such as a thin layer of latex <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> over the metal speaker cover <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and sandwiching it between the usual corrosion resistant metal screen grill <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> with all parts held together by resilient ring <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The latex could extend completely around the speaker <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, if desired. The flexible, thin latex membrane <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> will transmit sound with substantially negligible loss. Adhesive can be placed around the perimeter of the membrane <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to increase the waterproofing properties thereof. If desired, sealing materials such as a silicone rubber, may be placed around the wires extending from the end of boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and any other openings in speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may be sealed to substantially increase the water resistant properties of the speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> around the speaker, although this is not necessary to prevent corrosion of the speaker cover <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> If the earphones are to be used merely for listening, the speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> will be closed behind the speaker as shown in my referenced patent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> It has been found that earphones are worn during the use of various communication systems, particularly where communication is necessary during activities which occupy the hands, such as in the operation of switchboards, or in noisy environments, such as in airplanes. There are other times where hands-free communication systems may be useful such as in law enforcement situations where a police officer, for example, may need to keep his or her hands free but would still like to be in constant communication with a remote location, such as police headquarters. Further, with the growth in use of cellular and similar telephones, people participating in activities such as jogging or driving may like to be able to communicate by such telephone in a hands-free manner during such activity. Comfortable earphones that securely mount on the ears, such as those described above, are a desirable feature of such a communication system. For two-way communication, however, a microphone is needed. For hands free communication, it is necessary that the microphone be held in operative position near a user-s mouth. Generally, this will entail mounting the microphone on an earphone. It will generally be advantageous in a communication system to have two earphones, one for each ear, as it is with a personal audio system. However, in some instances a single earphone may be desirable, particularly where, in addition to the communication, a person has to be able to hear all surrounding sounds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> For use with a communication system, provision is made to have the single earphone when only one earphone is used, or one of the earphones when two earphones are used, include mounting means for a microphone. As shown, a microphone arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> extends from a microphone arm mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> adapted to be rotatably mounted on a receiving section <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> at the back of speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Receiving section <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is circular with an outwardly extending flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> around its circular perimeter. The microphone arm mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> has a circular opening to fit over flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of speaker housing receiving section <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, with inwardly extending lip <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> that snaps over flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to secure the mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to receiving section <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> in a manner that allows the mounting base to be rotated with respect to speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Stop <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> on microphone arm mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> adjacent lip <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> interacts with stops <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> on speaker housing receiving section <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> to limit rotation of the microphone arm mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and microphone arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> extending therefrom to back and forth rotation of about 270 degrees with respect to the speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. At one extreme of rotation, the microphone arm will be positioned as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4, 5</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to extend from the earphone worn on the user&apos;s right ear. At the other extreme of rotation, the extremes of rotation being shown by arrow <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the microphone arm will extend similarly but from the earphone worn on the user&apos;s left ear and on the opposite side of the mouth as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. This rotatability allows a user to have the microphone arm extend from either the right or left earphone as desired or to change from one ear to the other. The rotatability of the speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> through rotation of boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in sleeve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> allows the orientation of speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to be easily changed for wearing She same earphone on either the right or left ear. The stops are positioned so that at either extreme of rotation they will hold and prevent the microphone arm from rotating downwardly during vigorous activity by the user. In this regard, it should be noted that with the stop arrangement described and with the microphone arm mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> properly mounted on speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the microphone arm would never extend straight downwardly as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. This position is for illustration purposes only or with an arrangement of stops which would allow such downward positioning. If desired, stop <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> on microphone arm mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may have an extended portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, that is compressed and frictionally resists movement of the mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> between stops <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and which expands into detentes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, when positioned against a stop <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to substantially lock the base in rotated position. Various other arrangements of stops, detentes, etc. could be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> A microphone <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 7</cross-reference> is positioned in the end of microphone arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A pair of wires <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> extend from microphone <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> through a bore <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> In microphone arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, into microphone arm mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and into speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. In speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> wires <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> join with wires <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to become part of multiconductor wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which extends to the communication device <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, worn by the user. Signals from the microphone are transmitted to the communication device by wires <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> while signals from the communication device or audio system are transmitted to the speaker <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by wires <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. For ease of assembly, or to make the microphone arm removable, a plug and socket assembly <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> for wires <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> may be provided in speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Microphone arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> will generally be flexible but shape retaining so it can be bent by a user to a desired configuration as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> to position the microphone to pick up sounds from a user&apos;s mouth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> When a speaker housing is constructed for mounting a microphone thereto, if it is desired to not use the microphone, the earphone may be set up so that the microphone arm mounting base <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is removable and can be snapped off speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and a small circular cover <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> with lip <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, can be removably snapped in place instead of the microphone arm mounting base. The microphone wires <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> would be separated at plug and socket assembly <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> when the microphone assembly is removed and reconnected when the microphone assembly is again mounted on speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> It is desirable to have the wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> containing the wires to speakers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and wires to microphone <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> extend in and along earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from the remote end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to a position near sleeve end <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In my earphones as shown in my cited patent, the earpieces were molded in two halves, the wire placed along one half, and the second half glued to the first half with the wire between the halves. I have now found that the earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be molded as single integral parts with a slit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> extending into the earpiece along a portion of its length intermediate the ends thereof. The interior of the slit can be molded with a wire receiving recess <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, therealong. Wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can then be inserted through earpiece remote end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> into slit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> using a needle or similar item and similarly extended through earpiece <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> at the opposite end of slit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> as at <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will preferably be inserted in a manner so that it is tightly held by end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, but loosely held by the passage through the opposite end. Wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> does not have to be in slit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> during these operations and generally will not be. With the wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> extended through the opposite ends of the earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (enough wire is inserted through the earpiece so that the wires extend to speaker <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and microphone <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, if used), it is then pushed into slit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The wire can then be extended through boom <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> leaving loop <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to allow slack for positional adjustment of speaker housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The wire can also be inserted through earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the opposite direction to that indicated, the particular direction and order of insertion not being critical. Once in recess <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, wire <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will remain within earpiece <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As indicated, the earphones of the invention can be used with various types of audio and communication systems which can be worn by a user such as in a manner shown by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, or located separate from a user such as if used, for example, in an automobile or airplane. Various systems and arrangements can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Whereas this invention is here illustrated and described with reference to embodiments thereof presently contemplated as the best mode of carrying out such invention in actual practice, it is to be understood that various changes may be made in adapting the invention to different embodiments without departing from the broader inventive concepts disclosed herein and comprehended by the claims that follow. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone for use by a user having an ear with an entrance to an auditory canal therein, comprising a speaker; a speaker housing mounting the speaker; an elongate boom extending from the speaker housing; ear mounting means; sleeve means in the ear mounting means for frictionally holding the boom therein and allowing forced sliding of the boom in the sleeve longitudinally to adjust positioning of the speaker housing with respect to the mounting means and forced rotation of the boom in the sleeve means to adjust orientation of the speaker housing with respect to the mounting means, whereby the ear mounting means in combination with the speaker housing and boom will cooperate with a user&apos;s ear to position and hold the speaker at the entrance of the user&apos;s auditory canal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the boom includes a stop at the end remote from the housing to prevent the boom from sliding completely through the sleeve and separating from the earpiece. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a wire extends from the earpiece, through the boom, into the speaker housing to connect with the speaker. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, additionally including a water-resistant material positioned over the speaker to resist moisture contacting the speaker. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, additionally including a microphone arm and means mounting the microphone arm to the speaker housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means mounting the microphone arm to the speaker housing includes a microphone arm mounting base from which the microphone arm extends, and a receiving section in the speaker housing for receiving in attaching relationship the microphone arm mounting base. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the receiving section of the speaker housing includes a circular portion having a peripheral flange, and the microphone arm mounting base includes a circular opening into which the receiving section extends and includes a lip which interlocks with the flange to secure the base to the receiving section and allow relative rotation between the two. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, additionally including cooperating stops on the receiving section and on the microphone arm mounting base to limit the amount of rotation of the mounting base with respect to the microphone housing, the amount of rotation allowed being sufficient to change the position of the microphone arm to properly position a microphone when the earphone is worn on either a right ear or left ear. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the microphone arm mounting base is removably secured to the receiving section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, additionally including a cap which is removably secured to the receiving section when the microphone arm mounting base is removed from the receiving section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ear mounting means is an elongate, curved earpiece, wherein the earpiece has an elongate slit therealong intermediate ends of the earpiece, and wherein a wire extending from a signal source to the earphone extends in and along the slit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the slit has a bottom, and wherein the slit includes a wire receiving recess extending along the bottom of the slit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone for use by a user having an ear with an entrance to an auditory canal therein, comprising a speaker; a speaker housing mounting the speaker; an elongate, curved earpiece having ends; means mounting the speaker housing to the earpiece whereby the earpiece in combination with the speaker housing will cooperate with a user&apos;s ear to position and hold the speaker at the entrance of the user&apos;s auditory canal; and wire extending from the speaker housing through the earpiece and from the earpiece for connection to a signal source, said earpiece being formed with a slit therealong intermediate its ends, said wire extending along the slit as it extends through the earpiece. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the slit has a bottom, and wherein the slit includes a wire receiving recess extending along the bottom of the slit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone for use by a user having an ear with an entrance to an auditory canal therein, comprising a speaker; a speaker housing mounting the speaker; ear mounting means; means mounting the speaker housing to the ear mounting means whereby the ear mounting means in combination with the speaker housing will cooperate with a user&apos;s ear to position and hold the speaker at the entrance of the user&apos;s auditory canal; a microphone arm; a microphone arm mounting base from which the microphone arm extends; a receiving section in the speaker housing for removably and rotatably mounting the microphone arm mounting base to the speaker housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, additionally including cooperating stops on the receiving section and on the microphone arm mounting base to limit the amount of rotation of the mounting base with respect to the microphone housing, the amount of rotation allowed being sufficient to change the position of the microphone arm to properly position a microphone when the earphone is worn on either a right ear or left ear. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An ear mounted earphone according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, additionally including a cap which is removably secured to the receiving section when the microphone arm mounting base is removed from the receiving section.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002706A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002706A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002706A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
