<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000709A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000709A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000709</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10223048</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020816</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E21B019/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>166</class>
<subclass>380000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>166</class>
<subclass>384000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>166</class>
<subclass>207000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Expandable liner and associated methods of regulating fluid flow in a well</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10223048</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020816</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09565000</doc-number>
<document-date>20000504</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6478091</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Gano</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Carrollton</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Halliburton Energy Services, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KONNEKER SMITH</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>660 NORTH CENTRAL EXPRESSWAY</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 230</address-2>
<city>PLANO</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75074</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of regulating flow through a first tubular structure in a well provides flow control by use of an expandable second tubular structure inserted into the first tubular structure and deformed therein. In a described embodiment, a liner has sealing material externally disposed thereon. Expansion of the liner within a screen assembly may be used to sealingly engage the liner with one or more well screens of the screen assembly, and may be used to regulate a rate of fluid flow through one or more of the well screens. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to operations performed in conjunction with a subterranean well and, in an embodiment described herein, more particularly provides an expandable liner and associated methods of regulating flow through tubular structures in a well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A wellbore may intersect multiple formations or zones from which it is desired to produce fluids. It is common practice to utilize well screens and gravel packing where the formations or zones are unconsolidated or poorly consolidated, in order to prevent collapse of the wellbore or production of formation sand. Thus, fluid production from one zone may flow through one well screen while production from another zone may pass through another well screen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> It is frequently desirable to be able to individually control the rate of production from different zones. For example, water encroachment or gas coning may prompt a reduction or cessation of production from a particular zone, while production continues from other zones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventional practice has been to use a valve, such as a sliding sleeve-type valve, or a downhole choke to regulate fluid flow from a particular zone. However, where well screens are also utilized, it is often impractical, costly and inconvenient to use conventional valves or chokes to regulate fluid flow through the screens. Therefore, it is an object of the present invention to provide an improved method of regulating fluid flow through well screens. It is a further object of the present invention to provide methods and apparatus for regulating fluid flow through various tubular structures in a well. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In carrying out the principles of the present invention, in accordance with an embodiment thereof, a specially configured expandable liner is utilized in regulating fluid flow through a tubular structure in a wellbore. The flow regulating systems and methods described herein also permit economical, convenient and accurate control of production through individual well screens and screen assemblies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In one aspect of the present invention, a screen assembly including multiple well screens is installed in a wellbore. An expandable liner is then inserted into the screen assembly. The liner is expanded by any of various methods (e.g., inflation, swaging, etc.), so that the liner is sealingly engaged with the interior of the screen assembly. For example, the liner may be sealingly engaged straddling a well screen, so that fluid flow through the well screen must also pass through an opening formed through a sidewall of the liner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Expansion of the liner may also be used to control the rate of fluid flow through the screen assembly. For this purpose, a sealing material may be disposed externally on the liner between an inflow area of a well screen and the opening formed through the liner sidewall. By squeezing the sealing material between the liner and the screen assembly, a flow area formed between portions of the sealing material is reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> By retracting the liner inwardly away from the screen assembly, the flow area may also be increased, thereby increasing the rate of fluid flow through the well screen. Thus, the flow rate through the screen may be increased or decreased as desired by retracting or expanding the liner within the screen assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The exterior of the liner which contacts the interior of the screen assembly may be configured to provide further regulation of fluid flow. For example, the sealing material may have one or more channels formed therein or therethrough. The channels may be tortuous to provide flow choking. Plugs may be provided to reduce the number of channels through which fluid may flow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Tools for expanding and retracting the liner are also provided by the present invention. One such tool includes a sensor sensing a parameter, such as flow rate, temperature, pressure, etc., of the fluid flowing through a well screen. This permits the effect of expansion or retraction of the liner to be evaluated downhole for an individual well screen, or for multiple screens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> These and other features, advantages, benefits and objects of the present invention will become apparent to one of ordinary skill in the art upon careful consideration of the detailed description of representative embodiments of the invention hereinbelow and the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-E are schematic views of successive steps in a method of regulating flow through well screens, the method embodying principles of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an enlarged scale schematic view of a first method of expanding a tubular structure in the method of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A&amp;B</cross-reference> are enlarged scale schematic views of a second method of expanding a tubular structure in the method of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a first system for regulating flow through well screens, the system embodying principles of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A&amp;B</cross-reference> are schematic cross-sectional views of the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, taken along line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a first tool used to expand a liner, the tool embodying principles of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a second tool used to expand a liner, the tool embodying principles of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a second system for regulating flow through well screens, the system embodying principles of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic elevational view of a first expandable liner embodying principles of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic elevational view of a second expandable liner embodying principles of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A&amp;B</cross-reference> are schematic cross-sectional views of a tool for retracting a liner, the tool embodying principles of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an alternate configuration of the tool of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A&amp;B</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a tool for expanding a liner, the tool embodying principles of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a method of regulating flow through casing, the method embodying principles of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Representatively illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-E is a method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> which embodies principles of the present invention. In the following description of the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and other apparatus and methods described herein, directional terms, such as &ldquo;above&rdquo;, &ldquo;below&rdquo;, &ldquo;upper&rdquo;, &ldquo;lower&rdquo;, etc., are used only for convenience in referring to the accompanying drawings. Additionally, it is to be understood that the various embodiments of the present invention described herein may be utilized in various orientations, such as inclined, inverted, horizontal, vertical, etc., and in various configurations, without departing from the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Referring initially to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, in the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> including multiple well screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is conveyed into a wellbore <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The wellbore <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> intersects multiple formations or zones <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from which it is desired to produce fluids. The screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are positioned opposite respective ones of the zones <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The wellbore <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-E as being uncased, but it is to be clearly understood that the principles of the present invention may also be practiced in cased wellbores. Additionally, the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is depicted as including three individual screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, with only one of the screens being positioned opposite each of the zones <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, but it is to be clearly understood that any number of screens may be used in the assembly, and any number of the screens may be positioned opposite any of the zones, without departing from the principles of the present invention. Thus, each of the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> described herein and depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-E may represent multiple screens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Sealing devices <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are interconnected in the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> between, and above and below, the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The sealing devices <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> could be packers, in which case the packers would be set in the wellbore <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to isolate the zones <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from each other in the wellbore. However, the sealing devices <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are preferably expandable sealing devices, which are expanded into sealing contact with the wellbore <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> when the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is expanded as described in further detail below. For example, the sealing devices <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> may include a sealing material, such as an elastomer, a resilient material, a nonelastomer, etc., externally applied to the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B, the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has been expanded radially outward. The sealing devices <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> now sealingly engage the wellbore <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> between the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and above and below the screens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> preferably contact the wellbore <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at the zones <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Such contact between the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the wellbore <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may aid in preventing formation sand from being produced. However, this contact is not necessary in keeping with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The use of an expandable screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has several benefits. For example, the radially reduced configuration shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> may be advantageous for passing through a restriction uphole, and the radially expanded configuration shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> may be advantageous for providing a large flow area and enhanced access therethrough. However, the use of an expandable screen assembly is not required in keeping with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C, an expandable tubular structure or liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is received within the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> includes sealing devices <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> straddling flow control devices <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Note that the sealing devices <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are similar to the sealing devices <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in that they are radially expandable, but they may alternatively be conventional devices, such as packers, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The flow control devices <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are shown schematically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C, and are described in further detail below. Each of the flow control devices <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is used to regulate fluid flow through one of the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Production of the fluid to the surface is accomplished through the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, and the fluid passes inwardly through an inflow area of each screen (typically, a series of openings <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> formed through a base pipe of each screen), thus, each of the flow control devices <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> regulates fluid flow between the inflow area of one of the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the interior of the liner assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> A series of sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is carried externally on the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be any type of sensors, such as, temperature sensors, pressure sensors, water cut sensors, flowmeters, etc., or any combination of sensors. The sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are interconnected by one or more lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, which are preferably fiber optic, but which may be any type of line, such as hydraulic, electrical conductor, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> If the lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are fiber optic, then the lines may extend to the earth&apos;s surface, or they may terminate at a downhole junction <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The junction <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> may be a converter and may transform an optical signal on the lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to an electrical signal for transmission to a remote location. Alternatively, the junction <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> may be an item of equipment known to those skilled in the art as a wet connect or inductive coupling, whereby a tool (not shown) conveyed on wireline or another conveyance may be placed in communication with the sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, via the lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. As another alternative, the lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> may enter the interior of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> at the junction <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and extend uphole through the liner assembly to a remote location. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> If the lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are fiber optic, then the lines themselves may be used to sense temperature downhole. It is well known that light passing through a fiber optic line or cable is changed in a manner indicative of the temperature of the fiber optic line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>D, the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> has been expanded radially outward, so that the sealing devices <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are in sealing contact with the interior of the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The sealing devices <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> straddle the screen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, thereby constraining fluid flow through the screen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to also flow through the flow control device <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The sealing devices <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> straddle the screen <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, thereby constraining fluid flow through the screen <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to also flow through the flow control device <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The sealing devices <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> straddle the screen <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, thereby constraining fluid flow through the screen <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to also flow through the flow control device <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Note that the sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and junction <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>E, an alternate configuration of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is depicted, in which only portions of the liner assembly have been radially expanded. In this case, the sealing devices <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> have been expanded into sealing contact with the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> This result may be accomplished by utilizing a tool (described below) which is capable of individually expanding portions of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, selected portions of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which are desired to be expanded may be made less resistant to expansion than the remainder of the liner assembly. For example, the sealing devices <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may have a thinner cross-section, may be made of a more readily expandable material, may be initially configured at a larger radius, thereby producing greater hoop stresses, etc. In this manner, an inflation pressure may be applied to the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the portions less resistant to expansion will expand at a rate greater than the remainder of the liner assembly. A tool for applying an inflation pressure to the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A&amp;B</cross-reference> and is described below, but it should be understood that such an inflation pressure could also be applied directly to the liner assembly, for example, at the surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Expansion of selected portions of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may also be used to regulate fluid flow through the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. For example, if the flow control devices <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are made less resistant to radial expansion, so that flow regulating portions thereof (described in further detail below) are radially compressed when the inflation pressure is applied to the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, this compression of the flow regulating portions may be used to restrict fluid flow through the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The manner in which compression of a flow regulating portion of a flow control device may be used to alter a flowpath thereof and thereby regulate fluid flow therethrough is described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Note that the sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may now be used to individually measure characteristics of fluid flow between the respective zones <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the interior of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Of course, other parameters and characteristics may be sensed by the sensors <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, without departing from the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> swaging tool <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is shown being displaced through a tubular structure <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The tubular structure <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> may be the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> or the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> described above. As the swaging tool <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is displaced through the tubular structure <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, the tubular structure is radially expanded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A&amp;B</cross-reference>, a tubular membrane or inflation tool <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is used to radially expand a tubular structure <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The tubular structure <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> may be the screen assembly <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> or the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> described above. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, the inflation tool <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is received within the tubular structure <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, with the inflation tool being in a deflated configuration. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>B, the inflation tool <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> has been inflated, for example, by applying a fluid pressure to the interior thereof, thereby causing the tubular structure to be expanded radially outward. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> embodying principles of the present invention is representatively illustrated. The flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be used for the flow control devices <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, or it may be used in other methods. As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is positioned within a well screen <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of a screen assembly <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Sealing devices <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> constrain fluid flowing inwardly through the screen <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to also pass through the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> before entering an internal axial flow passage <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of a tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in which the flow control device is interconnected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> includes a flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, which operates in response to a degree of compression thereof. Note that the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is positioned radially between the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the screen assembly <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. When the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is radially expanded, the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is compressed between the tubular structure and the screen assembly <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Conversely, when the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is radially retracted, the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is decompressed. This degree of compression of the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is used to control the rate of fluid flow between the inflow area <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> of the screen <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and openings <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> formed through a sidewall of the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A&amp;B</cross-reference>, the manner in which the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> controls the rate of fluid flow therethrough is representatively illustrated. Note that the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> includes multiple longitudinal flowpaths or channels <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> formed between circumferentially distributed longitudinal strips <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of sealing material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In addition, the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> includes a semicircular longitudinal channel <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> in which lines <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> are received. The lines <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> may be similar to the lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> described above. In this manner, the lines <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> may be easily and conveniently attached to the exterior of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> while it is being run into the well. That is, the lines <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> are snapped into the longitudinal channel <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> as the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is lowered into the well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>A, the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> has been radially expanded sufficiently for the strips <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of sealing material to contact the interior of the screen assembly <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Flow area for fluid flow between the screen inflow area <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and the openings <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is provided by the channels <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>B, the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> has been further radially expanded. The sealing material has been compressed between the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the screen assembly <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, so that the channels <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> are now reduced in height and width, thereby reducing the flow area therethrough. Still further expansion of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> may completely close off the channels <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, thereby preventing fluid flow therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Note that the lines <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> remain in the channel <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and do not affect, or only minimally affect, the amount of flow area through the channels <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. No fluid flow is permitted through the channel <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> due to the compression of the strip <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of sealing material on which the channel is formed. As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>B, the lines <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> are compressed in the channel <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> between the sealing material and the screen assembly <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Of course, the lines <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> could be sealingly installed in the channel <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> initially, if desired, in which case compression of the strip <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of sealing material may not be used to seal the lines <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> in the channel <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> may be radially retracted from its configuration as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> to its configuration as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>. In this manner, restriction to fluid flow through the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> may be decreased if it is desired to increase the rate of fluid flow through the screen <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> It will, thus, be readily appreciated that the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> provides a convenient means of regulating fluid flow through the well screen <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Expansion of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> restricts, or ultimately prevents, fluid flow through the channels <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, and retraction of the tubular structure decreases the restriction to fluid flow through the channels, thereby increasing the rate of fluid flow through the screen <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> which may be used to expand selected portions of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is representatively illustrated received within the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> may be used to expand the sealing devices <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> into sealing contact with the screen assembly <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, may be used in the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to expand portions of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> includes a set of axially spaced apart seals <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, such as cup seals, and a tubular housing go. The tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> may be conveyed on a coiled tubing string <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> or other type of tubular string. Pressure is applied to the tubing string <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> to cause an expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to expand, thereby expanding a portion of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> opposite the expansion portion of the tool. Note that it is not necessary for the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to be conveyed on the tubing string <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, since pressure for expansion of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> may be delivered by a downhole pump conveyed on wireline, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In conjunction with use of the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to expand portions of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, the seals <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and openings <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> in the housing go are used to monitor fluid flow through the screen <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Specifically, when it is desired to monitor fluid flow through the screen <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, the seals <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> are positioned straddling the openings <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Fluid flowing inwardly through the openings <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> between the seals <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is thus constrained to flow inwardly through the openings <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and into the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> includes a check valve or float valve <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and a sensor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The check valve <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> prevents fluid pressure applied to the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to expand the expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> from being transmitted through the openings <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to the area between the seals <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. The sensor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is used to indicate a parameter of the fluid flowing through the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. For example, the sensor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is schematically represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> as a flowmeter, but it is to be clearly understood that the sensor may sense temperature, pressure, water cut, etc., or any other parameter of the fluid in addition to, or instead of, the flow rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> In operation, the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is conveyed into the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and positioned so that the expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is opposite the portion of the tubular structure to be expanded. As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is positioned opposite the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Pressure is applied to the tubular string <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, causing the expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> to expand radially outward, and thereby causing the expansion portion to contact and radially expand the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, radial expansion of the expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> would cause radial compression of the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, thereby increasing the restriction to fluid flow therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The effectiveness of this operation may be verified by repositioning the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> so that the seals <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> straddle the openings <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Fluid flowing inwardly through the openings <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> will flow into the openings <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, and parameters, such as flow rate, may be measured by the sensor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. If the flow rate is too high, the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> may again be repositioned so that the expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is opposite the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and the operation may be repeated until the desired flow rate is achieved. Note that a bypass passage <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may be provided in the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, so that production from the well below the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be continued during the expansion and flow rate measuring operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> It will be readily appreciated that the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> provides a convenient and effective means for individually adjusting the rate of fluid flow through well screens downhole. This result is accomplished merely by conveying the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> into the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, positioning it opposite the structure to be expanded, applying pressure to the tool, and repositioning the tool to verify that the flow rate is as desired. While the fluid flow rate is being adjusted and verified, the bypass passage <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> permits production from the well below the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to continue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, an enlarged scale cross-sectional view of the expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is representatively illustrated. The expansion portion <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> includes an annular-shaped resilient member <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> carried on a generally tubular mandrel <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. A piston <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is also carried on the mandrel <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The piston <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is in fluid communication with an internal fluid passage <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> of the mandrel <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> by means of openings <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> formed through a sidewall of the mandrel. Pressure applied internally to the tubing string <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is communicated to the passage <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> and is, thus, applied to the piston <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, biasing the piston downwardly and thereby axially compressing the member <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. When the member <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is axially compressed, it also expands radially outward. Such radially outward expansion of the member <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may be used to radially expand portions of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Note that the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> may be used to individually regulate fluid flow through multiple well screens. For example, in the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>E, the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> may be used to expand the flow control devices <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> so that a flow rate through the screen <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is less than a flow rate through the screen <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and the flow rate through the screen <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is less than a flow rate through the screen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. This result may be accomplished merely by using the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to expand a flow regulating portion of the flow control device <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> more than expansion of a flow regulating portion of the flow control device <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and to expand the flow regulating portion of the flow control device <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> more than expansion of a flow regulating portion of the flow control device <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Thus, the flow rate through each of the screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be individually controlled using the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, an alternate configuration of a flow control device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> embodying principles of the present invention is representatively illustrated. The flow control device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is similar in many respects to the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> described above, and it is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> received within the screen assembly <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Portions of the flow control device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> which are similar to those of the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> using the same reference numbers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The flow control device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> differs from the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> in part in that the flow control device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has the openings <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> axially separated from the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. Thus, as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A&amp;B</cross-reference>, the openings <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of the flow control device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are not located at the bottoms of the channels <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> but are instead positioned between the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and the sealing device <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9, a</cross-reference> flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> which may be used for the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> in the flow control device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is representatively illustrated. The flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> includes channels <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> formed thereon in sealing material <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The channels <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> undulate, so that they are at some points more restrictive to fluid flow therethrough than at other points. This channel configuration may provide a desired restriction to flow through the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> when the material <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is radially compressed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> A plug <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may be installed in one or more of the channels <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to further restrict fluid flow through the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may be set up before it is installed, based on information about the particular zone from which fluid will be produced through the flow regulating portion, to provide a desired range of flow restriction. This is readily accomplished by selecting a number of the channels <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> in which to install the plugs <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, another alternate configuration of a flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is representatively illustrated. The flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> has channels <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> formed thereon, which follow tortuous paths across the flow regulating portion. The tortuous shape of the channels <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> provides restriction to fluid flow through the channels. One or more of the channels <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be plugged, if desired, to provide further restriction to flow, for example, by using one or more of the plugs <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The channels <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> have been described above as if they are formed with an open side facing outwardly on the flow regulating portions <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. However, it is to be clearly understood that the channels <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> may be otherwise-shaped and may be differently positioned on the flow regulating portions <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, without departing from the principles of the present invention. For example, the channels <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> could be formed internally in the flow regulating portions <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the channels could have circular cross-sections, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A&amp;B</cross-reference>, a tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> used to radially retract portions of a tubular structure <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is representatively illustrated. The tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is preferably conveyed on a tubular string <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, such as a coiled tubing string, but it could also be conveyed by wireline or any other conveyance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is inserted into the tubular structure <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and seals <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> carried externally on the tool are positioned straddling a portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> of the tubular structure to be retracted. In the example depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A&amp;B</cross-reference>, the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> corresponds to a flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of a flow control device <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. Pressure is then applied to the tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, which causes a pressure decrease to be applied in the area between the seals <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> includes a piston <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> reciprocably received within a generally tubular outer housing <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> of the tool. Openings <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> are formed through the piston <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and provide fluid communication with an axial passage <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, which is in fluid communication with the interior of the tubing string <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Openings <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> are formed through the housing <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, providing fluid communication with the exterior thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> When pressure is applied to the passage <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> via the tubing string <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, the differential between the pressure in the passage and the pressure external to the housing <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> causes the piston <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> to displace upwardly, thereby creating a pressure decrease in the area between the seals <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. This creates a pressure differential across the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, causing the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> to radially retract inwardly toward the tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Thus, the piston <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and associated bores of the housing <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> in which the piston is sealingly engaged are a pressure generator for producing a decreased pressure between the seals <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Referring specifically now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>B, the tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and tubular structure <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> are depicted after the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> has been radially retracted. Note that the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is decompressed as compared to that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A and</cross-reference>, therefore, flow therethrough should be less restricted. A bypass passage <highlight><bold>147</bold></highlight> permits production of fluids from the well below the tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> during use of the tool, since the bypass passage interconnects the well below the tool with an annulus <highlight><bold>149</bold></highlight> formed between the tool and the tubular structure <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> above the seals <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, an alternate configuration of the retraction tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is representatively illustrated. Only a lower portion of the alternately configured retraction tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, it being understood that the remainder of the tool is similar to that described above in relation to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A&amp;B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The alternately configured retraction tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> differs substantially from the retraction tool depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A&amp;B</cross-reference> in that, instead of the seals <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, the retraction tool depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> includes two annular pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> sealingly and reciprocably disposed on the housing <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> have seals <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> carried externally thereon for sealing engagement straddling the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> to be retracted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Additionally, a series of annular stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> are positioned between the pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Each of the stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> is generally C-shaped, so that the stop members may be radially expanded as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. When radially expanded, the stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> are inherently biased radially inwardly, due to the resiliency of the material (e.g., steel) from which they are made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> are radially expanded when the pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> displace toward each other and the stop members are &ldquo;squeezed&rdquo; between the pistons and wedge members <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> positioned between the stop members. The pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and wedge members <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> have inclined surfaces formed thereon so that, when the pistons displace toward each other, the stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> are radially expanded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are made to displace toward each other when the piston <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> displaces upwardly as described above, that is, when fluid pressure is applied to the passage <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. It will be readily appreciated that a reduced pressure in the area between the pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (due to upward displacement of the piston <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>) will bias the pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> toward each other. When fluid pressure is released from the passage <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, the pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are no longer biased toward each other, and the resiliency of the stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> will bias the pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> to displace away from each other, thereby permitting the stop members to radially retract. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the piston <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> has displaced upwardly, thereby creating a reduced pressure in the area between the pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> have displaced toward each other, and the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> has radially retracted, in response to the reduced pressure. The stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> have been radially expanded in response to the displacement of the pistons <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and serve to prevent further radial retraction of the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Thus, the stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> are useful in limiting the radial retraction of the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. For example, the stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> may be dimensioned to prevent the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> from being radially retracted to such an extent that it prevents retrieval of the tool <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, or the stop members <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> may be dimensioned to cause the portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> to radially retract to a certain position, so that the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> provides a desired restriction to flow therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13, a</cross-reference> tool <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> used to radially extend portions of a tubular structure <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> is representatively illustrated. The tool <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is preferably conveyed on a tubular string <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>, such as a coiled tubing string, but it could also be conveyed by wireline or any other conveyance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The tool <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is inserted into the tubular structure <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> and seals <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> carried externally on the tool are positioned straddling a portion <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> of the tubular structure to be extended. In the example depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, the portion <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> corresponds to a flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> of a flow control device <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. Pressure is then applied to the tool <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, which causes a pressure increase to be applied in the area between the seals <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The tool <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> includes a piston <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> reciprocably received within a generally tubular outer housing <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> of the tool. Openings <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> are formed through the piston <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> and provide fluid communication with an axial passage <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>, which is in fluid communication with the interior of the tubing string <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>. Openings <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> are formed through the housing <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, providing fluid communication with the exterior thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> When pressure is applied to the passage <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> via the tubing string <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>, the differential between the pressure in the passage and the pressure external to the housing <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> causes the piston <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> to displace downwardly against an upwardly biasing force exerted by a spring or other bias member <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>, thereby creating a pressure increase in the area between the seals <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. Due to multiple differential areas formed on the piston <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> and housing <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, the pressure between the seals <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> is greater than the pressure in the passage <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>, although the use of multiple differential areas and a pressure between the seals greater than pressure in the passage is not necessary in keeping with the principles of the present invention. The piston <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> and the bores of the housing <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> in which the piston is sealingly received, thus, form a pressure generator for producing an increased pressure between the seals <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> This pressure increase between the seals <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> creates a pressure differential across the portion <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, causing the portion <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> to radially extend outwardly away from the tool <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Such outward extension of the portion <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> may be used to decrease a rate of fluid flow through the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> When the fluid pressure is released from the passage <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>, the spring <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> displaces the piston <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> upward, and the tool <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is ready to radially extend another portion of the tubular structure <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, for example, to regulate flow through another flow control device, etc. Alternatively, fluid flow through the flow regulating portion <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> may be checked after the portion <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> is extended, for example, utilizing the seals <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, housing go and sensor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> as described above for the tool <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, and the portion <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> may be further extended by applying further fluid pressure to the passage <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>, if needed to further reduce fluid flow through the flow regulating portion. A bypass passage <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> permits production of fluid from the well below the tool <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> during the use of the tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Referring additionally now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, another method <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> embodying principles of the present invention is representatively illustrated. The method <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is similar in many respects to the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> described above. However, the method <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is performed in a wellbore <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> lined with protective casing <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>, and well screens are not utilized. Instead, fluid flow from a formation or zone <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> intersected by the wellbore <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> enters perforations <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> formed through the casing <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> and passes through a flow control device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> interconnected between sealing devices <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in a liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. In the method <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>, the perforations <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> are analogous to the inflow area (the openings <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>) of the each of the well screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The sealing devices <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may be similar to any of the sealing devices <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> described above. The flow control device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be similar to any of the flow control devices <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> In the method <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>, the liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is conveyed into the wellbore <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> and positioned so that the sealing devices <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> straddle the perforations <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight>. The liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is expanded radially outward as described above for the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Substantially all of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> may be expanded, or only portions thereof (such as the sealing devices <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>) may be expanded. For example, selected portions of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> may be configured so that they are less resistant to extension thereof than other portions of the liner assembly, as described for the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> above in relation to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1E</cross-reference>. Expansion of the liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> causes the sealing devices <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to sealingly engage the casing <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> on each side of the perforations <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The flow control device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may then be utilized to regulate a rate of fluid flow into the liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. To regulate the fluid flow, a flow regulating portion of the flow control device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be compressed between the liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and the casing <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> by radially outwardly expanding a portion of the flow control device, as described above for the flow regulating portions <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. The tools <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> may be used with the liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> to radially expand or retract portions of the liner assembly to increase or decrease fluid flow through the flow regulating portion of the flow control device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Thus, the method <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> demonstrates that the principles of the present invention may be utilized in cased wellbores and in situations where a screen assembly is not utilized. In general, the liner assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is used to control fluid flow through the casing <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> in the method <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> in a manner similar to the way the liner assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is used to control fluid flow through the well screens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in the method <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> It will now be fully appreciated that the present invention provides convenient, economical and functionally enhanced regulation of fluid flow downhole. Additionally, flow through well screens may be individually controlled and monitored using the principles of the present invention. This result is accomplished merely by expanding and retracting portions of a tubular structure with an associated flow regulating device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Of course, a person skilled in the art would, upon a careful consideration of the above description of representative embodiments of the invention, readily appreciate that many modifications, additions, substitutions, deletions, and other changes may be made to these specific embodiments, and such changes are contemplated by the principles of the present invention. Accordingly, the foregoing detailed description is to be clearly understood as being given by way of illustration and example only, the spirit and scope of the present invention being limited solely by the appended claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of controlling fluid flow through a first tubular structure positioned in a well, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>positioning a second tubular structure within the first tubular structure in the well; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>deforming the second tubular structure, thereby altering a flowpath for flow of fluid through a first sidewall of the first tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the positioning step the second tubular structure is in a radially contracted configuration, and in the deforming step the second tubular structure is deformed to a radially enlarged configuration thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises radially retracting the second tubular structure, thereby increasing a flow area of the flowpath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises sealingly engaging the second tubular structure with the first tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises radially extending the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step comprises contacting the first tubular structure with an outer sealing material of the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the contacting step comprises decreasing a flow area disposed between adjacent portions of the sealing material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step comprises increasing a flow area of the flowpath disposed between portions of a sealing material of the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step comprises changing a flow area of the flowpath disposed externally on the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the changing step, a width of a longitudinal channel in fluid communication with an opening formed through a second sidewall of the second tubular structure is changed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the changing step, a depth of a longitudinal channel in fluid communication with an opening formed through a second sidewall of the second tubular structure is changed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath includes at least one restriction of the flow area, and wherein the changing step further comprises changing a resistance to fluid flow through the restriction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the restriction is formed externally on the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the restriction is formed between portions of sealing material on the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the restriction is formed in a channel formed externally on the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first tubular structure comprises a well screen, and wherein the deforming step further comprises sealingly engaging the second tubular structure at opposite ends of the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises outwardly extending the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step further comprises compressing a member within the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step further comprises displacing a swaging tool in the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step further comprises inflating a membrane within the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first tubular structure includes a well screen, and wherein the inflating step further comprises sealingly engaging portions of the second tubular structure with opposite ends of the well screen, thereby constraining fluid flow through the well screen to also flow through the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step further comprises extending only selected portions of the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the extending step, the selected portions are configured so that they are less resistant to extension thereof than unselected portions of the second tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises altering a flow area disposed radially between the second tubular structure and the first tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the deforming step, the flow area is disposed axially between an opening formed through a sidewall of the second tubular structure and an inflow area of the first tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second tubular structure includes a flow control device disposed between external seals, and wherein the extending step further comprises extending the seals into contact with the first tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath is a tortuous path formed on the second tubular structure, and wherein the deforming step further comprises engaging the tortuous path with the first tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the steps of positioning a sensor within the second tubular structure after the deforming step and sensing a parameter of fluid flowing through the flowpath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method of controlling fluid flow through multiple well screens of a screen assembly positioned in a wellbore, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>positioning a tubular structure within the screen assembly; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>deforming the tubular structure, thereby altering at least one flowpath for flow of fluid through at least one of the well screens. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises altering multiple flowpaths for flow of fluid through corresponding respective ones of the well screens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises altering first and second flowpaths for flow of fluid through first and second well screens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the altering step, the first flowpath is altered to restrict fluid flow therethrough differently from restriction to fluid flow through the second flowpath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of sealingly engaging the screen assembly with the wellbore between adjacent ones of the well screens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the positioning step the tubular structure is in a radially contracted configuration, and in the deforming step the tubular structure is deformed to a radially enlarged configuration thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises radially retracting the tubular structure, thereby increasing a flow area of the flowpath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises sealingly engaging the tubular structure with the screen assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises radially extending the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step comprises contacting the screen assembly with an outer sealing material of the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the contacting step comprises decreasing a flow area disposed between adjacent portions of the sealing material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step comprises increasing a flow area of the flowpath disposed between portions of a sealing material of the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step comprises changing a flow area of the flowpath disposed externally on the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the changing step, a width of a longitudinal channel in fluid communication with an opening formed through a sidewall of the tubular structure is changed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the changing step, a depth of a longitudinal channel in fluid communication with an opening formed through a sidewall of the tubular structure is changed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath includes at least one restriction of the flow area, and wherein the changing step further comprises changing a resistance to fluid flow through the restriction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the restriction is formed externally on the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the restriction is formed between portions of sealing material on the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the restriction is formed in a channel formed externally on the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises sealingly engaging the tubular structure with the screen assembly straddling at least one of the well screens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises outwardly extending the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step further comprises displacing a swaging tool in the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step further comprises compressing a member within the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step further comprises inflating a membrane within the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extending step further comprises extending selected portions of the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the extending step, the selected portions are configured so that they are less resistant to extension thereof than unselected portions of the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inflating step further comprises sealingly engaging portions of the tubular structure straddling at least one of the well screens, thereby constraining fluid flow through the well screen to also flow through the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deforming step further comprises altering a flow area disposed radially between the tubular structure and the screen assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in the deforming step, the flow area is disposed axially between an opening formed through a sidewall of the tubular structure and an inflow area of the screen assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular structure includes a flow control device disposed between external seals, and wherein the extending step further comprises extending the seals into contact with the screen assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath is a tortuous path formed on the tubular structure, and wherein the deforming step further comprises engaging the tortuous path with the screen assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the steps of positioning a sensor within the tubular structure after the deforming step and sensing a parameter of fluid flowing through the flowpath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of outwardly deforming the screen assembly, so that the well screens contact the wellbore. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 61</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of outwardly deforming the screen assembly is performed prior to the step of positioning the tubular structure within the screen assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. A system for controlling fluid flow in a wellbore, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>a well screen in the wellbore; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tubular structure received in the well screen, the tubular structure being deformed after reception within the well screen, thereby altering a flowpath for flow of fluid through the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a sensor positioned within the tubular structure, the sensor sensing a parameter of fluid flowing through the flowpath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath is a tortuous path formed on the tubular structure, and wherein the tortuous path is engaged with the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular structure includes a flow control device disposed between external seals, the seals being sealingly engaged straddling the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00067">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deformed tubular structure alters a flow area disposed radially between the tubular structure and the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00068">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 67</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flow area is disposed axially between an opening formed through a sidewall of the tubular structure and an inflow area of the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00069">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular structure is deformed so that it is outwardly extended relative to a configuration of the tubular structure prior to its reception within the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00070">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 69</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular structure includes selected portions thereof which are less resistant to outward extension thereof than unselected portions of the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00071">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 70</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a membrane received within the tubular structure, the membrane being inflated and thereby outwardly extending the selected tubular structure portions greater than the unselected tubular structure portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00072">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 70</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the selected tubular structure portions straddle the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00073">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 70</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the selected portions are sealingly engaged straddling the well screen, thereby constraining fluid flow through the well screen to also flow through the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00074">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a flow area disposed radially between the tubular structure and the well screen is altered by deformation of the tubular structure after reception within the well screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00075">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular structure includes at least one selected portion thereof which is less resistant to radial displacement than unselected portions of the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00076">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 75</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath extends across the selected tubular structure portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00077">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 76</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an area of the flowpath is decreased by radial extension of the selected tubular structure portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00078">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 76</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an area of the flowpath is increased by radial retraction of the selected tubular structure portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00079">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath is disposed externally on the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00080">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath is disposed at least partially in an external sealing material of the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00081">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 80</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath is disposed between portions of the sealing material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00082">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 80</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flowpath is disposed at least partially in a channel formed in the sealing material, the channel being in fluid communication with an opening formed through a sidewall of the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00083">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. A tool for radially deforming a tubular structure within a subterranean well, the tool comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>axially spaced apart seals carried externally on the housing; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure generating device configured for generating a pressure differential across a portion of the tubular structure when the seals are sealingly engaged with the tubular structure axially straddling the tubular structure portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00084">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 83</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pressure generating device increases fluid pressure between the seals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00085">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 84</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pressure generating device includes a piston responsive to a first fluid pressure in an internal passage of the housing to generate a second fluid pressure between the seals, the second fluid pressure being greater than the first fluid pressure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00086">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 83</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pressure generating device decreases fluid pressure between the seals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00087">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 86</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pressure generating device includes a piston responsive to a first fluid pressure in an internal passage of the housing to generate a second fluid pressure between the seals, the second fluid pressure being less than the first fluid pressure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00088">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 83</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the housing has an exterior and extends on opposite sides of the seals, and further comprising a bypass passage permitting fluid flow through the housing from the exterior of the housing on one opposite side of the seals to the exterior of the housing on the other opposite side of the seals when the seals are sealingly engaged with the tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00089">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 83</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a stop member carried externally on the housing, the stop member limiting radial deformation of the tubular structure when the pressure generating device generates the pressure differential across the tubular structure portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00090">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 89</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the stop member limits radially inward deformation of the tubular structure when the pressure generating device generates the pressure differential across the tubular structure portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00091">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00088">claim 89</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the stop member is extended outwardly when the pressure generating device generates the pressure differential across the tubular structure portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00092">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 91</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a piston carried externally on the housing, the piston displacing the stop member when the pressure generating device generates the pressure differential across the tubular structure portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00093">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight>. A tool for radially deforming a tubular structure within a subterranean well, the tool comprising: 
<claim-text>a generally tubular mandrel having an internal fluid passage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an annular member carried externally on the housing, the member extending radially outward when the member is axially compressed; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston responsive to fluid pressure in the fluid passage to axially compress the member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00094">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 93</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tool has an exterior and extends on opposite sides of the member, and further comprising a bypass passage permitting fluid flow through the tool from the exterior of the tool on one opposite side of the member to the exterior of the tool on the other opposite side of the member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00095">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 93</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising axially spaced apart external seals carried on a housing attached to the mandrel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00096">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 95</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an opening formed through a sidewall of the housing between the seals is in fluid communication with the mandrel fluid passage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00097">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 96</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a check valve permitting fluid flow from the opening to the mandrel fluid passage, but preventing fluid flow from the mandrel fluid passage to the opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00098">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 96</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a sensor, the sensor sensing a property of fluid flowing from the opening through the mandrel fluid passage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00099">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. The tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00099">claim 98</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor is a flowmeter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00100">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. A method of controlling fluid flow through a first tubular structure positioned in a well, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>installing a line externally on a second tubular structure having a sealing material carried externally thereon, the line extending across the sealing material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the second tubular structure within the first tubular structure in the well; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sealingly engaging the sealing material with the first tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00101">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The method according to claim <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, wherein in the installing step, the line is installed in a channel formed externally on the sealing material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00102">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The method according to claim <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, wherein in the sealingly engaging step, the line is sealingly engaged with the sealing material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00103">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. The method according to claim <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, wherein in the sealingly engaging step, the line is compressed between the sealing material and the first tubular structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00104">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The method according to claim <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, wherein in the installing step, the sealing material is part of a flow regulating portion of the second tubular structure, the sealing material having deformable flow channels formed thereon for adjusting a flow area therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00105">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The method according to claim <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, wherein the installing step further comprises installing the line in an external channel positioned between adjacent ones of the flow channels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00106">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The method according to claim <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, wherein the installing step further comprises interconnecting the line with a sensor external to the second tubular structure, and further comprising the step of establishing communication via the line between a remote location and the sensor on opposite sides of the sealing material after the sealingly engaging step.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1C 1D</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030000709A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
