<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005449A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005449A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005449A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005449A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005449</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896921</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04N007/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H04N007/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>078000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>067000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>070000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>071000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>System and method for content delivery to lodging entertainment systems</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lee</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>McKenna</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Canistota</city>
<state>SD</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Clay</given-name>
<middle-name>B.</middle-name>
<family-name>Meyer</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sioux Falls</city>
<state>SD</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Fenno</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sioux Falls</city>
<state>SD</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KINNEY &amp; LANGE, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>THE KINNEY &amp; LANGE BUILDING</address-1>
<address-2>312 SOUTH THIRD STREET</address-2>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55415-1002</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Entertainment content is delivered in an encrypted digital format from a home base via satellite to individual lodging properties (sites) having an in-room entertainment system. Each digital file containing content (such as a movie) is accompanied by a sites file which identifies the name of the content file and the sites to which the content file is being transmitted. Each site includes a host computer, a digital content receiver, a digital content server guest terminals in the guest rooms, and a distribution network for distributing content from the digital content server to the guest terminals. The digital content receiver receives the transmitted digital content and sites files, and provides the files to the digital content server for storage and later use. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION(S) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> None. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to systems that provide in-room entertainment at hotels and other lodging facilities. In particular, the invention is an improved system for delivery of entertainment content such as movies to individual hotel sites. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The past two decades have seen the wide scale introduction of entertainment systems in hotels and other lodging facilities. These systems provide a variety of services to the guest through the guest room television. The services typically include regular off-air television programs, pay-per-view movies, Internet access, and guest services such as video shopping and video checkout. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A typical hotel entertainment system contains a head end, a distribution system, and guest terminals located in each of the guest rooms. The head end includes devices to generate entertainment content such as movies and video games, as well as devices to provide Internet access and generate interactive menus and other services. The head end also includes modulators and video switching equipment necessary to place the television signals from the various sources on to the appropriate channels for transmission through the distribution system to the guest terminals. A host computer coordinates operation of the entertainment system by receiving key stroke information from the guest terminals and controlling operations of various sources of television signals so that the guest receives the entertainment or services which he or she has requested. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Typically, lodging entertainment systems are not owned by the hotel, but rather are owned by a vendor who provides the head end equipment, and the guest terminals (including the television, remote control, game controller, keyboard, and associated control circuitry which interfaces the television to the distribution system). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The entertainment system vendor owns the equipment and pays for the installation of the system in the lodging facility. The vendor must also provide the content, such as movies, games, and cable/satellite programming. The vendor receives compensation based upon amounts the hotel collects from the guest for pay-per-view movies, games, Internet access, and other services for which charges are made. The hotel usually receives a percentage of the guest charges, and the sources of content, such as motion picture studios and game program vendors, receive royalties for movies and games which are viewed and played by guest. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In the past, most of the video sources for pay-per-view movies in hotel entertainment systems have been video cassette players pre-loaded with videotapes of movies. Although the early systems offered only a small number of movies (typically six or eight) at scheduled playing times, the widespread adoption of video-on-demand movie offerings has resulted in the need for many more video tapes and video cassette players. Typical systems include from about 16 to more than 20 different movie offerings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The use of video cassette players and video tapes requires substantial tape duplication resources, and a service organization to deliver new tapes to each site, remove old or damaged tapes, and set up the system with a new lineup of movie offerings. This has, in the past, involved a monthly visit from service personnel to replace or change over movies. If tapes break or malfunction, additional service visits are required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> More recently, the development of very large mass memories and digital video server technology has offered an alternative to the use of arrays of video cassette players and videotapes. The digital server stores movies and other digital content in an encoded format such as MPEG-2 and includes decoders for decoding the digital data to create the audio and video television signals which are supplied to the guest terminal through the distribution system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> While the use of digital servers in a lodging entertainment system offers a number of advantages, the need for monthly service calls is not eliminated. Service personnel still must visit each site with a storage medium containing the content for the next month. This may be stored, for example, on a replaceable disk drive which is swapped each month by the service person. Duplication of storage media for each site is also required, just like in the systems that require the use of videotapes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> There is a continuing need for a system of delivering entertainment content to individual sites that reduces the number of visits required by service personnel to maintain conventional entertainment systems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> An improved system for delivering entertainment content to individual sites makes use of satellite transmission. The digital content is delivered from a home base of the system vendor, to a satellite uplink and then by satellite to each of the sites in the form of encrypted digital files representing the individual items of content (such as a movie). A sites file is associated with and transmitted prior to each digital file. The sites file identifies the digital file to be transmitted, and the intended recipients of that file. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> At each site, a digital content receiver receives the sites file and the associated digital file. Based upon the information contained in the sites file, the digital content receiver checks whether the digital files are intended for its site, and checks a directory of digital content already stored by a digital content server at the site. If the digital file to be transmitted is intended for that site, and if the digital content server has not already stored a file of that particular content, then the digital content server stores the digital file. The file is transferred to the digital content server, where it is stored and is listed in a directory of stored content. The stored content is then available for purchase on a guest-selectable basis over a distribution network located at the site. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagram of a digital entertainment content distribution system.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagram of digital entertainment content distribution system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> which delivers digital entertainment content (DEC) from home base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and then via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. For simplicity, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a single site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>&mdash;a hotel having an in-room entertainment system. In practice, DEC distribution system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> typically includes many sites in different geographic locations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Home base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is typically the corporate headquarters of the entertainment system vendor. Home base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes encoding server <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, system server <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, corporate LAN <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, corporate firewall <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and internal firewall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. System server <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> communicates with uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and sites <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through Internet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Encoded DEC is delivered to uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> either on high capacity storage device <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (such as a tape or a hard disc drive) or through Internet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes satellite uplink server <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, remote link <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and firewall <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Encoded DEC, along with related sites files, is provided by satellite uplink server <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for transmission to satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Other files, such as schedule files, software updates, and diagnostic information may also be transmitted to satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> includes satellite dish <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, digital content receiver (DCR) <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, Ethernet switch <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, digital content server <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, distribution system or network <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and guest terminals <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. For a further description of the components of network <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, see U.S. application Ser. No. 09/724,289, filed Nov. 28, 2000, for &ldquo;Lodging Entertainment System with Guest-Selected Time Shifting&rdquo; by D. Bankers, S, Silverberg, G. Kolbeck, B. Pelletier, and R. Califf. Each guest terminal <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> includes a television, a remote control, a game controller, a keyboard and a control card in the television which interfaces guest terminal <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> with network <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, UNIX host controller <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Prior to transmission of the DEC from satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the DEC is encrypted at home base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> using encoding server <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Encoding server <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> preferably uses GNU&apos;s Pretty Good Privacy (PGP) software to encrypt the DEC. The encrypted DEC is typically delivered to satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by storing the DEC on high capacity storage device <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and shipping high capacity storage device <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The encrypted DEC can also be delivered to satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via Internet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> As the DEC is encrypted, a &ldquo;sites file&rdquo; is attached to each DEC file (i.e., movie, video game, etc.). The sites file contains the name of the DEC file, a flag to indicate whether the DEC file is to be delivered to all sites, and, at times, an individual flag for every site that is to receive the DEC file. For example, if the flag indicating whether the DEC file is to be delivered to all sites is activated, then all sites having a satellite downlink would receive the DEC file, and no individual sites would be listed. Alternatively, if the flag indicating whether the DEC file is to be delivered to all sites is deactivated, then a list of individual sites to receive the DEC file (with flags activated) would also be included in the sites file. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> After delivery of the DEC to satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the sites files attached to each respective DEC file are added to an uplink list located on satellite uplink server <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Satellite uplink server <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is connected to satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and regulates the DEC transmitted over satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, according to the sites files in the uplink list. That is, the uplink list contains a list of all of the sites files that are to be broadcast over satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The software on satellite uplink server <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> continuously checks the uplink list to determine if any changes have been made to the list. If the uplink list has not changed, then satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> continues to broadcast the DEC listed in the unchanged uplink list. If the uplink list has been changed, satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> will start broadcasting the first DEC file listed in the uplink list. In both circumstances, when the last DEC file list in the uplink list has been sent, satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> starts over with the first DEC file listed in the uplink list and begins retransmission of all DEC files. The continuous retransmission of DEC files increases the probability that site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> receives at least one errorless copy of each DEC file. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> To understand the delivery of DEC between satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, an example involving the transmission of a single DEC file is provided. To begin, the sites file for the DEC file to be sent is transmitted by satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Satellite uplink server <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> then pauses briefly to allow site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to receive the sites file on a first reception channel on satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and to determine whether it is one of the sites included in the sites file. If site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is not included in the sites file, satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> will keep the first reception channel open and await transmission of subsequent sites files from satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. If site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is included in the sites file, site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> will open a second reception channel on satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and will receive the DEC file subsequently transmitted from satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by satellite uplink <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. After a DEC file is received by satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, a process to decrypt the DEC file is started. Once the decryption process has started, satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> will listen on the first reception channel for the next sites file transmitted from satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> stores the encrypted DEC after it has been received on satellite dish <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> contains a removable hard drive, preferably having a storage capacity of at least 75 gigabytes (GB). A hard drive this size is necessary to store all of the new DEC that is delivered to site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> at one time. Furthermore, the DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> hard drive preferably contains one partition with three directories: an &ldquo;acquire&rdquo; directory, a &ldquo;content&rdquo; directory, and a &ldquo;history&rdquo; directory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The &ldquo;acquire&rdquo; directory is used to acquire content from satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. After a DEC file has been acquired and placed in the acquire directory, the DEC file is then decrypted on DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. During the decryption process, the DEC file is decrypted into a file having a name such that the DEC file will not be recognized by UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> as being available for user purchase until the decryption process is complete. Decryption is performed on DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> because the decryption process is very CPU intensive and takes a considerable amount of time. In this embodiment, decryption is not performed on DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (where the guest-selectable DEC files are stored), since this would adversely affect the playing of the DEC. Once the decryption process is complete, the DEC file is renamed so that the DEC file will be recognized as being decrypted and ready for import to DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Finally, the original encrypted DEC file is removed from the acquire directory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The &ldquo;content&rdquo; directory is where a DEC file is placed by DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> after it has been successfully decrypted. UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> accesses this directory through Ethernet switch <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> to determine if a new DEC file available to be installed on DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> determines whether a DEC file is new by comparing the name DEC file in the &ldquo;content&rdquo; directory with the names of the DEC files on DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. If the DEC file is new, UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> begins installation of the new DEC file on DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> through Ethernet switch <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. When installing DEC from DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, care must be taken to ensure that each file is copied in its entirety. Because there are three separate systems involved in the installation process (DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>), site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> must be able to recover if any one of the systems goes down. Thus, when a DEC file is copied from the content directory on DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, a temporary DEC file is stored on DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Once the copy is completed, the temporary DEC file is given its permanent name and the DEC file is removed from DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. If the copy process fails, the next time the DEC file is installed from DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> will begin copying over the temporary DEC file on DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The &ldquo;history&rdquo; directory is used to keep track of the DEC files that have been successfully received on satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. After a DEC file has been decrypted and placed in the content directory, a zero byte file having the same name as the file placed in the content directory is created in the history directory. When a sites files is subsequently received on satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the history directory is checked to see if a file with the same name already exists. If such a file exists, the sites file is ignored, the content is not received, and satellite downlink <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> continues to listen for future sites files. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> When delivery of DEC via satellite is impractical or impossible, an alternative method of delivery is necessary. DEC can also be manually delivered by service personnel to site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> via a hard drive. In this situation, there is no need for a sites file to be generated; all of the content that will be written to the hard drive will be destined for a particular remote location. When the hard drive arrives at site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the service personnel shuts down DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, and swaps the new hard drive with the existing removable hard drive in DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Then, the service personnel restarts DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, and subsequently starts the DEC decryption process. The DEC is decrypted by DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into the same directory structure (described above) as if the content was delivered via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. This allows the DEC import process to work in the same manner for either type of delivery method. The manual delivery of a hard drive containing DEC to site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be used until a satellite distribution system is installed at a property, as a backup to that system, or as a permanent means of content delivery if a satellite receiver cannot be installed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> contains a hard drive with sufficient capacity to store all of the digital content for site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The hard drive in DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has different directories for each of the different services offered at site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. For example, DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may contain a directory for movies, a directory for music, and a directory for video games. This gives the ability for each site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to have a customized schedule of service, (i.e. different DEC) depending upon its needs. Site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may also incorporate multiple DCS&apos;s, depending on the size of site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, in which each DCS would contain the same DEC. Having multiple DCS&apos;s would decrease the possibility of overworking a single DCS. Overworking a DCS could adversely affect the playing of DEC. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> When a guest wishes to purchase DEC, the guest presses a key on the remote control to turn on the television. A welcome screen will first appear on the TV screen of guest terminals <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. If the guest wishes to view off-air or satellite programming, which is free programming, those channels are accessible by-pressing the channel up or channel down keys on the remote control. If, on the other hand, the guest wishes to view and perhaps select other offerings available on DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, such as on-demand movies, Internet access, interactive video games, recording of broadcast programs for time-shifted viewing, or interactive services, the welcome channel screen provides an instruction to the user to select a menu. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In order to provide guests with the described on-screen menus and messages, a file, called a &ldquo;schedule import file,&rdquo; must also be delivered to site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. This file may be delivered either at the same time as the encrypted DEC file via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, or independent from the encrypted DEC files, such as via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or Internet <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The schedule import file contains a schedule file and related GIF and text files. The schedule file may include a schedule for every service (e.g. movie, game, time-shifted TV programming, etc.) that requires scheduling, or it may contain a schedule just for those services that require a schedule change. Each schedule includes fields for different aspects of the service to which the schedule pertains. Thus, example fields in a movie schedule are the title of the movie, the category of the movie (e.g., action, adventure, new release, etc.), the movie rating, the purchase price of the movie, the start date of the movie (i.e., the date the movie first can be purchased), and the end date of the movie (i.e., the date the movie last can be purchsed). The GIF and text files are used in conjunction with the schedule file to present menus, on-screen descriptions and order screens to guests the DEC services in a visual format on the television screen at guest terminals <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> One important aspect of the present invention is the ability to deliver DEC at any time desired, rather than on a monthly basis, as was typical in entertainment systems requiring manual delivery of DEC. This is advantageous because, for example, new release movies typically are released at various times throughout a month. In other words, new release movies are not released at a certain point each month. This was problematic in entertainment systems requiring manual delivery of DEC each month because, if a movie was released shortly after the monthly delivery, several weeks would pass before the newly released movie would be available at a particular site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. According to the present invention, as soon as a movie is released, it can be sent from satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and be available for viewing at guest terminals <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> as soon as the day of release. In order to alert guests of the availability of the new movie, the new schedule import file (which would typically be sent at the same time as the new movie) may contain textual and visual alerts that would be displayed on the welcome screen. This alert system is especially important for long-stay guests, who can be informed of the latest updates to available DEC simply by turning on the television at guest terminals <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a method of delivering digital entertainment content from a central location to remote locations for use in an entertainment system offering guest-selectable entertainment content at the remote locations. In the past, most of the video sources for pay-per-view movies in hotel entertainment systems have been video cassette players pre-loaded with videotapes of movies. More recently, the development of very large mass memories and digital video server technology has offered an alternative to the use of arrays of video cassette players and videotapes. However, service personnel still must visit each site with a storage medium containing the content for the next month. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> To reduce the number of visits required by service personnel, the present invention allows electronic delivery of entertainment content in digital format from home base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to remote site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The DEC is first encoded at home base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Then, the encoded DEC is delivered to satellite uplink facility <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, where it is transmitted to the DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> at site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Once the encoded DEC arrives at site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> decrypts the DEC and stores it on DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The DEC is then accessible through the guest terminals <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> for purchase. This method of delivery is advantageous in that the DEC can be updated at any time, thus giving guests access to constantly current entertainment content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The present invention is compatible with a wide variety of different DEC of differing length, subject matter, and marketing lifetime. For example, in addition to providing movies and video games as DEC, home base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can also provide music, time-shifted television programs, and web videos. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of the present invention is the ability to transmit software updates, (e.g., for UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>), as well as DEC files, site files, and schedule files. DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> recognizes software updates as different files from schedules, sites files, and DEC, and routes the software update files to the appropriate device, such as UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. This further reduces the need for trips to every site <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> whenever a system upgrade is made. The system also allows diagnostic information to be exchanged between home base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and sites <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> either via satellite <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or the Internet <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, or by a combination of both. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The present invention also provides an important advantage during the initial installation of the entertainment system at each site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The installation may be made without requiring the installation personnel to install the DEC or the related schedule files in the system. Instead, the installation begins with the setup of satellite downlink <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, Ethernet switch <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, UNIX host computer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Then, while network <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and guest terminals <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> are being installed, DEC is being received, decrypted, and stored in DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. By the time the rest of the system is installed, DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is loaded with the latest DEC and is ready to begin operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Although the present invention has been described with reference to preferred embodiments, workers skilled in the art will recognize that changes may be made in form and detail without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. For example, in an alternative embodiment DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes on-the-fly decryption hardware and software associated with each output port, so that decryption takes place at DCS <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> rather than at DCR <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. This requires greater hardware/software cost at each site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, but provides greater security since the DEC is always stored in encrypted form. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of delivering digital entertainment content to a site having an in-room entertainment system including a digital content receiver, a digital content server, a distribution network and a plurality of guest terminals for selecting and receiving entertainment content transmitted from the digital content server over the distribution network, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>opening a first reception channel on the digital content receiver at the sites; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting via satellite, to the first reception channel at the site, a sites file containing an identification of sites to receive the digital entertainment content; </claim-text>
<claim-text>opening a second reception channel on the digital content receiver at the site if it is identified in the sites file; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting via satellite, to the open second reception channel at the site, the digital entertainment content; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the digital entertainment content with the digital content receiver; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the digital entertainment content from the digital content receiver to the digital content server. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>encrypting the digital entertainment content at a home base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>delivering the encrypted digital entertainment content from the home base to a satellite uplink; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>decrypting the digital entertainment content for delivery by the digital content server over the distribution network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the digital content receiver maintains a list of the digital entertainment content received by the digital content receiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the list of the digital entertainment content received by the digital content receiver is compared to the digital entertainment content received on the second reception channel to prevent duplication. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including: 
<claim-text>regulating, with a host computer interface, the digital entertainment content transfer from the digital content receiver to the digital content server. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, at the sites omitted from the sites file, the first reception channel remains open to receive subsequent sites files. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sites file includes a designation flag such that, when the designation flag is activated, all sites open the second reception channel on the digital content receiver to receive the digital entertainment content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>transmitting schedule files via satellite to the sites. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method of delivering digital entertainment content from a first location to remote locations for use in an entertainment system offering guest-selectable entertainment content at the remote locations, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>encrypting the digital entertainment content at the first location; </claim-text>
<claim-text>delivering the encrypted digital entertainment content from the first location to a satellite uplink location; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting via satellite the encrypted digital entertainment content from the satellite uplink location to remote locations; </claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the encrypted digital entertainment content on a digital content receiver; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the digital entertainment content on the digital content receiver to a digital content server; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the digital entertainment content on the digital content server. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further including: 
<claim-text>regulating, with a host computer interface, the digital entertainment content transfer from the digital content receiver to the digital content server. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the digital content receiver maintains a list of the digital entertainment content received by the digital content receiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the list of the digital entertainment content received by the digital content receiver is compared to the digital entertainment content received via satellite to prevent duplication. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, in case of satellite malfunction, the digital entertainment content is transmitted to the remote locations via a terrestial link. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>transmitting schedule files via satellite to the remote locations. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An entertainment system comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of guest terminals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a distribution system connected to the guest terminals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a digital content server for storing digital entertainment content in digital files and supplying the entertainment content signals based upon the digital files over the distribution system to the guest terminals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a digital content receiver for receiving digital entertainment content via satellite, and storing the entertainment content on the digital content server; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a computer which communicates with the guest terminals over the distribution system and controls operation of the digital content receiver and the digital content server. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the digital content receiver includes a hard drive for storing digital entertainment content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the removable hard drive contains an acquire directory, a content directory and a history directory. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer controls the installation of the digital entertainment content from the digital content receiver to the digital content server. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, in response to a request from a guest terminal, the computer causes the digital content server to supply digital entertainment content based upon the digital file representing selected content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer provides the guest terminals with on screen information about the digital entertainment content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer provides information on screen about the digital entertainment content based upon a schedule file received by the digital content receiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer controls operation of the digital content server based upon a selection by a guest of digital entertainment content to be viewed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method of delivering digital content to a site having a digital content receiver, a digital content server, a distribution network and a plurality of video devices for viewing the content transmitted from the digital content server over the distribution network, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>opening a first reception channel on the digital content receiver at the sites; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting via satellite, to the first reception channel at the site, a sites file containing an identification of sites to receive the digital content; </claim-text>
<claim-text>opening a second reception channel on the digital content receiver at the site if it is identified in the sites file; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting via satellite, to the open second reception channel at the site, the digital content; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the digital content with the digital content receiver; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the digital content from the digital content receiver to the digital content server. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>encrypting the digital content at a home base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>delivering the encrypted digital content from the home base to a satellite uplink; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>decrypting the digital content for delivery by the digital content server over the distribution network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, at the sites omitted from the sites file, the first reception channel remains open to receive subsequent sites files. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sites file includes a designation flag such that, when the designation flag is activated, all sites open the second reception channel on the digital content receiver to receive the digital entertainment content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>transmitting schedule files via satellite to the sites.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005449A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005449A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
