<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000409A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000409A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000409A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000409A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000409A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000409A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000409A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000409A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000409</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10186795</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B41N001/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>101</class>
<subclass>454000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>101</class>
<subclass>467000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Printing plate with dyed and anodized surface</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60302396</doc-number>
<document-date>20010702</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sallie</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Blake</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Long Grove</city>
<state>IA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Albert</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Askin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lower Burrell</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Bombalski</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>New Kensington</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Daniel</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Serafin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Wexford</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ALCOA INC</name-1>
<name-2>ALCOA TECHNICAL CENTER</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>100 TECHNICAL DRIVE</address-1>
<city>ALCOA CENTER</city>
<state>PA</state>
<postalcode>15069-0001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A printing plate for computer-to plate lithography having a metal substrate with an anodized surface portion. The anodized surface portion has a porous texture in which a radiation-absorbing composition, preferably a black dye, is deposited. The surface portion with the radiation-absorbing composition is covered with a hydrophilic polymer or a sealant both. Upon exposure to laser radiation, the underlying oleophilic anodized surface portion containing the radiation-absorbing composition is revealed. Alternatively, laser radiation of the polymer composition may cause the affinity of the polymer for water and ink to change so that an irradiated portion of the polymer becomes oleophilic while the non-irradiated portion remains hydrophilic. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/302,396 filed Jul. 2, 2001 entitled &ldquo;Printing Plate With Dyed And Anodized Surface.&rdquo;</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to printing plates suitable for imaging by digitally controlled laser radiation. More particularly, the invention relates to a printing plate having a dyed, anodized metal substrate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Printing plates suitable for imaging by digitally controlled laser radiation include a plurality of imaging layers and intermediate layers coated thereon. Laser radiation suitable for imaging printing plates preferably has a wavelength in the visible or near-infrared region, between about 400 and 1500 nm, typically at about 830 nm. Solid state laser sources (commonly termed &ldquo;semiconductor lasers&rdquo;) are economical and convenient sources that may be used with a variety of imaging devices. Other laser sources such as CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>lasers and lasers emitting light in the visible wavelengths are also useful. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Laser output can be provided directly to the plate surface via lenses or other beam-guiding components, or transmitted to the surface of a blank printing plate from a remotely sited laser through a fiber-optic cable. Some prior art patents disclosing printing plates suitable for imaging by laser ablation are Lewis et al. U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,339,737; 5,996,496 and 5,996,498. These prior art printing plates require multiple layers of differing materials and often are costly to produce. Accordingly, a need remains for a simple and inexpensive radiation treatable printing plate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> This need is met by the printing plate of the present invention having a metal substrate with an anodized surface portion. The surface portion defines a plurality of pores containing a radiation-absorbing composition. A coating composition covers the surface portion along with the radiation-absorbing composition. The metal may be an aluminum alloy that may be roll textured to have a roughness of about 5 to about 45 microinches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The radiation-absorbing composition may be oleophilic while the coating composition is hydrophilic such as an acrylic polymer. A suitable acrylic polymer is a copolymer of vinyl phosphonic acid and acrylic acid cured under conditions such that said copolymer is hydrophilic or oleophilic. If the radiation-absorbing composition is hydrophilic, the coating composition may be oleophilic. Other suitable coating compositions include nickel acetate, silicate, and polyvinylphosphonic acid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The coating composition may be ablated by radiation directed onto the coating composition overlying the radiation-absorbing composition. Alternatively, a first affinity for ink by the coating composition may change to a second affinity for ink when the coating composition overlying the radiation-absorbing composition is subjected to radiation without ablation of the coating composition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The printing plate may further include a sealant composition disposed between the radiation-absorbing composition and the coating composition. In that case, both of the sealant composition and the coating composition overlying the radiation-absorbing composition are ablatable by radiation directed thereto. Alternatively, the sealant and coating compositions may not be ablated. Instead, a first affinity for ink by the coating composition may change to a second affinity for ink when the coating composition overlying the radiation-absorbing composition is subjected to radiation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention also includes a method of imaging having the steps of (i) providing a printing plate having a metal substrate with an anodized surface portion defining a plurality of pores, a radiation-absorbing composition received in the pores, and a coating composition covering the surface portion with the radiation-absorbing composition; and (ii) exposing the printing plate to a pattern of imaging radiation such that a first portion of the printing plate has an affinity for a printing fluid and a second portion of the printing plate has a different affinity for the printing fluid. The exposing step may include ablating the coating composition in the location of the pattern of imaging radiation to reveal the anodized surface portion as the first portion of the printing plate, the coating composition not exposed to the radiation being the second portion of the printing plate. Alternatively, the exposing step may include changing the affinity of the coating composition for a printing fluid in the location of the pattern of imaging radiation to the different affinity.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a printing plate made in accordance with the present invention having a coating composition; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the printing plate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> following radiation ablation of the coating composition; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of an alternative view of the printing plate of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> following radiation treatment of the coating composition to change the affinity of the coating composition for a printing liquid; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a printing plate made in accordance with the present invention having a sealant layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the printing plate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> following radiation ablation of the sealant layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a printing plate made in accordance with the present invention having a sealant layer covered with a coating composition; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the printing plate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> following radiation ablation of the sealant layer and coating composition; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the printing plate of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> following radiation treatment of the coating composition to change the affinity of the coating composition for a printing liquid.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> For purposes of the description hereinafter, it is to be understood that the invention may assume various alternative variations and step sequences, except where expressly specified to the contrary. It is also to be understood that the specific products and processes illustrated in the attached drawings, and described in the following specification, are simply exemplary embodiments of the invention. Hence, specific dimensions and other physical characteristics related to the embodiments disclosed herein are not to be considered as limiting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the present invention includes a printing plate <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> having a metal substrate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> with an anodized principal surface portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> defining a plurality of pores or wells <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> therein. A radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which absorbs radiation, is deposited in the pores <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of a polymeric coating composition covers the anodized surface portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, including the radiation-absorbing composition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The substrate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> may be an anodizable metal such as an alloy of aluminum, titanium or magnesium. Suitable aluminum alloys include alloys of the AA 1000, 3000, and 5000 series. The substrate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> preferably has a thickness of about 1-30 mils, preferably about 5-20 mils, and more preferably about 8-20 mils. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the substrate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is roll textured using one or more rolls treated with a texturing means to provide an extended surface area to the substrate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The texture of the treated roll has a substantially uniform topography which imparts a substantially uniform topography in the rolling and cross-rolling directions of the substrate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and having an Ra value of about 5 to about 45 microinches wherein the Ra ratio of rolling to cross-rolling is about 0.8 to 1.2, as described in U.S. Pat. No. 6,290,632 entitled &ldquo;Ultrafine Matte Finish Roll for Treatment for Sheet Products and Method of Production&rdquo;, incorporated herein by reference. The texturing means may be electron discharge texturing, laser texturing, electron beam, shot peening, mechanical texturing, and chemical etching and some combination thereof, preferably electron discharge texturing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The principal surface portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> may be cleaned to remove surface contaminants such as lubricant residues. Suitable chemical surface cleaners include alkaline and acid aqueous solutions. Plasma radiation, corona discharge and laser radiation may also be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> A conventional anodization process may be used to create the pores <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. For an aluminum alloy substrate, the substrate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is placed in a conventional anodizing bath containing a conductive electrolyte such as sulfuric acid, phosphoric acid, oxalic acid, chromic acid or salicylic acid to produce a layer of porous alumina. The dimensions of the pores <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> may be controlled by the concentration of the electrolyte in the bath and the bath temperature. A suitable concentration of the electrolyte is about 10-30 wt. %. A preferred electrolyte bath contains about 20 wt. % sulfuric acid. When the substrate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is an aluminum alloy, anodization creates a layer of alumina on the surface portion, which is about 0.05 to about 0.7 mil thick. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is applied to the surface portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> by spraying, brushing, dipping or the like and is absorbed into the pores <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and become trapped therein. The radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> maybe an oleophilic material, which absorbs infrared radiation such as a black dye. A suitable dye is an azine compound or an azide compound or any other dye that absorbs light having a wavelength in the range of about 500 to about 1100 nanometers. One such dye is Nigrosine Base BA available from Bayer Corporation of Pittsburgh, Pa. The anodized metal generally is hydrophilic. However, by including an oleophilic radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the pores <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the surface portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> may become oleophilic depending on the amount and composition of the radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> deposited in the pores <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be hydrophilic and the surface portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> remains hydrophilic following deposition of the hydrophilic radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the pores <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The polymer coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> preferably includes an acrylic polymer, more preferably a copolymer of an organophosphorus compound. As used herein, the term &ldquo;organophosphorus compound&rdquo; includes organophosphoric acids, organophosphonic acids, organophosphinic acids, as well as various salts, esters, partial salts, and partial esters thereof. The organophosphorus compound may be copolymerized with acrylic acid or methacrylic acid. Copolymers of vinyl phosphonic acid are particularly preferred, especially copolymers containing about 5-50 mole % vinyl phosphonic acid and about 50-95 mole % acrylic acid and having a molecular weight of about 20,000-100,000. Copolymers containing about 70 mole % acrylic acid groups and about 30 mole % vinyl phosphonic acid groups are particularly preferred. The acrylic polymer may be applied in batch processing of sheet or in coil processing by conventional coating processes including roll coating, powder coating, spray coating, vacuum coating, emulsion coating or immersion coating. Preferably, the acrylic polymer is applied by roll coating, typically to a thickness of about 0.001-1.0 mil, preferably about 0.01-0.03 mil. Acrylic polymers including copolymers of vinyl phosphonic acid and acrylic acid are hydrophilic when cured at about 420&deg; F. for about two minutes. These same acrylic polymers may be made oleophilic when cured at about 500&deg; F. for about two minutes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In use, the printing plate <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is imaged with a laser or the like. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> pattern of radiation R from a laser ablates the coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the regions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the printing plate <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in which ink is to be received. Ablation of the coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> exposes regions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the substrate leaving unablated regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The ablated regions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are oleophilic while the unablated regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> remain hydrophilic. Ink of a printing liquid containing water or a fountain solution will adhere to the ablated regions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> while the unablated regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> will be covered with water or a fountain solution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The regions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may have a reverse affinity for ink and water. In that case, a hydrophilic material is used as the radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (e.g. Nigrosine WLF from Bayer) and the polymer coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is oleophilic. A suitable oleophilic polymer is a copolymer of vinyl phosphonic acid and acrylic acid cured at about 500&deg; F. for about two minutes. Following ablative imaging with a laser, the ablated regions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are hydrophilic and the unablated regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are oleophilic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the invention shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a hydrophilic polymer, e.g. a copolymer of vinyl phosphonic acid and acrylic acid cured at about 420&deg; F. for about two minutes. A pattern of imaging radiation R from a laser or the like causes regions <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to become oleophilic (without ablating the coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) while unexposed regions <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> remain hydrophilic. Ink of a printing liquid containing water or a fountain solution will adhere to the regions <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> while the regions <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> will be covered with water or a fountain solution. It is believed that when radiation is absorbed by the radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, heat is generated which is conducted to the regions <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Heating of the regions <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is believed to change the surface chemistry of the polymer such that the affinity of the regions <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for a printing liquid is altered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A second embodiment of the invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. Printing plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes a sealant layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The sealant layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> plugs the pores <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and may be continuous or discontinuous over the principal surface portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Suitable materials for the sealant layer are oleophobic and include nickel acetate, silicate, polyvinyl phosphonic acid and copolymers of acrylic acid and vinyl phosphonic acid. Preferably, the sealant layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is applied to the principal surface portion in an immersion process. A pattern of imaging radiation R shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> causes the sealant layer to ablate in regions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> leaving unablated regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The ablated regions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are oleophilic, while the unablated regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are oleophobic. Ink of a printing liquid containing water or a fountain solution will adhere to the ablated regions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> while the unablated regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> will be covered with water or a fountain solution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> A third embodiment of the invention is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Printing plate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> includes sealant layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (as described above) and a coating composition <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Coating composition <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is similar to coating composition <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and includes a hydrophilic polymer, e.g. a copolymer of vinyl phosphonic acid and acrylic acid cured at about 420&deg; F. for about two minutes. In one aspect of the invention shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> pattern of imaging radiation R from a laser or the like causes the sealant layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and the polymer coating composition <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to ablate in regions <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> leaving unablated regions <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Unablated regions <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> are hydrophilic while the ablated regions <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> are oleophilic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Alternatively as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, radiation R causes regions <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of the coating composition <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to become oleophilic (without ablating the layer <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) while unexposed regions <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> remain hydrophilic. Ink of a printing liquid containing water or a fountain solution will adhere to the regions <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> while the regions <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> will be covered with water or a fountain solution. It is believed that when radiation is absorbed by the radiation-absorbing composition <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, heat is generated which is conducted to the regions <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of the layer <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Heating of the regions <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is believed to change the surface chemistry of the polymer such that the affinity of the regions <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> to a printing liquid is altered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> It will be readily appreciated by those skilled in the art that modifications may be made to the invention without departing from the concepts disclosed in the foregoing description. Accordingly, the particular embodiments described in detail herein are illustrative only and are not limiting to the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Having described the presently preferred embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention may be otherwise embodied within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A printing plate comprising: 
<claim-text>a metal substrate having an anodized surface portion, said surface portion defining a plurality of pores; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a radiation-absorbing composition received in said pores; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a coating composition covering said surface portion and said radiation-absorbing composition. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said metal is an aluminum alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said substrate is roll textured. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said substrate has a roughness of about 5 to about 45 microinches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said radiation-absorbing composition is oleophilic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said radiation-absorbing composition comprises a black dye. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating composition is hydrophilic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating composition comprises an acrylic polymer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said acrylic polymer comprises a copolymer of vinyl phosphonic acid and acrylic acid cured under conditions such that said copolymer is hydrophilic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said radiation-absorbing composition is hydrophilic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said radiation-absorbing composition comprises a black dye. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating composition is oleophilic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating composition comprises a copolymer of vinyl phosphonic acid and acrylic acid cured under conditions such that said copolymer is oleophilic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating composition is ablatable by radiation directed onto said coating composition overlying said radiation-absorbing composition. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating composition overlying said radiation-absorbing composition has an affinity for ink, such that when said coating composition is subjected to radiation, said coating composition changes to have a different affinity for ink. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a sealant composition disposed between said radiation-absorbing composition and said coating composition. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sealant composition is selected from the group consisting of nickel acetate, silicate, and polyvinylphosphonic acid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating composition and said sealant composition overlying said radiation-absorbing composition are ablatable by radiation directed thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The printing plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a first affinity for ink by said coating composition changes to a second affinity for ink when said coating composition overlying said radiation-absorbing composition is subjected to radiation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method of imaging comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a printing plate having a metal substrate with an anodized surface portion defining a plurality of pores, a radiation-absorbing composition received in the pores, and a coating composition covering the surface portion with the radiation-absorbing composition; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing the printing plate to a pattern of imaging radiation until a first portion of the printing plate has an affinity for a printing fluid and a second portion of the printing plate has a different affinity for the printing fluid. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said exposing step comprises ablating the coating composition in the location of the pattern of imaging radiation to reveal the anodized surface portion as the first portion of the printing plate, the coating composition not exposed to the radiation being the second portion of the printing plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said exposing step comprises changing the affinity of the coating composition for a printing fluid in the location of the</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000409A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000409A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000409A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000409A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
