<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001407A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001407A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001407A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001407A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001407A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001407A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001407A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001407A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001407A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001407A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001407A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001407A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001407</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10183689</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020625</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>P.2001-198548</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B60J001/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B60S001/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>296</class>
<subclass>096150</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>250300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>250310</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Front body structure of vehicle</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Akira</given-name>
<family-name>Hoshikawa</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tadashi</given-name>
<family-name>Masuda</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Fuji Jukogyo Kabushiki Kaisha</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>DARBY &amp; DARBY P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>805 Third Avenue</address-1>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10022</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A motor bracket is installed in a concave portion formed in a front bulkhead of a vehicle and onto an upper surface of which a wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19 </bold></highlight>is fixed. The bracket is fixed to a front wall surface of the front bulkhead and is operable to deform or fracture based upon an impact to the front wall surface during a collision. In addition, the wiper motor unit is positioned at a higher position than that of upper end surfaces of strut towers so that the concave portion can be crashed and deformed without interference from the wiper motor even if the strut towers are moved backwardly at the time of frontal crash of the vehicle to push the front wall surface of the front bulkhead. As a result, the impact energy generated from a frontal crash can be absorbed. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a front body structure of a vehicle (such as a &ldquo;car&rdquo;) in which an impact energy generated during a crash can be absorbed effectively by a front bulkhead, therefore promoting passenger safety. More particularly, the present invention relates to the front body structure in which wiper units are arranged on the front bulkhead such that the wiper units do not interfere with a collapse of the front bulkhead during a collision. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In the related art, such as disclosed in a Japanese Patent Unexamined Publication No. Hei. 9-95261, a front bulkhead is arranged along a lower edge portion of front windshield of a vehicle in a widthwise direction thereof so as to partition an engine room from a passenger compartment. In addition, a concave portion is opened upwardly and formed in the front bulkhead. A wiper unit is provided in the concave portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> As the wiper unit, a modular wiper unit disclosed in Japanese Utility Model Examined Publication No. Hei. 8-6641, for example, is often employed. In the wiper unit of this type, in many cases a motor bracket used to fix the wiper motor to the front bulkhead is fixed to the inside of the concave portion of the bulkhead such that the motor bracket extends in the longitudinal direction of the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> However, when the vehicle collides head-on with an obstacle in front of the vehicle as the vehicle is moving forward, often at a high speed (referred to as the &ldquo;frontal crash&rdquo; hereinafter), naturally, a large impact load (shock) is applied to a vehicle body from a front side. Then, the impact energy generated at that time is transmitted to a rear side of the vehicle via a front portion of the vehicle. In response, respective constituent parts provided in the front portion of the body are plastically deformed to absorb the impact energy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Of course, if the impact load is transmitted to the bulkhead, the bulkhead is crashed to absorb the impact energy, so that an impact energy transmission into the compartment is reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> However, in a structure disclosed in the above Publication, since the motor bracket is fixed to the concave portion of the bulkhead such that the motor bracket extends in the longitudinal direction, the motor bracket acts inevitably as a reinforcement to the bulkhead. In addition, since the wiper motor is arranged at a lower position than that of upper surfaces of a strut towers that are arranged on both right and left sides of the front bulkhead, the wiper motor interferes with retreating strut towers to disturb the crash of the bulkhead. For this reason, the portion of the bulkhead to which the wiper motor is arranged becomes difficult to be locally crashed. Thus, there is a disadvantage in that the effect of absorbing the impact energy generated by the deformation of the bulkhead cannot be sufficiently achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Also, since the wiper motor has a rigid body, a large reaction force is generated by the wiper motor when the impact load is applied to the wiper motor from the upper side of the vehicle. Therefore, the structure of the related art is less than ideal for reducing or eliminating the transmission of the impact energy to the passenger compartment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention has been made in view of above circumstances, and it is an object of the present invention to provide a front body structure of a vehicle that can effectively absorb an impact energy which is transmitted to a rear side of the vehicle, by accelerating a crash of a bulkhead by an impact load applied during a collision of the vehicle. Thus, the present invention is for effectively protecting passengers from an impact applied during the collision, and also for absorbing the impact energy to prevent a generation of a large reaction force even when the impact load is applied to a wiper motor from an upper side of the vehicle body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve the above object, the present invention provides a body structure of the vehicle comprising the bulkhead including a concave portion opened upwardly. The concave portion has front and rear wall surfaces and a wiper unit having a wiper motor is disposed between the front and rear wall surfaces of the concave portion. Further, the wiper motor is also disposed at a higher position than that of upper surfaces of strut towers of the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to such structure, the strut towers are moved toward the rear side of the vehicle by the impact energy at the time of the frontal crash to push the bulkhead. At this time, since the wiper motor is arranged at the higher position than that of the upper surfaces of the strut towers, such retreating strut towers can accelerate the crash of the bulkhead toward the rear side of the vehicle without an interference from the wiper motor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In this case, preferably the wiper motor is fixed to the front bulkhead via a motor bracket, an inclined portion of which is bent downwardly and formed in front of the wiper motor. A lower end of the inclined portion is fixed to a front portion of the concave portion of the front bulkhead, and a weakening portion is provided in the inclined portion. Therefore, the crash of the bulkhead toward the rear side of the vehicle by the frontal crash can be accelerated even further. Also, the motor bracket can be easily broken if the impact load is applied to the wiper motor from the upper side of the vehicle. As a result, the impact energy can be absorbed effectively.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing a front portion of a vehicle without a front hood and a cowl panel; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing a right side portion of the front portion of the vehicle in the situation where the front hood is opened; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a plan view showing a modular wiper unit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing a modular wiper unit, taken along a IV-IV line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a front view showing the modular wiper unit, viewed from an arrow V in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing the front portion of the vehicle in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing a brittle fracture state of the front portion of the vehicle in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the present invention will be explained with reference to drawings hereinafter. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing a front portion of a vehicle except for a front hood and a cowl panel. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is the perspective view showing a right side portion of the front portion in the situation that the front hood is opened. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, reference <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> denotes a front body portion of a vehicle. Front wheel aprons <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are provided on both sides of the front body portion <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in a vehicle widthwise direction. A longitudinal wall is formed on both sides of an engine room by the front wheel apron <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the vehicle widthwise direction. In this case, only the front wheel apron <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on the right side of the body is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Also, although not shown, toe boards are arranged under a front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is formed in a concave shape that is opened upwardly. A reinforcement <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is arranged at the back of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> along the widthwise direction. An air duct <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> that extends in the widthwise direction is formed by a reinforcement <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and a rear wall surface <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Also, a concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> opened upwardly is formed by a front wall surface <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a front wall surface <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the reinforcement <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. In addition, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> lower edge portion of a front glass (windshield) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is fixed to an upper surface of the reinforcement <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and an upper surface of the concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is closed by a cowl panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A front edge portion <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the cowl panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is fixed to an upper end surface of the front wall surface <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a rear edge portion <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is fixed to a lower edge portion of the front glass <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Further, a bent portion <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>that can be bent upwardly is formed in the longitudinally middle portion of the cowl panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> along the vehicle widthwise direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Further, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, strut towers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are arranged in front of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and on both sides thereof in the vehicle widthwise direction and on the inside of the front wheel apron <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, only the right strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated. As an upper surface of the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a strut fitting plane <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to a lower surface of which a strut upper end of a front suspension is fixed via such an elastic member as a rubber is fixed. Also, rear portions of the strut towers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are coupled to both sides of the front wall surface <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A reference <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> denotes a brake masterback which integrally includes a brake master cylinder <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and of which rear surface is supported by the toe board (not shown). A reference <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front hood. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Also, a modular wiper unit (abbreviated as a &ldquo;wiper unit&rdquo; hereinafter) <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is installed in the concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> formed in the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. One configuration of the wiper unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> hereunder. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, pivot holders <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are arranged on both sides of the wiper unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and both pivot holders <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are fixed integrally to both ends of a connection pipe <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> respectively by caulking, or the like (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). Also, left and right pivot shafts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are supported rotatably to the pivot holders <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> respectively. Then, left and right wiper levers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are pivotably coupled to both pivot shafts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>respectively, and both wiper levers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are connected via a wiper rod <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In addition, a motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to an upper surface of which a wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is fixed is arranged in front of the right side (the driver&apos;s seat side) of the body. A rear portion of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is fixed to the connection pipe <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> by caulking, or the like. Also, an inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that is inclined downwardly is formed integrally and positioned ahead of the portion to which the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is fixed. In addition, a flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is formed integrally with the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is fixed to a supporting bracket <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> fixed to the front portion of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Further, a hole portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, as a weakening portion, is opened laterally, such as in an oblong shape, in the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be die-cast molded using, for example, aluminum alloy, or the like as the material, and have relatively hard and fragile material properties. Accordingly, if a load is applied to the flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from the front side of the body, a bending moment is concentrated into the edge portion between the flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, or the edge portion between the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the upper surface, and thus any one of the edge portions is subjected to brittle fracture. Also, if the load is applied to the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> from the upper side, the stress is concentrated into the periphery of the hole portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>since the hole portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is cut through in the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and thus, the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is subjected to brittle fracture from the periphery of the hole portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Further, the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> has a motor main body <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a reduction gear <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>integrally combined. A motor lever <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> that is coupled to an output shaft <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the reduction gear <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is connected to a left wiper lever <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> via a motor rod <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. In addition, the pivot holders <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the wiper unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are fastened to a bracket (not shown), which is provided to the reinforcement <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> (or the body frame) to project therefrom, by the bolts and are fixed thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Then, a driving force of the motor main body <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is transmitted to the pivot shafts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which are supported by the left and right pivot holders <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, via the motor lever <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the motor rod <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the wiper rod <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and both wiper levers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to swing reciprocally the left and right pivot holders <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As a result, left and right wiper arms <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>(see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) fixed to the pivot shafts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are swung to reciprocally wipe, so that a surface of the front glass <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> can be wiped by wiper blades (not shown) that are provided to top ends of the left and right wiper arms <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In this case, the wiping operation of the wiper unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is similar to that in the related art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Also, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 6</cross-reference>, the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is fitted at a higher position than or above that of the upper surfaces of the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the brake masterback <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. In detail, the plane on which the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> exists is set to the higher position than that of the upper end surfaces of the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the brake masterback <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, and also the flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is set to almost the same height as the upper end surface of the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> An operation of the embodiment having the above structure will be explained hereunder. If the strut towers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are moved toward the rear portion of the vehicle at the time of a frontal crash of there, the strut towers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are pushed against the front wall surface <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which is fixed to the front wall surface <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> via the supporting bracket <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and provided to the front end of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, is pushed. At this time, the flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to the upper surface, onto which the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is fixed, via the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Therefore, if the flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is pushed toward the rear portion of the vehicle, the stress is concentrated into the edge portion between the flange portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, or the edge portion between the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the upper surface, and thus any one of these edge portions may be broken by brittle fracture. In this case, a state where the edge portion between the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the upper surface is broken by brittle fracture is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Then, the reinforcement of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the longitudinal direction is released, and accordingly, the portion of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> constituting the concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is crashed and deformed. At the same time, the cowl panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of which front end portion <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is fixed to the upper end of the front wall surface <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is pushed backwardly, and then this cowl panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is bent around the bent portion <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, which is formed in the middle of the cowl panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in the longitudinal direction, and then deformed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Since the wiper unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> arranged in the concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is fitted to the higher position than that of the upper end surfaces of the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the brake masterback <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> that is fixed to the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is rotated upwardly around the connection pipe <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Thus, even if the concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is crashed toward the rear side of the vehicle because of the retreat of the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the brake masterback <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the crash of the concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> can be accelerated without an interference of the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> with the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the brake masterback <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. As a result, the impact energy applied from the front side of the vehicle can be absorbed by the plastic deformation of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the cowl panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In this manner, according to the embodiment, if the impact load applied at the time of a frontal crash is transmitted to the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by the retreat of the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the crash of the concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> can be accelerated since the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> that is installed in the concave portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> formed in the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is broken and also the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> does not interfere with the strut tower <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. For this reason, the impact energy can be absorbed effectively in front of the air duct <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and thus, the passengers can be protected effectively from the impact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Also, since the impact energy at the time of the frontal crash is absorbed by the deformation of the front bulkhead <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the reinforcement structure required to prevent the deformation of the compartment can be simplified which allows for a lighter weight to be achieved. Also, a reduction in production costs can be realized by simplification of the structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In addition, if the impact load is applied to the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> from the upper side, the stress can be concentrated into the periphery of the hole portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>since the hole portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is formed in the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to which the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is fixed. Therefore, the inclined portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is broken by brittle fracture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As a result, the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, onto which the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is fixed, are turned downwardly around the connection pipe <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> by the impact load applied from the upper side of the vehicle. Thus, a large reaction force is never transmitted upwardly from the wiper motor unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and accordingly, the impact energy can be absorbed effectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The present invention is not limited to the above embodiment. For example, the motor bracket <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> need not be formed by the die-cast molding, but may be formed by a sheet metal. Also, the embodiment described above is not limited to use of the modular wiper unit, but, for example, a component wiper unit may be used instead. In addition, the strut tower is not limited to the case where the strut tower is provided in front of the front bulkhead, but the strut tower may also be provided under the front bulkhead. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> As described above, according to the present invention, the crash of the bulkhead by the impact load at the time of the frontal crash can be accelerated, and thus the impact energy that is transmitted to the rear side of the vehicle can be absorbed effectively by the front bulkhead. Therefore, the passengers can be protected effectively from the impact applied at the time of the frontal crash. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Also, even if the impact load is applied to the wiper motor from the upper side of the vehicle, the large reaction force is never generated upwardly since the wiper motor can be moved so as to escape from the impact load. Therefore, the impact energy can be absorbed effectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> While there has been described in connection with the preferred embodiments of the present invention, it will be understood to those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications may be made therein without departing from the present invention, and it is aimed, therefore, to cover in the appended claims all such changes and modifications as fall within the true spirit and scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A body structure of vehicle comprising: 
<claim-text>a bulkhead including a concave portion opened upwardly and having front and rear wall surfaces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wiper unit having a wiper motor disposed between the front and rear wall surfaces of the concave portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the wiper motor is also disposed at a higher position than that of upper surfaces of strut towers of the vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The body structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a motor bracket with the wiper motor fixed to a bulkhead of said motor bracket and including an inclined portion bent downwardly and disposed to a front of the wiper motor with a weakening portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The body structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: the bracket is made of an aluminum alloy material and is formed by a molding process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The body structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wiper motor is fixed to the bulkhead with a bracket being fracturable by a predetermined load. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The body structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a cowl panel, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first end of the cowl panel fixed to an upper end surface of the front wall surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second end of the cowl panel fixed to a lower edge portion of a front windshield of the vehicle, the cowl panel further including a bent portion formed in a longitudinally middle portion of the cowl panel that is operable to be bent upwardly in reaction to a rearward movement of the front wall surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A body structure of a vehicle comprising: 
<claim-text>an energy absorption component being operable to absorb an impact energy during a collision so as to reduce an impact energy into a passenger compartment; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wiper unit having a wiper motor disposed between the energy absorption component and the passenger compartment without interfering a collapse of the energy absorption component by the wiper motor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A body structure of a vehicle comprising: 
<claim-text>an energy absorption component being operable to absorb an impact energy during a collision so as to reduce the impact energy into a passenger compartment; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wiper unit having a wiper motor disposed between the energy absorption component and the passenger compartment, wherein the wiper motor is fixed to the energy absorption component with a bracket being operable to deform or fracture at a predetermined load. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A body structure of a vehicle comprising: 
<claim-text>an energy absorption component being operable to absorb an impact energy during a collision so as to reduce an impact energy into a passenger compartment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wiper unit having a wiper motor disposed between the the energy absorption component and the passenger compartment without interfering a collapse of the energy absorption component by the wiper motor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001407A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001407A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001407A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001407A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001407A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001407A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
