<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000930A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000930A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000930A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000930A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000930A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000930A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000930A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000930A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000930</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10181423</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020724</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>19505/2000</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000128</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B23K026/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G03F009/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>219</class>
<subclass>121730</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>430</class>
<subclass>005000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Laser machining device and laser machining mask and production method therefor</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shiro</given-name>
<family-name>Hamada</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Hiratsuka-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Arent Fox Kintner</name-1>
<name-2>Plotkin &amp; Kahn</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 600</address-1>
<address-2>1050 Connecticut Avenue NW</address-2>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20036-5339</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/JP01/00039</doc-number>
<document-date>20010109</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A mask <highlight><bold>10 </bold></highlight>comprises a mask member layer <highlight><bold>12 </bold></highlight>having a laser processing pattern and comprising a metallic material and first and second substrate members <highlight><bold>11 </bold></highlight>and <highlight><bold>13 </bold></highlight>holding the mask member on two faces thereof and comprising a material that transmits laser light. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a laser processing apparatus for carrying out processing defined by a predetermined processing pattern to a work by irradiating the work with a laser beam from a laser oscillator thorough a mask having the predetermined pattern, to a mask for laser processing, and to a method for making the mask. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Laser drilling apparatuses for carrying out drilling to a resin layer of printed circuit boards by a laser beam are provided. Nowadays, laser drilling apparatuses for collectively making a plurality of holes also are provided. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an example thereof will be described. A pulsed laser beam from a CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>laser oscillator <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is incident on a homogeneous optical system <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, so that the energy density distribution in the cross-section of the beam becomes homogeneous. The laser beam emerging from the homogeneous optical system <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is reflected downward by a reflective mirror <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and is incident on a conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The laser beam incident on the conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> has a circular or rectangular cross-sectional shape. The conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> converts the circular or rectangular cross-sectional shape into a linear laser beam having a predetermined width W and length L. Thus, the conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> includes a cylindrical lens system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for defining the width W and a cylindrical lens <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> for defining the length L. Such a conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is well known, the width W being in the range of 0.1 mm to several mm and the length being about several tens of mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A mask stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is arranged right below the conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to drive a mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in one axial direction. The mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, as described below, has many holes for defining a processing pattern for a resin layer of a work <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. An imaging lens system <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is arranged between the mask stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the work <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The imaging lens system <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> defines the reduction ratio of the processing pattern of the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> projected onto the work <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Herein, the reduction ratio is 1:1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The work <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is loaded on a work stage <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> that is movable at least in the inverse direction relative to that of the movement of the mask stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, along the same axial direction. In particular, the mask stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the work stage <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> are controlled with a controller, which is not shown in the drawing, so that these move synchronously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the relationship between the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the cross-sectional shape (shown by hatching) of a linear laser beam, which is converted in the conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> has a processing pattern including a plurality of holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> that are arranged at random or regularly at a given pitch P with respect to the direction of the movement shown by an arrow. In the linear laser beam, the width W is larger than the diameter of the holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the length L is larger than the range of the processing pattern in the width direction of the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> moves across the linear laser beam so that a plurality of laser beam components passing through the holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> lying in one row of the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> reach the work <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> through the imaging lens <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Since the mask stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the work stage <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> are controlled so that these move synchronously in the opposite directions along the same axial direction, holes are continuously formed in the work <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> for every row of the processing pattern of the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in sequence. Of course, the pulse frequency of the laser beam from the CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>laser oscillator <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is set so as to be synchronized with the movement corresponding to one pitch of the mask stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. For example, the holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the same row are irradiated with the laser beam at least one time or two times, if necessary, depending on the energy intensity of the laser beam. This means that the same region in the work <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is irradiated with the laser beam at least one time or two times if necessary. As a result, holes are formed in the region irradiated with the laser beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In the above example, the laser beam is fixed while the mask stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the work stage <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> are movable. Alternatively, for the same diameter, distance, and pitch of the holes formed in the work and for a pulse width of the laser beam on the order of microseconds, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>&prime; having a row of holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; is used. In this case, it is not necessary to drive the mask stage during laser irradiation. In other words, the linear laser beam from the conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is incident on the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>&prime;, which is always fixed, whereas only the work stage <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> moves in the direction of an arrow in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be fixed while the work <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is irradiated with a linear laser beam that is scanned on the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in one axial direction by a galvano-scanner. For this case, the galvano-scanner is provided between the conversion optical system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In this case, after the scanning by the galvano-scanner, the work stage <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> moves the subsequent processing region to a scanning region by the galvano-scanner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In any case, the diameter of the holes formed by the above-mentioned drilling is in the range of about 30 to 300 &mgr;m. Assuming that the reduction ratio of the imaging lens system <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is 1:1, the diameter of the holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> formed in the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is also in the range of 30 to 300 &mgr;m. The mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is generally formed of a metallic material and the holes have an aspect ratio (ratio of the diameter to the depth of the hole) of about 1. When the diameter of the holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is 50 &mgr;m, the thickness of the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is also 50 &mgr;m. The same relationship applies to the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>&prime; shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> However, in the mask having the above-mentioned thickness, an increased density of the holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> impairs heat dissipation during laser beam irradiation, resulting in the thermal deformation of the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The deformation of the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> causes the difference of the positions and the distortion of the shape of the holes formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, an object of the present invention is to provide a mask for laser processing which does not cause thermal deformation during irradiation with a laser beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a method for making the mask. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Still another object of the present invention is to provide a laser processing apparatus using the mask. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> DISCLOSURE OF INVENTION </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A mask for laser processing according to the present invention has a predetermined processing pattern. The mask comprises a mask member having the processing pattern and comprised of a material that reflects laser light and substrate members for holding the mask member on both faces thereof and comprised of a material that transmits the laser light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The above-mentioned laser light is, for example, infrared light, the mask member comprises one of Au, Cu, Ni, and beryllium-copper, and the substrate members comprise one of Ge, ZnS, and ZnSe. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A laser processing apparatus according to the present invention carries out processing defined by a predetermined processing pattern to a work by irradiating the work with a laser beam from a laser oscillator thorough a mask having the predetermined pattern. The mask also comprises a mask member having the processing pattern and comprised of a material that reflects laser light and substrate members for holding the mask member on both faces thereof and comprised of a material that transmits the laser light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The above-mentioned laser oscillator is a CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>laser oscillator, the mask member comprises one of Au, Cu, Ni, and beryllium-copper, and the substrate members comprise one of Ge, ZnS, and ZnSe. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, a method for making a mask for laser processing having a predetermined processing pattern is further provided. The method comprises a first step of forming a material layer comprising a material that reflects laser light on one face of a first substrate member comprising a material that transmits the laser light, a second step of forming the processing pattern in the material layer, and a third step of bonding a second substrate member comprising a material that transmits the laser light to a face, which is not in contact with the first substrate, of the material layer provided with the processing pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The above-mentioned first step is performed by a vacuum evaporation or plating process, and the second step is performed by lithography, etching, or laser processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In the third step, high-frequency vibrations are applied to at least one of the assembly of the material layer provided with the processing pattern and the first substrate member and the second substrate member to bond them.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows the configuration of a laser processing apparatus used for collectively forming a plurality of holes according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the relationship between a mask used in the laser processing apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and the cross-sectional shape of linear laser light; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the relationship between another mask and the cross-sectional shape of linear laser light; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows cross-sections illustrating steps of making a mask according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> method for making a mask according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention will now be described. Herein, the description will be made in a case that the laser oscillator is the CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>laser oscillator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), Au is deposited on one face of a Ge substrate member <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (first substrate member) having high transmittance for the wavelengths of the CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>laser beam (9.3 &mgr;m, 9.4 &mgr;m, 10.6 &mgr;m, or the like) to form a mask member layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> having a thickness of about 50 &mgr;m, by vacuum evaporation. A plating process may be employed instead of the vacuum evaporation process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Next, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), a plurality of holes <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having a diameter of 50 &mgr;m that define the processing pattern are formed in the mask member layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by a well known combination of lithography and etching or by direct laser processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>), a substrate member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> (second substrate membr) is placed onto a face, which is not in contact with the substrate member <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, of the mask member layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to bond them. As a bonding method, at least one of the substrate member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and the assembly of the substrate member <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the mask member layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is vibrated in a direction parallel to the plane at a high frequency. The mask member layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the substrate member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are bonded to each other by frictional heat generated therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As a result, a mask <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of holes <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having a diameter of 50 &mgr;m and an aspect ratio of 1 is obtained. The thickness of the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, respectively, is in the range of about several tens of &mgr;m to several hundred &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In the mask member layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the mask <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, portions corresponding to the holes <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are composed of only Ge and thus have high transmittance for the laser beam. Since Au has high reflectance for the laser beam, the heat absorbed dissipates through the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and the mask <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not heated to a high temperature, and therefore no deformation is caused. Furthermore, the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> mechanically prevent thermal deformation of the mask member layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Materials for each component of the mask <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are as follows. Materials for the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> include Ge, ZnS (zinc sulfide), and ZnSe (zinc selenide). Materials for the mask member layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> include Au, Cu, Ni, and beryllium-copper. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Preferred combinations are Ge&mdash;Au, Ge&mdash;Cu, and Ge&mdash;Ni. In the case of Ge&mdash;Au, these are immiscible with each other and form a eutectic alloy. The eutectic composition contains 17 atomic percent Ge and is a low-melting-point alloy having a eutectic point of 356&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In the case of Ge&mdash;Cu, about 10 atomic percent Ge is dissolved into Cu. In the region containing a larger amount of Ge, various intermetallic compounds are formed. At a Ge content of about 25 atomic percent or more, a eutectic alloy (having a eutectic point of about 640&deg; C.) of Cu<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>Ge and Ge is formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In the case of Ge&mdash;Ni, about 12 atomic percent Ge is dissolved into Ni. In the region containing a larger amount of Ge, various intermetallic compounds are formed. At a Ge content of about 50 atomic percent or more, a eutectic alloy (having a eutectic point of about 780&deg; C.) of NiGe and Ge is formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As described above, the Ge&mdash;Au system is most preferred because an alloy is readily formed. However, it should be noted that this alloy melts at a low temperature of 356&deg; C. Since Ge and Au readily form a eutectic alloy, a homogeneous structure of Ge and Au exhibits high thermal conductivity. In addition, a small amount of heat generated in Au due to laser beam absorption readily dissipates through the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The mask according to the above embodiments is suitable for the mask <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the laser drilling apparatus for carrying out the drilling to the resin layer of the printed circuit board shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. However, the mask according to the present invention is not limited to the mask of the laser drilling apparatus. For example, this is also applicable to a mask of a laser distortion processing apparatus that irradiates a plurality of fine ceramic substrates arranged in a row with a plurality of laser beams to impart microdistorsion to each ceramic substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The laser oscillator is not limited to the CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>laser oscillator. Other laser oscillators, for example, a YAG laser oscillator and a YLF laser oscillator can also be used. Materials for the first and second substrate and the mask member layer may be selected depending on the laser oscillator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the first and second substrates dissipate heat from the mask member layer and mechanically fix the mask member layer; hence, the resulting mask for laser drilling does not undergo thermal deformation due to irradiation with laser light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As described above, the mask according to the present invention is suitable for a mask of a laser drilling apparatus for carrying out the drilling to a work and a mask of a laser distortion processing apparatus for imparting distortion to a work. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A mask for laser processing having a predetermined processing pattern, the mask comprising a mask member having the processing pattern and comprised of a material that reflects laser light and substrate members for holding the mask member on both faces thereof and comprised of a material that transmits the laser light, the mask member comprises one of Au, Cu, Ni, and beryllium-copper. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The mask for laser processing according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the laser light is infrared light, and the substrate members comprise one of Ge, ZnS, and ZnSe. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A laser processing apparatus for carrying out processing defined by a predetermined processing pattern to a work by irradiating the work with a laser beam from a laser oscillator thorough a mask having the predetermined pattern, wherein the mask comprises: 
<claim-text>a mask member having the processing pattern and comprised of a material that reflects laser light and substrate members for holding the mask member on both faces thereof and comprised of a material that transmits the laser light, the mask member comprises one of Au, Cu, Ni, and beryllium-copper. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The laser processing apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the laser oscillator is a CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>laser oscillator and the substrate members comprise one of Ge, ZnS, and ZnSe. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method for making a mask for laser processing having a predetermined processing pattern, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>a first step of forming a material layer comprising a material that reflects laser light on one face of a first substrate member comprising a material that transmits the laser light; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second step of forming the processing pattern in the material layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third step of bonding a second substrate member comprising a material that transmits the laser light to a face, which is not in contact with the first substrate, of the material layer provided with the processing pattern, the reflecting material comprises one of Au, Cu, Ni, and beryllium-copper. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method for making a mask for laser processing according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first step is performed by a vacuum evaporation or plating process, and the second step is performed by lithography, etching, or laser processing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method for making a mask for laser processing having a predetermined processing pattern, the method comprising a first step of forming a material layer comprising a material that reflects laser light on one face of a first substrate member comprising a material that transmits the laser light; a second step of forming the processing pattern in the material layer; and a third step of bonding a second substrate member comprising a material that transmits the laser light to a face, which is not in contact with the first substrate, of the material layer provided with the processing pattern, wherein, in the third step, high-frequency vibrations are applied to at least one of the assembly of the material layer provided with the processing pattern and the first substrate member and the second substrate member to bond them.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000930A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000930A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000930A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000930A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
