<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000720A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000720A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000720A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000720A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000720</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10160084</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020604</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-177342</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010612</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H02G003/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>174</class>
<subclass>050000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Electrical junction box having double-wall structure</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hidetoshi</given-name>
<family-name>Sato</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Shizuoka</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Yazaki Corporation</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ARMSTRONG,WESTERMAN &amp; HATTORI, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1725 K STREET, NW.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1000</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20006</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An electrical junction box <highlight><bold>1 </bold></highlight>having a double-wall structure includes a container body <highlight><bold>2 </bold></highlight>and an upper cover <highlight><bold>3 </bold></highlight>to be mounted on the container body. A peripheral wall of the container body <highlight><bold>2 </bold></highlight>is composed of an outer wall <highlight><bold>9 </bold></highlight>and an inner wall <highlight><bold>10. </bold></highlight>There is provided a horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19 </bold></highlight>between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9 </bold></highlight>and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10 </bold></highlight>for partitioning a space between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9 </bold></highlight>and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10 </bold></highlight>into an upper space <highlight><bold>17 </bold></highlight>and a lower space <highlight><bold>18. </bold></highlight>A plurality of upper ribs <highlight><bold>20 </bold></highlight>and a plurality of lower ribs <highlight><bold>21 </bold></highlight>extending in a vertical direction are respectively provided at a determined interval above and below the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19. </bold></highlight>The horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19 </bold></highlight>is provided with communicating holes <highlight><bold>22, </bold></highlight>between respective pairs of the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20, </bold></highlight>which communicate the upper space <highlight><bold>17 </bold></highlight>with the lower space <highlight><bold>18. </bold></highlight></paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an electrical junction box which is used for wiring arrangement in a motor vehicle or the like, and more particularly to the electrical junction box having a double-wall structure in which deformation of outer walls can be prevented and invasion of water can be restrained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> There have been employed in motor vehicles electrical junction boxes such as a junction box, fuse box, relay box, etc. in order to contain various parts required for connecting and treating wire harnesses in the vehicle, and electrical components such as fuses, relays, electronic control unit, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Various types of the electrical junction boxes have been employed according to types of the vehicles. For example, various types of electrical components are contained in a box-like case made of synthetic resin or the like, which is composed of a case body and an upper cover. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Because the electrical junction box is generally arranged at side areas in a lower part of a vehicle body, there is such anxiety that components such as circuits may cause a short circuit or a leaked current may flow, when water has intruded into an interior while driving in rain or at car wash. Therefore, it is necessary to render the electrical junction box waterproof. In case of washing a large car especially, high pressure water jetted with force is liable to intrude into the electrical junction box. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Specifically, the water which has collided against a side wall of the case body will sometimes flow along the side wall, enter between the side wall and the upper cover, and intrude into the case body. For this reason, it has been proposed that the side wall of the case body is formed to have a double-wall structure consisting of an outer wall and an inner wall. According to this structure, even though the water which has collided against the side wall has flowed along the side wall, and entered between the side wall and the upper cover, the water will intrude between the double walls, that is, between the outer wall and the inner wall. This water intruded between the double walls will lose force, and intrusion of the water into the case body can be restrained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In the above described electrical junction box, the outer wall is held by the inner wall by means of some fixation members at several upper and lower positions between the outer wall and the inner wall, for example. However, since the high pressure water is splashed to the electrical junction box, the outer wall may sometimes be deformed because they are fixed only by means of such fixation means. Moreover, there is formed an opening in a lower part between the outer wall and the inner wall to drain water. When the high pressure water is splashed to this opening, the water may intrude from the opening into a gap between the outer wall and the inner wall, and may arrive at a position between the inner wall and the upper cover. In such cases, there is an anxiety that the water may intrude into the case body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention has been made in view of such circumstances, and an object of the invention is to provide an electrical junction box having a double-wall structure in which deformation of outer walls can be prevented and invasion of water can be restrained. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In order to attain the above described object, there is provided according to the present invention, an electrical junction box having a double-wall structure comprising a container body and an upper cover to be mounted on the container body, a peripheral wall of the container body including an outer wall and an inner wall, wherein a horizontal rib is provided between the outer wall and the inner wall for partitioning a space between the outer wall and the inner wall into an upper space and a lower space, a plurality of upper ribs and a plurality of lower ribs extending in a vertical direction are respectively provided at a determined interval above and below the horizontal rib, and the horizontal rib is provided with communicating holes, between respective pairs of the upper ribs, which communicate the upper space with the lower space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> With such a structure, the outer wall can be held without deformation, because the outer wall is supported by means of the horizontal rib and a plurality of the upper and lower ribs which are provided above and below the horizontal rib. Moreover, since the horizontal rib is formed between the outer wall and the inner wall, even though high pressurized water has entered into a gap between the outer wall and the inner wall through an opening between them, a large amount of the water will be blocked by the horizontal rib, and invasion of the water into the container body can be restrained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> It is preferable that the upper ribs and the lower ribs are provided substantially in a vertical direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> This means that the container body, particularly the outer wall, the inner wall, the horizontal, the upper and the lower ribs can be integrally molded by injection molding, for example. Therefore, deformation of the outer wall can be reliably prevented, and a mass production can be attained easily, thus enhancing industrial values. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The horizontal rib is preferably arranged between the outer wall and the inner wall substantially in a middle part in a vertical direction, and each of the lower ribs is preferably arranged substantially in a middle part of a pair of the upper ribs in a horizontal direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In this manner, it will be possible to more reliably prevent deformation of the outer wall, because the horizontal rib is arranged substantially in the middle part between the outer wall and the inner wall, and each of the lower ribs is arranged substantially in the middle part between a pair of the upper ribs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Each of the communicating holes is preferably arranged substantially in a middle part between a pair of the lower ribs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Because each of the communicating holes is provided substantially in the middle part between a pair of the lower ribs, the water which has intruded from the opening formed in the lower part between the outer wall and the inner wall will collide against the lower ribs and flow along the lower ribs. Since the water will be blocked by the horizontal rib and will not easily intrude into the upper space through the communicating holes, invasion of the water into the container body can be more reliably prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The lower rib is preferably formed in an inverted convex shape having a wider width in its upper part than in its lower part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In this manner, even though the water flows along the lower ribs, the water will collide against the wider part, and so, invasion of the water into the upper space through the communicating holes will be all the more difficult. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Both lower end portions of the wider part are preferably tapered downwardly toward both ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In this manner, the water which has flowed along the lower rib and collided against the wider part will flow along the lower ends to be guided downwardly, and invasion of the water into the upper space through the communicating holes will be all the more difficult.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view partly cut away showing an embodiment of an electrical junction box having a double-wall structure according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing arrangement of ribs according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing relation between an upper cover and a side wall of a case body according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Now, an embodiment according to the present invention will be described in detail, referring to the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, numeral <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> represents an electrical junction box, which contains parts required for connecting and treating wire harnesses in a vehicle, and electrical components such as fuses, relays, electronic control unit, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The electrical junction box <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which is composed of a case body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in a box-like shape and an upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> formed of synthetic resin, for example, is molded by injection molding or the like. The electrical junction box <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is tightly sealed, by elastically engaging a locking hook <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> with a locking claw <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the case body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, after the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> has covered an opening in an upper part of the case body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> There is formed, on one of side walls <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the case body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a mounting part <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in a semi-circular shape for introducing electric wires such as the wire harness to be connected to the electrical components in the case body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A grommet <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> for protecting the wire harness is fitted to the mounting part <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A peripheral wall <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the case body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is formed in a double-wall structure consisting of an outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and an inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> along its entire area except the mounting part <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Specifically, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</cross-reference>, the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is arranged outside the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> at a determined distance so as to enclose the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Moreover, an upper end <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is made higher than an upper end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A horizontally extending projection <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is formed on an outer face of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> at an upper position along a substantially entire periphery thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is a lid to be fitted to the opening of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and provided with a peripheral wall <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which surrounds an upper part of a peripheral wall of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The peripheral wall <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is provided with an engaging part <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with which the upper ends of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are adapted to be engaged. The engaging part <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a first groove <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> into which the upper end <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the inner wall is inserted. A packing <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> made of rubber, for example, is provided in this first groove <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Outside the first groove <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and at a lower position than the first groove <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, there is formed a second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> into which the upper end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is inserted. An inner face of an outer wall <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which defines this second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is formed in a step-like shape so as to be engaged with an outer face of the upper wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> having the projection <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. When the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is placed on the opening in the upper part of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the outer face of the upper wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> comes into contact with the inner face <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and at the same time, the upper end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> comes into contact with a bottom of the second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Simultaneously, the upper end <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is inserted into the first groove <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> pressing the packing <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, thereby to seal. The second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be also provided with a packing made of rubber or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, there is formed a horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> which partitions a space between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into an upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and a lower space <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. There are further provided above and below the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is provided with communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for communicating the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and the lower space <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is extended in a horizontal direction. A shape of the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is not particularly limited, but may be in a form of rod having a rectangular cross section. The horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is preferably arranged between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> at a substantially middle position in a vertical direction. Near corner areas of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> may be provided in a lower part as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. This is because the corner areas are difficult to be deformed. However, it is apparent that in these areas too, the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> may be arranged at a substantially middle position in a vertical direction between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The upper rib <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is preferably extended in a vertical direction. A shape of the upper rib <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is not particularly limited, but may be in a form of rod having a rectangular cross section. A plurality of the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are provided above the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> at a determined interval. In other words, the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is divided by the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into a plurality of spaces. An interval between the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be optionally determined in such a range that the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may not be deformed when high pressure water is jetted to the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Positions of upper ends of the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are not particularly limited, but the upper ribs may be preferably extended up to positions above an area to which the high pressure water is directly jetted, for example, positions of the projection <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> or adjacent to the projection <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. By providing the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in this manner, deformation of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> with the high pressure water will hardly occur when the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is mounted on the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, because there are provided the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> inside the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> to which the high pressure water is directly jetted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The lower rib <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is preferably extended in a vertical direction. A plurality of the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are provided below the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> at a determined interval. An interval between the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> can be optionally determined in such a range that the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> may not be deformed when high pressure water is jetted to the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Although not particularly limited, lower ends of the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are preferably extended up to a bottom of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are fixed to the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> at different positions in a horizontal direction, and more preferably, each of the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is positioned at a substantially middle part between a pair of the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> A shape of the lower rib <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is not particularly limited provided that it extends in a vertical direction. The lower rib <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> may be in a shape of rod in cross section, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and preferably, is in an inverted convex shape having a wider width in an upper part than in a lower part, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In case of forming it in the inverted convex shape, both lower end portions <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of a wider part <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> are preferably tapered downwardly, or curved toward both ends. Two or more steps of the inverted convex shape may be formed in the lower rib <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are provided so as to guide the water intruded into the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to the lower space <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. One communicating hole <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is provided between a pair of the upper ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and may be in any shape provided that the water can be guided therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Positions of the communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are not particularly limited, but they are preferably arranged at other positions than positions along rib faces of the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. More preferably, each of the communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is arranged in a substantially middle part between a pair of the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Moreover, an upper part of the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is preferably formed to have an inclined face which is inclined downwardly toward the communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. By forming the inclined face in the upper part of the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> in this manner, the water intruded into the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> can be smoothly guided to the lower space <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Then, operation will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is mounted over the opening in the upper part of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and locked to the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by elastically engaging the locking hooks <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> with the locking claws <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. On this occasion, the outer face in the upper part of the upper wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> comes into contact with the inner face <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and at the same time, the upper end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> comes into contact with a bottom of the second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Simultaneously, the upper end <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is inserted into the first groove <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> pressing the packing <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to be sealed, and accordingly, the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are tightly sealed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As described above, the upper wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is in contact with the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in such a manner that the outer face in the upper part is abutted against the inner face <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and at the same time, the upper end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is abutted against the bottom of the second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. As the results, the upper part of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> will be prevented from being deformed, because the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is in face to face contact with the second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, as compared with a case wherein the upper end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is abutted against only the bottom of the second groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> When high pressure water is splashed to the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of this electrical junction box <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> at car wash or so, the water collided against the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> will flow along the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The water flowing upward will strike the projection <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and will scarcely flow between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In case where the water has flowed between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the water may sometimes intrude between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. However, since the water will lose force (water pressure will drop) and will flow along the wall constituting the second groove, there is least water flowing upward between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, because the water flowing from an interface between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> into the gap between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> flows in a downward direction. Consequently, the water will flow downward through the communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and will be discharged from the lower part between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In addition, because the upper end <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned higher than the upper end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, the water will be further prevented from flowing from between the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> into the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Even when high pressure water is jetted to the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> will not be deformed because the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is held by the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by means of the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and a plurality of the upper and the lower ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> which are provided above and below the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. It will be possible to reliably prevent deformation of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> on this occasion, by arranging the upper and the lower ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> substantially in a vertical direction, and by arranging the upper and the lower ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in staggered positions in a horizontal direction. It will be possible to more reliably prevent deformation of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, by arranging the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> substantially in the middle part between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and each of the lower ribs is arranged substantially in the middle part between a pair of the upper ribs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In case where high pressure water has entered into the gap between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through the opening between them, the water will flow upwardly along the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, the inner face of the outer wall, and the outer face of the inner wall. Then, a large amount of the water will be blocked by the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and invasion of the water into the container body can be restrained. In case where the water has intruded into the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> through the communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the water pressure will be decreased in the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and the water will not flow into the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> from the area between the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the upper cover <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the water which flows between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not likely to flow in a substantially vertical direction, but deflected in either direction to be blocked by the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Thus, most portion of the water will flow upwardly along the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Because each of the communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is provided substantially in the middle part between a pair of the lower ribs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, most portion of the water will be blocked by the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and will not easily intrude into the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> through the communicating holes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. For this reason, invasion of the water into the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be more reliably prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> By forming the lower rib <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in an inverted convex shape having a wider width in an upper part than in a lower part, the water flowing along the lower rib <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> will strike the wider parts <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Even though the water has flowed in a horizontal direction, the water will scarcely intrude into the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, because there is a distance from the communicating hole <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Further, by tapering the lower end portions <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the wider part <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the water which has struck the wider part <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> will be returned to the lower part. Consequently, invasion of the water into the upper space <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> will be all the more difficult. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As described, in the electrical junction box <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> according to the present invention, the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is held by the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the upper and the lower ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> which are provided on the outer face of the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, when water has intruded from the lower part between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, most portion of the water will be blocked by the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and discharged from the lower part between the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Thus, deformation of the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> can be prevented and, invasion of the water into the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Still further, the upper and the lower ribs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are arranged substantially in a vertical direction, and the horizontal rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is preferably arranged substantially in a horizontal direction. This means that the container body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> including the outer wall <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, the inner wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the horizontal, the upper and the lower ribs <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> can be integrally molded by injection molding employing an upper and a lower molds, for example. Therefore, deformation of the outer wall can be reliably prevented, and a mass production can be attained easily, thus enhancing industrial values. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Although the present invention has been fully described by way of examples with reference to the accompanying drawings, it is to be noted that various changes and modifications can be made within a scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An electrical junction box having a double-wall structure comprising a container body and an upper cover to be mounted on said container body, a peripheral wall of said container body including an outer wall and an inner wall, wherein 
<claim-text>a horizontal rib is provided between said outer wall and said inner wall for partitioning a space between said outer wall and said inner wall into an upper space and a lower space, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of upper ribs and a plurality of lower ribs extending in a vertical direction are respectively provided at a determined interval above and below said horizontal rib, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said horizontal rib is provided with communicating holes, between a pair of said upper ribs, which communicate said upper space with said lower space. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The electrical junction box having the double-wall structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said horizontal rib is arranged between said outer wall and said inner wall substantially in a middle part in a vertical direction, and each of said lower ribs is arranged substantially in a middle part of a pair of said upper ribs in a horizontal direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The electrical junction box having the double-wall structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, wherein each of said communicating holes is arranged substantially in a middle part between a pair of said lower ribs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The electrical junction box having the double-wall structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower rib is formed in an inverted convex shape having a wider width in its upper part than in its lower part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The electrical junction box having the double-wall structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower rib is formed in an inverted convex shape having a wider width in its upper part than in its lower part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The electrical junction box having the double-wall structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower rib is formed in an inverted convex shape having a wider width in its upper part than in its lower part.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000720A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000720A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
