<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004575A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004575A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004575A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004575A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004575A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004575A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004575A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004575A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004575A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004575A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004575</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10153188</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020520</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61F002/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>623</class>
<subclass>017150</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Expandable fusion device and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10153188</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020520</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09338688</doc-number>
<document-date>19990623</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6419705</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Erickson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Edina</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Sulzer Spine-Tech Inc.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Attention: Nancy J. Parsons</name-1>
<name-2>MERCHANT &amp; GOULD P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 2903</address-1>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402-0903</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention is directed to expandable bone fusion devices and methods of use. In general, a fusion device according to the invention includes a first member and a second member which can be deployed and locked into an expanded configuration to stabilize the adjacent bone during fusion of the bone. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention pertains to devices and methods for facilitating bone fusion. The devices and methods disclosed can be used for fusion of joints. The invention is particularly advantageous for fusion of intervertebral joints. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Chronic back problems cause pain and disability for a large segment of the population. Frequently, the cause of back pain is traceable to diseased disc material between opposing vertebrae. When the disc material is diseased, the opposing vertebrae may be inadequately supported, resulting in persistent pain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Surgical techniques have been developed to remove the diseased disc material and fuse the joint between opposing vertebral bodies. Stabilization and/or arthrodesis of the intervertebral joint can reduce the pain associated with movement of an intervertebral joint having diseased disc material. Generally, fusion techniques involve removal of the diseased disc and packing the void area with a suitable matrix for facilitating a bony union between the opposing vertebral bodies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Surgical devices for facilitating interbody fusion have also been developed. These devices typically provide for maintaining appropriate intervertebral spacing and stabilization of the vertebrae during the fusion process. Examples of such devices are disclosed in, for example, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,458,638, 5,489,307, 5,055,104, 5,026,373, 5,015,247, 4,961,740, 4,743,256 and 4,501,269, the entire disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Present methods for implanting a fusion device often require that the vertebrae be distracted to restore a diseased disc space to its normal height prior to implanting a fusion device In addition, the disc space is typically prepared for receiving an implant by drilling and tapping a bore of appropriate size for receiving the implant. Hence, current methods used for inserting presently available fusion implants require several steps and specialized instrumentation to prepare the implant site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The time required to perform the steps for preparing the implant site prolongs the duration of the surgical procedure and thus, increases the duration of time that the patient is under general anesthesia. Also, the instrumentation used may require making a substantial skin incision. Furthermore, the steps used to distract and prepare the implant site increase the chance for trauma to neural, vascular and other tissues in the vicinity of the implant site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, there is a continuing need for improved intervertebral stabilizing devices and methods. The present invention is directed to addressing these needs. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to an implant and methods for facilitating fusion of bone. The invention can be advantageously used in the stabilization and fusion of a joint, particularly an intervertebral joint. The invention helps to reduce the steps necessary for preparing the implant site and the time required for performing the overall implantation procedure. The invention also reduces the chance of injury to tissues near the surgical site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that throughout the specification, guidance may be provided through lists of examples. In each instance, the recited list serves only as a representative group. It is not meant, however, that the lists are exclusive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> An intervertebral fusion device according to the invention can have an expanded and a non-expanded configuration. The fusion devices have an internal surface, an external surface, a leading end and a trailing end. A portion of the external surfaces include an engagement arrangement to reduce the likelihood of movement or expulsion of the fusion device once implanted within the intervertebral space. The interior of the fusion devices can be packed with a bone support matrix to facilitate fusion between opposing bone surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The fusion devices each include an external member and an internal member. A portion of both the external and internal members can have a U-shaped configuration. The external member includes an external base and a first and second external side wall spaced apart by a width of the external base. The internal member also includes an internal base and a first and second internal wall spaced at an appropriate distance to permit the first and second internal walls to fit within the first and second external walls. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The fusion devices also include a locking arrangement. In general, a locking arrangement includes a pair of pins which interdigitate with a pair of apertures. In one embodiment, a first pin can project from the first internal wall and a second pin can project from the second internal wall. The first and second pins lock by interdigitating with a first and second aperture located on the first and second external walls respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment, a first pin can project from the first external wall and the second pin can project from the second external wall. According to this embodiment, when locked in the deployed position, the first pin interdigitates with a first aperture located on the first internal wall and the second pin interdigitates with a second aperture located on the second internal wall. The invention describes various permutations of the relative positioning of the pins and the apertures to permit locking the fusion device in various expanded configurations. In some embodiments, the walls in which the apertures are located also include a groove to guide the pins into the aperture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides methods for implanting the fusion devices disclosed. In general, after preparation of the joint space, the leading end of the fusion device is inserted into the joint space and deployed into the expanded configuration. In addition to other advantages, the method disclosed can provide for reduced surgery time and reduced chance of trauma to tissues surrounding the joint space being fused.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a fusion device according to the invention in an expanded configuration; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a transverse cross-section through line <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the fusion device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternative embodiment of a fusion device according to the invention in an expanded configuration; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an end-on view of an alternative embodiment of a fusion device according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a lateral view of the fusion device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> positioned between adjacent vertebrae; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternative embodiment of a fusion device according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a transverse section view through line <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the fusion device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in a non-expanded configuration; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a section view through line <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the fusion device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in an expanded configuration; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a section view through line <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of the external member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a section view through line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a section view taken from the same position as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> in an alternative embodiment of a locking arrangement according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a side view of one embodiment of a lordotic fusion device according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a side view of an alternative embodiment of a lordotic fusion device of the invention in a non-expanded configuration; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a side view of the lordotic fusion device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> in an expanded configuration; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is an anterior view of adjacent vertebrae with two fusion devices according to the invention inserted therebetween; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is an anterior view of adjacent vertebrae with a single fusion device according to the invention inserted therebetween.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to an implant and methods for facilitating stabilization or fusion of bones. The invention can be advantageously used in the stabilization and fusion of a joint, particularly an intervertebral joint. Thus, the invention will be described with reference to stabilization and fusion of adjacent lumbar vertebrae. It will be appreciated, however, that the devices and methods disclosed are applicable for use with all types of joints (e.g., ankle, intervertebral, interdigital, etc.) and in all regions (e.g., arms, legs, spine, etc.) of a human or animal body. In the spinal column, the devices and methods disclosed can be used at all intervertebral joints, including those in the cervical, thoracic and lumbar region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In use, a fusion device of the invention can be inserted into a joint space in a close packed configuration and then deployed into an expanded configuration and locked in the expanded configuration to stabilize the joint space. In preferred embodiments, the devices can include openings for bone growth through the device to fuse the joint. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> According to the invention a fusion device (implant) includes a body having an exterior region and an interior region. Generally portions of the exterior region engage the bones adjacent the joint space to be fused. When inserted between the bones and deployed, the device stabilizes the joint by exerting an outward force against the bones which counters the contracting (inward) force of the soft tissue structures surrounding the joint. The interior region of the fusion device defines an interior space or chamber which can be filled with a bone growth matrix to facilitate bone growth across the fusion site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The body of a fusion device comprises, at least, a first and second member, one of which nests inside the other in a close packed configuration when the fusion device is in the non-deployed state. A portion of each member includes a generally U-shaped configuration in cross-section, regardless if the member is open or closed (i.e., tubular). The U shape can be in the form of a rectangle, circular, oval, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Each member includes opposing side walls spaced apart by a base. The width of the bases of each member determines the overall width of the device. The height of the walls and position of the locking arrangement determines the overall height and angulation of the device when in the deployed configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Once inserted into a joint space, the implant can be deployed and the members locked into an expanded configuration. A locking arrangement for locking the device preferably includes a locking pin and locking pin hole for receiving the locking pin. The transverse cross sectional configuration of the locking pin can be any shape, including, circular, square, rectangular, polygonal, etc. The longitudinal cross-sectional configuration of the pin can be parallel, conical, etc. The cross sectional configuration of the locking pin hole is selected to cooperatively receive the locking pin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In use, the implants are typically inserted into a disc space in a compact (non-expanded) configuration between adjacent vertebrae. Once inserted into the joint space the implant can be deployed and locked into an expanded configuration to form a desired disc space height between the vertebrae. As used herein, a &ldquo;desired&rdquo; disc space height refers to the distance between the vertebrae which is determined to be appropriate for the particular condition of the patient. Thus, depending on the condition, the desired height may be that of the normal disc space when in a non-diseased condition or the disc space may be greater than the normal disc space height or less than normal. An example of the range of the overall height dimension of an implant of the invention for intervertebral use when in the contracted configuration can be about 2 to 10 mm. An example of the range of the overall height dimension of the same implant when in the expanded configuration is about 4 to 20 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In general, the overall height of the fusion devices can be varied by varying the height of each member of the body. In addition, in some embodiments, a device of the invention can include a taper to provide a desired degree of angulation between the adjacent bones. In the case of an intervertebral joint, the angle provided can be about 0&deg; to 25&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> One or more fusion devices can be implanted in a single joint space. In the case of an intervertebral joint, the number of devices and the length and width dimensions of the devices can preferably be selected such that the device or devices fit and operate within the margins of the adjacent vertebral bodies. Examples of ranges of lengths and widths of devices of the invention are about 20 to 50 mm long and 5 to 50 mm wide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The fusion devices have a &ldquo;leading end&rdquo; and a &ldquo;trailing end.&rdquo; The terms &ldquo;leading end&rdquo; and &ldquo;trailing end&rdquo; are relative terms indicating that in typical use, the leading end of the implant is inserted into the joint space followed by the trailing end. The device can also be referred to in terms of a &ldquo;distal end&rdquo; and a &ldquo;proximal end&rdquo; based on the orientation of the implant relative to the surgeon. The fusion devices can be inserted into an intervertebral disc space through most known approaches including, anterior, posterior, lateral, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> A portion of the exterior region of each of the members can include a biological surface or a biocompatible material having surfaces which coaptate with the surfaces of bone or bone end plates surrounding the joint space. Suitable coaptating surfaces are typically contoured and include, for example, a porous bone in growth surface, spikes, knurls, ridges, threads, or other similar arrangement to facilitate stabilization of the implant in the joint space. In the case of a device having a circular cross section, helical threads can be provided for inserting the implant into a tapped or non-tapped disc space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Suitable materials for manufacturing a fusion device of the invention include metals such as titanium, stainless steel, cobalt-chromium, etc.; alloys including titanium alloys and non-titanium alloys; superelastic materials such as nitinol; plastics and plastic composites; carbon graphite; ceramic; etc. In some embodiments, the first and/or second member may be deflected when in the close packed position or the member may be deflected when being deployed into the expanded configuration. In these embodiments, the member deflected preferably has elastic properties permitting deflection of the member within its material limits without significantly affecting the structural integrity of the member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> According to the method of the invention, in one embodiment, prior to insertion, a discectomy can be performed, and, preferably, the annular ligament preserved. The endplates of the bone can be scraped, curretted or similar procedure performed to create an exposed end surface for facilitating bone growth across the fusion site. Then, with the device in the close packed configuration, the leading end can be inserted into the disc space followed by the trailing end. In some circumstances, it may be advantageous to distract the adjacent vertebrae prior to insertion of a fusion device. Such distraction can provide for easier removal of disc material and/or greater exposure to facilitate preparation of the end plates. Distraction can also provide greater accuracy in determining the appropriate size fusion device to implanted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Once inserted at the appropriate location the device can be deployed. If more than one implant is used at a particular joint space, each implant can be positioned within the joint space prior to deployment. Alternatively, individual implants can be inserted and deployed prior to insertion of a subsequent implant at the same joint space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> When a cylindrical fusion device is used, it may be advantageous to first drill a bore into the disc space of a size sufficient for receiving the device prior to insertion. In some embodiments, the bore may also be tapped for guiding threads which may be present on the surface of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The fusion devices can be deployed into the expanded configuration and locked in this configuration using, for example, a reverse plier, spreader, retractor, etc. Once deployed, the interior chamber of the fusion device and/or void areas surrounding the device(s) can be packed with a bone support matrix to facilitate bone growth into the joint space. As used herein, a &ldquo;bone support matrix&rdquo; is a material that facilitates new bone growth between the opposing vertebral bodies. Suitable bone support matrices can be resorbable or nonresorbable and osteoconductive or osteoinductive. Examples of suitable matrices according to the invention include synthetic materials, such as Healous&trade;, available from Orquest, Mountain View, Calif.; NeOsteo&trade;, available from Sulzer Orthopedic Biologics, Denver, Colo.; or any of a variety of bone morphogenic proteins (BMPs). Suitable bone support matrices also include heterologous (xenograft), homologous (allograft), or autologous (autograft) bone and derivatives thereof. Preferably, the bone support matrix is radiolucent on x-rays. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The fusion devices of the invention can be included in a kit comprising a plurality of incrementally sized implants which can be selected by the clinician based on the size needed for a particular patient. In other embodiments kits can include instrumentation for performing an implant procedure with or without a plurality of incrementally sized implants. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The fusion devices of the invention will now be further described by reference to the following illustrated embodiments. The illustrated embodiments are not intended to limit the scope of the invention, but rather, are provided to facilitate understanding of the devices and methods within the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE ILLUSTRATED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> With reference to the several drawing figures, a description of embodiments of an expandable fusion device according to the present invention will now be provided. The following discussion describes a fusion device of the invention with reference to implanting the device between adjacent lumbar vertebrae. However, this description is for explanatory purposes only. As stated above, the devices disclosed herein can be used at other joints or other spinal locations to facilitate bone fusion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of one embodiment of a fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the invention in an expanded configuration. Fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a first member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a second member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, first member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes a first side wall <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a second side wall <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> spaced apart by a base <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Second member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> also includes a first side wall <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and a second side wall <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> spaced apart by base <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, the exterior surface <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of first side wall <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the exterior surface <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of second side wall <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of first member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> fit within the interior surfaces <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> a and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of first side wall <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and second side wall <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, respectively, of second member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Thus, because first side wall <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and second side wall <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of second member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are &ldquo;external&rdquo; to first side wall <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and second side wall <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of first member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, second member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can also be referred to as external member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and first member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be referred to as internal member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the leading end <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is identical to trailing end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a transverse cross-section view through line <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As illustrated, the cross-section of internal member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and external member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> have a &ldquo;U&rdquo;-shaped appearance. The U-shape of fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is substantially rectangular. That is, for example, side walls <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> each form a right angle with base <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. However, the shape of a fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not limited to a rectangular cross section, other shape fusion devices are included within the scope of the invention. For example, fusion device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, has a substantially circular transverse cross section appearance. According to the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, first member <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> includes side walls <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> which meet at apex <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Second member <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> includes side walls <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> which meet at apex <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Fusion device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be implanted within a cylindrical bore prepared between adjacent vertebrae as will be described below. When implanted, fusion device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> will contact the end plates of opposing vertebrae at the apexes (<highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>) and along a portion of each of the side walls (<highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an end-on view of another embodiment of a fusion device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> which comprises an internal member <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> and an external member <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, internal member <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> is closed, or has a tubular configuration <highlight><bold>153</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a lateral view of a fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> inserted between opposing vertebrae. In use, fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is inserted in the disc space <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> between the end plates <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of opposing vertebrae <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is inserted into disc space <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the orientation illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Thus, base <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of internal member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is positioned to contact end plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and base <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of external member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is positioned to contact end plate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. However, it will be appreciated that fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> could also be inserted into a disc space <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> rotated <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>&deg; around long axis AL, regardless of the approach used for insertion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the bases <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which contact the end plates of the adjacent vertebrae can include openings <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> as illustrated for base <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> or no openings as illustrated for base <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Providing openings <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in base <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> advantageously promotes greater continuity of new bone growth within fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the leading end <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and trailing end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are identical. Thus, the height (H<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of side walls <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of external member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> measured from the exterior base <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of base <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to either of external edges <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, is identical at the leading end and trailing end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the device. Likewise, the height (H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) of the side walls of internal member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, measured from the exterior base <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of base <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to either internal edge <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, is the same at the leading and trailing end. In some embodiments, the overall height (H<highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight>) measured from the exterior <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of base <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to the exterior <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of base <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, can be different due to: a difference in the height (H<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) of internal side wall (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) at the leading end and trailing end, a difference in the height (H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) of external side wall (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) at the leading and trailing end; or a difference in the position of the components of the locking arrangement (discussed below). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates an alternative embodiment of a fusion device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> including internal member <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and external member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, base <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> of internal member <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. In addition, base <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> of external member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> also includes openings <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>. In alternative embodiments, the bases can include none, one, two, three or more openings. In addition, the exterior surfaces <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> of bases <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>, respectively, include an engagement arrangement <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> to facilitate engagement of fusion device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> with the end plates of the vertebrae. Use of an engagement arrangement <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> reduces the likelihood of migration or expulsion of the device after implantation. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, engagement arrangement <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of spikes <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> along the exterior base surfaces <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. Alternative engagement arrangements <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> can also be used including, for example, porous coated exterior in growth surfaces, knurls, ridges, threads, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The operation of a fusion device according to the invention will now be described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a transverse cross-section view through fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> at line <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in a non-expanded configuration. As illustrated, apertures <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>extend through side walls <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, near the external edges <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of external member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Apertures <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are sized for receiving pins <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>positioned near the internal ends <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively, of side walls <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of internal member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Thus, when in the non-expanded position, internal ends <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are positioned near or against base <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Also, when fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is in the non-deployed configuration, side walls <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of internal member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are deflected towards one another within the elastic limits of the material of the internal member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> After insertion into the intervertebral space, fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be deployed into the expanded position using a reverse plier (e.g., Inge Retractor, KMedic), spreader or retractor to force bases <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> away from one another into the deployed configuration in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. As illustrated, pins <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>interdigitate with apertures <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively, to lock fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the expanded position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6, 9</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, fusion device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes an alternative embodiment of a locking arrangement <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> for locking fusion device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> in the deployed configuration. According to this embodiment, external member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> includes grooves <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(not visible) and <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>along the interior surface of side walls <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>, respectively, for guiding pins <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(not visible) and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>into apertures <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a longitudinal section view through line <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of external member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, a locking arrangement <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is present at the leading end <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and trailing end <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> of fusion device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Focusing on the leading end <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, aperture <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is positioned near the external edge <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of external member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. Groove <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>extends from near base <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> to aperture <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a section view through line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> showing that groove <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>extends from near base <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> to aperture <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In this embodiment, when in the non-deployed state, side walls <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> of internal member <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> are deflected towards the longitudinal axis AL of fusion device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that while the embodiment of fusion device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6, 9</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrate that the aperture <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>traverses the thickness of wall <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> from interior <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to exterior <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the depth of apertures such as <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>need not traverse the entire wall thickness, but need only be sufficiently deep to provide the locking function of the locking arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, an alternative embodiment of a locking arrangement <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is illustrated for fusion device <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a view from the same location of a fusion device as that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. In this embodiment, side wall <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> of internal member <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of fusion device <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes a pin <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> near the internal edge <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight> of side wall <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. Side wall <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of external member <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> includes a groove <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> leading to aperture <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> near the external edge <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. However, according to this embodiment, groove <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> is ramped <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight>. That is, groove <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> extends deeper into the thickness of wall <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (from the interior surface <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the exterior surface <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) near base <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> than it does near aperture <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight>. Thus, in one preferred form of this embodiment, side wall <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> is only deflected inwardly towards the opposing internal wall during deployment as external member <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> and internal member <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> are being separated and pin <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> is moving from a position near base <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> to aperture <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> While the foregoing embodiments describe a fusion device having pins projecting from the internal wall and apertures (and grooves) in the external wall, the pins could also project inwardly from the external walls to interdigitate with apertures in the internal walls. Also, while the foregoing discussion of fusion devices describes deflection of internal walls, depending on the material of the device, some elastic deflection of the walls of both the internal and external members can occur without substantially affecting the function of the devices of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, a fusion device according to the invention can be configured for creating and maintaining a desired degree of lordosis between the adjacent vertebrae. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a side view of one embodiment of such a lordotic fusion device. As illustrated, device <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> includes a divergent angle &agr; tapering from leading end <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight> to trailing end <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, external member <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight> is positioned above internal member <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>. Side wall <highlight><bold>405</bold></highlight> of external member <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight> includes parallel surfaces along external edge <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> and base <highlight><bold>407</bold></highlight>. In contrast, base <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> of internal member <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> is not parallel with internal edge <highlight><bold>409</bold></highlight>. Locking arrangements <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> can be in the form of any of the embodiments described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> illustrates a side view of an alternative embodiment of a lordotic fusion device <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. According to this embodiment, when in the non-expanded configuration, there is no taper from leading end <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> to trailing end <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> when fusion device <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> is in non-expanded configuration. However, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, apertures <highlight><bold>503</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> of external member <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> are not positioned an equal distance from base <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. Rather, aperture <highlight><bold>503</bold></highlight> is positioned closer to base <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> than is aperture <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. Pins <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> (hatches) of internal member <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> are located the same distance from base <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>. Thus, when deployed, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, fusion device <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> can be locked into position to a configuration providing a lordotic taper of angle &agr;. Various relative positions of apertures <highlight><bold>503</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> can be used to create different devices having different degrees of angulation. Alternatively, the aperture positions can remain fixed and the position of pins <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> can be varied to provide a lordotic fusion device similar to that described for fusion device <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In use, a single fusion device may be inserted into the disc space between opposing vertebrae. Alternatively, two fusion devices may be implanted parallel to one another as described for non-expandable fusion devices as disclosed in, for example, U.S. Pat. No. 5,489,307, the entire disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> According to the method of the invention, the disc space to be fused can be identified, and a surgical approach to the disc made, using methods known in the art. Once the disc space is exposed, a discectomy can be performed. A portion of the end plates can be removed to create bleeding edges to facilitate fusion. If an anterior approach is used for implanting two fusion devices, a first fusion device is inserted between the adjacent vertebrae on a first side of the mid-line of the disc space. The first fusion device can be deployed once in position. The second fusion device can then be placed on the second side of the midline and subsequently deployed. Alternatively, the first and second fusion devices may first be placed into the intervertebral disc space and subsequently deployed. If the tissues surrounding the joint prevent full deployment of a selected fusion device for the locking arrangement to lock, an alternative fusion device having a shorter overall height Ho may need to be used. Alternatively, a greater depth of the bone ends may be removed to accommodate the overall height (Ho) of the originally selected fusion device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic illustration of an anterior view two fusion devices <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the invention in an expanded configuration between adjacent vertebrae <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. According to this embodiment, preferably, the width (W) of each fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is selected such that when in the disc space, the fusion devices are completely within the margins of vertebrae <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic illustration of an anterior view of a single fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the disc space between adjacent vertebrae <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. According to this embodiment, the width (W) of fusion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is of sufficient size to provide stability across a major portion of the articular surfaces of vertebrae <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, preferably without extending beyond the margins of the vertebrae. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> As stated previously, the fusion devices disclosed herein can be implanted through approaches known in the art, including, anterior, posterior, lateral, etc. Various size implants will be available ranging in size from 5 to 50 mm in width. Because a fusion device(s) of the invention can assume a close packed configuration, the devices of the invention require a smaller skin incision and reduce the likelihood of trauma to neural and/or vascular structures during surgical implantation. In addition, the time required for performing an implant procedure can be reduced because distraction procedures prior to implementation are optional. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> If a fusion device having a circular cross-section as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is used, a cylindrical bore will likely need to be created between adjacent vertebrae at the affected disc space. Methods for creating cylindrical bores are known. However, in contrast to some methods for creating a cylindrical bore between opposing vertebrae such as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,489,307, no distraction is required prior to preparing the bore according to the methods of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> After the fusion devices are inserted, the intervertebral space not occupied by the fusion devices and the interior of the body of the fusion devices may be filled with a bone support matrix as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing detailed description and examples, it will be evident that modifications and variations can be made in the devices and methods of the invention without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention. Therefore, it is intended that all modifications and verifications not departing from the spirit of the invention come within the scope of the claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What I claim is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant having an expanded and non-expanded configuration and comprising: 
<claim-text>an external member including: 
<claim-text>a leading end and a trailing end, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an external base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first external wall and a second external wall spaced apart by a width of the external base, each of the first and second external walls having an external base end nearest the external base and an external edge away from the external base; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an internal member including: 
<claim-text>a leading end and a trailing end, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an internal base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first internal wall and a second internal wall having a spacing therebetween for the first and second internal walls to fit within the first and second external walls, each of the first and second internal walls having an internal base end nearest the internal base and an internal edge away from the internal base; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pin and a second pin projecting from a selected one of the walls of the external member and the walls of the internal member; 
<claim-text>a first aperture and a second aperture each positioned in a selected one of the walls of the external members and the walls of the internal members such that the first pin is receivable by the first aperture and the second pin is receivable by the second aperture. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the first pin projects from the first internal wall and the second pin projects from the second internal wall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first aperture is in the first external wall and the second pin is in the second external wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first external member is U-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the internal member is U-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the internal member is tubular. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second pins project from the leading end of the internal member and the first and second apertures are at the leading end of the external member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An expandable intervertebral fusion device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein when in the expanded configuration, the first pin interdigitates with the first apertures and the second pin interdigitates with the second aperture. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein when in the non-expanded configuration the first and second internal walls are deflected towards one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a trailing height of the first and second internal walls, measured from the internal base to the internal edge at the trailing end of the first and second internal walls, is greater than a leading height of the first and second internal walls, measured from the internal base to the internal edge at the leading end of the first and second internal walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the external member includes a third aperture at the trailing end of the first external wall and a fourth aperture at the trailing end of the second external wall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the internal member includes a third pin projecting externally from the trailing end of the first internal wall and positioned to be received by the third aperture and a fourth pin projecting externally from the trailing end of the second internal wall and positioned to be received by the fourth aperture. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first aperture is positioned at the leading end and a distance between the external base and the first aperture is less than a distance between the external base and the third aperture. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first pin is positioned at the leading end and a distance between the internal base and the first pin is less than a distance between the internal base and the third pin. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second members each have a circular cross section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the internal and external members each have a rectangular cross section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>the first aperture is positioned near the first external edge and the second aperture is positioned near the second external edge; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first external wall includes a first groove extending from the first external base end of the first external wall to the first aperture and the second external wall includes a second groove extending from the second external base end to the second aperture. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second grooves are ramped from the first and second external base ends to the first and second apertures, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the internal base and external base each include at least one opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein an exterior surface of the external base and an exterior surface of the internal base each include an engagement arrangement for engaging end plates of adjacent vertebrae. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An intervertebral implant according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the engagement arrangement comprises a plurality of spikes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method for stabilizing an intervertebral disc space between adjacent vertebrae, the method comprising a step of: 
<claim-text>removing disc material from the disc space; </claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting an expandable fusion implant into the disc space, wherein the fusion implant comprises: 
<claim-text>(a) an external member including: 
<claim-text>(i) a leading end and a trailing end, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) an external base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) a first external wall and a second external wall spaced apart by a width of the external base, each of the first and second external walls having an external base end nearest the external base and an external edge away from the external base; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) an internal member including: 
<claim-text>(i) a leading end and a trailing end, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) a first internal base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) a first internal wall and a second internal wall having a spacing therebetween for the first and second internal walls to fit within the first and second external walls, each of the first and second internal walls having an internal base end nearest the internal base and an internal edge away from the internal base; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a first pin and a second pin projecting from a selected one of the walls of the external member and the walls of the internal member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a first aperture and a second aperture each positioned in a selected one of the walls of the external members and the walls of the internal members such that the first pin is receivable by the first aperture and the second pin is receivable by the second aperture. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>expanding the fusion device into an expanded configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein two expandable fusion implants are inserted into the disc space. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the expandable fusion implant is packed with a bone support matrix after inserting the fusion implant into the disc space. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> including a step of forming a bore between adjacent vertebrae before inserting the expandable fusion implant into the disc space. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the bore is circular.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004575A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004575A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004575A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004575A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004575A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
