<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001083A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001083A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001083A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001083A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001083A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001083A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001083A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001083A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001083</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10171192</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020612</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01J005/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>250</class>
<subclass>239000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Self contained sensing apparatus and system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301557</doc-number>
<document-date>20010628</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Christopher</given-name>
<family-name>Corrado</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hatfield</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>George</given-name>
<family-name>Rawa</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Harleysville</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Carmin</given-name>
<family-name>Quartapella</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Schwenksville</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Timothy</given-name>
<family-name>Edwards</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Harleysville</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Greene Tweed of Delaware, Inc.</organization-name>
<address>
<address-1>1100 North Market Street</address-1>
<city>Wilmington</city>
<state>DE</state>
<postalcode>19890</postalcode>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>AKIN, GUMP, STRAUSS, HAUER &amp; FELD, L.L.P.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>ONE COMMERCE SQUARE, SUITE 2200</address-1>
<address-2>2005 MARKET STREET</address-2>
<city>PHILADELPHIA</city>
<state>PA</state>
<postalcode>19103</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A self contained sensing apparatus includes a housing establishing an interior compartment, the housing having a maximum thickness which is less than the size of an access portal for inserting the housing into an area for sensing. The housing includes a window extending through a principal housing surface. A sensor is provided within the housing and generally aligned with the window for sensing at least one parameter. In a preferred embodiment, the sensor is an optical sensor for sensing images through the window. A transmitter is provided within the housing and coupled with the sensor for receiving signals representative of the sensed parameter and transmitting the signals out of the housing. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/301,557, filed Jun. 28, 2001 and entitled &ldquo;Self Contained Monitoring Apparatus and System For Use In A Harsh or Hostile Environment&rdquo;, the entire subject matter of which is hereby incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to a self contained sensing apparatus and system and, more particularly, to a self contained sensing apparatus for monitoring or measuring one or more parameters, performing visual inspections, calibration or otherwise obtaining information within a controlled environment, such as in a sealed semiconductor wafer processing chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> There are many situations in which it is desirable to have the ability to measure or monitor one or more parameters or to make visual inspections or calibration within a controlled environment which is not readily accessible. For example, it is desirable to have the ability to monitor one or more parameters, such as temperature, pressure, etc. within a controlled environment such as the environment within an operating semiconductor wafer processing chamber. The environment within such a semiconductor wafer processing chamber, particularly during the processing of semiconductor wafers, includes high vacuum pressures and low visibility. The use of existing, standard, monitoring equipment and/or techniques within such a semiconductor wafer processing chamber is ineffective because most existing monitoring equipment is not constructed to withstand the conditions present or to operate within the physical or dimensional constraints within such a semiconductor wafer processing chamber. The present invention overcomes the problems of the prior art by providing a self contained sensing apparatus for insertion into a controlled environment, such as the interior of a semiconductor processing chamber, for the purpose of monitoring or measuring one or more such parameters and and/or performing visual inspections, calibration or otherwise obtaining information concerning features within the controlled environment. In a preferred embodiment, as described below, the present invention comprises a self contained apparatus for viewing the interior of a semiconductor wafer processing chamber for the purpose of inspection, calibration or other applications. The described viewing apparatus is of a particular size and shape which facilitates insertion of the apparatus into the semiconductor wafer processing chamber through an existing gate opening so as to preclude a significant disruption of any semiconductor processing which may be ongoing within the chamber. The described viewing apparatus is also particularly suited to be received within the robotic arm within the semiconductor wafer processing chamber to facilitate movement of the apparatus for viewing at various locations within the semiconductor processing chamber. The apparatus contains a transmitter for transmitting viewed images to a receiver outside of the semiconductor wafer processing chamber for receiving and displaying the viewed images in real time or near real time. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Briefly stated, the present invention comprises a self contained sensing apparatus including a housing establishing an interior compartment. The housing has a thickness which is less than the size of an access portal for inserting the housing into an area for sensing. The housing includes a window extending through a principal housing surface. A sensor is located within the housing and is generally aligned with the window for sensing at least one parameter through the window. In a preferred embodiment, the sensor comprises an optical sensor for sensing images through the window. A transmitter within the housing is coupled with the sensor for receiving signals representative of the parameter or images sensed and transmitting the signals out of the housing. In a preferred embodiment, a receiver is located out of the area being sensed for receiving the transmitted signals. The receiver is coupled to a monitor for displaying the sensed parameter or images. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The foregoing summary, as well as the following detailed description of preferred embodiments of the invention, will be better understood when read in conjunction with the appended drawings. For the purpose of illustrating the invention, there are shown in the drawings embodiments which are presently preferred. It should be understood, however, that the invention is not limited to the precise arrangements and instrumentalities shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In the drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a preferred embodiment of a self contained sensing apparatus and system in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of the sensing apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a printed circuit board of the sensing apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a lens and holder assembly of the sensing apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a charging jack of the sensing apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of the sensing apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Referring to the drawings, wherein like numerals are used to designate like components throughout the several figures, there is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, a self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with a first preferred embodiment of the present invention. The preferred embodiment of the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as hereinafter described may be used for performing visual inspections, calibration or otherwise obtaining information from within a controlled environment. In the presently preferred embodiment, the controlled environment comprises a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> including a robotic arm assembly for wafer delivery. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, is a generally sealed environment which is formed of materials and methods well known to those of ordinary skill in the art. Contained within the chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are the equipment and components (not shown), which are necessary for establishing the environment required for processing semiconductor wafers. Such equipment and components are also well known to those of ordinary skill in the art and further details regarding the structure and operation of such equipment and components are not necessary for a complete understanding of the present invention. One such component which is contained within the chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is a robotic arm assembly <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, which is primarily employed for the purpose of transferring semiconductor wafers into an out of the chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> through a suitable slot-like sealed doorway referred to as a gate opening <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The robotic arm assembly <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, often referred to as a robot arm, is comprised of a base member (not shown), a wafer holding assembly <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and supporting linkage members <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> which are employed for moving the remainder of the robotic arm assembly <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to and at least partially through the gate opening <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and to various locations within the chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to facilitate processing of the semiconductor wafers. The robotic arm assembly <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is of a type well known to those of ordinary skill in the semiconductor wafer processing art. Further details concerning the structure and operation of the robotic arm assembly <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> are not necessary for a complete understanding of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The foregoing description relates to a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of a type well known to those of ordinary skill in the semiconductor wafer processing art. Such chambers <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are commercially available from several well known manufacturers, including Applied Materials, Inc. Further details regarding the structure and operation of the chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are available from the various manufacturers and a variety of publicly available sources and are not necessary for a complete understanding of the present invention. It is also understood by those of ordinary skill in the art that during a semiconductor wafer processing operation, the interior of a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the type described and shown is maintained at a temperature in the range of 60-400&deg; C. and is subjected to vacuum pressures in the range of 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>Torr, thereby creating an environment which effectively precludes the use of standard, unprotected sensing or monitoring equipment and techniques, including standard video cameras or other unprotected viewing equipment. The inability to effectively use such sensing equipment and techniques within such a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> makes it more difficult to fully know the values of certain parameters within the chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> at various times during the processing of semiconductor wafers, which are desirable to better control the processing of the semiconductor wafers. The present invention overcomes the difficulties associated with the prior art by providing a self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for measuring or monitoring one or more parameters or obtaining visual images from within a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> during the processing of the semiconductor wafers and for transmitting the information obtained to equipment outside of the semiconductor processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for analysis by an operator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> It should be clearly understood by those of ordinary skill in the art that while in the embodiment described below and shown in the drawings, the self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is particularly well suited for use in measuring or monitoring parameters or making visual inspections within a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, this is but one of many uses for a self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention. It should also be clearly understood by those of ordinary skill in art that while the below described embodiment of the self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> specifically relates to the sensing of visual images using an optical sensor, the invention is not limited to visual or optical sensing but is also applicable to the sensing of other parameters including pressure, temperature, air content, humidity or other environmental factors, spectrographic analysis or other analysis of chemical composition and the like. It will also be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that more than one sensor or more than one type of sensor may be employed within the self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for a particular application. Thus, it should be clearly understood that the present invention is not limited to the particular optical sensor described below and shown in the drawings nor is the present invention limited to use of the sensing apparatus in a particular environment, such as the interior of a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is comprised of a housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> establishing an interior compartment <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for purposes which will hereinafter become apparent. The housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, in the present embodiment, is comprised of a generally flat base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> having a first principal surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>a second principal surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a first predetermined thickness T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In the present embodiment, the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is generally circular and includes a central axis <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the circumference of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is generally the same as or smaller than the circumference of a semiconductor wafer of the type which may be processed within the semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and preferably the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is in the range of 6 to 18 inches in diameter. As best shown on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</cross-reference>, the first surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is generally flat and includes a pair of thin, generally parallel, spaced apart outwardly extending flange members <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with a chamfered area <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> generally in the shape of a truncated circle therebetween. The parallel flange members <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the chamfered area <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are provided to permit the first surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to interface with complimentary shaped features on the surface of the wafer holding assembly <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the robot arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> within the semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to facilitate orienting the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with respect to the robot arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> when the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is installed on the wafer holding assembly <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) and to help hold the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in place as it is moved by the robot arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> into, out of and to locations within the chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. If desired, other structural features may be incorporated into or extend from the first surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to facilitate proper orientation and interfacing of the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with the robot arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 8</cross-reference>, a first, generally annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> extends from the generally flat second surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is generally coaxial with the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and includes an outer dimension which, in the present embodiment, is established by the outer circumference of the first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and which is less than the circumference of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> includes a distal surface <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and has a second predetermined thickness T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 8</cross-reference>, the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> further includes a generally flat cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> which, in the present embodiment, is generally circular having an outer dimension or circumference which is at least as great as and preferably the same as the outer circumference of the first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> has a first principal surface <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>a second principal surface and a third predetermined thickness T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the second surface of the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> engages the distal surface <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to establish, with the first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> the interior compartment <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. In the present embodiment, when the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is assembled, the first, second and third predetermined thicknesses T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> combine to establish a maximum thickness of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the maximum thickness of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is less than the size of an access portal to an area within which sensing is to take place, in the present embodiment the gate opening <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, to facilitate inserting the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> into the semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> or into some other area for performing the desired sensing. It is important that the self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> have the ability to be inserted into and removed from the semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> through the gate opening <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> or from any such other area within which sensing is desired in order to permit the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to perform the desired sensing task(s) without disrupting or unduly affecting the environment within the semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> or other area for sensing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 8</cross-reference>, the second surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes four additional flange members <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, which together form a subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> within the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In the presently preferred embodiment, the flange members <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are generally of the same thickness, have two different lengths and are generally perpendicular to each other so that the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is generally rectangular. It will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may be of some other shape, if desired. The subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is established for the purpose of receiving and retaining a printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> in a manner which will hereinafter be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The second surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> further includes a plurality of generally parallel and generally perpendicular reinforcing members or ribs <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> at spaced locations between the inner circumference of the first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the flange members <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> which form the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to provide additional rigidity to the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in a manner well known to those of ordinary skill in the art. The base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> further includes an opening or port which extends completely through the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from the first surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the second surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for the purpose of establishing a viewing window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In the present embodiment, the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is generally circular and is coaxial with the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, i.e., the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extends through the axial center of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> need not be circular and need not extend through the axial center of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, if desired. In the present embodiment, the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is generally open. However, in other applications, the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may be covered or enclosed with a protective material. The protective material, which is preferably transparent, may be generally flat and formed of a substance which is resistant to abrasion, scoring and other conditions present in the environment within which the self contained sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be operating but which also has lens quality, high light transmission, particularly in the infrared, visible and ultraviolet ranges. Such materials may include synthetic sapphire, particularly a single crystal synthetic sapphire, glass, quartz, a polymeric material or any other suitable light transmissive material resistant to the particular environment within which the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be operating. If desired, additional windows (not shown) could be provided at other locations of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, a generally square boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> generally surrounds the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> on the second surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In addition, a second, smaller, generally elongated, oval shaped opening <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> extends through the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> within the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> at a location slightly spaced from one side of the boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Further, an opening <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> extends through the flange member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The purposes of the boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and the openings <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> will hereinafter be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The second surface of the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> also includes four flange members, which are arranged in substantially the same manner as the flange members <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In this manner, when the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is installed as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the flange members on the second surface of the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> align with the corresponding flange members <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> on the second surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to effectively establish the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for receiving and retaining the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> as will hereinafter be described. One of the flange members of the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes an opening extending therethrough. The second surface of the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> also includes a plurality of reinforcing members or ribs to provide additional rigidity. The second surface of the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> further includes a second generally annular flange member <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in a location generally aligned with the first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, in this embodiment corresponding to the outer circumference of the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The first annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the second flange member <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> each include generally semicircular shaped openings <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> which are generally aligned with each other so that when the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is installed on the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a generally circular opening <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is established. A second pair of openings extend through the first and second annular flange members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> generally aligned with each other to establish a second generally circular opening when the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is installed on the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> When the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is installed on the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> the first and second annular flange member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> align with each other to establish the interior compartment <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The openings extend through the annular flange members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to provide access to the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for purposes which will hereinafter be described. In the preferred embodiment, the maximum thickness of the housing (established by the combination of T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) is less than the thickness of the gate opening <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in the semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and preferably is less than one half of an inch thick. In the presently preferred embodiment, the maximum thickness of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is about 0.35 inch. For purposes of measuring parameters or sensing images within the semiconductor wafer chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> the interior compartment <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> need not be sealed or gas tight. However, in other applications, it may desirable to have a gas tight or sealed interior compartment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (and all of the associated components thus far described) are formed of a generally rigid polymeric material. However, it will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be formed of any other suitable structurally sound, non-warping, preferably light weight, resilient material which is resistant to the environment in which the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be used. The material may be gas impervious and capable of forming a gas tight seal in some applications. Materials which may be employed include ferrous metals and alloys, non-ferrous metals and alloys, ceramics, polymeric materials such as thermoplastic or thermoset polymeric materials and composite materials such as glass, aramid or carbon fiber thermoplastics. In some applications, the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and associated components may be made of a first material and the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and associated components may be made of a second material as long as the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> remains structurally sound, non-warping and provides sufficient protection for components (hereinafter described) contained within the interior compartment <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be made utilizing known material forming techniques including casting, molding, machining, etc. or any combination of such techniques. Preferably, the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is secured to the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> utilizing a snap in engagement of a type well known to those of ordinary skill in the art supplemented with an adhesive, preferably an ultraviolet curable adhesive also well known to those of ordinary skill in the art. Alternatively, the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be secured to the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> utilizing suitable mechanical fasteners, such as screws or bolts (not shown) or in any other suitable manner including thermal welding, brazing, some other type of clamp or fastener or using some other type of adhesive. Thus, the present invention is not limited to the use of a particular manner or technique for fastening the cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> as thus far described is conveniently sized and shaped to be received within a robot arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> or other suitable movement device located within a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for the purpose of moving the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into and out of the chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> through the existing gate opening <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and to selected locations to facilitate visual inspection, calibration and/or monitoring or measuring at any desired location within the processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. This is an important feature because it permits the insertion, removal and movement of the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> without having to breakdown or open the semiconductor processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and without having to disrupt, in any significant manner; the processing of semiconductor wafers. In the present embodiment, the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is not air tight or otherwise sealed. However, in other applications, the interior compartment <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be sealed or encapsulated to provide enhanced protection for the components contained therein. In some applications, the interior compartment <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may include thermal insulation (not shown) or a coolant (not shown) and/or EMI shielding (not shown) to further protect the components contained therein. Thus, it should be clearly understood that the size, shape and configuration of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> as shown and described is merely for a single preferred embodiment of the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for use in a semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. It will be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art that the size, shape and configuration of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> could vary substantially from what is shown and described, particularly for other applications. Therefore, the present invention is not limited to a sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the above-described housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The interior compartment <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and, particularly the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> contains the various components and subassemblies, which together form the operational aspects of the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which are collectively referred to as the sensor assembly. The sensor assembly includes three principal subassemblies, a sensor subassembly, a transmitter subassembly and a power source subassembly. In the present embodiment, each of the principal subassemblies are mounted on or otherwise secured to a substrate, in the present embodiment a printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, which is of a type well known to those of ordinary skill in the art. In the present embodiment, the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is generally rectangular and is sized to be received and retained within the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> when the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is assembled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, the sensor subassembly includes an optical sensor for sensing images through the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extending through the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In the present embodiment, the optical sensor comprises a high efficiency, low voltage CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, which functions as a single chip video camera. The CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, in the present embodiment, is of the VGA type which is PAL/NTSC and SEcam compatible and comprises 640&times;480 pixels in EIA TV standard format. The CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is secured to the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> at a central location so that when the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is installed within the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> extends into and is surrounded by the square boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>), which surrounds the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extending through the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A lens and lens holder <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> are also located and retained within the square boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> such that the lens is located between the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the lens is of the plano-convex type and includes an appropriate focal length to provide sufficient visual clarity within the desired range of operation of the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. It will be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art that different lenses may be employed for different applications. For example, in some applications, a telescoping lens may be employed whereas in other applications a rotational prism lens may be employed. Accordingly, the precise type of lens employed and/or its focal length should not be considered to be a limitation on the present invention. In the present embodiment, the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is generally square with outer dimensions, which closely correspond to the inner dimensions of the square boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. In this manner, when the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is installed within the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> with the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> extending into the square boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the square boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> blocks extraneous light (i.e., light received other than through the window <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>) from entering either the lens or the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The sensor subassembly also includes a pair of light emitting diodes (LEDs) <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, which are secured to the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> a short distance from the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The LEDs <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are located on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> so that when the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is installed within the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, the LEDs <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are aligned with the elongated, oval-shaped opening <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> extending through the housing base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In this manner, when the LEDs <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are lit, light from the LEDs <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> shines through the elongated oval opening <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to illuminate the viewing area of the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. In the present embodiment, the LEDs <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are of the infrared type and provide sufficient illumination of the area within the focal length of the lens and CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that other types of LEDs may be employed if desired or, if desired, some other lighting source may be provided. It will also be appreciated by those skilled in the art that in some applications less that or more than two LEDs or no lighting source may be needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that while, in the present embodiment, a CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is employed for sensing the visual images, other types of cameras or visual sensors could alternatively be employed including cameras of the SVGA, XGA or MEGA pixel type. If desired, multiple cameras of differing types of resolution could be employed with lenses of varying types and focal lengths. The camera could be of a static (still) or dynamic (video) type and could either be of the charged coupled device (CCD) type, if desired. In addition, the camera chip or CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> could be used to output a video signal in any standard TV format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The transmitter subassembly includes a transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and an associated antenna (not shown). In the present embodiment, the transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is of the standard FM type and includes a voltage controlled oscillator (VCO). Preferably, the transmitter operates in the 2.4 to 2.5 gigaHertz microwave channel, which is generally known as the &ldquo;Blue Tooth&rdquo; channel. The video signal output from the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is preconditioned utilizing standard conditioning circuitry and is fed into the input of the transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> for transmission out of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> utilizing the antenna. Preferably, the antenna is of the directional tuned type and is incorporated into the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> but any other suitable antenna could be used. Further details concerning the structure and operation of the transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and antenna are well known to those of ordinary skill in the art and are not necessary for a complete understanding of the present invention. It will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that any other suitable type of transmitter and antenna combination may alternatively be employed as long as the transmitter and antenna are compatible with the conditioned video signals received from the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> for transmission out of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. It will also be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that the transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> may operate in some other frequency range, if desired. Alternatively, some other type of transmitter, such as an infrared transmitter, could be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The power source subassembly includes a battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, which is secured to the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and associated circuit components (not shown). In the present embodiment, the battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is of the lithium ion type with a nominal voltage in the range of 3.7 volts. The battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is also preferably of the rechargeable type and may be recharged without removing the battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> from the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. For this purpose, a charging jack <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is connected to the battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and/or its associated circuitry. The charging jack <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is installed within the opening <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> extending through the first and second annular flange members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> as described above. In this manner, the distal end of the charging jack <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be conveniently accessed from outside of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to facilitate charging of the battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Associated with the battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is the usual protection circuitry (not shown), including circuitry to preclude short circuits, to minimize discharging of the battery and to facilitate the use of the charging jack <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. A voltage regulator (not shown) of the type well known to those of ordinary skill in the art is also provided. The battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and associated circuitry provides power at the required voltage levels for all of the other components on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. While in the present embodiment, the battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is of the lithium ion type, it will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that other types of rechargeable batteries may be alternatively employed including a silver oxide battery, a lithium metal halide battery, a Ni-CAD battery or an alkaline battery. Further, although in the present embodiment, the battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is of the rechargeable type, a non-rechargeable battery may be used in some applications. In addition, while in the presently preferred embodiment, recharging of the battery <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is accomplished by physically connecting a charger (not shown) to the charging jack <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, other methods may be employed for recharging the battery including utilizing a charge coupled coil, photovoltaic cells or some other method or technique known to those of ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The power source subassembly further includes an on/off switch to power down the other subassemblies and thereby save battery life when the sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not in use. In the present embodiment, the on/off switch comprises a standard magnetically actuated reed switch <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> connected between the power source subassembly <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and the other components on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. The reed switch <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is located on the circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> so as to be next to the opening <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> in the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and generally aligned with openings of the first and second annular flange members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. In this manner, a small magnet (not shown) may be moved into the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> through the associated openings to change the state of the magnetically actuated reed switch <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. In the presently preferred embodiment, the close proximity of the magnet to the magnetically actuated reed switch <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> causes power to be applied to the various components on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and the absence of the magnet results in no power being applied to any of the components. It will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that other types of on/off switching devices may alternatively be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The sensing apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is assembled by first placing the printed circuit board within the subcompartment <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> so that the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and its associated lens is within the square boss <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> with the LEDs <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> aligned with the elongated oval-shaped opening <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The battery jack <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is positioned within the circular opening <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The cover member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is then placed over the base member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> with the various features aligned as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> receiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is provided for receiving the signals transmitted by the transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and antenna. Preferably, the receiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is located outside of the semiconductor wafer processing chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> but within the reception range of the transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. In the present embodiment, the receiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is a four channel 2.4-2.5 gigaHertz FM type receiver of a type well known to those of ordinary skill in the art and adapted for receiving transmissions from the transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. The receiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> in turn is connected to a monitor <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, which preferably is of the flat screen type and is fully compatible for reception and display of signals generated by the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the monitor <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is of the VGA type but other types of compatible monitors may alternatively be employed. In this manner, images sensed by the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> are transmitted out of the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by the transmitter <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and antenna where they are received by the receiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, demodulated and sent to the monitor <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> for display and viewing by an operator. It will be apparent by those of ordinary skill in the art that other types of receivers and/or types of monitor devices may alternatively be employed in a particular application. For example, the monitor could comprise a personal computer, laptop computer, notebook computer, PDA, cellular phone or any other electronic device which includes data acquisition software for receiving and displaying the demodulated video signals. Further, the receiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and monitor <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> may be integrated as a single unit. The monitor <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> could include a liquid crystal display device or any other suitable type of display known to those of ordinary skill in the art. If desired, a printer (not shown) could be associated with the monitor <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> for providing a more permanent record of images captured by the CMOS sensor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that changes could be made to the embodiments described above without departing from the broad inventive concept thereof. It is understood, therefore, that this invention is not limited to the particular embodiments disclosed, but it is intended to cover modifications within the spirit and scope of the present invention as defined by the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I/we claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A self contained sensing apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing establishing an interior compartment, the housing having a maximum thickness which is less than the size of an access portal for inserting the housing into an area for sensing, the housing including a window extending through a principal housing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor within the housing and generally aligned with the window for sensing at least one parameter; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmitter within the housing coupled with the sensor for receiving signals representative of the sensed parameter and transmitting the signals out of the housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the housing comprises: 
<claim-text>a generally flat base member having a first principal surface, a second principal surface and a first predetermined thickness, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first flange member extending from the second surface of the base member, the first flange member having a distal surface, an outer dimension and a second predetermined thickness, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a generally flat cover member having a first principal surface, a second principal surface and a third predetermined thickness, the cover member having a dimension which is at least as great as the dimension of the first flange member, the second surface of the cover member engaging the distal surface of the first flange member to establish, with base member, the compartment, the first, second and third predetermined thicknesses, when combined, establishing the maximum thickness of the housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the base member is generally circular and has an axis, the first flange member is generally annular, has an axis and an outer circumference and is coaxial with the base member and the cover member is generally circular, has an axis and is coaxial with the base member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor comprises an optical sensor for sensing images through the window. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, which is used for viewing the interior of a semiconductor wafer processing chamber having a gate opening and a robot arm, wherein the base member is sized to be received by the robot arm and the maximum thickness of the housing is less than the size of the gate opening so that the housing may be inserted into the chamber through the gate opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical sensor comprises a video camera. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the video camera comprises a CMOS sensor located adjacent to the window. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the video camera further comprises a lens having a predetermined focal length positioned between the CMOS sensor and the window. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the housing further includes an opening extending through the principal housing surface proximate to the window and wherein the video camera further comprises a light emitting diode aligned with the opening for providing illumination to an area viewed by the CMOS sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transmitter is of the FM type and operates at a frequency in the range of 2.4-2.5 gigaHertz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> further including a tuned antenna connected to the transmitter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> further including: 
<claim-text>a receiver located out of the processing chamber for receiving signals from the transmitter and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a monitor coupled to the receiver for displaying the sensed images. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> further including a power source comprised of a rechargeable battery. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the battery is of the lithium ion type. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> further including a charging jack accessible from the outside of the housing for recharging the battery. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> further including an on/off switch for applying or removing power from the battery to other components within the housing period. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the on/off switch comprises a magnetically actuated reed switch accessible from the outside of the housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further including a receiver located outside of the area for sensing for receiving signals from the transmitter and a monitor coupled to the receiver for displaying the signals representative of the sensed parameter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transmitter is of the FM type and operates at a frequency in the range of 2.4-2.5 gigahertz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The sensing apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further including a power source comprised of a rechargeable battery.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001083A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001083A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001083A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001083A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
