<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001492A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001492A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001492A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001492A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001492A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001492A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001492A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001492A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001492A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001492A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001492</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896249</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01J007/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>313</class>
<subclass>496000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Cleaning of cathode-ray tube display</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shiyou</given-name>
<family-name>Pei</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Saratoga</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Colin</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Stanners</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Frederick</given-name>
<middle-name>K.</middle-name>
<family-name>Byers</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Los Gatos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SKJERVEN MORRILL LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>25 METRO DRIVE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 700</address-2>
<city>SAN JOSE</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95110</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Inert gas provided at a suitable level inside a hermetically sealed cathode-ray tube display, typically of the flat-panel type, enables the display&apos;s electron-emitting device (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) to be automatically cleaned during display operation subsequent to final display sealing. Upon being struck by electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device, atoms (<highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>) of the inert gas ionize to produce positively charged ions (<highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>) which travel backward to the electron-emitting device and dislodge overlying contaminant material (<highlight><bold>130 </bold></highlight>and <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>). A getter (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>) collects dislodged contaminant. A reservoir (<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) provides inert gas to replace inert gas lost during the cleaning process. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF USE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to cathode-ray tube (&ldquo;CRT&rdquo;) displays, especially CRT displays of the flat-panel type. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A flat-panel CRT display basically consists of an electron-emitting device and a light-emitting device that operate at low internal pressure, typically from 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr to 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr. The electron-emitting device, commonly referred to as a cathode, contains electron-emissive elements allocated into a group of laterally separated electron-emissive regions for emitting electrons over a relatively wide area. The emitted electrons are directed towards light-emissive regions distributed over a corresponding area in the light-emitting device. Upon being struck by the electrons, the light-emissive regions emit light that produces an image on the viewing surface of the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The electron-emissive elements need to be clean during display operation. Contaminants that build up on the surfaces of the electron-emissive elements act to increase the height and/or width of the electron tunneling barriers. This leads to higher operating voltages for the displays, and attendant emission degradation. Also, contamination of the electron-emissive surfaces produces emission non-uniformity and leads to undesirable image artifacts. Degraded display performance, even display failure, is commonly the result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Various techniques have been reported for cleaning electron-emissive elements in flat-panel CRT displays. For example, see U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,635,790 and 6,004,180. The cleaning techniques described in these two patents are performed during display fabrication and thus prior to final display sealing including evacuation to the desired initial internal display pressure. The cleaning techniques may, as occurs in some of the techniques described in U.S. Pat. No. 6,004,180, entail operating the electron-emissive elements. Nonetheless, the cleaning techniques are still completed prior to final display sealing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In addition to becoming contaminated during display fabrication, electron-emissive elements in a flat-panel CRT display also become contaminated during display operation subsequent to final display sealing. For instance, material that contaminates the electron-emissive elements can be released from the display&apos;s light-emitting device when it is struck by electrons emitted by the display&apos;s electron-emitting device. Accordingly, it would be desirable to have technique for cleaning a flat-panel CRT display during display operation subsequent to final display sealing. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">GENERAL DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention furnishes a CRT display, typically a flat-panel CRT display, having a built-in capability for cleaning the display&apos;s electron-emitting device. That is, the electron-emitting device is automatically cleaned during normal display operation subsequent to final display sealing and evacuation to a low internal display pressure. The self-cleaning capability is achieved with inert gas provided inside the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The pressure (or density) of gas inside a flat-panel CRT display is normally made low for two main reasons: (1) to avoid interfering with the flow of electrons from the display&apos;s electron-emitting device to the display&apos;s light-emitting device and (2) to avoid contaminating the electron-emitting and light-emitting devices. While inert gases do have some chemical reactivity, the level of chemical reactivity of an inert gas compared to a typical non-inert element or compound is generally so low that the presence of inert gas inside a flat-panel CRT display does not usually cause appreciable contamination of the display&apos;s electron-emitting and light-emitting devices. Hence, the second reason for avoiding gas inside a flat-panel CRT display generally does not apply to inert gases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Some inert gas is invariably present inside a conventional hermetically sealed CRT display. Argon is typically the most prevalent inert gas inside a conventional CRT display. The substantial presence of argon inside a conventional CRT display can arise for various reasons. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In any event, we have recognized that some of the electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device of a conventional hermetically sealed CRT display during display operation collide with atoms of the inert gas inside the display to produce positively charged ions which travel backward toward the electron-emitting device. The positively charged inert-gas ions bombard contaminant material on the electron-emitting device and cause some of the contaminant material to be dislodged from, and thereby be removed from, the electron-emitting device. Hence, a conventional CRT display has an inherent capability for automatically removing contaminant material from the electron-emitting device during display operation subsequent to final display sealing. However, the partial pressure of the inert gas inside a conventional CRT display is normally quite low so that the display&apos;s inherent capability for removing contaminant material from the electron-emitting device is quite low. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Also, some of the positively charged inert-gas ions lodge (or become trapped) in the electron-emitting device of a conventional CRT display and are effectively lost during display operation. Consequently, the inherent capability which a conventional CRT display has for removing contaminant material from the display&apos;s electron-emitting device degrades with operational time and eventually drops essentially to zero. Furthermore, contaminant material removed from the electron-emitting device due to bombardment by inert-gas ions can later return to the electron-emitting device and re-contaminate it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> With the foregoing in mind, the CRT display of the invention is constituted with an electron-emitting device and a light-emitting device coupled to the electron-emitting device to form a hermetically sealed enclosure. Electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device pass through the sealed enclosure to strike the light-emitting device and cause it to emit light that produces an image. Inert gas is present in open space of the sealed enclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the invention, the inert gas in the open space of the sealed enclosure of the present CRT display consists of at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) argon at a partial pressure of at least 3&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (c) one or more of neon, krypton, xenon, and radon at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr. As little as one of these six inert gases may be present in the sealed enclosure at a partial pressure of at least the minimum partial pressure given here for that inert gas or gases. The partial pressure of the inert gas is normally at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr in the case of neon and at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr in the case of krypton. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The present CRT display, again typically a flat-panel CRT display, operates generally in the manner described above with respect to the generation of positively charged inert-gas ions for bombarding contaminant material on the electron-emitting device. The partial pressures of the various inert gases utilized to implement the contaminant-removal capability in a CRT display configured according to the invention are normally considerably greater than the partial pressures of those inert gases present in a conventional CRT display. Accordingly, the capability for automatically removing contaminant material from the electron-emitting device is considerably greater in the present CRT display than in a conventional CRT display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present CRT display preferably includes a reservoir for supplying inert gas to the open space of the display&apos;s sealed enclosure. The reservoir replaces inert gas which lodges in the electron-emitting device (or elsewhere) during the ion-bombardment process and is effectively lost during display operation. As a result, the CRT display of the invention can maintain an adequate level of contaminant-removal capability and substantially avoids the loss of contaminant-removal capability which occurs with operational time in a conventional CRT display. When the present display includes the inert-gas reservoir, the partial pressure of all the inert gas in the sealed enclosure is at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr. The minimum partial pressures given above for helium, for argon, and for one or more of neon, krypton, xenon, and radon, generally apply to the situation in which the inert-gas reservoir is employed in the display except that the minimum partial pressure of argon is slightly lower, typically as little as 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The inert-gas reservoir can be implemented as a container that encloses the replacement inert gas. The container has a wall, typically gas permeable, through which the replacement inert gas passes from the container into the sealed enclosure. Additionally or alternatively, the reservoir can be implemented in the form of one or more pieces of (a) inert-gas compound material, (b) absorbent material charged with inert gas, or/and (c) material impregnated with inert gas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The CRT display of the invention also preferably includes a getter for collecting non-inert material. The getter collects contaminant material dislodged from the electron-emitting device and thereby prevents that material from re-contaminating the electron-emitting device. The getter is preferably positioned close to electron-emissive regions where display-damaging contaminant can accumulate so as to reduce the likelihood that dislodged contaminant material will return to those regions. For example, the getter can be distributed across the active electron-emitting portion of the electron-emitting device. Importantly, the getter normally does not collect inert gas to a significant degree and therefore does not cause the ion-bombardment self-cleaning capability of the invention to degrade significantly with time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In short, the present inert-gas cleaning technique is highly advantageous because it enables the electron-emitting device of a CRT display, especially one of the flat-panel type, to be cleaned subsequent to final display sealing. The invention thus provides an important and substantial advance.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are cross-sectional side views, taken perpendicular to each other, of a flat-panel CRT display provided with a self-cleaning capability according to the invention. The cross section of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is taken through plane <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The cross section of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is taken through plane <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are cross sectional side views of implementations of the inert-gas reservoir in the flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross sectional side view of part of the active region of an implementation of the flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>directly after display sealing and getter activation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view of part of the active region of an implementation of a flat-panel CRT display generally corresponding to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> but not provided with the self-cleaning capability of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are cross-sectional side views of part of the active region of the implementation of the flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> respectively at an instance of time during normal display operation and at a later instance of time when the display is not in operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Like reference symbols are employed in the drawings and in the description of the preferred embodiments to represent the same, or very similar, item or items.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A flat-panel CRT display having a built-in capability, in accordance with the invention, for automatically cleaning the display&apos;s electron-emitting device during normal display operation is described below. The present flat-panel CRT display is typically suitable for a flat-panel television or a flat-panel video monitor for a personal computer, a laptop computer, a workstation, or a hand-held device such as a personal digital assistant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A flat-panel CRT display whose electron-emitting device is cleaned according to the invention is typically a color display but can be a monochrome, e.g., black-and-white or black-and-green, display. Each electron-emissive region and the corresponding oppositely positioned light-emissive region form a pixel in a monochrome display, and a sub-pixel in a color display. A color pixel typically consists of three sub-pixels, one for red, another for blue, and the third for green. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In the following description, the term &ldquo;electrically insulating&rdquo; or &ldquo;dielectric&rdquo; generally applies to materials having a resistivity greater than 10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>ohm-cm. The term &ldquo;electrically non-insulating&rdquo; thus refers to materials having a resistivity of no more than 10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>ohm-cm. Electrically non-insulating materials are divided into (a) electrically conductive materials for which the resistivity is less than 1 ohm-cm and (b) electrically resistive materials for which the resistivity is in the range of 1 ohm-cm to 10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>ohm-cm. These categories are determined at an electric field of no more than 10 volts/&mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>schematically illustrate intersecting side cross sections of a hermetically sealed flat-panel CRT display provided with a self-cleaning capability in accordance with the invention&apos;s teachings. The side cross sections of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are taken perpendicular to each other. The flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>can be characterized by two perpendicular lateral directions referred to here as the row and column directions. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1 a</cross-reference> can, for example, represent a cross section of the display as viewed in the column direction. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>then represents a cross section of the display as viewed in the row direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>(collectively &ldquo;<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>&rdquo;) consists of an electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, an oppositely positioned light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, an annular rectangular outer wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, an optional inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and a group of spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is coupled to light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> through annular wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to form a hermetically sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> maintained at a low internal pressure level. Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are accessible to sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and, for exemplary purposes, are illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as being situated on electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> within sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. As discussed further below, getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may access enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in other ways. Electronic circuitry (not shown) for controlling the display may be situated over the exterior surface (lower surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are situated within sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> between devices <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> prevent external forces, such as the external-to-internal pressure differential of approximately 1 atm. from collapsing the display. Spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> also maintain a largely uniform separation between devices <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Each spacer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is typically shaped generally like a flat wall. This exemplary situation is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>where spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extend parallel to one another in the row direction. Other shapes, such as posts, can be employed for spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Electron-emitting device, or backplate structure, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> consists of a generally flat electrically insulating backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and a group of layers and regions situated over the interior surface (upper surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. These layers and regions include a two-dimensional array of rows and columns of laterally separated electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Each electron-emissive region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> consists of one or more of electron-emissive elements (not separately shown here), such as cones, filaments, and randomly shaped particles, which emit electrons directed toward light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> typically operates according to field emission in which each region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> emits electrons when subjected to a suitable electrical potential. Device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can operate according to other electron-emission techniques such as thermal emission. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The layers and regions in electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also typically include an electron-focusing system <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> which helps focus the emitted electrons toward target areas of light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Electron-focusing system <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> extends vertically beyond electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Items <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> respectively represent the typical trajectories of two electrons traveling from device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> after being emitting by regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Light-emitting device, or faceplate structure, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is formed with a generally flat electrically insulating faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and a group of layers and regions situated over the interior surface (lower surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is transparent at least where visible light is intended to pass through faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to produce the display&apos;s image on the exterior surface (upper surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> at the front of the display. The layers and regions overlying faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> include a two-dimensional array of rows and columns of light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, a patterned black matrix <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and an anode (not separately shown here). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> emit light upon being struck by electrons. Each light-emissive region <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is situated directly opposite a corresponding one of electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Electrons emitted by each region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are thereby intended to strike corresponding light-emissive region <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to produce suitable light. In a color implementation of the display, three consecutive light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in a row respectively emit red, green, and blue light when struck by electrons emitted from the three corresponding regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The light emitted by elements <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> produces the display&apos;s image on the exterior faceplate surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Black matrix <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> laterally surrounds each light-emissive region <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and appears dark, largely black, as viewed from the front of the display. Matrix <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> enhances the contrast of the display&apos;s image. In the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, matrix <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> extends vertically beyond light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The display&apos;s anode may be situated above or below light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and black matrix <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. When situated above components <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> so as to be further away from faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> than components <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the anode is normally light reflective. This enables the anode to reflect forward some of the initially rear-directed light emitted by regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> so as to enhance the image intensity. When the anode is situated between faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, on one hand, and components <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> on the other hand, the anode is largely transparent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has an open space consisting of the portion of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> not occupied by solid components such as spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. During display operation, electrons are extracted from regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, typically by field emission. Various voltages, typically within 20-40 volts of one another, are applied to electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for extracting electrons from regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and controlling the electron trajectories. Relative to these voltages, the anode in light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is provided with a high electrical potential that attracts the extracted electrons toward light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Consequently, the extracted electrons pass through the open space in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and impinge on light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> More particularly, the flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> has an active image-producing region consisting of an active electron-emitting portion, an active light-emitting portion, and an active intermediate portion. The active electron-emitting portion is formed with the portion of electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> extending laterally from the first row of electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to the last row of regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and from the first column of regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to the last column of regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The active light-emitting portion is formed with the portion of light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> extending laterally from the first row of light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to the last row of regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and from the first column of regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to the last column of regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The active intermediate portion consists of the portion of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> between the active electron-emitting portion and the active light-emitting portion. Electrons which are emitted by regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and directed toward light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> pass through the active portion of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to the sides of spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> When the anode is a light-reflective layer situated over components <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the electrons pass through the anode and strike light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to cause light emission. When the anode is a transparent layer situated below components <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the electrons strike light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> directly to produce light which passes through the anode. In either case, the display&apos;s image appears on the exterior surface of faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The open space in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> contains gas, i.e., atoms and molecules in gas phase, at a very low pressure compared to normal atmospheric pressure (approximately 760 torr). The internal pressure in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, i.e., the pressure of all the gas in the open space of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, is normally 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7</superscript></highlight>&minus;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr. Part of the gas in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is inert gas of which there are six inert gases: helium, neon, argon, krypton, xenon, and radon. The gas, including the inert gas, is distributed in a relatively uniform manner throughout the open space in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> A very small, but important, portion of the electrons which are emitted by regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and which move through the open space in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> toward light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> during normal display operation collide with (or strike) atoms of the inert gas located in the open space of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Part of the inert-gas atoms lose electrons when struck by electrons emitted by regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and thereby become positively charged ions. Although the inert gas is distributed throughout the open space in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, nearly all of the inert-gas atoms which become positively charged ions upon being struck by electrons emitted by regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is located in the active intermediate portion of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> when those atoms undergo ionization. Because the anode in light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is at a high electrical potential relative to the voltages present in the electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the positively charged inert-gas ions are attracted to electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Relative to the electrons traveling from electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> toward light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the positively charged inert-gas ions thereby travel backward toward election-emitting devise <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The positively charged inert-gas ions pick up speed, and thereby become more energetic, as they approach electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Some of the positively charged inert-gas ions impinge on electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Upon reaching regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, those positively charged inert-gas ions bombard contaminant material situated on regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> according to the mechanism of ion etch (or ion milling). This causes contaminant on regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to be dislodged from regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. At least part of the dislodged contaminant typically becomes volatile, i.e. is converted to gaseous form. The dislodged contaminant moves away from regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Nearly all of the dislodged contaminant consists of non-inert material, i.e., material other than the six inert gases. Part of non-inert dislodged contaminant reaches getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and is collected by getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so as to be prevented from re-contaminating regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Some of the non-inert dislodged contaminant material invariably returns to electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. To the extent that part of the non-inert volatized contaminant returns to regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and re-contaminates them, this material is re-bombarded in the course of the ion etch mechanism that results from the electron-produced positive ionization of the inert gas present in the open space of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The material that re-contaminates regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is again dislodged from regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and moves away from them. Part of this now dislodged contaminant is similarly collected by getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so as to prevent it from further re-contaminating regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A situation is thus reached in which the ion etch mechanism acts to clean regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> as they become contaminated by both new contaminant material and previously removed contaminant material. By suitably adjusting the species and partial pressure(s) of the inert gas in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the ion etch mechanism can be controlled so that regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are maintained in a substantially clean condition for a long time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> collects non-inert material such as the vast majority of the dislodged contaminant material as well as other non-inert, typically volatile, material present in the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> does not significantly collect inert gas. Consequently, the presence of getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> does not cause a significant reduction in the amount of inert gas present in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. However, some of the positively charged inert-gas ions impinge on portions of electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with sufficient energy to become lodged (or implanted) in device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and thus become effectively lost. As discussed further below, inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> provides additional inert gas to replace the inert gas which is lost, for example, due to being lodged in device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the course of the ion etch process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The ion etch action in the self-cleaning process of the invention generally becomes stronger as the positively charged inert-gas ions are made more energetic. For a given positive potential on the display&apos;s anode, the positively charged inert-gas ions become more energetic as their average molecular weight increases. Also, the probability of an inert-gas atom being ionized upon being struck by an electron increases as the atom&apos;s atomic number, and thus the atom&apos;s molecular weight, increases. The molecular weights of the six inert gases increase in going from helium respectively through neon, argon, krypton, and xenon to radon. Hence, the ion etch action provided by a given number of atoms of inert gas achieves a progressively higher etch rate as the inert gas is changed from helium to neon, to argon, to krypton, to xenon, and finally to radon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> A given number of atoms of inert gas produce largely the same partial pressure irrespective of the constituency of the inert gas in the display. Since the ion etch rate increases as the average molecular weight of the inert gas increases, the partial pressure needed to achieve a given level of ion etch with the present inert gas decreases as the average inert-gas molecular weight increases. Accordingly, the partial pressure needed to achieve a given level of ion etch generally decreases in going from helium respectively through neon, argon, krypton, and xenon to radon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the invention, the partial pressure of all the inert gas in the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is normally at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr. The inert gas in the open space of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be variously constituted with helium, neon, argon, krypton, xenon, and radon at various partial pressures. All six of these inert gases are invariably present in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to some degree. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The lowest pressure of inert gas that can be measured in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> using standard residual gas analyzer equipment is in the vicinity of 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr. Except as otherwise indicated, a specific inert gas present in the open space of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> at a partial pressure of less than approximately 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr is ignored in the following description. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The inert gas present in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can, as generally indicated above, be constituted with any one or more of helium, neon, argon, krypton, xenon, and radon. Argon is attractive because it is the most prevalent inert gas, by far, in air and thus is relatively inexpensive compared to the other inert gases. Xenon and krypton are attractive because their relatively high molecular weights allow the partial pressure of the inert gas in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to be made relatively low, thereby reducing the amount of interference that the inert gas has with the electrons flowing from electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> For the case where the inert-gas in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is constituted with helium, the partial pressure of the helium is normally at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr. The helium partial pressure is preferably at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferably at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr. The partial pressure of the helium in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is normally no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr. The helium partial pressure is preferably no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferably no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> When the inert gas in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is constituted with neon, the partial pressure of the neon is normally at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr. The neon partial pressure is preferably at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferably at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr The partial pressure of the neon in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be as high as 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr but is normally no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr. The neon partial pressure is preferably no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferably no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> For the case in which the inert gas in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is constituted with argon, the partial pressure of the argon is normally at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, preferably at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, when inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is present. When reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is absent, the argon partial pressure is slightly higher, normally at least 3&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, preferably at least 4&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr. In either case, the argon partial pressure is more preferably at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, even more preferably at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr. The partial pressure of the argon in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be as high as 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr but is normally no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr. The argon partial pressure is preferably no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferably no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> When the inert gas in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is krypton, the partial pressure of the krypton is normally at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr. The krypton partial pressure is preferably at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferably at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr. The partial pressure of the krypton in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be as high as 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr but is normally no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr. The krypton partial pressure is preferably no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferably no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> For the case where the inert gas in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> consists of xenon or radon, the partial pressure of the xenon or radon is normally at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr, the minimum level given above for all the inert gas in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The xenon or radon partial pressure is preferably at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferable at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr. The partial pressure of the xenon or radon in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be as high as 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr but is normally no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr. The xenon or radon partial pressure is preferably no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr, more preferably no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr, and even more preferably no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The inert gas in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may consist of two or more of helium, neon, argon, krypton, xenon, and radon where each of the two or more inert gases is present at a partial pressure of at least the typical minimum measurable partial pressure of approximately 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr. In that case, the minimum value of the partial pressure of all the inert gas normally present in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be determined by appropriately averaging the above-mentioned normal minimum partial pressure values for the six inert gases as a function of the molar fractions of the inert gases in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The maximum value of the partial pressure of all the inert gas normally present in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can similarly be determined by appropriately averaging the above-mentioned normal maximum partial pressure values for the six inert gases as a function of the molar fractions of the inert gases in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Because two or more inert gases are present in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> at partial pressures greater than or equal to the typical minimum measurable value, the actual normal minimum or normal maximum value of each constituent inert gas will then be less than the normal minimum or normal maximum value given above for that gas. Similar averaging procedures apply to the preferred, more preferred, and even more preferred partial pressure conditions given above when two or more of the inert gases are present in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> at partial pressures greater than or equal to the typical minimum measurable partial pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is illustrated schematically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as a single component but may, and often does, consist of multiple spaced-apart components. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>also depicts getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> as being situated over backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> outside the active image-producing region of the flat-panel CRT display. Alternatively or additionally, getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be situated over faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> outside the display&apos;s active region or/and over the inside surface of outer wall <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and thus again outside the display&apos;s active region. Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can also alternatively or additionally be located in an auxiliary compartment situated outside sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and connected to enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by way of one or more openings through backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, or/and outer wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. U.S. Pat. No. 5,977,706 present examples for implementing getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in this manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> As another variation, getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can alternatively or additionally be located in the active image-producing region of the flat-panel CRT display in such a manner as to not interfere with the display&apos;s image-producing function. In that case, the material of getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is typically distributed laterally in a relatively uniform manner across the display&apos;s active region. For instance, the getter material can be distributed in a relatively uniform manner across the top (upper surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of the active electron-emitting portion of electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as generally described in Curtin, U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/698,698, filed Oct. 27. 2000. By having the getter material distributed across the top of the active electron-emitting portion, the volatized contaminant material that leaves electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> can be collected by getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> before that contaminant material leaves the immediate vicinity of regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. This improves the efficiency of the gettering process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The material of getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can likewise be distributed in a relatively uniform manner across the top (lower surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of the active light emitting portion of light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. See Cummings et al, U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/823,872, filed Mar. 30, 2001, as well as Curtin et al, U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/698,696, cited above, for examples of how getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is implemented in this way. As described in U.S. patent application Ser. Nos. 09/823,872 and 09/698,696, candidate materials for getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> include magnesium, aluminum, titanium, vanadium, chromium, manganese, iron, cobalt, copper, zirconium, niobium, molybdenum, palladium, silver, barium, tantalum, tungsten, platinum, lead, thorium, magnesium oxide, chromium oxide, manganese oxide, cobalt oxide, nickel oxide, and lead oxide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is normally porous. Contaminant material, typically gaseous, gathers along or near the outside surface of getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, causing its gettering capability to decrease as time passes. By appropriately treating the getter material according to an &ldquo;activation&rdquo; process, the material accumulated along or near the outside surface of getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is driven into its interior. This enables getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to regain much of its gettering capability up to the point at which the internal material-holding capability of getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is reached. Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can typically be activated a large number of times. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is created before hermetically sealing the light-emitting and electron-emitting devices together to assemble the flat-panel CRT display. In a typical fabrication sequence, the completed light-emitting device is exposed to air prior to the display sealing operation. Contaminant material then accumulates along much of the effective gettering surface of getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> typically needs to be activated during or subsequent to the display sealing operation while sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is at a high vacuum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Activation of getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be done in various ways. Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be activated by raising its temperature to a sufficiently high value, typically 300-900&deg; C., for a sufficiently long period of time. In general, the amount of time needed to activate getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> decreases with increasing activation temperature. By sealing the display at a temperature in excess of 300&deg; C., typically 350&deg; C., in a highly evacuated environment, the activation can be automatically accomplished during the sealing operation. When a component adjoining getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> contains electrically resistive material, a voltage can sometimes be applied to the resistive material to raise its temperature high enough to activate getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> As mentioned above, some of the inert gas present in sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is effectively lost, for example, due to becoming lodged (or trapped) in electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the course of the self-cleaning ion etch process. Reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> supplies inert gas to the open space in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to compensate, at least partially, for the inert gas that lodges in device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or is otherwise lost. The inert gas provided by reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> typically has roughly the same composition as the inert gas present in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> directly after the final display sealing operation. In any event, the characteristics of inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are preferably chosen so that the rate at which reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> furnishes inert gas to enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> roughly balances the rate at which the open space in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> loses inert gas over the life of the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is depicted schematically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as a single component. However, reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may consist of multiple components spaced apart from one another. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1 a</cross-reference> also illustrates reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as being situated over backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> outside the display&apos;s active image-producing region. Alternatively or additionally, reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> can be situated over faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> outside the display&apos;s active region or/and over the inside surface of outer wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, likewise outside the active region. Similar to getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> can also alternatively or additionally be located in an auxiliary compartment situated outside sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and connected to enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by way of one or more openings through backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, or/and outer wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. This auxiliary compartment may also contain (part or all of) getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Aside from consisting of multiple spaced-apart components, inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> can be configured in various ways. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate two implementations of reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> configured as a container <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> formed with a container wall <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> that fully surrounds an enclosed region <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> where the replacement inert gas is located. In the implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the replacement inert gas consists of freely moving inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> whose movement is constrained substantially only by container wall <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Although all of wall <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> can be gas permeable, wall <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is gas permeable along at least part of the portion of wall <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> exposed to sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> pass through wall <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> at a controlled rate to enter enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Items <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>represent the inert-gas atoms in the open space of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>presents an implementation in which container <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is shaped generally like a rectangular box or like a cylinder as viewed (in cross section) perpendicular to the axis of the cylinder. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>presents an implementation in which container <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is shaped like a sphere or like a circular cylinder as viewed (in cross section) along the axis of the cylinder. Container <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> can have various other shapes. As discussed further below, the replacement inert gas present in enclosed region <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of container <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> can also be provided from sources other than freely moving inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates an implementation of inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> consisting of inert-gas compound <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Candidates for inert-gas compound <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> include argon hydrofluoride (ArHF), krypton fluoride (KrF<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), xenon fluoride (XeF<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), xenon platinum fluoride (XePtF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>), xenon hydrocyanide (XeHCN), and xenon hydrochloride (XeHCl). These inert-gas compounds are generally unstable and slowly dissociate to release the replacement inert gas. Although <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> does not indicate any supporting structure for inert-gas compound <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, some of the exemplary inert-gas compounds identified here are liquids or gases, and thus need supporting structures such as a piece of material that adsorbs or/and absorbs compound <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> or a container that holds compound <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> presents an implementation of inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> that combines the inert-gas compound implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> with the container implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is implemented as container <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in which the replacement inert gas is provided from inert-gas compound <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> situated in enclosed region <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Since compound <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is fully enclosed by region <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, compound <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can be a solid, a liquid, or a gas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates an implementation of inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in which a piece <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of porous absorbent material is charged with atoms <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the replacement inert gas. Absorbent piece <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> has pores <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> in which inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> are situated. Inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> slowly escape from pores <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and enter the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> where they are identified as inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> For inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> to escape slowly from pores <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> in absorbent piece <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, the average diameter of pores <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> needs to match the average diameter of replacement inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Candidate absorbent materials having appropriate average pore diameters suitable for implementing absorbent piece <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> when the replacement gas is krypton whose atomic diameter is approximately 0.35 nm include Zeolite KA, Erionite K, carbon molecular sieve material, porous aluminum oxide, and pillar clay. When the replacement inert gas is xenon whose atomic diameter is approximately 0.4 nm, candidate sorbent materials suitable for implementing absorbent piece <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> to match the atomic diameter of xenon include Zeolite NaA, Zeolite CaA, carbon molecular sieve material, porous aluminum oxide, and pillar clay. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> presents an implementation of inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> that combines the porous absorbent material implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> with the container implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is implemented as container <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in which atoms <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the replacement inert gas are provided from absorbent piece <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> situated in enclosed region <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> situated in pores <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of absorbent piece <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> escape pores <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> to become freely moving inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> located inside enclosed region <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> pass slowly through outer wall <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of container <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to become inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate two implementations of inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> consisting of a piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> of material impregnated with atoms <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of the replacement inert gas. Items <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>represent the paths along which replacement inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> enter piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to become impregnated. The impregnation of piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> can be done by ion implanting inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> into piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The impregnation of piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> can also be done by sputtering atoms <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> toward piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. Somewhat similar to reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, impregnated inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> slowly leave impregnated piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> along paths <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to become inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> It may be necessary to activate impregnated piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to cause impregnated inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> to leave piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The activation can be achieved by having positively charged inert-gas ions impinge on piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. As shown in the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is then situated over backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The activation of impregnated piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> can alternatively be done by having electrons emitted from regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> impinge on piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. In that case, piece <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is situated over faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> as shown in the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> presents a side cross section of part of the active image-producing region of an implementation of the hermetically sealed flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> immediately subsequent to final display sealing and getter activation. The cross section of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> as being a cross section viewed in the row direction but can as well be a cross section viewed in the column direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The layers and regions situated directly over backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> consists of a lower electrically non-insulating region <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, a dielectric layer <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, a two-dimensional array of laterally separated sets of electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, a group of laterally separated generally parallel control electrodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, and electron-focusing system <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Each set of electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> consists of multiple elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and forms one of electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Only one set of elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. Likewise, only one control electrode <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Lower non-insulating region <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> contains a group of laterally separated generally parallel emitter electrodes (not separately shown) situated on backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The emitter electrodes extend longitudinally in the column direction. Lower non-insulating region <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> also normally includes an electrically resistive layer (likewise not separately shown) which overlies the emitter electrodes and, depending on its lateral shape, may extend down to backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in the spaces between the emitter electrodes. At a minimum, the resistive layer underlies electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Dielectric layer <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> lies on lower non-insulating region <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Openings <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> extend through dielectric layer <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> down to non-insulating region <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Each electron-emissive element <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is situated mostly in a corresponding one of dielectric openings <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and contacts region <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are typically conical in shape as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. Alternatively, elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> can be of filamentary shape. When elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are conical or filamentary in shape, they typically consist of metal such as molybdenum. Each element <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> can also consist of one or more randomly shaped particles. Control electrodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> lie on dielectric layer <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and extend in the row direction. Openings <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> extend through control electrodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. Each electron-emissive element <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is exposed through a corresponding one of control openings <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Electron-focusing system <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> lies on dielectric layer <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and extends over portions of control electrodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> (outside the plane of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>). A two-dimensional array of rows and columns of focus openings <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> extend through system <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Each column of focus openings <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is situated above a corresponding one of control electrodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. The electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> in each electron-emissive region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are exposed through a corresponding one of focus openings <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Control electrodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> selectively extract electrons from elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> in electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Electron-focusing system <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> focuses the extracted electrons toward target ones of light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the light-emitting device. System <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> helps overcome undesired electron-trajectory deflections caused by various factors such as the presence of spacers, e.g., spacer walls <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, located between devices <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> A metallic light-reflective layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, which serves as the display&apos;s anode, overlies light-emissive regions <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and black matrix <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. As in the figures that present particular implementations of inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, items <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> are atoms of the inert gas present in the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, which is normally positioned outside the display&apos;s active image-producing portion, does not appear in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> since it illustrates part of the display&apos;s active region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> also does not appear in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. However, as indicated above, getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be distributed laterally across the active electron-emitting portion of device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or/and across the active light-emitting portion of device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. For instance, as described in Curtin et al, U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/698,696, cited above, getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be provided in openings in electron-focusing system <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> so as to be quite close to electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> To pictorially illustrate the advantages furnished by the present invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> presents a side cross section of part of the active image-producing region of an implementation of a hermetically sealed baseline flat-panel CRT display identical to the implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> except that the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the baseline implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> effectively has zero inert gas compared to the open space of enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the inventive implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> also represents an instance of time at which the baseline display is in operation and has been operating for some significant period of time. Item <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> represents the trajectory of an electron emitted by one of elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> As <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> indicates, coatings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of contaminant material have accumulated on the conical surfaces of electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. Since effectively no inert gas is present in the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the baseline implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the emission of electrons from elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> of the illustrated electron-emissive region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> does not produce the ion etch process of the invention to a significant degree. Contaminant coatings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> thus remain on elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> in the baseline display and cause its performance to degrade. In fact, contaminant coatings <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> grow with time as the display is being operated so that its performance becomes progressively worse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> More particularly, contaminant coatings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> cause the amount of electron emission from electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> to degrade with time during display operation. Although contaminant coatings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are, for simplicity, illustrated as substantially fully covering the conical surfaces of elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, coatings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can cause significant degradation in the electron emission even though their average thickness is only a fraction of an atomic monolayer so that coatings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are perforated or/and discontinuous. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Additional contaminant material may be present inside the baseline display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> at locations other than the conical surfaces of electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. For example, additional contaminant may accumulate on electron-focusing system <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> or/and control electrodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> in electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or above light-emissive elements <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Although the additional contaminant which accumulates on light-emitting device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may affect its performance, the additional contaminant which accumulates on device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> or on parts of electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> other than electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> will generally not significantly damage the electron-emitting capability of device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the baseline display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. Inasmuch as the present invention is directed toward cleaning electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in such a way as to avoid loss in their electron-emitting capability, contaminant that accumulates inside the baseline display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> at locations other than the conical surfaces of electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is, for simplicity, not illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>present side cross sections of part of the active image-producing region of an implementation of the flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> at two respective instances of time where the implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> has been operated for approximately the same amount of time as the baseline implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>represents an instance of time at which the display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is in operation. In this regard, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>qualitatively illustrates how electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are cleaned according to the ion etch process of the invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>represents a somewhat later instance of time at which the display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> has been turned off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, items <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> represent the trajectories of electrons which are emitted by elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> of the illustrated electron-emissive region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and which reach the oppositely situated light-emissive region <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to cause light emission. Item <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> represents the trajectory of an electron which is emitted by one of elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and which strikes one of inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. Items <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are positively charged inert-gas ions which are produced from inert-gas atoms <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> when they are struck by electrons emitted by elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. Items <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> represent the trajectories of positively charged inert-gas ions <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> as they travel backward to electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> As mentioned above, some of the positively charged inert-gas ions lodge in electron-emitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> during the ion etch process of the invention. The positively charged inert-gas ions that lodge in device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> pick up electrons and become neutral inert-gas atoms again. Items <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>represent positively charged inert-gas atoms that lodge in device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as a result of the ion etch self-cleaning process of the invention. Finally, item <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is a piece of contaminant material that accumulates on the conical surface of one of electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> The ion etch mechanism of the present invention is depicted qualitatively in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Nonetheless, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>illustrates how trajectory <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> followed by one of positively charged inert-gas ions <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> takes that ion <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> directly back to contaminant piece <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. As a result of being bombarded (or struck) by that ion <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, contaminant piece <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is dislodged from underlying electron-emissive element <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and moves away from that element <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. In moving away from underlying element <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, contaminant piece <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is in the form of one or more particles which may be solid or gaseous depending on the size of each particle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Contaminant piece <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> does not appear in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which illustrates the display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> at a later instance of time when the display is turned off. Hence, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows how the display has been cleaned in accordance with the invention to remove contaminant <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> from electron-emissive element <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> on which contaminant <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> had earlier accumulated. During display operation, further contaminant material accumulates on electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. Item <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>represents a further piece of contaminant material that accumulates on one of elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. In the course of later display operation, further contaminant <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is also removed from underlying element <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> as a result of ion etch process of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>together show that contaminant material which accumulates on electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is progressively removed during display operation. As can be seen by comparing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the amount of contaminant present on elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> at any instance of time is much less in the inventive display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> than in the baseline display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> where the self-cleaning ion etch process does not occur to a significant degree. Configuring the display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> to have the present self-cleaning capability thereby enables elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> to be maintained in a highly clean condition for a substantially increased period of operational time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Similar to what was said above about the baseline display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, additional contaminant material may accumulate inside the inventive display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> at locations other than electron-emissive elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. As with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, this additional contaminant is, for simplicity, not illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> or in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>because the additional contaminant would generally not significantly damage the electron-emitting capability of device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. Nonetheless, the additional contaminant which accumulates on device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at locations other than elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> in the display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is generally removed by the ion etch process of the invention in the course of removing the contaminant that accumulates on elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. For instance, contaminant that accumulates over control electrodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is removed simultaneously with contaminant that accumulates on elements <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. All portions of electron-emissive regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, along with other parts of device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the active electron-emitting portion, are automatically cleaned during display operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The general flat-panel CRT display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, including the implementation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, is fabricated in largely the following manner. Devices <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are separately manufactured. If getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is to be incorporated into the active image-producing region of the display, the manufacture of device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or/and device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is performed in such a way as to appropriately incorporate getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> into device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or/and device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is simply mounted over backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, or/and outer wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> depending on where getter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is to be located in the display. Inert-gas reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is also mounted over backplate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, faceplate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, or/and outer wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> depending on where reservoir <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is to be located in the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Spacers <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are mounted on device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Outer wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is also mounted on device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The assembly of the display is largely completed by sealing device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> through wall <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. During the assembly procedure, the display is provided with a tip-off tube (not shown) through which sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is externally accessible in the assembled, but not yet hermetically sealed, display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The display is now hermetically sealed. The display sealing procedure is performed in a gaseous environment that contains inert gas at the desired molar fraction(s) suitable for achieving the desired initial partial pressure(s) of the desired inert gas(es) in the open space of sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. More particularly, the assembled display is placed in a vacuum chamber. The vacuum chamber is evacuated, normally at elevated temperature. Inert gas of the desired composition is introduced into the vacuum chamber at room temperature or at elevated temperature. Part of the inert gas enters sealed enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> through the tip-off tube. The pressure of the inert gas introduced into the vacuum chamber is controlled so as to achieve the desired initial partial pressure for the inert gas in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The tip-off tube is then closed by a suitable sealing technique in order to hermetically seal enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and thus the display. The partial pressure in enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is thereby set at the desired initial value, normally 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7</superscript></highlight>&minus;1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr, which is typically approximately the same as the pressure in the vacuum chamber. Air is subsequently introduced into the vacuum chamber after which the hermetically sealed display is removed from the vacuum chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Directional terms such as &ldquo;lateral&rdquo;, &ldquo;vertical&rdquo;, &ldquo;above&rdquo;, and &ldquo;below&rdquo; have been employed in describing the present invention to establish a frame of reference by which the reader can more easily understand how the various parts of the invention fit together. In actual practice, the components of a flat-panel CRT display may be situated at orientations different from that implied by the directional terms used here. Inasmuch as directional terms are used for convenience to facilitate the description, the invention encompasses implementations in which the orientations differ from those strictly covered by the directional terms employed here. The terms &ldquo;row&rdquo; and &ldquo;column&rdquo; are arbitrary relative to each other and can be reversed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described with reference to particular embodiments, this description is solely for the purpose of illustration and is not to be construed as limiting the scope of the invention claimed below. Field emission includes the planar phenomenon generally termed surface conduction emission. Various modifications and applications may thus be made by those skilled in the art without departing from the true scope and spirit of the invention as defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A structure comprising: 
<claim-text>an electron-emitting device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a light-emitting device coupled to the electron-emitting device to form a hermetically sealed enclosure through which electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device pass to strike the light-emitting device and cause it to emit light that produces an image; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>inert gas located in open space of the sealed enclosure, the inert gas consisting of at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) argon at a partial pressure of at least 3&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (c) at least one of neon, krypton, xenon, and radon at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the structure is a flat-panel display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electron-emitting device comprises: 
<claim-text>a backplate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an array of laterally separated electron-emissive regions situated over the backplate, each electron-emissive region comprising at least one electron-emissive element. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electron-emissive regions emit electrons according to field emission. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) neon at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr and (b) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) neon at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) argon at a partial pressure of at least 4&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (d) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (e) at least one of xenon and radon at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) at least one of neon and argon at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (d) at least one of xenon and radon at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further including a getter for collecting non-inert contaminant material present in the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electron-emitting device has an active electron-emitting portion across which electrons are emitted from the electron-emitting device, the getter being distributed across the active electron-emitting portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further including a reservoir for supplying inert gas to the open space of the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas is at a partial pressure of no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) neon at a partial pressure of no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) argon at a partial pressure of no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr, (d) krypton at a partial pressure of no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (e) xenon or radon at a partial pressure of no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A structure comprising: 
<claim-text>an electron-emitting device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a light-emitting device coupled to the electron-emitting device to form a hermetically sealed enclosure through which electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device pass to strike the light-emitting device and cause it to emit light that produces an image; </claim-text>
<claim-text>inert gas located in open space of the sealed enclosure at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reservoir for supplying inert gas to the open space of the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the structure is a flat-panel display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electron-emitting device comprises: 
<claim-text>a backplate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an array of laterally separated electron-emissive regions situated over the backplate, each electron-emissive region comprising at least one electron-emissive element. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electron-emissive regions emit electrons according to field emission. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reservoir comprises a container that encloses inert gas, the container having a wall through which inert gas passes from the container to the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the wall is gas permeable. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least part of the inert gas in the container is in gaseous form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least part of the inert gas in the container is in inert-gas compound form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least part of the inert gas in the container is present in inert-gas absorbent-material form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reservoir comprises at least one piece of inert-gas compound material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein t he reservoir comprises at least one piece of absorbent material charged with inert gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reservoir comprises of at least one piece of material impregnated with inert gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> further including a getter for collecting non-inert contaminant material present in the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electron-emitting device has an active electron-emitting portion across which electrons are emitted from the electron-emitting device, the getter being distributed across the active electron-emitting portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) at least one of neon and argon at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (d) at least one of xenon and radon at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) at least one of neon and argon at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (d) at least one of xenon and radon at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas is at a partial pressure of no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A structure as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) neon at a partial pressure of no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) argon at a partial pressure of no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>torr, (d) krypton at a partial pressure of no more than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (e) xenon or radon at a partial pressure of no more than 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A method of cleaning a structure comprising an electron-emitting device and a light-emitting device coupled to the electron-emitting device to form a hermetically sealed enclosure through which electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device pass to strike the light-emitting device and cause it to emit light that produces an image, open space of the sealed enclosure containing inert gas consisting of at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) argon at a partial pressure of at least 3&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (c) at least one of neon, krypton, xenon, and radon at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr, the method comprising operating the electron-emitting device so that part of the electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device collide with atoms of the inert gas to produce inert-gas ions which bombard contaminant material situated over the electron-emitting device in the sealed enclosure and cause at least part of the contaminant material to be dislodged from the electron-emitting device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the structure is a flat-panel display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electron-emitting device comprises a backplate and an array of laterally separated electron-emissive regions situated over the backplate, each electron-emissive region comprising at least one electron-emissive element, the contaminant material attacked by the inert-gas ions comprising contaminant material situated over the electron-emissive elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) neon at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr and (b) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) neon at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) argon at a partial pressure of at least 4&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (d) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (e) at least one of xenon and radon at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> further including collecting non-inert material, including particles of the dislodged contaminant material, present in the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> further including supplying the open space of the sealed enclosure with inert gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> further including collecting non-inert material, including particles of the dislodged contaminant material, present in the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A method of cleaning a structure comprising an electron-emitting device and a light-emitting device coupled to the electron-emitting device to form a hermetically sealed enclosure through which electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device pass to strike the light-emitting device and cause it to emit light that produces an image, open space of the sealed enclosure containing inert gas at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr, the method comprising; 
<claim-text>operating the electron-emitting device so that part of the electrons emitted by the electron-emitting device collide with atoms of the inert gas to produce inert-gas ions which bombard contaminant material situated over the electron-emitting device in the sealed enclosure and cause at least part of the contaminant material to be dislodged from the electron-emitting device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>supplying the open space of the sealed enclosure with inert gas. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the structure is a flat-panel display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electron-emitting device comprises a backplate and an array of laterally separated electron-emissive regions situated over the backplate, each electron-emissive region comprising at least one electron-emissive element, the contaminant material bombarded by the inert-gas ions comprising contaminant material situated over the electron-emissive elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> further including collecting non-inert material, including particles of the dislodged contaminant material, present in the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas supplied to the open space of the sealed enclosure compensates at least partially for inert-gas ions that lodge in the electron-emitting device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> further including collecting non-inert material, including particles of the dislodged contaminant material, present in the sealed enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) at least one of neon and argon at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (d) at least one of xenon and radon at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inert gas comprises at least one of (a) helium at a partial pressure of at least 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (b) at least one of neon and argon at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>torr, (c) krypton at a partial pressure of at least 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr, and (d) at least one of xenon and radon at a partial pressure of at least 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>torr.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001492A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001492A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001492A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001492A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001492A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
