<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001375A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001375A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001375A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001375A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001375A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001375A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001375</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09892936</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B62D001/19</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>280</class>
<subclass>777000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Mounting apparatus for motor vehicle steering column</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<middle-name>Patrick</middle-name>
<family-name>Anspaugh</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Bay City</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Thomas</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Tighe</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Saginaw</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Marc</given-name>
<middle-name>William</middle-name>
<family-name>Heinzman</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Frankenmuth</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>EDMUND P. ANDERSON</name-1>
<name-2>DELPHI TECHNOLOGIES, INC.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Legal Staff, Mail Code: 480-414-420</address-1>
<address-2>P.O. Box 5052</address-2>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48007-5052</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A mounting apparatus for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column including a molded structural plastic honey comb mounting bracket having a center passage around a mast jacket of the steering column. The top of the plastic mounting bracket is clamped flush against a flat panel on a body of the motor vehicle by a pair of spring washers supported below respective ones of a pair of platforms on the mounting bracket by a pair of rigid studs on the vehicle body. The rigid studs are exposed through a pair of vertical slots in the mounting bracket. In some embodiments of the mounting apparatus, the spring washers release the plastic mounting bracket for linear translation as a unit with the mast jacket through an energy absorbing collapse stroke of the latter with the path traversed by the mast jacket being defined by the vertical slots in the mounting bracket and the flat panel above the mounting bracket. In another embodiment of the mounting apparatus, the plastic mounting bracket remains stationary and the path traversed by the mast jacket during its collapse stroke is defined by the center passage in the plastic mounting bracket. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a mounting apparatus for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A mounting apparatus for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column described in U.S. Pat. No. 3,702,081 includes a metal mounting bracket rigidly attached to a tubular mast jacket of the steering column and a pair of metal capsules in slots in the mounting bracket. Each capsule is secured to the mounting bracket by a plurality of injection molded plastic pins and rigidly clamped to a body of the motor vehicle by hanger bolts. A force attributable to an impact on the steering column fractures the injection molded plastic pins and releases the mounting bracket from the capsules for linear translation as a unit with the mast jacket through an energy absorbing collapse stroke of the latter. After the mounting bracket releases from the capsules it engages a channel-shaped guide on the vehicle body above the steering column which defines the path followed by the mast jacket during its collapse stroke. In the interval before the mounting bracket engages the channel-shaped guide, the path traversed by the mast jacket is uncontrolled. A mounting apparatus according this invention positively controls the path of the mast jacket from the onset of its energy absorbing collapse stroke and is, therefore, an improvement over the mounting apparatus described in the aforesaid U.S. Pat. No. 3,702,081. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention is a new and improved mounting apparatus for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column including a molded structural plastic honey comb mounting bracket having a center passage therethrough around a mast jacket of the steering column. The top of the plastic mounting bracket is clamped flush against a flat panel on a body of the motor vehicle by a pair of spring washers supported below respective ones of a pair of platforms on the mounting bracket by a pair of rigid studs on the vehicle body. The rigid studs are exposed through a pair of vertical slots in the mounting bracket facing an upper or outboard end of the steering column. In some embodiments of the mounting apparatus according to this invention, the spring washers release the plastic mounting bracket for linear translation as a unit with the mast jacket through an energy absorbing collapse stroke of the latter with the path traversed by the mast jacket being defined by the vertical slots in the mounting bracket and the flat panel above the mounting bracket. In another embodiment of the mounting apparatus according to this invention, the plastic mounting bracket remains stationary and the path traversed by the mast jacket during its collapse stroke is defined by the center passage in the plastic mounting bracket.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a fragmentary perspective view of a mounting apparatus according to this invention for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an enlarged sectional view taken generally along the plane indicated by lines <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a fragmentary perspective view taken generally in the direction indicated by arrow &ldquo;<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&rdquo; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> of a modified mounting apparatus according to this invention for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a fragmentary perspective view taken generally in the direction indicated by arrow &ldquo;<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>&rdquo; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a fragmentary perspective view of a second modified mounting apparatus according to this invention for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a fragmentarily illustrated energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a tubular lower mast jacket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a tubular upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> telescopically overlapping the lower mast jacket, and an energy absorber, not shown, between the upper and lower mast jackets such as described in U.S. Pat. No. 3,392,599, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference. A steering shaft <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is supported on the upper and the lower mast jackets for rotation about a longitudinal centerline <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the steering column. A steering hand wheel, not shown, is attached to an upper or outboard end <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the steering shaft <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in conventional fashion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A longitudinal vector component of a force on the steering column attributable to an impact on the steering hand wheel induces telescopic linear translation of the upper mast jacket over the lower mast jacket through an energy absorbing collapse stroke and is reacted to a body of the motor vehicle through a bracket, not shown, at the bottom of the lower mast jacket. A mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> according to this invention supports the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> vertically on the motor vehicle body, releases the upper mast jacket for energy absorbing collapse, and defines the path traversed by the upper mast jacket throughout its energy absorbing collapse stroke. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a mounting bracket <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> made of molded structural plastic having a plurality of honey comb cells <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> defined between a plurality of integral lateral and longitudinal partitions <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B. The structural rigidity of the plastic mounting bracket attributable to the cellular honey comb structure thereof is comparable to the structural rigidity of the metal mounting bracket in the mounting apparatus described in the aforesaid U.S. Pat. No. 3,702,081. Importantly, the plastic mounting bracket is substantially more economical to manufacture than and weighs less than the metal mounting bracket and, therefore, is an improvement over the metal mounting bracket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The lateral and longitudinal partitions <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B are interrupted by a cylindrical passage <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> through the plastic mounting bracket <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> which fits closely around the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the steering column, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The cylindrical passage <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is interrupted by a plurality of schematically represented abutments <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> on the plastic mounting bracket which seat in corresponding ones of a plurality of sockets, not shown, in the upper mast jacket and couple the plastic mounting bracket to the upper mast jacket for unitary linear translation therewith through its collapse stroke. The plastic mounting bracket is molded as a unit around the upper mast jacket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The plastic mounting bracket <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> has a flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and a pair of lateral flanges <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>B on opposite sides of the upper mast jacket. The lateral flanges <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>B are interrupted by respective ones of a pair of vertical slots <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B each open through a vertical side <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the plastic mounting bracket facing the steering hand wheel on the upper end <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the steering shaft <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The vertical slots <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B intersect the flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the plastic mounting bracket and respective ones of a pair of slanted platforms <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>B on the lateral flanges <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>B around the slots constituting the bottoms of the lateral flanges. The plane of the slanted platforms <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>B intercepts an angle &thgr; with the plane of the flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the plastic mounting bracket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> An attachment means of the mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a pair of vertical screw-threaded studs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>B on opposite sides of the steering column closely received in respective ones of the vertical slots <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B and rigidly attached to a schematically represented flat panel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, of the body of the motor vehicle above the steering column. A pair of spring washers <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are retained on respective ones of the vertical studs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>B below the slanted platforms <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>B by corresponding ones of a pair of screw-threaded retainers <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> on the studs which thus cooperate with the studs and the spring washers in supporting the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> vertically on the body of the motor vehicle. When the screw-threaded retainers <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are tightened on the vertical studs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>B, the spring washers <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are resiliently flexed against the slanted platforms <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>B and clamp the flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the plastic mounting bracket flush against the flat panel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> on the motor vehicle body. At the same time, friction between the plastic mounting bracket and the spring washers and the flat panel attributable to the clamping forces applied by the spring washers resists linear translation of the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> relative to the body of the motor vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> When the motor vehicle on which the steering column <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is vertically supported by the mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> impacts another object, the steering hand wheel on the upper end <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the steering shaft is commonly impacted by the operator of the motor vehicle. In addition to the aforesaid longitudinal vector component which induces telescopic linear translation of the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> over the lower mast jacket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the impact on the steering hand wheel typically also has vertical and lateral vector components which urge upward and lateral pivotal movement of the steering column about the bracket at the bottom of the lower mast jacket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The longitudinal vector component of the impact is initially resisted by the aforesaid friction between the plastic mounting bracket, the spring washers, and flat panel. When that vector component exceeds the friction force, linear translation of the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in its energy absorbing collapse stroke commences. From the onset of the collapse stroke of the upper mast jacket, the vertical vector component of the impact on the steering column is reacted to the vehicle body through the flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the plastic mounting bracket and the flat panel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> on the body which thereby cooperate in defining the vertical position of the upper mast jacket during its collapse stroke. Importantly, because of the angle &thgr; between the plane of the slanted platforms <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>B and the flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the plastic mounting bracket, the spring washers separate quickly from the platforms for minimum interference with the collapse stroke of the upper mast jacket. At the same time, the lateral vector component of the impact on the steering column is reacted to the vehicle body through the sides of the vertical slots <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B in the plastic mounting bracket and the vertical studs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>B which thereby cooperate in defining the lateral position of the upper mast jacket during its collapse stroke. The flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the flat panel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, therefore, cooperate with the vertical studs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>B and the vertical slots <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A,<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B in constituting a guide means of the mounting apparatus which positively defines the path traversed by the upper mast jacket relative to the motor vehicle body during its energy absorbing collapse stroke. The path thus defined is calculated to promote optimum energy absorbing performance of the steering column. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A modified mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> according this invention is illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in which structural features common to both the modified mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are identified by primed reference characters. In the modified mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the plastic mounting bracket <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; on the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> has a slanted flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime; facing a similarly slated flat panel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>&prime; on the body of the motor vehicle above the steering column and a pair of horizontal platforms around respective ones of a pair of vertical slots in corresponding ones of a pair of lateral flanges of the plastic mounting bracket, only the horizontal flat platform <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>A&prime; around the vertical slot <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A&prime; in the lateral flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A&prime; being visible in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The slanted flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime; and the slanted flat panel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>&prime; intercept an angle &thgr;&prime; with the plane of the horizontal platforms. The plastic mounting bracket <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; is supported vertically on a vehicle body with its slanted flat top clamped against the slanted flat panel by a pair of spring washers on a corresponding pair of vertical studs on the vehicle body, only the spring washer <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>&prime; on the vertical stud <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>A&prime; in the vertical slot <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A&prime; in the plastic mounting bracket being visible in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> A longitudinal vector component of an impact on the steering hand wheel is initially resisted by friction between the plastic mounting bracket <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;, the spring washers <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>&prime;, and the slanted flat panel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>&prime;. When that vector component exceeds the friction force, linear translation of the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in its energy absorbing collapse stroke commences. A vertical vector component of the impact on the steering column is reacted to the vehicle body through the slanted flat top of the plastic mounting bracket and the slanted flat panel on the vehicle body which thereby cooperate in defining the vertical position of the upper mast jacket during its collapse stroke. Importantly, because of the angle &thgr;&prime;, the spring washers separate quickly from the horizontal platforms for minimum interference with the collapse stroke of the upper mast jacket. At the same time, a lateral vector component of the impact on the steering column is reacted to the vehicle body through the sides of the vertical slots in the plastic mounting bracket and the vertical studs which thereby cooperate in defining the lateral position of the upper mast jacket during its collapse stroke. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A second modified mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> according this invention is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> in which structural features common to both the second modified mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and the mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are identified by double primed reference characters. In the second modified mounting apparatus, the plastic mounting bracket <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&Prime; is molded as a single structural element around the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> with the pair of schematically represented abutments <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&Prime; in the cylindrical passage <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&Prime; through the bracket received in corresponding sockets, not shown, in the upper mast jacket. The plastic mounting bracket <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&Prime; is rigidly vertically supported on the body of the motor vehicle on a pair of vertical studs, not shown, in the pair of vertical slots <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A&Prime;,<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B&Prime; in the plastic mounting bracket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> A longitudinal vector component of an impact on the steering hand wheel is initially resisted by the schematically represented abutments <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&Prime; which are designed to fracture substantially concurrent with the impact so that the plastic mounting bracket remains stationary as linear translation of the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in its energy absorbing collapse stroke commences through the center passage <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&Prime; which then constitutes a slide bearing for the upper mast jacket. Because the energy absorber between the upper and the lower mast jackets rigidly resists relative linear translation therebetween except during an impact on the steering column, the schematically represented abutments <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&Prime; may be eliminated if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A vertical vector component of the impact on the steering column is reacted to the vehicle body through the flat top <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&Prime; of the plastic mounting bracket clamped against a flat panel, not shown, on the vehicle body so that the center passage <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&Prime; defines the vertical position of the upper mast jacket during its collapse stroke. At the same time, a lateral vector component of the impact on the steering column is reacted to the vehicle body through the mounting bracket and the vertical studs so that the center passage <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&Prime; also defines the lateral position of the upper mast jacket during its collapse stroke. The path traversed by the upper mast jacket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> during its energy absorbing collapse stroke is thus positively defined by the second modified mounting apparatus <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and calculated to promote optimum energy absorbing performance of the steering column.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">Having thus described the invention, what is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A mounting bracket for a steering column having a mast jacket and a longitudinal axis, comprising: 
<claim-text>a molded plastic mounting bracket which is rigidly attached to the mast jacket, the bracket having a top surface, a bottom surface, a front surface, a rear surface, a plurality of interconnected reinforcing ribs extending between the top surface and the bottom surface, an outer contour defined by the plurality of ribs, a center passage through the ribs which is adapted to receive the mast jacket, and a pair of lateral flanges located on opposite sides of the center passage, each flange having a slot formed therein which extends generally parallel to the longitudinal axis of the mast jacket to the front surface of the bracket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The invention of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a guide means incorporated into the top surface of the mounting bracket which extends . </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The invention of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the guide means comprises at least one guide rib extending above the top surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The invention of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the guide means comprises at least one guide channel formed into the top surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The invention of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pair of lateral flanges has an attachment surface and wherein the attachment surface and the top surface are oriented at an angle &thgr; opening toward the back surface relative to one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002-1">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A mounting apparatus for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column including a lower mast jacket and an upper mast jacket supported on the lower mast jacket for linear translation relative thereto in the direction of a longitudinal centerline of the steering column in response a longitudinal vector component of an impact on the steering column comprising: 
<claim-text>a honey comb molded plastic mounting bracket having a center passage around the upper mast jacket and a planar top above the upper mast jacket and a pair of lateral flanges on opposite sides of the upper mast jacket, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an attachment means operative to couple the plastic mounting bracket to the upper mast jacket for linear translation as a unit therewith relative to the lower mast jacket, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of platforms on the plastic mounting bracket each defining a lower side of a corresponding one of the pair of lateral flanges of the plastic mounting bracket, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of vertical slots in respective ones of the pair of lateral flanges of the plastic mounting bracket each open through a side of the plastic mounting bracket facing an upper end of the energy absorbing steering column and intersecting the planar top of the plastic mounting bracket and the corresponding one of the pair of platforms, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a planar panel on a body of a motor vehicle above the upper mast jacket, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of vertical studs rigidly attached to the planar panel and extending through respective ones of the vertical slots in the plastic mounting bracket, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of springs retained on respective ones of the vertical studs below and bearing resiliently against corresponding ones of the pair of platforms on the plastic mounting bracket thereby to clamp the planar top of the plastic mounting bracket against the planar panel on the motor vehicle body to vertically support the upper mast jacket on the motor vehicle body and to release the plastic mounting bracket through the pair of vertical slots therein for linear translation as a unit with the upper mast jacket in response the longitudinal vector component of the impact on the steering column, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vertical vector component of the impact on the steering column being reacted to the motor vehicle body from the onset of linear translation of the upper mast jacket through the planar top of the plastic mounting bracket and the planar panel on the motor vehicle body and a lateral vector component of the impact on the steering column being reacted to the motor vehicle body from the onset of linear translation of the upper mast jacket through the sides of the pair of vertical slots in the plastic mounting bracket and the pair of vertical studs on the motor vehicle body thereby to positively define the path of an energy absorbing collapse stroke of the upper mast jacket relative to the vehicle body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003-2">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The mounting apparatus for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the plane of each of the pair of platforms on the plastic mounting bracket intercepts an angle &thgr; with the plane of the planar top of the plastic mounting bracket to promote rapid separation of each of the pair of springs from the corresponding one of the pair of platforms at the onset of linear translation of the plastic mounting bracket as a unit with the upper mast jacket relative to the lower mast jacket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004-3">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A mounting apparatus for an energy absorbing motor vehicle steering column including a lower mast jacket and an upper mast jacket supported on the lower mast jacket for linear translation relative thereto in the direction of a longitudinal centerline of the steering column in response a longitudinal vector component of an impact on the steering column comprising: 
<claim-text>a honey comb molded plastic mounting bracket having a pair of lateral flanges and a center passage closely received around the upper mast jacket and supporting the plastic mounting bracket on the upper mast jacket for linear translation relative thereto in the direction of the longitudinal centerline of the steering column, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a clamp means operative to rigidly clamp a planar top of the plastic mounting bracket against a planar panel on a body of the motor vehicle so that the upper mast jacket is supported vertically on the motor vehicle body and the center passage in the plastic mounting bracket defines a slide bearing for the upper mast jacket, 
<claim-text>a vertical vector component of the impact on the steering column being reacted to the motor vehicle body from the onset of linear translation of the upper mast jacket through the planar top of the plastic mounting bracket and the planar panel on the motor vehicle body and a lateral vector component of the impact on the steering column being reacted to the motor vehicle body from the onset of linear translation of the upper mast jacket through the clamp means thereby to positively define the path of an energy absorbing collapse stroke of the upper mast jacket relative to the vehicle body.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001375A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001375A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001375A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
