<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001469A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001469A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001469A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001469A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001469A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001469A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001469A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001469A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001469A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001469A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001469</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10163894</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020604</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A47B043/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>312</class>
<subclass>257100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Structural reinforcement and method of use therefor</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60296312</doc-number>
<document-date>20010606</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Timothy</given-name>
<family-name>Hankins</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Oxford</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Douglas</given-name>
<family-name>Larsen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Highland</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dennis</given-name>
<family-name>Lowe</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Romeo</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<family-name>Stolarski</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Shelby Twp.</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>L&amp;L Products, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Scott A. Chapple</name-1>
<name-2>Dobrusin &amp; Thennisch PC</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 311</address-1>
<address-2>401 South Old Woodward Avenue</address-2>
<city>Birmingham</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48009</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The invention provides a structural reinforcement and method of use therefore. The structural reinforcement preferably includes a bracket and a reinforcement material attached to the bracket. The bracket may include flanges for assisting in attaching the reinforcement to a wall of an article of manufacture. Preferably, the reinforcement material is expandable to wet and bond to the wall of the article and is also curable to harden and strengthen the wall of the article. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to a structural reinforcement for locally reinforcing portions of containers or other articles of manufacture. More particularly, the present invention relates to a structural reinforcement having a bracket associated with a reinforcement material. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> An article of manufacture is often required to endure various different loads during use of the article. Examples of articles, which are required to endure such loads include, without limitation, furniture, buildings, containers, automotive vehicles and others. Depending on the materials used to form an article, the structural configuration of the article and the like, it may be advantageous to structurally reinforce a portion of the article with a reinforcement. As examples, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,755,486; 4,901,500; and 4,751,249 describe prior art reinforcing devices. Thus, the present invention provide a structural reinforcement for reinforcing an article of manufacture and a method of using the reinforcement. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to a structural reinforcement member and an article structurally reinforced with the member. The article may be chosen from various articles of manufacture, but is preferably a container and more preferably a filing cabinet. Accordingly, the article will typically include a plurality defining a cavity therein. Preferably, the article includes a first wall and a second wall of the plurality of walls wherein the first wall is skew (e.g., substantially perpendicular) to the second wall. The first wall and second wall may be supplied by various articles or members such as a structural frame member of a filing cabinet, a housing of filing cabinet or both may supply such walls. In a preferred embodiment with structural member, a first wall is integrally connected to a second wall via a curved portion of the structural frame member wherein the curved portion has at least one rib. In a more preferred embodiment, a third wall and a fourth wall are supplied by an outer housing of the filing cabinet, the third wall being substantially perpendicular to the fourth, the third and fourth wall corresponding to the first and second wall of the structural member. The reinforcement member will typically include a bracket. The bracket preferably includes a generally planar portion and a first extension extending from a first side of the planar portion and a second extension extending from a second side of the planar portion. The planar portion of the bracket may include at least one throughhole. The first extension and the second extension may each include protrusions frictionally assisting in gripping the frame member. The reinforcement member will also typically include an reinforcement material that is preferably expandable. The reinforcement material preferably has a generally planar configuration coextensive with and parallel to the generally planar portion of the bracket. The reinforcement material preferably expands upon exposure to heat and contacts at least the first and second and preferably the third and fourth walls. Additionally, the reinforcement material preferably cures and hardens after expansion to structurally reinforce the first and second walls and also may reinforce the third and fourth walls. In a highly preferred embodiment, the reinforcement material expands through a through-hole of the bracket to contact and wet at least one of the plurality of walls.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The features and inventive aspects of the present invention will become more apparent upon reading the following detailed description, claims, and drawings, of which the following is a brief description: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective view of an exemplary embodiment of a structural reinforcement in accordance with an aspect of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a front view of the exemplary structural reinforcement of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a rear view of the exemplary structural reinforcement of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of the exemplary structural reinforcement of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a side view of the exemplary structural reinforcement of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) illustrates side cut-away views of the exemplary structural reinforcement of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> applied to a container.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally provides a structural reinforcement, a method of use for the reinforcement and a structurally reinforced article. Preferably the reinforcement, the method of use and the reinforced article provide one or a combination of the following: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> (1) a portion of an article of manufacture (e.g., a container), which preferably includes a plurality of walls, and which preferably includes a cavity or corner, which is at least partially defined by the wall; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> (2) a bracket having a generally planar portion and at least one flange, the flange preferably extending away from the generally planar portion at least partially in a direction perpendicular to the planar portion, the flange preferably providing an attachment surface supporting a fastening protrusion, the fastening protrusion preferably assisting in attaching the bracket adjacent the plurality of walls of the portion of the article of manufacture; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> (3) a reinforcement material connected to the bracket, the reinforcement material preferably being activatible to change states (e.g., expand, flow, soften, harden), the reinforcement material preferably being generally planar and generally parallel with the planar portion of the bracket, the reinforcement material preferably positioned between the at least one wall and the generally planar portion of the bracket upon attachment of the bracket to the at least one wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, there is illustrated an exemplary structural reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to an aspect of the present invention. The reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention may find utility in a variety of articles of manufacture. For example, and without limitation, the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be integrated into furniture, appliances, transportation vehicles, buildings or other items, which preferably exhibit structural integrity against one or mores forces during their use. In one preferred embodiment, the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is utilized to reinforce a portion of a container such as a file cabinet or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the present invention may be formed in a variety of configurations. Preferably, the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a pair of flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a pair of walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment shown, the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is substantially planar, and substantially rectangular. In alternative embodiments, it is contemplated that the central portion may be provided in a variety of geometric configurations such as circular, elliptical, square, polygonal or the like. It is additionally contemplated that the central portion may be contoured. For maintaining a lower weight for the bracket, the central portion is preferably skeletal and includes one or more through-holes. As shown, the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a pair of equally sized substantially square through-holes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> extending through the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, however, the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may include more or less through-holes and the through-holes may be sized and positioned as desired or needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> extend from opposite sides of the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and include a first portion <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> extending away from the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in a direction at least partially perpendicular and preferably substantially perpendicular to the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Each of the first portions <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is connected at one end to the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and at another end to a second portion <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. As shown, each of the second portions <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is generally L-shaped and provides a substantially planar surface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, however, the second portions <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be provided in a variety of shapes and configurations and the planar surface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may be contoured to correspond to a wall of an article of manufacture. Preferably, as shown, one or more fastening protrusions <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extend outwardly from the substantially planar surface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> extend in a direction at least partially and preferably substantially perpendicular to the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are located adjacent to the flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and extend from the same sides of the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> as the flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. It is contemplated that the walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be separate from or integrated with the flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. It is preferable for the walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to generally extend with (e.g., substantially parallel to) the first portions <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> although not necessarily required. In the embodiment shown, each of the walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a pair of generally arcuate portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> although various alternative contours may be included in the walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> or the walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be substantially planar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is attached to the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and is preferably attached to the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment shown, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is substantially block-shaped and provides an attachment surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> wherein the surface is configured to oppose, contact and attach the reinforcement material to the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Additionally the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes an optional through-hole <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> extending therethrough. In alternative embodiments, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be provided in various shapes such as disk-shaped, contoured or the like and various surfaces of the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may contact the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is preferably located or positioned between the walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or both. As shown, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes concavities <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> for matingly receiving the arcuate portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for assisting in securing the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is a high compressive strength heat activated reinforcement material having foamable characteristics. The material may be generally dry to the touch or tacky, may have magnetic attributes, and can be placed intermediate the flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in any form or desired pattern, placement, or thickness, which may be uniform or non-uniform. In one preferred embodiment, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is between about 1 mm and about 10 mm thick. One exemplary expandable material is L-5204 structural foam available through L&amp;L Products, Inc. of Romeo, Mich. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Though other heat activated materials are possible for the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a preferred heat activated material is an expandable plastic, and preferably one that is foamable. A particularly preferred material is an epoxy-based structural foam. For example, without limitation, the structural foam may be an epoxy-based material, including an ethylene copolymer or terpolymer that may possess an alpha-olefin. As a copolymer or terpolymer, the polymer is composed of two or three different monomers, i.e., small molecules with high chemical reactivity that are capable of linking up with similar molecules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A number of epoxy-based structural reinforcing foams are known in the art and may also be used to produce the structural foam. A typical structural foam includes a polymeric base material, such as an epoxy resin or ethylene-based polymer which, when compounded with appropriate ingredients (typically a blowing and curing agent), expands and cures in a reliable and predicable manner upon the application of heat or the occurrence of a particular ambient condition. From a chemical standpoint for a thermally-activated material, the structural foam is usually initially processed as a flowable thermoplastic material before curing. It will crosslink upon curing, which makes the material incapable of further flow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Examples of preferred structural foam formulations that are epoxy-based materials are commercially available from L&amp;L Products of Romeo, Mich., under the designations L5206, L5207, L5208, L5209, L5020, L5222, L5214, L4200, L4200, L4100, L8000, L5001, XP321 and XP721. One advantage of the preferred structural foam materials over prior art materials is that the preferred materials can be processed in several ways. The preferred materials can be processed by injection molding, extrusion compression molding or with a mini-applicator. This enables the formation and creation of part designs that exceed the capability of most prior art materials. In one preferred embodiment, the structural foam (in its uncured state) generally is dry or relatively free of tack to the touch and can easily be attached to the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through fastening means which are well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> While the preferred materials for fabricating the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> have been disclosed, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be formed of other materials provided that the material selected is heat-activated or otherwise activated by an ambient condition (e.g. moisture, pressure, time or the like) and cures in a predictable and reliable manner under appropriate conditions for the selected application. One such material is the epoxy based resin disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,131,897, the teachings of which are incorporated herein by reference, filed with the United States Patent and Trademark Office on Mar. 8, 1999 by the assignee of this application. Some other possible materials include, but are not limited to, polyolefin materials, copolymers and terpolymers with at least one monomer type an alpha-olefin, phenol/formaldehyde materials, phenoxy materials, and polyurethane materials with high glass transition temperatures. See also, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,766,719; 5,755,486; 5,575,526; and 5,932,680, (incorporated by reference). In general, the desired characteristics of the structural foam include relatively high stiffness, high strength, high glass transition temperature (typically greater than 70 degrees Celsius), and good corrosion resistance properties. In this manner, the material does not generally interfere with the materials systems employed by manufacturers such as furniture manufacturers, automobile manufacturers and others. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In applications where the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is a heat activated, thermally expanding material, an important consideration involved with the selection and formulation of the material comprising the structural foam is the temperature at which a material reaction or expansion, and possibly curing, will take place. For instance, in most applications, it is undesirable for the material to be reactive at room temperature or otherwise at the ambient temperature in a production environment. More typically, the structural foam becomes reactive at higher processing temperatures, such as those encountered in an assembly plant or such as those, which might be induced upon the foam. Exemplary activation temperatures may range from about 140&deg; C. to about 204.44&deg; C. (about 290&deg; F. to 400&deg; F.) (e.g. temperatures experienced in a paint or priming oven. If needed, blowing agents and blowing agent activators can be incorporated into the composition to cause expansion at different temperatures outside the above ranges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Generally, suitable expandable foams have a range of expansion ranging from approximately 0 to over 1000 percent. The level of expansion of the structural foam may be increased to as high as 1500 percent or more. Typically, strength is obtained from products that possess low expansion. Preferably, the expansion level is in the range of about 0% to about 400%, more preferably about 30% to about 200 % and most preferably about 50% to about 100% </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Some other possible materials include, but are not limited to, polyolefin materials, copolymers and terpolymers with at least one monomer type an alpha-olefin, phenol/formaldehyde materials, phenoxy materials, and polyurethane. See also, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,266,133; 5,766,719; 5,755,486; 5,575,526; 5,932,680; and WO 00/27920 (PCT/US 99/24795) (all of which are expressly incorporated by reference). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is provided in an encapsulated or partially encapsulated form, which may comprise a pellet, which includes an expandable foamable material, encapsulated or partially encapsulated in an adhesive shell. An example of one such system is disclosed in commonly owned, co-pending U.S. application Ser. No. 09/524,298 (&ldquo;Expandable Pre-Formed Plug&rdquo;), hereby incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In addition, as discussed previously, preformed patterns may also be employed such as those made by extruding a sheet (having a flat or contoured surface) and then die cutting it according to a predetermined configuration in accordance with the chosen article of manufacture, and applying it thereto. The reinforcement material may include up to 60% filler materials. Moreover, the reinforcement material may include strength additives such as glass, carbon, or aramid fibers, and may include viscosity controllers, thickeners (e.g. silica) or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The skilled artisan will appreciate that the system may be employed in combination with or as a component of a conventional sound blocking baffle, or a vehicle structural reinforcement system, such as is disclosed in commonly owned co-pending U.S. application Ser. Nos. 09/524,961 or 09/502,686 (hereby incorporated by reference). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Assembly </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In a particular preferred embodiment, the bracket could be formed of injection molded nylon, injection molded polymer, or molded metal (such as high strength to weight aluminum, magnesium, steel and titanium, an alloy derived from the metals, and even a metallic foam). The materials may be reinforced with fibers (e.g. glass fibers). In other alternatives, the bracket may be shaped sheet metal or low carbon rolled steel (e.g., 1008 or 1010 twin rolled steel). It is additionally contemplated that the bracket may be coated or heat treated and may include members of fasteners for assisting the attachment of the reinforcement material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> For forming the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be applied to the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> using a variety of techniques or protocols. For example, and without limitation, the reinforcement material may be applied to the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by spraying, brushing, hand applying, swabbing, taping, pumping from reservoir, extrusion coating, die cutting, injection molding (e.g., overmolding, two-shot molding or the like), mechanically fastening, heat bonding or the like. In highly preferred embodiments, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is applied to the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in a viscoelastic state (i.e., at a temperature that softens the material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> without activating it). Such a viscoelastic state may be achieved by injection molding the material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, extruding the material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the like. In one embodiment, the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is placed at least partially in a mold followed by injection molding the material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into the mold in the viscoelastic state such that the material adheres to the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> upon cooling. In another embodiment, an extruder such as the mini-applicator described above extrudes the material directly onto the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the viscoelastic state. For extrusion techniques, it may be necessary to further cut or shape the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> or both after application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Operation </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> For application of the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to an article of manufacture, the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be initially attached to the article of manufacture using a variety of techniques. For example, and without limitation, the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be mechanically fastened to an article with fasteners such as a strap, a push pin, a rivet, a heat stake, welding an interference fit of the like or the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be adhered to the article. Alternatively, a variety of art-known techniques may be used to initially attach the reinforcement to the article. Additionally, the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be attached to nearly any portion of an article of manufacture that needs reinforcing or to a portion of the article adjacent a portion that needs reinforcement. For instance, the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be attached at or near corners, edges, relatively weak portions, side walls, load bearing seams, stress points or the like for reinforcement thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the present invention contemplates that the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be used to reinforce a first wall and a second wall that cooperatively form a corner or edge of a container and which are skew with respect to one another. More particularly, the present invention contemplates that the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be used to reinforce a first wall, a second wall and optionally a third wall wherein each of the walls are substantially perpendicular to each other and form a corner of a cabinet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> According to one preferred embodiment, and referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is attached adjacent to one or more of a plurality of walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> that form a metal housing of a cabinet <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Preferably, at least two and possibly three (e.g., two side walls and a bottom wall) of the plurality of walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are substantially perpendicular to each other and form a corner or edge <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of the cabinet <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> (e.g., a storage or file cabinet). In the embodiment shown, the cabinet <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> includes a structural frame member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> (preferably metal) for supporting drawers or otherwise (not shown) within the cabinet <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The structural frame member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> also provides a plurality of walls <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> (e.g., a pair a wall perpendicular to each other). Preferably, the walls <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> are connected by a curved edge or corner portion <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> of the member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and the curved portion <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> may include one or more ribs <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> for structural integrity. It is also preferable for at least two of the walls <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the structural member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> to correspond to the walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of the housing of the cabinet <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated that the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be positioned in a variety of positions or locations and may be secured in a variety of manners. As shown, the plurality of walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of the cabinet <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and the walls <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the frame member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> cooperatively or alone define a cavity <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> within the cabinet <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. In this preferred embodiment, the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned within the cavity <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> between the various walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> by interferingly engaging the flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with flanges <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the structural member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> such that the fastening the flanges <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the protrusions <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> or both frictionally engage or protrude into the material (e.g., the metal) of the flanges <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. As shown, the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are generally parallel to at least one of the walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is positioned between at least one of the walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and the central portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> After initial attachment, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is activated to expand and then cure and harden as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>). During expansion of this preferred embodiment, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> wets the walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to form a bond with the walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> upon curing. During such expansion, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> preferably expands through the through-holes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the brackets to contact and wet at least one of the walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. Upon curing, the reinforcement material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, either in conjunction with or on its own, imparts stiffness, rigidity and reinforcement to the walls <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> the corner <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> or both. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Advantageously, the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> structurally reinforces the walls. Such reinforcement can be quite advantageous for walls of cabinets or other containers where one of the walls such as a bottom wall is contacted by the floor or other objects, which may place force on the walls. More specifically, during transportation, placement, positioning and the like of containers or cabinets (e.g., particularly for cabinets having objects inside), various forces from a floor or from other objects may be exerted upon the walls, and the reinforcement <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can guard against deformation of the walls. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiment of the present invention has been disclosed. A person of ordinary skill in the art would realize however, that certain modifications would come within the teachings of this invention. Therefore, the following claims should be studied to determine the true scope and content of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article, comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of walls of a container, a first wall of the plurality of walls being skew relative to a second wall of the container for forming a corner; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bracket capable of securing itself adjacent said corner; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reinforcement material attached to the bracket, the reinforcement material expanding and curing to form an intimate bond with and to reinforce the first wall and the second wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the container is a filing cabinet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first wall and second wall are part of a housing of the filing cabinet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first wall and second wall are part of a structural frame member of the filing cabinet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the plurality of walls are part of a structural frame member of the filing cabinet and part of a housing of the filing cabinet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the bracket includes a generally planar portion having at least one through-hole extending therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reinforcement material expands through the at least one through-hole of the bracket to contact and wet at least one of the plurality of walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the bracket includes an extension with a protrusion for assisting in attaching the bracket adjacent the plurality of walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article, comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of walls of a filing cabinet, a first wall of the plurality of walls substantially perpendicular to a second wall of the plurality of walls, the first and second walls at least partially defining a cavity therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bracket having a generally planar portion and a first extension extending from a first side of the planar portion and a second extension extending from a second side of the planar portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an expandable reinforcement material having a generally planar configuration, the expandable material being substantially coextensive with and parallel to the generally planar portion of the bracket, the expandable material expanding and curing to form an intimate bond with and to reinforce the first wall and the second wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the plurality of walls are part of a housing of the filing cabinet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first wall and second wall are part of a structural frame member of the filing cabinet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first wall and second wall are part of a structural frame member of the filing cabinet and part of a housing of the filing cabinet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least one through-hole extends through the generally planar portion of the bracket. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reinforcement material expands through the at least one through-hole of the bracket to contact and wet at least one of the plurality of walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the extensions of the bracket each include a protrusion for assisting in attaching the bracket adjacent the plurality of walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article, comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of walls of a filing cabinet, the plurality of walls defining a cavity therein wherein: 
<claim-text>i) a first wall and a second wall of the plurality of walls are supplied by a structural frame member of the filing cabinet, the first wall being substantially perpendicular to the second wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) the first wall is integrally connected to the second wall via a curved portion of the structural frame member, the curved portion having at least one rib; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>iii) a third wall and a fourth wall of the of the plurality of walls are supplied by an outer housing of the filing cabinet, the third wall being substantially perpendicular to the fourth, the third and fourth wall corresponding to the first and second wall; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bracket having a generally planar portion and a first extension extending from a first side of the planar portion and a second extension extending from a second side of the planar portion wherein: 
<claim-text>i) the planar portion includes at least one through-hole; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) the first extension and the second extension each include protrusions frictionally assisting in gripping the frame member; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an expandable reinforcement material having a generally planar configuration, the expandable material being generally coextensive with and parallel to the generally planar portion of the bracket wherein: 
<claim-text>i) the expandable material expands upon exposure to heat and contacts the first, second, third and fourth walls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) the expandable material cures and hardens after expansion to structurally reinforce the first, second, third and fourth walls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A structurally reinforced article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reinforcement material expands through the through-hole of the bracket to contact and wet at least one of the plurality of walls.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001469A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001469A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001469A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001469A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001469A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
