<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-M00001.NB SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-M00001.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-M00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00019.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00020.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00021.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00022.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00023.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00024.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00025.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00026.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00027.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00027.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00028.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00028.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00029.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00029.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00030.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00030.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002673A1-20030102-D00031.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002673A1-20030102-D00031.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002673</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10189231</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020705</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04N007/167</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>380</class>
<subclass>232000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Steganographic techniques for securely delivering electronic digital rights management control information over insecure communication channels</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10189231</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020705</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09790566</doc-number>
<document-date>20010223</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6449367</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09790566</doc-number>
<document-date>20010223</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09247328</doc-number>
<document-date>19990210</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6240185</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09247328</doc-number>
<document-date>19990210</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>08689606</doc-number>
<document-date>19960812</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>5943422</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Van Wie</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Eugene</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>P.</middle-name>
<family-name>Weber</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Menlo Park</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>InterTrust Technologies Corp.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>FINNEGAN, HENDERSON, FARABOW, GARRETT &amp;</name-1>
<name-2>DUNNER LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1300 I STREET, NW</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20006</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Electronic steganographic techniques can be used to encode a rights management control signal onto an information signal carried over an insecure communications channel. Steganographic techniques ensure that the digital control information is substantially invisibly and substantially indelibly carried by the information signal. These techniques can provide end-to-end rights management protection of an information signal irrespective of transformations between analog and digital. An electronic appliance can recover the control information and use it for electronic rights management to provide compatibility with a Virtual Distribution Environment. In one example, the system encodes low data rate pointers within high bandwidth time periods of the content signal to improve overall control information read/seek times. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is related to commonly assigned copending application Ser. No. 08/388,107 of Ginter et al., filed Feb. 13, 1995, entitled &ldquo;SYSTEMS AND METHODS FOR SECURE TRANSACTION MANAGEMENT AND ELECTRONIC RIGHTS PROTECTION&rdquo; (attorney reference number 895-13). We incorporate by reference, into this application, the entire disclosure of this prior-filed Ginter et al. patent application just as if its entire written specification and drawings were expressly set forth in this application.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present inventions relate generally to computer security, and more particularly to steganographic techniques for hiding or encoding electronic control information within an information signal carried by an insecure communications channel. Still more particularly, the present inventions relate to systems, methods and techniques that substantially invisibly and/or indelibly convey, over analog or other insecure communications channels, digital rights management control information for use within a virtual distribution environment electronic rights management system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND AND SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The world is becoming digital. Digital signals are everywhere&mdash;in our computers, television sets, VCRs, home stereos, and CD players. Digital processing&mdash;which operates on information &ldquo;bits&rdquo; (numerical &ldquo;on&rdquo; or &ldquo;off&rdquo; values)&mdash;provides a degree of precision and protection from noise that cannot be matched by the older, &ldquo;analog&rdquo; formats we have used since the beginning of the electronic ace. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Despite the clear advantage of digital communications, the older &ldquo;analog&rdquo; domain remains significant. Many of our most important information delivery mechanisms continue to be based on analog&mdash;not digital&mdash;signaling. In fact, most of our electronic entertainment, news, sports and music program material comes to us in the form of analog signals. For example: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Television remains largely analog. Although the distribution of television programming to local cable systems is increasingly digital and most modern television sets include digital signal processing circuits, the local cable television &ldquo;head end&rdquo; continues to send television signals to the subscriber&apos;s set top box and television in analog&mdash;not digital&mdash;form. It will cost a great deal to convert local cable distribution from analog to digital. In the United States, for example, the widespread conversion from analog to digital television is projected to take no less than 15 years and perhaps even longer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In radio broadcasting, too, analog communication continues to reign supreme. Thousands of radio stations broadcast music, news and other programs every day in analog form. Except for a few experimental digital systems, practically all radio broadcasting is carried over analog communications channels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The movies and videos we rent at the local video tape rental store are analog. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Commercially available music tape cassettes are recorded in analog formats. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the &ldquo;real world&rdquo; is analog. Everything digital must ultimately be turned into something analog if we are to experience it; and conversely, everything analog must be turned into something digital if the power of modern digital technology will be used to handle it. Modern digital technology also allows people to get better quality for less money. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Despite the pervasiveness of analog signals, existing methods for managing rights and protecting copyright in the analog realm are primitive or non-existent. For example: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Quality degradation inherent in multigenerational analog copying has not prevented a multi-billion dollar pirating industry from flourishing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Some methods for video tape copy and pay per view protection attempt to prevent any copying at all of commercially released content, or allow only one generation of copying. These methods can generally be easily circumvented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Not all existing devices respond appropriately to copy protection signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Existing schemes are limited for example to &ldquo;copy/no copy&rdquo; controls. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Copy protection for sound recordings has not been commercially implemented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A related problem relates to the conversion of information between the analog and digital domains. Even if information is effectively protected and controlled initially using strong digital rights management techniques, an analog copy of the same information may no longer be securely protected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> For example, it is generally possible for someone to make an analog recording of program material initially delivered in digital form. Some analog recordings based on digital originals are of quite good quality. For example, a Digital Versatile Disk (&ldquo;DVD&rdquo;) player may convert a movie from digital to analog format and provide the analog signal to a high quality analog home VCR. The home VCR records the analog signal. A consumer now has a high quality analog copy of the original digital property. A person could re-record the analog signal on a DVD-R (a Digital Versatile Disk appliance and media supporting both read and write operations). This recording will in many circumstances have substantial quality&mdash;and would no longer be subject to &ldquo;pay per view&rdquo; or other digital rights management controls associated with the digital form of the same content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Since analog formats will be with us for a long time to come, rightsholders such as film studios, video rental and distribution companies, music studios and distributors, and other value chain participants would very much like to have significantly better rights management capabilities for analog film, video, sound recordings and other content. Solving this problem generally requires a way to securely associate rights management information with the content being protected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> People have for many years been using various techniques allowing digital information to, in effect, ride &ldquo;piggyback&rdquo; on analog information signals. For example, since the 1960s, it has been common to digitally encode text information such as subtitles into otherwise unused portions of analog television signals (e.g., within the so-called &ldquo;Vertical Blanking Interval&rdquo;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Unfortunately, sending digital information using such known digital encoding techniques is problematic because the digital information is not persistent. It is relatively easy to strip out or eliminate digital information encoded using prior techniques commonly employed for superimposing digital signals onto an analog information signal. Analog communications channels may commonly be subjected to various signal processing that may (intentionally or unintentionally) strip out digital information added to the analog signal&mdash;defeating any downstream system, process or technique that depends on the presence and readability of the digital information. For example, the television vertical blanking signal&mdash;along with any signal components disposed within the vertical blanking interval&mdash;is typically routinely eliminated whenever a video signal is processed by a computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Attempting to use insecure techniques for providing rights management is at best ineffective, and can be worse than no rights management at all. Unscrupulous people can strip out insecure control information altogether so that the corresponding information signal is subject to no controls at all&mdash;for example, defeating copy protection mechanisms and allowing users to avoid paying for rights usage. More nefariously, an unscrupulous person could alter an insecure system by substituting false control information in place of the proper information. Such substitutions could, for example, divert payments to someone other than legitimate rights holders&mdash;facilitating electronic fraud and theft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Prior, insecure techniques fail to solve the overall problem of how to provide and securely manage advanced automatic electronic rights management for analog and other information signals conveyed over an insecure communications channel. The lack of strong rights management for analog signals creates a huge gap in any comprehensive electronic rights management strategy, and makes it possible for consumers and others to circumvent&mdash;to at least some extent&mdash;even the strongest digital rights management technologies. Consequently, there is a real need to seamlessly integrate analog delivery models with modem electronic digital rights management techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The present inventions solve these and other problems by providing &ldquo;end to end&rdquo; secure rights management protection allowing content providers and rights holders to be sure their content will be adequately protected&mdash;irrespective of the types of devices, signaling formats and nature of signal processing within the content distribution chain. This &ldquo;end to end&rdquo; protection also allows authorized analog appliances to be easily, seamlessly and cost-effectively integrated into a modem digital rights management architecture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The present inventions may provide a Virtual Distribution Environment (&ldquo;VDE&rdquo;) in which electronic rights management control information may be delivered over insecure (e.g., analog) communications channels. This Virtual Distribution Environment is highly flexible and convenient, accommodating existing and new business models while also providing an unprecedented degree of flexibility in facilitating ad hoc creation of new arrangements and relationships between electronic commerce and value chain participants&mdash;regardless of whether content is distributed in digital and/or analog formats. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The present inventions additionally provide the following important and advantageous features: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> An indelible and invisible, secure technique for providing rights management information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> An indelible method of associating electronic commerce and/or rights management controls with analog content such as film, video, and sound recordings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Persistent association of the commerce and/or rights management controls with content from one end of a distribution system to the other&mdash;regardless of the number and types of transformations between signaling formats (for example, analog to digital, and digital to analog). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The ability to specify &ldquo;no copy/ one copy/ many copies&rdquo; rights management rules, and also more complex rights and transaction pricing models (such as, for example, &ldquo;pay per view&rdquo; and others). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The ability to fully and seamlessly integrate with comprehensive, general electronic rights management solutions (such as those disclosed in the Ginter et al. patent specification referenced above). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Secure control information delivery in conjunction with authorized analog and other non-digital and/or non-secure information signal delivery mechanisms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The ability to provide more complex and/or more flexible commerce and/or rights management rules as content moves from the analog to the digital realm and back. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The flexible ability to communicate commerce and/or rights management rules implementing new, updated, or additional business models to authorized analog and/or digital devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Briefly, the present inventions use &ldquo;steganography&rdquo; to substantially indelibly and substantially invisibly encode rights management and/or electronic commerce rules and controls within an information signal such as, for example, an analog signal or a digitized (for example, sampled) version of an analog signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The Greek term &ldquo;steganography&rdquo; refers to various &ldquo;hidden writing&rdquo; secret communication techniques that allow important messages to be securely carried over insecure communications channels. Here are some examples of steganography: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In ancient Persia an important message was once tattooed on a trusted messenger&apos;s shaved scalp. The messenger then allowed his hair to grow back&mdash;completely hiding the message. Once the messenger made his way to his destination, he shaved his hair off again&mdash;exposing the secret message so the recipient could read it on the messenger&apos;s shaved scalp. See Kahn, David, <highlight><italic>The Codebreakers </italic></highlight>page 81 et seq. and page 513 et seq. (Macmillan 1967). This unusual technique for hiding a message is one illustration of &ldquo;steganography.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Another &ldquo;steganographic&rdquo; technique encodes a secret message within another, routine message. For example, the message &ldquo;Hey Elmer, Lisa Parked My Edsel&rdquo; encodes the secret message &ldquo;HELP ME&rdquo;&mdash;the first letter of each word of the message forming the letters of the secret message (&ldquo;Hey Elmer, Lisa Parked My Edsel&rdquo;). Variations on this technique can provide additional security, but the basic concept is the same&mdash;finding a way to hide a secret message within information that can or will be sent over an insecure channel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Invisible ink is another commonly used &ldquo;steganography&rdquo; technique. The secret message is written using a special disappearing or invisible ink The message can be written on a blank piece of paper, or more commonly, on the back or front of the piece of paper carrying a routine-looking or legitimate letter or other written communication. The recipient performs a special process on the received document (e.g., exposing it to a chemical or other process that makes the invisible ink visible) so that he or she can read the message. Anyone intercepting the paper will be unable to detect the secret message&mdash;or even know that it is there&mdash;unless the interceptor knows to look for the invisible message and also knows how to treat the paper to make the invisible ink visible </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The present inventions use steganography to ensure that encoded control information is both substantially invisible and substantially indelible as it passes over an insecure communications channel. At the receiving end, a secure, trusted component (such as a protected processing environment described in Ginter et al.) recovers the steganographically-encoded control information, and uses the recovered information to perform electronic rights management (for example, on analog or other information signals carried over the same channel). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> One specific aspect provided by the present inventions involve steganographically encoding digital rights management control information onto an information signal such as, for example, an analog or digitized television, video or radio signal. The steganographic encoding process substantially inextricably intertwines the digital control information with images, sounds and/or other content the information signal carries&mdash;but preferably without noticeably degrading or otherwise affecting those images, sounds and/or other content. It may be difficult to detect (even with educated signal processing techniques) that the analog signal has been steganographically encoded with a rights management control signal, and it may be difficult to eliminate the steganographically encoded control signal without destroying or degrading the other information or content the signal carries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The present inventions also provide a secure, trusted protected processing environment to recover the steganographically-encoded control signal from the information signal, and to enforce rights management processes based on the recovered steganographically encoded control signal. This allows the information signal delivery mechanism to be fully integrated (and made compatible) with a digital virtual distribution environment and/or other electronic rights management system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In accordance with yet another aspect provided by this invention, steganographically encoded, digital rights management control information may be used in conjunction with a scrambled and/or encrypted information signal. The scrambling and/or encryption can be used to enforce the rights management provided in accordance with the steganographically encoded rights management control information. For example, the control signal can be steganographically decoded and used to control, at least in part, under what circumstances and/or how the information signal is to be descrambled and/or decrypted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In accordance with yet another feature provided by the invention, digital certificates can be used to securely enforce steganographically encoded rights management control information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In accordance with still another feature provided by the invention, steganography is used to encode an information signal with rights management control information in the form of one or more protected organizational structures having association with electronic controls. The electronic controls may, for example, define permitted and/or required operation(s) on content, and consequences of performing and/or failing to perform such operations. The organizational structure(s) may identify, implicitly or explicitly, the content the electronic controls apply to. The organizational structure(s) may also define the extent of the content, and semantics of the content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The type, amount and characteristics of the steganographically encoded rights management control information are flexible and programmable&mdash;providing a rich, diverse mechanism for accommodating a wide variety of rights management schemes. The control information can be used to securely enforce straightforward secure rights management consequences such as &ldquo;copy/no copy/one copy&rdquo; type controls&mdash;but are by no means limited to such models. To the contrary, the present invention can be used to enable and enforce much richer, more complex rights management models&mdash;including for example those involving usage auditing, automatic electronic payment, and the use of additional electronic network connections. Moreover, the rights management control arrangements provided by the present invention are infinitely extensible and scaleable&mdash;fully accommodating future models as they are commercially deployed while preserving full compatibility with different (and possibly more limited) rights management models deployed during earlier stages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The organizational structure(s) may be steganographically encoded in such a way that they are protected for purposes of secrecy and/or integrity. The employed steganographic techniques may provide some degree of secrecy protection&mdash;or other security techniques (e.g., digital encryption, digital seals, etc.) may be used to provide a desired or requisite degree of security and/or integrity protection for the steganographically encoded information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In one example, the organizational structure(s) may comprise digital electronic containers that securely contain corresponding digital electronic control information. Such containers may, for example, use cryptographic techniques. In other examples, the organizational structure(s) may define associations with other electronic control information. The other electronic control information may be delivered independently over the same or different communications path used to deliver the organizational structure(s). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In one example, the steganographic techniques employed may involve applying the organizational structure information in the form of high frequency &ldquo;noise&rdquo; to an analog information signal. Spectral transforms may be used to apply and recover such steganographically-encoded high frequency &ldquo;noise.&rdquo; Since the high frequency noise components of the information signal may be essentially random, adding a pseudo-random steganographically encoded control signal component may introduce substantially no discernible information signal degradation, and may be difficult to strip out once introduced (at least without additional knowledge of how the signal was incorporated, which may include a shared secret). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect provided by the invention, a steganographic encoding process analyzes an information signal to determine how much excess bandwidth is available for steganographic encoding. The steganographic encoding process may use variable data rate encoding to apply more control information to parts of an information signal that use much less than all of the available communications channel bandwidth, and to apply less control information to parts of an information signal that use nearly all of the available communications channel bandwidth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In accordance with still another aspect provided by the invention, multiple organizational structures may be steganographically encoded within a given information signal. The multiple organizational structures may apply to different corresponding portions of the information signal, and/or the multiple organizational structures may be repetitions or copies of one another to ensure that an electronic appliance has &ldquo;late entry&rdquo; and/or error correcting capability and/or can rapidly locate a pertinent organizational structure(s) starting from any arbitrary portion of the information signal stream. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In accordance with yet another aspect provided by this invention, an organizational structure may be steganographically encoded within a particular portion of a content-carrying information signal to which the organizational structure applies&mdash;thereby establishing an implicit correspondence between the organizational structure and the identification and/or extent and/or semantics of the information content to which the organizational structure applies. The correspondence may, for example, include explicit components (e.g., internally stated start/end points), with the storage or other physical association determined by convenience (i.e., it may make sense to put the organizational structure close to where it is used, in order to avoid seeking around storage media to find it). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In accordance with yet another aspect provided by this invention, pointers can be steganographically encoded into parts of an information signal stream that has little excess available bandwidth. Such pointers may be used, for example, to direct an electronic appliance to portions of the information signal stream having more available bandwidth for steganographic encoding. Such pointers may provide improved steganographic decode access time&mdash;especially, for example, in applications in which the information signal stream is stored or otherwise available on a random access basis.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> These and other features and advantages provided by this invention may be better and more completely understood by referring to the following detailed description of presently preferred example embodiments in conjunction with the drawings, of which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a virtual distribution environment providing steganographic encoding of digital rights management control information; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>E show example electronic appliances embodying aspects of this invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an example of how electronic control information can be steganographically encoded within an image; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows an example rights management component providing a steganographic decoding function; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows an example of how steganographically encoded electronic control signals can be extracted and used for digital rights management; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>D show example techniques for enforcing steganographically encoded rights management control information; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>E-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>F show example &ldquo;end to end&rdquo; protected distribution systems provided in accordance with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows an example of multiple sets of digital rights management control information steganographically encoded onto different parts of the same information signal stream; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> shows an example detailed steganographic encoding process; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> shows an example detailed steganographic decoding process; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows an example frequency domain view of an example steganographic signal encoding technique; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows an example use of a variable steganographic encoding rate to avoid exceeding channel bandwidths; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 10</cross-reference>A show how steganographically encoded pointers can be used to minimize access times to control signals steganographically encoded onto information signal streams available on a random access basis; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows an example steganographically encoded organizational structure; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> shows an example electronic appliance architecture having electronic rights management capabilities based at least in part on steganographically encoded control information; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 13</cross-reference>A show example control steps that may be performed by the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> appliance; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> shows an example steganographic refresh arrangement; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>F show example distribution systems using steganographic encoding of rights management control information along at least one leg of an information distribution path.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PRESENTLY PREFERRED EXAMPLE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows an example Virtual Distribution Environment (VDE) <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> employing steganography to deliver electronic digital rights management control information over an insecure (e.g., analog) communications channel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> In this example, a provider <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> delivers an information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to multiple electronic appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), . . . , <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>(N). In this particular example, provider <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is shown as being a television broadcaster that delivers an analog television information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> over a wireless or cable communications path, and appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), . . . , <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>(N) are shown as being home color television sets <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. As made clear by FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>E, the present inventions may be used by a variety of different types of electronic appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> receiving a variety of different types of information signals via a variety of different types of communications channels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> In the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> example, provider <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> steganographically encodes electronic rights management control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> into the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. This control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is represented in this diagram as a traffic light because it may define permitted and/or required operation(s), and consequences of performing or failing to perform such operations. For example, control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> could specify that a viewer or class of viewers has permission to watch a particular program, is forbidden to watch a program, or may watch a program only under certain conditions (for example, based on paying a certain amount, being over a certain age, etc.). In this example the control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is shown as being packaged within an electronic &ldquo;container&rdquo; <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. Container <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> (which in at least one example is provided by steganographic encoding techniques) is used to protect the integrity of the control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The provider <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> encodes the electronic rights management control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> onto information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> using steganographic techniques that make the control information both: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> substantially invisible, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> substantially indelible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is substantially indelibly encoded because, in this example, it is substantially inextricably intertwined with the television images and/or sound&mdash;and can&apos;t easily be eliminated from information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> without destroying the images, sound or other information carried by the information signal. For example, steganographically encoding rights management control information will generally survive compression and decompression of a digitized analog signal, and will also survive repeated analog/digital/analog conversion sequences. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Even though the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is substantially indelible, the television viewer is not bothered by the steganographically encoded information because the steganographically encoded rights management control information is, in this example, also encoded substantially invisibly. In fact, the viewer may not be able to see the steganographic control information at all&mdash;and it may have no effect whatsoever on his or her viewing experience (other than in terms of the effect is has on associated rights management processes). The control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is shown in dotted lines on the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> screens of television sets <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to emphasize that the control information is substantially inextricably intertwined with the television images and/or sounds&mdash;and yet can&apos;t really be seen or noticed by the television viewer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an example of how digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> may be encoded within an image <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> so that, in one particular example, it is both substantially invisible and substantially indelible. In this specific image context, for example, &ldquo;substantially invisible&rdquo; may refer to the characteristic of the encoded control information as not substantially interfering with or adversely affecting the viewer&apos;s experience in viewing image <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> or otherwise using the content carried by the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and/or that it is difficult to detect using various types of signal processing techniques, for example. For example, invisibility can be a measurable quantity (measured in a number of processor instructions, such as MIPS years, for example), and can be related to signal processing as opposed to the naked eye. In this context, &ldquo;substantially indelible&rdquo; can mean, for example, that the encoded digital control information is substantially inextricably intertwined with the content information, making it difficult for example to strip out the encoded digital control information without also damaging or degrading the content. Degree of indelibility may, for example, be measured by the number of processor instructions required to strip the information out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows that a slight rearrangement of picture element configuration in a small portion of image <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is one way to steganographically encode electronic control information into the image to provide a substantially indelible, substantially invisible encoding. This encoding may be unnoticeable to the viewer, and yet it may be difficult to strip out or eliminate without also damaging the image. Steganographically encoding digital control information into the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may effectively merge, from a practical standpoint, the digital control information with the other information carried by the signal (for example, television programming or other content). The steganographic techniques make it difficult for someone to intentionally or unintentionally eliminate the encoded control information without damaging the content, but may (in one example) nevertheless hide the encoded control information so that it does not unduly detract from the content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Since indelibility of the steganographic encoding provides persistence, indelibility may be more important than invisibility in at least some applications. For example, it may be desirable in some applications to use a shared secret to decode and then remove the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> before presenting the information signal (or its content) to the user. The steganographically encoded information need not be particularly invisible in this scenario. Even though someone with knowledge of the shared secret can remove the steganographically encoded information, it may nevertheless remain substantially indelible to anyone who doesn&apos;t know the shared secret required to remove it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Organization Structures </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows that control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> may be packaged within one or more organizational structures such as secure digital containers <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. Containers <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> may be, for example, of the type described in the Ginter et al. patent specification in connection with FIGS. <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B. The organizational structure(s) may identify, implicitly or explicitly, the content the electronic controls apply to. The organizational structure(s) may also define the extent of the content, and semantics of the content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The organizational structure(s) may be encoded in such a way that they are protected for purposes of secrecy, authenticity and/or integrity. The employed steganographic technique may provide such protection, or another security technique may be used in conjunction with steganography to provide a desired or requisite degree of protection depending on the application. Containers <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> may, for example, use mathematical techniques called &ldquo;encryption&rdquo; that help guarantee the integrity and/or secrecy of the control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> they contain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Example Rights Management Component </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Each of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> example appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may include a electronic digital rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> may, for example, comprise one or more tamper-resistant integrated circuit &ldquo;chips&rdquo;. Components <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> may, for example, be of the general type described in detail at <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> and following of the Ginter et al. patent specification. Briefly, Ginter et al. describes a Virtual Distribution Environment (&ldquo;VDE&rdquo;) including multiple electronic appliances coupled together through a communications capability. Each electronic appliance has such a secure, tamper-resistant &ldquo;protected processing environment&rdquo; in which rights management processes may securely take place. The Virtual Distribution Environment delivers digital control information to the protected processing environments by packaging the control information within secure electronic digital containers. This delivered control information provides at least part of the basis for performing electronic rights management functions within the protected processing environments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> The ability to securely deliver digital control information to such protected processing environments as embodied with components <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is important at least because it increases flexibility and enhances functionality. For example, different digital control information can be delivered for the same or different electronic content. As one specific example, one set of rules may apply to a particular television program, another set of rules might apply to a particular film, and a still different set of rules could apply to a particular musical work. As yet another example, different classes of users of the same electronic content can receive different control information depending upon their respective needs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Rights management components <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> are able to steganographically decode the control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> carried by the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Components <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> use the decoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to electronically manage rights. For example, components <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> may use the decoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to control how the images and/or sound carried by information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> In one example, digital rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> may comprise or include one or more integrated circuit chips as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> example rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> includes an analog-to-digital converter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, a steganographic decoder <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, and a rights management processor <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. Rights management processor <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> may include or comprise a protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> as described in Ginter et al. FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, for example, providing a tamper-resistant execution environment for effecting the operations provided by electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> may also include a steganographic encoder and a digital-to-analog converter (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The analog-to-digital converter (ADC) <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> takes the incoming information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and&mdash;if it is in analog form&mdash;converts it to a digital signal (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, step &ldquo;A&rdquo;). Steganographic decoder 132 obtains the digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> from the resulting digital signal (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, step &ldquo;B&rdquo;). As mentioned above, digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> may define permitted and/or required operation(s) on the content carried by signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, and may further define consequences of performing and/or failing to perform such operations. Rights management processor <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> may manage these rights and/or permissions and associated consequences (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, step &ldquo;C&rdquo;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Example Electronic Appliances </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The present inventions may be used with all sorts of different kinds of electronic appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> each of which may include a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>E show various example electronic appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> embodying aspects of the present invention. For example: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> shows an example media player <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> capable of playing Digital Versatile Disks (DVDs) <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> on a home color television set <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. For example, media player <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may provide analog output signals to television set <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, and may also process digitized video and/or audio analog signals stored on optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>A provides digital rights protection based on steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> shows an example set top box <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> that can receive cable television signals (for example, via a satellite dish antenna <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> from a satellite <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>) for performance on home television set <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Set top box <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> may receive television signals from antenna <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in analog scrambled or unscrambled form, and provide analog signals to television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>B provides digital rights protection based on steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> shows an example radio receiver <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> that receives radio signals and plays the radio sound or music on a loud speaker <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The radio receiver <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> may receive analog radio signals, and provide analog audio signals to loud speaker <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>C provides digital rights protection based on steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> shows an example video cassette recorder <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> that can play back video and sound signals recorded on a video cassette tape <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> onto television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>D, the video tape <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may store video and audio signals in analog form, which VCR <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may read and provide to television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> in analog form. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>D provides digital rights protection based on steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1E</cross-reference> shows an example television camera that can capture video images and produce video signals for recording on a video cassette tape <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and play back on television set <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1E</cross-reference> camcorder <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may generate analog video and audio signals for storage onto video tape <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and/or may provide analog signals for processing by television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>E provides digital rights protection based on steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Example Rights Management Enforcement Techniques </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Different rights holders want different types of rights management and control. For example, some rights holders may be completely satisfied with a relatively simple &ldquo;copy/no copy/one copy&rdquo; rights management control model, whereas other rights holders may desire a richer, more complex rights management scheme. The present inventions flexibly accommodate a wide variety of electronic rights management techniques&mdash;giving rightsholders extreme flexibility and programmability in defining, for example, commerce and rights management models that far exceed the simple &ldquo;copy/no copy, one copy.&rdquo; Assuming a closed appliance, that is, one lacking at least an occasional connection to a payment method (e.g., Visa, MasterCard, American Express, electronic cash, Automated Clearinghouses (ACHs) and/or a Financial Clearinghouse that serves as the interface for at least one payment method), the following are non-limiting examples of steganographically encoded rights controls and associated consequences that can be accommodated by the present invention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Limiting use of a given property to a specified number of times this property can be used on a given appliance; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Prohibiting digital to analog and analog to digital conversions; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Ensuring that one analog or digital appliance will communicate the protected property only to another appliance that is also VDE enabled and capable of enforcing the controls associated with that property; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Time-based rental models in which a consumer may &ldquo;perform&rdquo; or &ldquo;play&rdquo; the property an unlimited number of times in a given interval (assuming the appliance has a built-in secure time clock, can operatively connect itself to such a clock, or otherwise receive time from a reliable source); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> Enforcing an expiration date after which the property cannot be performed (also assuming access to a reliable time source); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> Associating different control sets with each of several properties on a single physical media. In one example, a &ldquo;trailer&rdquo; might have unlimited copying and use associated while a digital film property may have an associated control set that prevents any copying; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Associating multiple control sets with a given property regardless of media and whether the appliance is closed or has an occasionally connected communications &ldquo;backchannel.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> An even more flexible and diverse array of rights controls and associated consequences are enabled by the present inventions if at least one appliance is connected to some form of communications &ldquo;backchannel&rdquo; between the appliance and some form of payment method. This backchannel may be a telephone call, the use of a modem, a computer data network, such as the Internet, a communications channel from a settop box to the head end or some other point on a cable TV distribution system, or a hybrid arrangement involving high bandwidth distribution of analog properties with a slower return channel, a phone line and modem&mdash;just to name a few examples. Non-limiting examples of such more rights controls and associated consequences enabled by the present invention include the following: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Associating with a given property in analog format new, independently delivered controls obtained from a rightsholder or other authorized source; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> A broad range of usage-based pricing models, including pay-per-view or pay-per-use; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Creating permissions enabling excerpting of properties in analog formats, maintaining persistent control over those excerpts, and charging for those excerpts; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Pay-per-use models in which a customer pays a specified price for each use of the property and/or different unit prices depending on the number of uses. In one example, the customer might pay $3.99 for the first viewing and $2.99 for each subsequent viewing; and, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> Controls that prevent an analog property being converted to digital format and then being transmitted or communicated except in a container with controls and/or with a pointer to a source of controls, that apply in a digital environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>D show some examples of how rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> can enforce steganographically encoded digital rights management controls. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> In the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> example, rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> controls an on/off switch <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> based on steganographically encoded electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> turns switch <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> on (for example, to allow the analog television signal to pass to television set <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>) when electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> permit, and otherwise opens (turns off) switch <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to prevent the analog signal from reaching the output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> In a more secure example, the incoming analog signal is scrambled, and the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> on/off switch <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is replaced by a <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> descrambler <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of conventional design. The descrambler <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> descrambles the analog input signal to provide a descrambled output under control of rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> allows descrambler <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> to descramble the analog signal only under conditions specified by electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> that the component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> obtains from the analog input signal. Scrambling the analog signal gives the rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> a relatively secure way of enforcing electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>&mdash;since the rights management component can prevent the descrambler from operating unless conditions set by the controls are satisfied. The rights management function and the descrambling function may be integrated into a single component in which the descramble and decrypt functions of the rights management component are essentially serving the same function, but may still be distinct to account for specialized approaches to descrambling that may not be sufficiently strong or interoperable with other environments to use generally. If they are separate components, the data path between them should be protected (for example, by ensuring that both components are in a tamper resistant enclosure, or using secure authentication and key exchange to send the descrambling sequence to the descrambler). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference> shows how digital certificates may be used to enforce steganographically encoded electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. In this example, appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A outputs content to another appliance <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>D only if appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>D has a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>D that can enforce the electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. In this example, there may be a &ldquo;handshake&rdquo; between the content supplying appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A and the content receiving appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>D sufficient to ensure the content supplying appliance that the content receiving appliance will enforce the electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. For example, the supplying appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A&apos;s rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>A may require the receiving appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>D&apos;s rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>D to present a digital certificate <highlight><bold>199</bold></highlight> attesting to the fact that the receiving appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>D has a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> fully capable of securely enforcing electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Receiving appliance <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>D could present this digital certificate <highlight><bold>199</bold></highlight> by steganographically encoding it within an analog signal it provides to the supplying appliance over an analog signal channel for example (the analog signal channel could be the same one the supplying appliance will use to deliver the steganographically encoded content). If a digital channel is available, the handshake can be over a digital link between the two appliances using, for example, secure authentication techniques disclosed in Ginter et al. and/or for example in Schneier, <highlight><italic>Applied Cryptography </italic></highlight>(2d Ed. Wiley 1996) at page 52 et seq. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</cross-reference> shows that rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>A can enforce electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> by marking the content through &ldquo;fingerprinting&rdquo; and/or &ldquo;watermarking&rdquo; prior to releasing the content to a device that doesn&apos;t have a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. See Ginter et al. patent specification, FIGS. <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>C. Such fingerprinting could involve using steganographic techniques to fingerprint the content. For example, a movie delivered using &ldquo;conventional&rdquo; containers as disclosed in Ginter et al. could use steganographically encoded containers &ldquo;on the way&rdquo; to the display device. Furthermore, it could include the identity of the user, etc. as well as the control information appropriate for the device. Another case could be text sent to a printer, using different steganographic encoding techniques such as line and/or character shifting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> End to End Protection </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>E-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>F illustrate how the persistent association with content provided by steganographically encoded electronic rights management control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> provides &ldquo;end to end&rdquo; protection within an arbitrary information signal distribution system&mdash;irrespective of the processes the information signal is subjected to as it travels to its final destination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5E</cross-reference> shows an example of how the present inventions can be used to maintain end-to-end rights management protection over content initially distributed in an analog signal format. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5F</cross-reference> shows an example of how the present invention can be used to maintain end-to-end rights management protection over content initially distributed in digital form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> In the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5E</cross-reference> example, an analog signal transmission site (e.g., a radio or television broadcaster) transmits an analog signal A steganographically encoded with an organizational structure <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> including electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. This analog signal A may be received by an electronic appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A having a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>A as described above. Appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A may, for example, convert the signal into digital and/or digitized format, and store the digitized version of the signal onto a digital storage medium <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Electronic appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A may play back the recorded digitized signal, convert the signal back to analog form, and deliver the analog signal A to a further electronic appliance <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B. In this example, electronic appliance <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B also has a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> The steganographic techniques provided by the present invention ensure that the electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> persist in the signal A delivered from appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A to appliance <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B&mdash;and from appliance <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B to still other appliances. Because of the substantial indelibility characteristics of the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, this information persists in the signal as stored on recording medium <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, in copies of the recorded signal produced by replaying the medium, and in further downstream versions of the signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> This persistence will, for example, survive conversion from analog to digital format (e.g., sampling or &ldquo;digitizing&rdquo;), storage, and subsequent conversion from digital to analog format. For example, because the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is substantially indelibly, substantially inextricably intertwined and integrated with the information signal A, the digitized version of the information signal that appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A records on medium <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> will also contain the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Similarly, when appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A plays back the recording from medium <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, it will reproduce information signal A along with the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. The steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> thus persists irrespective of digitization (or other processing) of signal A. In some cases, lossy compression techniques used on the data may remove high frequency noise&mdash;thereby potentially damaging the steganographic channel. When these lossy compression techniques are used or may be encountered, the steganographic encoding function should be matched to the compression algorithm(s) using conventional signal analysis techniques to avoid this consequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> Similarly, appliance <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B may output further copies or versions of signal A in analog form and/or digital form. Because of its inherently persistent characteristics, the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> will be present in all subsequent versions of the signal outputted by appliance <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B&mdash;be they in analog format, digital format, or any other useful format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> Degrading a digital signal carrying control information is fatal&mdash;the rights management system typically may no longer function properly if even a single bit is altered. To avoid this, the preferred embodiment provides redundancy (repeating pointers and the organizational structures and/or any control information incorporated into the organizational structures), and also uses conventional error correction coding such as, for example, Reed-Solomon (or similar) error correcting codes. Additionally, because the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is substantially inextricably intertwined with the desired content carried by information signal A, any process that degrades the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> will also tend to degrade the information signal&apos;s desired content. Although the steganographically encoded information may degrade (along with the content) in multi-generation &ldquo;copies&rdquo; of the signal, degraded copies may not be commercially significant since the information content of the signal will be similarly degraded due to the substantially inextricable intertwining between the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and the content carried by signal A. The refresh circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> with appropriate error correcting capabilities is one way to prevent the steganographically encoded information from being degraded even if the rest of the information the signal carries becomes degraded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5F</cross-reference> example shows content being initially distributed in digital form over a network to an electronic appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>J such as a personal computer. Personal computer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>J may convert the digitally delivered content to an analog signal A for distribution to other appliances <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A. Personal computer appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>J may include a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>J that ensures, based on controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, that appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>J does not release a version of the content associated with controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> that is not protected by the controls. In this example, rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>J is capable of steganographically encoding the analog signal A with the control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> (e.g., it may perform the processes shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> below). Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>J enforces controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, at least in part, by ensuring that any analog version of the content associated with controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is steganographically encoded with those controls. Further &ldquo;downstream&rdquo; appliances <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A may each include their own rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> for use in interacting with steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Example Control Information </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows that a particular information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may be encoded with many different containers <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> and associated rights management control sets <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. For example, different portions of an information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may be associated with different control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. In this example of a movie <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> a first &ldquo;trailer&rdquo; <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> may be associated with control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> a second trailer <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> may be associated with control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> a title section <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> may be associated with control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> the first five minutes of the movie may be associated with control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>), and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> the rest of the movie may be associated with control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> Control information portions <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) may all be different. For example, control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) may permit the user to copy trailer <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>, whereas control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) may prohibit the user from copying the first five minutes <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> of the film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, multiple, identical copies of control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) may be steganographically encoded onto the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. For example, control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) could be encoded once per minute onto the rest of movie <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>. This redundancy allows a media player <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> or other electronic appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to rapidly obtain a copy of the control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>(<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) no matter where the user begins watching or playing the movie <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>, and also helps ensure that transmission errors will not prevent the rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> from recovering at least one &ldquo;good&rdquo; copy of the organizational structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> Example Steganographic Encoding and Decoding Processes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A and 7B</cross-reference> show example overall steganographic encoding and decoding processes, respectively. The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> process may be used to steganographically encode digital control information onto an analog signal, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> performs the inverse operation of steganographically decoding the control information from the analog signal. Generally, the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> process may be performed at a supply point, and the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> process may be performed at a usage point. An electronic appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be both a supply point and a usage point, and so it may perform both the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> process and the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, the analog information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> inputted to the steganographic encoding process may be any sort of information signal such as, for example, the analog signal shown in Graph A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A conventional analog-to-digital conversion block <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> may be used, if necessary, to convert this analog input signal to a digitized signal (see Graph A<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). A spectral transform block <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> may then be used to transform the digitized information from the time domain to the frequency domain. Spectral transform block <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> may be any conventional transformation such as, for example, a Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) or a Walsh Transform. An example of the resulting spectral information is shown in the A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> graph. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> A steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may be used to steganographically encode digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, in clear text form and/or after encryption by a conventional digital encryption block <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> based on an encryption key Key<highlight><subscript>s </subscript></highlight>Steganographic information can be combined with a pseudo-random data stream (e.g. exclusive-or&apos;d into the output of a DES engine)&mdash;in effect shuffling around the noise in the signal rather than replacing noise with the signal, per se. When protection is desired, the values in the pseudo-random stream can be protected by encryption (e.g. the key that initializes the DES engine should be protected). When the steganographic channel is &ldquo;public&rdquo; (e.g., unencrypted), the stream should be readily reproducible (e.g. by using one of a preset collection of values shared by every device). A small portion (a &ldquo;public header&rdquo;&mdash;see Ginter et al.) is always detectable using a shared preset value (that does not need to be protected, distinguishing it from the private header keys), may be provided to ensure that the rights management technology can be activated properly. Since the rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> at the receiving side needs to know how to descramble the signal, there normally will be an indication in the &ldquo;public header&rdquo; that names a key that will be used to unlock the private header (and so on, as described, for example, in Ginter et al.). Some publicly available, agreed upon preset values may be used to extract the &ldquo;public header&rdquo; information from the steganographically encoded channel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> Steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may be any conventional steganographic encoding arrangement capable of steganographically encoding a digital signal onto information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Steganographic encode step <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may be based on a key K<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>&mdash;allowing the same basic steganographic encoding and decoding transformations to be used by a wide variety of different appliances while still maintaining individuality and secrecy through the use of different steganographic keys. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> In one example, the steganographic encoding step <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may introduce the (encrypted) digital control information into the high frequency spectrum portion of the spectrally transformed information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The spectrally transformed signal with steganographic encoding is shown in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> Graph A<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and is shown in more detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. As <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows, the steganographic encoding may affect the higher order frequency components of the spectrally transformed signal (see dotted perturbations in the fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh and eighth order components in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>). The steganographic encoding may add to and/or subtract from the amplitudes of these higher order components. The effect of introducing high frequency steganographically encoded signal components may be to mask the steganographic encoding within the random high frequency noise inherently provided within information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>&mdash;thereby providing substantial invisibility and substantial indelibility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> The amount of amplitude modification performed by steganographic encode step <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may be limited in this example to ensure that the resulting steganographically encoded signal does not exceed the available channel bandwidth. See, for example, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> J. Millen, &ldquo;Covert Channel Capacity,&rdquo; <highlight><italic>IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy </italic></highlight>(1987). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> R. Browne, &ldquo;An Entropy Conservation Law for Testing the Completeness of Covert Channel Analysis,&rdquo; <highlight><italic>Fairfax </italic></highlight>94, pp 270-281 (1994). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> Moskovitz et al., &ldquo;The Channel Capacity of a Certain Noisy Timing Channel,&rdquo;, <highlight><italic>IEEE Trans. on Information Theory v IT</italic></highlight>-38 no. 4, pp. 1330-43, (1992). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> Venkatraman, et al., &ldquo;Capacity Estimation and Auditability of Network Covert Channels,&rdquo;, <highlight><italic>Oakland </italic></highlight>95, pp. 186-298. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> The following equations show the relationship between total bandwidth, bandwidth available for steganographic encoding, and the data rate of the steganographically encoded signal:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<math>
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mi>S</mi>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msubsup>
            <mo>&Integral;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>t</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>a</mi>
            </mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>t</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>b</mi>
            </mrow>
          </msubsup>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>B</mi>
              <mo>&af;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mi>t</mi>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&dd;</mo>
              <mi>t</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>&TildeFullEqual;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <munderover>
            <mo>&Sum;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mi>i</mi>
              <mo>=</mo>
              <mi>a</mi>
            </mrow>
            <mi>b</mi>
          </munderover>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mi>B</mi>
              <mo>&af;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mi>i</mi>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>&Delta;</mi>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>t</mi>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mn>1</mn>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>A</mi>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00001" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-M00001.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00001" wi="216.027" he="49.92435" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> where </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> &Dgr;t&equals;t<highlight><subscript>n&plus;I</subscript></highlight>&minus;t<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> B is a function of time in bits/second. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> In the above expressions, the function S corresponds to an area under a curve resulting from the product of B (bandwidth) and t (time). The parameter delta t refers to the &ldquo;granularity&rdquo; of the analog-to-digital conversion (i.e., 1/sampling rate). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows an example plot of information signal bandwidth versus time. The total bandwidth available is limited by the bandwidth of the transmission channel&mdash;including the bandwidth of the storage medium (if any) used to deliver the signal, and the bandwidth of the reproduction equipment. Since the total bandwidth depends on the inherent characteristics of the transmission channel used to communicate information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, it is typically a fixed constant. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows that the bandwidth actually used by the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> typically varies with time. For example, although somewhat counterintuitive, the more complex an image, the more noise is typically available for &ldquo;shuffling around&rdquo; to create a steganographic channel. Of course, this isn&apos;t always true&mdash;a highly intricate geometric pattern may have very little noise available for encoding, and a simple picture of a cloud may have a great deal of noise available. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> Steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> can use an encoding rate and characteristic that ensures the steganographically encoded signal bandwidth doesn&apos;t exceed the total bandwidth available in the communication channel. Typically, the amount of bandwidth available for steganographic encoding may be on the order of on the average of 0.1% of the total transmission channel bandwidth&mdash;but as mentioned above, this bandwidth available for steganographic encoding may be unequally distributed with respect to time within the information signal stream <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and may depend on the content of the information signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> In this example, steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> analyzes the content (e.g., by performing statistical weighted averaging), and provides a responsive variable steganographic encoding rate. For example, steganographic encoding block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> can use a high data rate during example time periods &ldquo;II&rdquo; and &ldquo;IV&rdquo; in which the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> has characteristics that allow high steganographic rate encoding without the resulting signal exceeding the available overall channel bandwidth. Encoding block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> can use a low data rate during time periods &ldquo;I&rdquo; and &ldquo;III&rdquo; in which the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> has characteristics that do not allow high data rate steganographic encoding without exceeding available overall channel bandwidth. Steganographic encoding block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may use any number of different variable rates to accommodate different relationships between information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> characteristics and available channel bandwidth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, the steganographically encoded spectral information outputted by steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may be subjected to an inverse spectral transform <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>. Inverse spectral transform <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> in this example may perform the inverse of the transform performed by step <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>&mdash;outputting a version of the digitized time domain signal shown in Graph A<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> but now bearing the steganographically encoded information (Graph A<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). The digital control information steganographically encoded by block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may be substantially indelible and substantially invisible with respect to the Graph A<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> signal&mdash;that is, it may be very difficult to eliminate the steganographically encoded information and it may also be very difficult to discern it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> This signal may be further scrambled and/or encrypted (e.g., based on a scrambling and/or encryption key Key<highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>) before being converted to analog form (shown in Graph A<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) by a conventional digital-to-analog conversion block <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> (if necessary). Signal scrambling may be independent of steganographically encoded control information. For example, a good way to support existing devices is to not scramble the signal, and to use legislative means to ensure that each new device manufactured is equipped with rights management technology. Scrambling/encrypting of content, can be used to enforce use of rights management. If legislative means can enforce the use of rights management technology, encryption or scrambling of content may not be necessary (although a decision to provide cryptographic protection for the control information is independent of this factor and must be evaluated in light of protecting the rights management system). Rights holders can choose an enticement technique(s) based on their business model(s). The benefit of scrambling is that it provides technical means for enforcing rights management. The benefit of unscrambled content is support of hundreds of millions of devices in the installed base&mdash;with the promise that new devices (potentially including computers) will enforce the control information even though they don&apos;t &ldquo;have to&rdquo; from a technical perspective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> The resulting steganographically encoded information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may then be transmitted over an insecure communications channel. Digital-to-analog conversion step <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> may be omitted if a digital communications channel (e.g., an optical disk, a digital satellite link, etc.) is available to deliver the signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> shows an example inverse process for recovering digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> from the steganographically encoded information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. In this recovery example, the steganographically encoded analog signal is converted to a digitized signal (if necessary) by an analog-to-digital conversion step <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>&prime; and decrypted/descrambled (if necessary) by a decryption/descrambling block <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight>&prime; to yield a facsimile of the inverse spectral transform block <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> output shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference>. In this <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> example, the analog-to-digital conversion block <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>&prime; is the inverse operation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, block <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>, and the decrypt/descramble block <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight>&prime; is the inverse of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> scramble/encrypt block <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> The resulting digitized signal provided by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> block <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight>&prime; is spectrally transformed by step <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>&prime; (this may be the same spectral transform used in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, block <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>) to yield a steganographically encoded spectral signal A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Steganographic decode block <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> may perform the inverse operation of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> based on the same steganographic key Key<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>(if a key-based steganographic encoding/decoding transformation is used). The output of steganographic decode block <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> may be decrypted by block <highlight><bold>426</bold></highlight> (the inverse of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> encrypt block <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> based on key Key<highlight><subscript>s</subscript></highlight>) to provide recovered digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. The resulting control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> may be used for performing electronic rights management functions Required keys may be delivered in containers and/or using the key distribution techniques and device initialization approaches disclosed in Ginter et al., for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> Example Control Information Arrangements </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> In a further example shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 10</cross-reference>A, steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may encode control information organizational structures such as secure containers (see Ginter et al., FIGS. <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B and associated text) during times when the content bandwidth is low relative to the total available bandwidth (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> regions II and IV), and may not attempt to encode such organizational structures during times when the content bandwidth is high relative to the total available bandwidth (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, regions I, III). In this way, steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may maximize the total bandwidth use without causing the steganographically encoded signal to exceed available bandwidth. As an optimization for certain applications, steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may encode &ldquo;pointers&rdquo; or other directional information into the information signal <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> during times when the content is such that it doesn&apos;t allow high data rate steganographic encoding of organizational structures <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. Multiple pointers and multiple &ldquo;pointed to&rdquo; locations can also help provide redundancy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> This particular <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> example involving steganographic encoding of pointers <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> may be especially suited for content delivery or presentation on random access storage media such as optical disks. Using such random access media, a content handling device may be able to rapidly &ldquo;seek&rdquo; to the place where an organizational structure is stored at a higher recorded bandwidth and then read the organizational structure at this higher bandwidth (See <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference>). For these example arrangements, steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> in this example encodes, during periods when the content is such that it is not possible to steganographically encode organizational structures, pointers <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> that direct the content handling device to one or more places where the organizational structure appears in the content stream. In one example, pointers <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> might encode the location(s) on a storage medium (e.g., an optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>&mdash;see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference>) at which the closest organizational structure is stored. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> An optical disk player <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> with random access capability may &ldquo;seek&rdquo; to the place at which the closest organizational structure <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is stored on the disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, and rapidly read the organizational structure off of the disk in less time than might be required to read an organizational structure that steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> encodes at a lower data rate during times when the content bandwidth occupies most of the available channel bandwidth. In such arrangements, the process of reading a pointer <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight>, &ldquo;seeking&rdquo; to a position on the medium specified by the pointer, and then reading an organization structure <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> steganographically encoded at a high data rate may provide overall faster access times than if the organizational structure was itself encoded at a lower data rate within the parts of the information signal stream used in this example to encode only pointers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows an example organizational structure <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> suitable for steganographic encoding similar to that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> of the co-pending Ginter et al. application. In the case of container <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> with controls for an analog property, the organizational structure may include one or more permissions records <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>providing control sets <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>providing electronic controls especially for an analog device(s). The permissions record <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>may also provide a reference <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>at least one location or other external source for additional controls. This reference may be to an Internet &ldquo;Uniform Resource Locator&rdquo; (URL), for example. The organizational structure <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> may optionally include a content block <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>g </italic></highlight>providing digital content subject to the controls. In this example, organizational structure <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is encased in a protective &ldquo;wrapper&rdquo; <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>x </italic></highlight>provided by the steganographic technique used to encode the organizational structure <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, digital encryption techniques, and/or a combination of the steganography and encryption. This protective wrapper <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>x </italic></highlight>is used to ensure that the organizational structure <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> cannot be tampered with and maintains its integrity. Wrapper <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>x </italic></highlight>may also provide a degree of confidentiality if required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> Detailed Example Electronic Appliance Architecture </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> shows an example detailed internal architecture for an example electronic appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> such as optical disk player <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. In this specific example, rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> may be a tamper-resistant integrated circuit including internal microprocessor <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, flash memory <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and cryptographic engine <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> (see Ginter et al. FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>B and associated text for a more detailed internal view of an example tamper-resistant rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and a &ldquo;protected processing environment&rdquo; <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> it provides). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> A main system bus <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> may couple rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> to a main system microprocessor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and various system components such as, for example, a CD-ROM decoder <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, a control and audio block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, a video decoder <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, a digital output protection block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, and a communications system <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. In this example, main microprocessor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> controls the overall operations of appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, with rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> performing security-related functions such as rights management and steganographic decoding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> In the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> example appliance <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, an optical pickup <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> reads information from optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and provides it to RF amplifier <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. RF amplifier <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> provides its output to digital signal processor (DSP) <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, which processes the output in a conventional manner and also controls the orientation of the optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> relative to optical pickup <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> via a driver <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. DSP <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> coordinates with a conventional CD-ROM decoder <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to provide decoded digitized video and audio information. Decoder <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> operates in conjunction with a buffer memory <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>, and may also cooperate with cryptographic engine <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> to ensure that any encrypted video information is decrypted appropriately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> The video output of CD-ROM decoder <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may be decompressed by MPEG-2 video decoder <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and applied via an NTSC and/or PAL encoder <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. (In another example, the output could be in a non-interlaced format such as RGB rather than in interlaced formats such as NTSC and PAL.) Meanwhile, control and audio block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> (which may operate in conjunction with its own buffer memory <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>) may receive digitized audio information recorded on optical disk <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> via DSP <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> and CD-ROM decoder <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. Control and audio block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may provide this audio output to audio processing block <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> for output to loudspeakers <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Control and audio block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may also provide an interface to the user via an infrared sensor <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> (for a remote control, for example), front-panel user controls <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> and/or an LED display <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0171" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0171&rsqb;</number> In this example, security microprocessor <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> within rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> receives the digitized video and/or audio that DSP <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> reads from optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> via pickup <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and RF amp <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. Security microprocessor <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> steganographically decodes this digitized analog information signal to recover the digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> encoded onto the information signal. Security microprocessor <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> also performs rights management functions based on the digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> it recovers. In addition, if desired security microprocessor may remove the steganographic encoding from a received digitized analog signal (since it shares a secret such as the steganographic encoding key Key<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>with the steganographic encoding point, it can remove the steganographic encoding) and/or steganographically encode a signal with received, augmented and/or new rights management control information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0172" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0172&rsqb;</number> In this example, microprocessor <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may selectively control cryptography engine <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> to decrypt encrypted content provided by optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>&mdash;thus enforcing the rights management activities provided in accordance with electronic controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Security component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> may also control digital output protection block <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> in accordance with rights management control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>&mdash;thus, selectively permitting digital appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to output content in digital form. Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> may take other steps (e.g., watermarking and/or fingerprinting information before releasing it) to provide a degree of copy protection and/or quality degradation to prevent or discourage someone from creating an unlimited number of high quality copies of the content of optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Rules contained in the control information can also govern how other parts of the system behave. For example, the control information could specify that no sound can be played unless the content is paid for. Another property may specify that certain copy protection schemes should be turned on in the NTSC encoder. Still another might disable the digital outputs of the device altogether, or unless an additional fee is paid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0173" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0173&rsqb;</number> Rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> (protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>) may, in this particular example, communicate over a network <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> (such as, for example, the Internet or other data communications path) with other rights management related entities, such as, for example, clearinghouses and repositories. This &ldquo;back channel&rdquo; allows rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> to, for example, report usage and payment information and/or to retrieve additional rights management control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to augment or supplement the control information it steganographically decodes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0174" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0174&rsqb;</number> Example Control Steps </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0175" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0175&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> shows example control steps that may be performed by protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> (e.g., security microprocessor <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>) to provide electronic digital rights protection. The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> read/play routine <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> begins with protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> applying rules <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>&mdash;in effect, setting the initial state in which rights management can occur (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>). Protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> then reads the output of CD-ROM decoder <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>) and obtains steganographically encoded data from the output stream (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>). If protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> encounters the beginning of the control information organizational structure (&ldquo;yes&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>), the protected processing environment performs an initialization step (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>) to begin receiving new control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and then returns to block <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> to again apply current control information (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>). If, on the other hand, protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> encounters a continuation of an organizational structure (&ldquo;yes&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>), the protected processing environment stores the organizational structure information it has received (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>) and turns again to the apply rules step (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0176" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0176&rsqb;</number> If protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> encounters a pointer (&ldquo;yes&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>), then the protected processing environment determines whether it already has received the corresponding organizational structure pointed to by the received pointer (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, decision block <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>). The protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> retrieves the organizational structure if it does not already have it (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>)&mdash;for example, by controlling DSP <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> to seek to the corresponding location on optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> indicated by the pointer, and by reading the organizational structure from the disk beginning at that disk location (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0177" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0177&rsqb;</number> If protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> has received no organizational structures or pointers (&ldquo;no&rdquo; exits to each of decision blocks <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>), then the protected processing environment may determine whether there is any bandwidth available to carry control information. For example, some types of content stored on optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may take up substantially all available channel bandwidths so that no bandwidth remains for steganographic encoding. If there is no available bandwidth for steganographic encoding (&ldquo;no&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>), then the protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> may return to the &ldquo;apply rules&rdquo; block <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and repeat steps <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> to wait until bandwidth is available for steganographic encoding. On the other hand, if there is bandwidth available and still no steganographically encoded information has appeared (&ldquo;yes&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>), protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> performs an error handling routine that processes the exception (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, block <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>) and determines whether the exception is critical (decision block <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>). In some cases, protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> will continue to allow the appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to process the content, finding the error to be non-critical (&ldquo;no&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>). An example of this would be a timer that permits playing for a period of time. In other cases (e.g., if the error conditions indicate that optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> has been tampered with), protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> may halt processing and return an error condition (&ldquo;yes&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>, bubble <highlight><bold>329</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0178" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0178&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</cross-reference> shows example steps that may be performed by the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> &ldquo;apply rules&rdquo; routine <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. In this example, protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> may determine if it has received a complete organizational structure on which to base rights management for the rights being read from optical disk <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, decision block <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>). If the protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> has not received a complete organizational structure (&ldquo;no&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>), it may disable content processing until it receives a complete organizational structure (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, block <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>). If protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> has a complete organizational structure (&ldquo;yes&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>), it determines whether it has the current organizational structure (decision block <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>). If the current organizational structure is present (&ldquo;yes&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>), the protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> then processes the current operation with respect to the control information embodied in the organizational structure (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, block <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>). If the protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> does not have the current organizational structure (&ldquo;no&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>), it determines whether it has an organizational structure that has the same identification as the current organizational structure (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, decision block <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>). The protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> may use that matching organizational structure as a default (&ldquo;yes&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>, block <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>). Otherwise, protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> disables content operations until it receives a current organizational structure (&ldquo;no&rdquo; exit to decision block <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>, block <highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0179" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0179&rsqb;</number> As mentioned above, protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> may also perform any or all of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> steganographic encoding steps, and may also or alternatively remove the steganographic encoding from a signal by using a shared secret to generate a steganographic encoding stream and then subtracting that stream from the signal. Such techniques may be useful, for example, to allow protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> to encode new control information or to change the encoded control information. For example, the steganographically encoded control information might provide a chain of handling and control that authorizes certain protected processing environments to change some elements and add new elements to the control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Protected processing environment <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> could: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0180" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0180&rsqb;</number> steganographically decode the signal using shared secrets to obtain the control information; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0181" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0181&rsqb;</number> modify the control information to the extent authorized by the control information; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0182" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0182&rsqb;</number> remove the steganographic encoding from the signal based on the shared secret; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0183" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0183&rsqb;</number> steganographically encode the signal with the modified control information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0184" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0184&rsqb;</number> Example Refresh Capability </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0185" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0185&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> shows another example electronic appliance arrangement including a &ldquo;refresh&rdquo; capability involving both steganographic decoding and steganographic encoding. In this example, electronic appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a steganographic decoding block <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> as described above plus an additional steganographic encoding block <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>. The appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may obtain the digital control information from the content signal, and then may &ldquo;refresh&rdquo; the extracted information (e.g., using coding techniques, such as, for example, Reed-Solomon decoding based on Reed-Solomon codes applied to the signal by the steganographic encoding process) to correct errors and otherwise accurately recover the digital control information. The error-corrected digital control information outputted by refresh decoder <highlight><bold>900</bold></highlight> may be applied to a steganographic encoding circuit <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> which steganographically encodes the content signal with the refreshed control information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0186" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0186&rsqb;</number> The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> refresh operation could, for example, be performed on a selective basis based on the encoded digital control information itself. For example, the control information might authorize appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to redistribute the content signal only under certain conditions&mdash;one of which is to ensure that a refreshed steganographic encoding of the same (or modified) digital control information is provided within the redistributed content signal. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0187" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0187&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15A</cross-reference> shows an example analog signal distribution arrangement <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> provided in accordance with this invention. Within arrangement <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, a steganographic encode block <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> encodes an analog information signal A with rights management control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and associated organizational structure(s) <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. The steganographically encoded information signal A&prime; is distributed by various mechanisms to user electronic appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. For example, the encoded signal A&prime; may be broadcast wirelessly over the air by a broadcaster <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>A, distributed over a cable television network by a cable television head end <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, and/or distributed via a satellite communications network <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. Encoded signal A&prime; may, during the process of being distributed, be converted from analog to digital form and back again. For example, the satellite uplink <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>A may digitize signal A&prime; before transmitting it to the satellite <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and the satellite downlink <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>may convert the signal back to analog before providing it to user appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. As explained above, the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> persists within the signal A&prime; despite conversions between analog and digital formats. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0188" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0188&rsqb;</number> In this example, an example set top box user appliance <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> may receive the distributed steganographically encoded analog signal A&prime;. Set top box <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> may include a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> as described above, and may perform rights management operations and/or processes in response to and based on steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0189" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0189&rsqb;</number> Set top box <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in this example may output the steganographically encoded analog signal (or a facsimile of it) to additional user electronic appliances such as, for example, a television set <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, a digital optical recording device (e.g., DVD-R) <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and/or a video tape recorder <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Each of these additional appliances <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may include a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> that performs electronic rights management based on the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Any recordings made by recording devices <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may also be steganographically encoded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0190" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0190&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15B</cross-reference> shows another example analog signal distribution arrangement <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. In this example, a radio broadcaster <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>B broadcasts an analog radio signal A&prime; that is steganographically encoded with associated rights management control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and associated organizational structure(s) <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. A wire network <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> such as a cable television system may similarly distribute the same or different steganographically encoded analog radio signal A&prime;. Broadcaster <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>B and/or network <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> may deliver the steganographically encoded radio signal A&prime; to a user receiving appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>C such as a FM radio receiver <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In this example, radio receiver <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> has a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> that processes and automatically manages rights based on steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. In this example, radio receiver <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may (if permitted by controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>) output steganographically encoded analog signal A&prime; to additional appliances such as, for example, a digital recorder <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and/or an analog recorder <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>. In this example, each of appliances <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>B has a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> that electronically manages rights based on the steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Because the steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> persist, recording devices <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> record the steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> in any recordings they make of signal A&prime;. In one non-limiting example, when rights control information is encoded in steganographic sound recordings that are broadcast via radio or some other method, an airplay audit service can sample stations in a given market and identify particular properties being broadcast from &ldquo;object identifier&rdquo; information contained in the steganographically encoded VDE container. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0191" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0191&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15C</cross-reference> shows an example signal distribution arrangement <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> in which the steganographically encoded analog signal A&prime; is initially distributed in the same manner as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>A, and is then converted by an electronic appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G such as a personal computer, for example, into a digital signal D. In this example, appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G includes a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> that manages rights based on steganographically encoded controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G may convert received analog signal A&prime; into digital form for distribution to and processing by digital appliances such as a digital high definition television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B, a digital optical disk recorder <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and/or a digital tape recorder <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. In one example, the steganographically encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> persists within the digitized signal D. In another example, appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G removes the steganographic encoding from received analog signal A&prime; and outputs a digital signal D that is &ldquo;clean&rdquo; and free of steganographic encoding&mdash;but is otherwise protected so that it remains persistently associated with the now-digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> (which appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G may distribute, for example, within secure electronic containers <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> and digital, encrypted form. In one specific example, appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G may package the received, digitized content from analog signal A&prime; within the same digital electronic container <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> that also contains associated control information that appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G steganographically decodes from analog signal A&prime;. In another specific example, appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G may distribute controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> independently of the digital signal D&mdash;but under circumstances in which the rights management components <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> within each of digital appliances <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>A all securely associate the control information with the now-digital content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0192" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0192&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15D</cross-reference> shows a similar distribution arrangement <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> for analog radio or other audio signals. In this example, appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G may include a digital radio receiver that receives analog radio signal A&prime; and converts it into a digital information signal for distribution to digital recorders <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>A. As discussed above, appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G may distribute the digitized analog signal A&prime; with steganographic encoding to appliances <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>A&mdash;each of which includes a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> that may recover the steganographically-encoded control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and perform rights management functions based thereon. In another particular example, appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G may remove the steganographic encoding from the content before distributing it in digital form&mdash;and user other techniques (such as those described in the above-referenced Ginter et al. patent specification) to provide a secure association between the now-digital content and the digital control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0193" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0193&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15E</cross-reference> shows yet another example distribution arrangement <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> in which digital appliances <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G distribute information in digital form to a digital television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B. For example, appliance <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may provide digital video signals D to digital television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B by playing them back form DVD <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. DVD player <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may provide controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> within electronic digital containers <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> to digital television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B. Digital television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B may include a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>C that manages rights in the digital content based on digitally-provided control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Similarly, computer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G may receive digital content and associated control information <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> from a digital network <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, and provide digital video signals D and associated controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to digital television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0194" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0194&rsqb;</number> In this example, digital television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B includes an analog output that may provide analog television signals to additional devices, such as, for example, an analog video cassette recorder <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. In this example, the rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>C within digital television <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>B may steganographically encode the analog television signal A with controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and associated organizational structure(s) <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> before releasing the analog signal to the outside world. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0195" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0195&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15F</cross-reference> shows a further example arrangement <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> in which a digital appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G such as a personal computer receives digital video signal D and converts it into various analog television signal formats (e.g., NTSC/PAL and/or RGB) for output to analog devices such as an analog VCR <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, an analog set top box <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and/or an analog television set <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A. In this example, a rights management component <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>G within digital appliance <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>G steganographically encodes the received digital controls <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> onto the analog signal A&prime;, A&Prime; before releasing the analog signal to the additional appliances <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0196" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0196&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in connection with what is presently considered to be the most practical and preferred embodiment, it is to be understood that the invention is not to be limited to the disclosed embodiment, but on the contrary, is intended to cover various modifications and equivalent arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A rights management method comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) receiving an information signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) steganographically decoding the received information signal to recover digital rights management control information; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) performing at least one rights management operation based at least in part on the recovered digital rights management control information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein receiving step (a) comprises receiving an analog signal steganographically encoded with the digital rights management control information, and decoding step (b) comprises steganographically decoding the analog signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein performing step (c) comprises the step of selectively enabling descrambling of the information signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein performing step (c) comprises the step of selectively enabling decrypting of the information signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein decoding step (b) comprises recovering digital rights management control information packaged within at least one digital container, and performing step (c) comprises performing the rights management operation based at least in part on the recovered digital rights management control information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the decoding step (b) includes the step of steganographically decoding information representing at least one permissions record. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further including the step of decrypting contents of the digital container for use in performing step (c). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the information signal carries further information in addition to the steganographically encoded information, and the performing step (b) comprises the step of managing at least one right in respect of the further information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the decoding step (b) includes the step of analyzing the information signal using a spectral transform. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the decoding step (b) includes the step of analyzing the information signal using a key-based steganographic decoder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the decoding step (b) includes the step of steganographically decoding a pointer that points to another portion of the information signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the steganographically encoded container includes at least one organization structure, and the decoding step (b) comprises steganographically decoding the organizational structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A rights management method comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) receiving an information signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) steganographically decoding the received information signal to recover at least one rights management permission; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) performing at least one rights management operation based at least in part on the recovered rights management permission. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A virtual distribution environment comprising: 
<claim-text>plural tamper-resistant protected processing environments coupled together via at least one communications path; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for delivering, to the plural tamper-resistant protected processing environments, an information signal having at least one digital rights management control set substantially invisibly and substantially indelibly encoded thereon. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An electronic appliance comprising: 
<claim-text>decoding means for steganographically decoding a signal to provide control information; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>rights management means coupled to the decoding means for performing at least one rights management operation based at least in part on the control information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management means includes means for means for selectively blocking the signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management means includes means for selectively descrambling the signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management means includes means for authenticating a further appliance before delivering the signal to said further appliance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management means includes means for requiring that a further appliance present an appropriate digital certificate before delivering the signal to said further appliance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the right management means includes means for fingerprinting the signal based at least in part on the control information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the right management means includes means for further steganographically encoding the signal based at least in part on the control information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An electronic appliance comprising: 
<claim-text>a steganographic decoder that steganographically decode a signal to provide control information; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>rights management component coupled to the decoder, the rights management component performing at least one rights management operation based at least in part on the control information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management component includes or controls a signal blocking circuit that selectively blocks the signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management component includes or controls a signal descrambler. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management component includes an authenticating circuit for authenticating a further appliance before delivering the signal to said further appliance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management component includes a circuit for requiring that a further appliance present an appropriate digital certificate before delivering the signal to said further appliance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management component includes a circuit for fingerprinting the signal based at least in part on the control information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. An appliance as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rights management component includes a circuit for further steganographically encoding the signal based at least in part on the control information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method of steganographically encoding a signal comprising: 
<claim-text>providing at least one organization structure including control information; </claim-text>
<claim-text>selectively encrypting at least a part of the organizational structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>frequency transforming an input signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>encoding the input signal with the selectively encrypted organizational structure in such a way so as to make the encoded organizational structure substantially indelible and substantially invisible; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>delivering the encoded input signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00019">
<image id="EMI-D00019" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00020">
<image id="EMI-D00020" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00021">
<image id="EMI-D00021" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00022">
<image id="EMI-D00022" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00023">
<image id="EMI-D00023" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00024">
<image id="EMI-D00024" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00025">
<image id="EMI-D00025" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00026">
<image id="EMI-D00026" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00027">
<image id="EMI-D00027" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00027.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00028">
<image id="EMI-D00028" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00028.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00029">
<image id="EMI-D00029" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00029.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00030">
<image id="EMI-D00030" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00030.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00031">
<image id="EMI-D00031" file="US20030002673A1-20030102-D00031.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
