<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002089A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002089A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002089</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10133538</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020425</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04N001/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>358</class>
<subclass>474000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Automated scanning system and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60288905</doc-number>
<document-date>20010504</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Timothy</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Vadnais</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Victoria</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Marshall</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Savage</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MERCHANT &amp; GOULD PC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 2903</address-1>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402-0903</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system and method for mass, automated scanning of objects, including dental study casts, housing parts, and other objects. The system and method are able to function with little or no human operator intervention, thereby facilitating high volume scanning and reducing scanning costs. The system includes a scanner having a scanning table, a conveyor mechanism adjacent the scanner for delivering objects to be scanned to the scanner, and a pick and place mechanism for taking an object from the conveyor mechanism and mounting it onto the scanning table of the scanner. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority from provisional application Serial No. 60/288,905, filed May 4, 2001, and which is incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to scanning of objects. More particularly, the invention relates to mass automated scanning of objects, such as dental study casts, housings for electronic devices including cellular telephones and electronic organizers, and other objects. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Scanning of three-dimensional objects is generally known from the prior art. As disclosed in commonly assigned U.S. Pat. No. 6,217,334, dental study casts are scanned, and the data obtained from scanning the study casts is used for a variety of purposes, such as displaying a three-dimensional image of the static bite relationship of a particular patient for diagnostic and teaching purposes, or creating similar study casts in a suitable fabrication device based upon the scan data. Using the teachings from U.S. Pat. No. 6,217,34, individual objects can also be scanned for displaying a three-dimensional image of the objects or for use in fabricating similar objects based upon the scan data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Scanning can also be used to verify a mating relationship between mating housing parts, such as housing parts for electronic devices including cellular telephones and electronic organizers. When housing parts are scanned, the scan data can be used to display three-dimensional images of the parts, with the displayed images being electronically brought together and displayed as a three-dimensional image, from which the accuracy of the fit between the housing parts can be determined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Although scanning of objects is previously known, extensive human operator interaction is typically required in conventional scanning processes to monitor the process. For example, an operator typically must be present to load as well as unload the object(s) to be scanned onto and from the scanner. The need for human interaction in the scanning process creates problems. If the object is not loaded properly onto the scanner by the operator, inaccurate scan data can result. Further, the presence of an operator adds a labor cost to the scanning process, thereby increasing overall costs. Costs are increased even further if scanning is to be performed 24 hours a day, which is necessary for scanning large numbers of objects. In this case, additional employees must be hired for second and third shifts in order to operate and monitor the scanner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Therefore, there is a need for an automated scanning system and method which reduces or eliminates the need for operator interaction, thereby facilitating mass scanning operations, improving the accuracy of the scan data and reducing the costs associated with the scanning operation. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a system and method for mass, automated scanning of objects, including dental study casts, housing parts, and other objects. The system and method are able to function with little or no human operator intervention, thereby facilitating high volume, automated scanning and reducing scanning costs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In one aspect of the invention, a scanning system is provided. The system comprises a scanner having a scanning table, a conveyor mechanism adjacent the scanner for delivering an object to be scanned to the scanner, and a pick and place mechanism for taking the object from the conveyor mechanism and mounting it on the scanning table of the scanner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In yet another aspect of the invention, a method of scanning of objects by a scanner having a scanning table is provided. The method comprises conveying one or more objects to be scanned to the scanner using a conveyor mechanism; picking an object from the conveyor mechanism and mounting the object on the scanning table of the scanner; scanning the object; and removing the scanned object from the scanning table and delivering the scanned object to a discharge location. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In still another aspect of the invention, a system for mass, automated scanning of dental study casts is provided. The system comprises a scanner having a scanning table, and a plurality of cassettes, each of which has a maxilla and mandible study cast for a single patient mounted thereon in known positions relative to each another. The system also includes a conveyor adjacent the scanner for delivering the cassettes to the scanner; and a pick and place mechanism engageable with the cassettes for picking one of the cassettes from the conveyor and mounting the picked cassette on the scanning table. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> These and various other advantages and features of novelty which characterize the invention are pointed out with particularity in the claims annexed hereto and forming a part hereof. However, for a better understanding of the invention, its advantages and objects obtained by its use, reference should be made to the drawings which form a further part hereof, and to the accompanying description, in which there is described a preferred embodiment of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Referring to the drawings, wherein like numerals represent like parts throughout the several views: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates the method steps used to practice the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> diagrammatically illustrates functional blocks associated with the scanning process and processing data from the scanner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an automated scanning system according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a portion of the scanner and the infeed conveyor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the rotary table of the scanner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary tool used to implement the automated scanning system and method according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a cassette used with the tool of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a calibration procedure for determining reference points. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> schematically illustrates the use of the tool and cassette in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> schematically illustrates a pair of housing shells that can be scanned in order to verify their mating relationship.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> A detailed discussion of a preferred embodiment of the automated scanning system and method of the present invention will be deferred pending a discussion of the concepts of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> 1. Overview </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the overall method of the present invention is illustrated, and is designated generally by the numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. First, at block <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the object(s) to be scanned is fixedly mounted onto a cassette. Any object(s) which one finds desirable to scan can be mounted onto the cassette. Examples of suitable objects include dental study casts and mating housing parts for electronic devices such as cell phones and electronic organizers. The preferred embodiment will be described below with respect to scanning dental study casts. The cassette and the procedure for mounting dental study casts on the cassette are described below with respect to FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> At block <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the cassette is transported to the scanner by a suitable transport mechanism, and at block <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the cassette is picked from the transport by a picking mechanism and placed onto a table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of a scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The transport mechanism and picking mechanism are described below and best seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Once the cassette is properly mounted, the object(s) is then scanned at block <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. In the preferred embodiment described below, two dental study casts are mounted on the cassette and the data obtained from scanning the study casts is used to create and display study cast images. The scan data can also be used to fabricate replicas of the study casts in a fabrication device based upon the scan data. In the preferred embodiment, the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is a laser scanner with a laser <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> that is capable of movements along x-y-z axes to permit scanning of the complex geometries of dental study casts. However, other scanning concepts can also be used to practice the system and methods described herein, such as digitizing scanning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Next, at block <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, once the scan of the object(s) is complete, the cassette is removed from the scanner by the picking mechanism and placed onto a transport for subsequent transport away from the scanner. As described in the preferred embodiment below, the transport that conveys a scanned object(s) away from the scanner is preferably a transport mechanism that is separate from the transport mechanism that conveys the object(s) to the scanner. However, a single transport mechanism could be used to both convey the object(s) to and away from the scanner. It is also contemplated that instead of conveying the cassette away from the scanner after scanning, the cassette could be placed in a suitable discharge location for later removal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the image data obtained from the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is processed by processor <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> of a computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> to create the image(s) of the scanned object(s), which in the preferred embodiment is the dental study casts. The processing by the processor <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> may include converting the scan data into images for display on a video display unit <highlight><bold>503</bold></highlight>; converting the scan data into CNC or other format of output for use by a fabrication device <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight> (also known as a prototyping apparatus); storing the scan data in a memory location or device <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>; and/or transmitting the scan data to a remote processor <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> via modem block <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. A user input device <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> permits input commands to control operation of the scanner, as well as permits the input of information concerning the object(s) to be scanned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated by those of skill in the art that the computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> may be a personal computer (e.g., a Pentium based PC) or a special purpose computer. Further, the video display unit <highlight><bold>503</bold></highlight> may include any number of display devices such as cathode ray tubes, LCD displays, etc. Still further, the memory device <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> may include hard drives, floppy drives, magnetic tape, CD-ROM, random access memory, and readonly memory devices. Further, the modem <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is illustrated to show a communications capability. Such capability may also be by way of a network, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Fabrication device <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight> may be connected directly to the computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> or may be connected to the remote computer <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>. The fabrication device <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight> may be any number of devices which can utilize computer generated data and create a threedimensional object from such data. One example of such a machine are the devices utilizing stereo lithography technology manufactured by 3-D Systems of Valencia, Calif. under the model designations SLA-250 and SLA-500. Another example is the device utilizing filament technology (fused deposition modeling) manufactured by Statasys Corporation of Minneapolis, Minn. under the model designation FDM1500. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Further details on scanning, in the preferred embodiment, dental study casts and processing the image data can be found in U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,217,334, 6,206,693, and 6,200,135, which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> 2. Automated Scanning </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiment will now be discussed. In the preferred embodiment, a pair of dental study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> are mounted onto a cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for scanning by the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> are three-dimensional models of a patient&apos;s maxilla (i.e. upper) and mandible (i.e. lower) sets of teeth, respectively. The specifics of creating dental study casts from impressions that are taken of a patient&apos;s teeth is well known in the art. See, for example, U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,217,334, 6,206,693, and 6,200,135. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Turning now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, a system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to achieve automated scanning of the study casts is illustrated. Prior to explaining the system in detail, some of the difficulties that are faced in implementing automated scanning will be discussed. An automated scanning system should be able to operate with minimal or no operator input. This reduces the costs associated with scanning, and increases throughput of the system because the system is able to run essentially all the time, day and night, with minimal operator input. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> One of the primary factors in being able to implement automated scanning of dental study casts is the ability to achieve an accurate bite registration of the images that result from the scanned upper and lower study casts. Without some basis by which the computer is able to properly register the scanned images of the upper and lower casts, an accurate visual representation of the bite registration cannot be achieved. Therefore, a suitable method for achieving bite registration is needed. A bite registration method that is suitable for use with the automated scanning system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is described later in this specification, as well as in copending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/746,468, filed on Dec. 22, 2000. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Returning now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the automated scanning system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes a scanning station <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> at which the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> are scanned by the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is preferably a laser scanner as discussed above. Alternatively, other scanning concepts can be used, such as a digitizing scanning. Regardless of the particular scanner that is utilized, the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is capable of scanning both the upper and lower casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>, with the scan data therefrom being processed by the computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> as discussed above. An operator input station <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is provided that preferably includes a controller, such as the computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, for controlling operation of the system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The station <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> also preferably includes the display unit <highlight><bold>503</bold></highlight> and input device <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> for displaying system information and allowing operator inputs, such as system operation commands and patient data for each pair of study casts to be scanned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> further includes a conveyor mechanism <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> for transporting the cassettes <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to and from the station <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The conveyor mechanism <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> includes an infeed conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> with a conveyor belt <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> upon which the cassettes <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> mounted thereon are placed for subsequent feeding to the station <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The conveyor mechanism <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> further includes an outfeed conveyor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> with a conveyor belt <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> that feeds the cassettes <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, after scanning, to a downstream location for subsequent handling. Alternatively, the outfeed conveyor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> could be eliminated, and the conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> extended past the station <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> so that the conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> acts both as the infeed conveyor and the outfeed conveyor. In addition, conveying mechanisms other than belts can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Each cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is picked by a pick and place mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, from the infeed conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and placed onto the table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> where it is fixed in place for scanning. After scanning, the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is removed from the table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by the pick and place mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and placed onto the outfeed conveyor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> for subsequent handling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> permits automated, mass scanning of dental study casts, as well as other objects. As long as the system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is able to correlate the scanned data from each pair of study casts with a particular patient, such as through operator input via the input station <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> or by system identification of patient identifying indicia on the cassettes <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> or study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>, the system is able to operate independently while performing its scanning and data collection functions, with little or no human operator interaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, it is seen that the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is mounted on a support structure <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, such as a table, located adjacent the conveyor mechanism <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. An L-shaped support arm <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extends upwardly from the support <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and towards the conveyor mechanism <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. A y-axis slide <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is fixed on top of the support <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, and a support <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> for the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is mounted on the y-axis slide <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> so as to movable along the y-axis. An actuator <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, such as a reversible electric motor, is mounted to the slide <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and is in driving engagement with the support <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> for actuating the support <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> along the y-axis. An actuator <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, such as a reversible electric motor, is also mounted to the support <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and is in driving engagement with the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for rotating the table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> about a central axis X-X. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> An x-axis slide <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is fixed to the overhanging portion of the support arm <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> to allow movement of the laser <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> along the x-axis. In addition, a z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is mounted to the x-axis slide <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to allow movement of the laser <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> along the z-axis. An actuator <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, such as a reversible electric motor, is mounted to the x-axis slide <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and is in driving engagement with the z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> for actuating the z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> along the x-axis. In addition, an actuator <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, such as a reversible electric motor, is mounted to the z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and is in driving engagement with a support arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> for actuating the support arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> along the z-axis. The support arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> forms part of the pick and place mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and supports the laser <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the laser <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is mounted for linear movements along the x-axis slide <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Further, the scanning table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is mounted for linear movement along the y-axis slide <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, as well as for rotary movement about the axis X-X. The entire surface area of the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> can thus be completely scanned through suitable movements of the laser <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> or the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> along the x-y-z axes and about the X-X axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the details of the pick and place mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> that is used to pick a cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> from the conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and place the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> on the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for scanning of the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is also used to remove the cassette from the rotary table and place it onto the conveyor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The laser <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is fixed to the support arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> of the pick and place mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> through a laser support <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, whereby the laser <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> moves up and down along the z-axis when the arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is actuated along the z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. In addition, a cassette engagement finger <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and a release finger <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are fixed to the arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> at locations spaced from each other as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The mechanism for fixedly mounting the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> onto the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> will now be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes a face plate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> on the top surface thereof. A stop <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, a pin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and a spring loaded lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> are all disposed on top of the face plate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> for interacting with the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and retaining the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> on the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The stop <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> includes a beveled surface <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (also seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) that is designed to engage a beveled edge <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The pin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is positioned to interact with a notch <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> that is formed in the side of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and counteract a rotational force that is applied to the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> by the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> includes a pivot post <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> that is pivotally mounted on the face plate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> directly opposite the stop <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The post <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is resiliently biased by a spring or other suitable resilient means in order to provide a force F in the direction of the arrow against the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> thereby forcing the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> against the stop <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the pin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. A tooling ball <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is fixed to the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> directly opposite the pin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, and engages a beveled edge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> on the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> When the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is disposed on the face plate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, the force provided by the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> pushes the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> against the stop <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the pin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Further, the engagement between the beveled surface <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the stop and the beveled edge <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, as well as between the tooling ball <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and the beveled edge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, create a downward force that presses the cassette downward against the face plate, firmly holding the cassette in place for subsequent scanning. The pin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, because it is located directly opposite the tooling ball <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, counteracts any tendency for the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to rotate about the stop <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> as a result of the force F applied by the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The procedure for picking a cassette from the conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and placing it onto the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> using the pick and place mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> will now be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. The cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is formed with a key hole slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> (shown in dashed lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) proximate the center thereof and extending generally parallel to the x-axis slide <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The cassette engagement finger <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> of the pick and place mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> includes a male tab <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> that has a shape that is complimentary to the slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The finger <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> further includes tab <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> that engages the exterior of the cassette when the male tab <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is within the slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. It is further evident from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> that the removal finger <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, which is intended to engage the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and remove the bias force F, projects a distance below the male tab <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> for a purpose which will become evident. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In order to pick a cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> from the conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, the z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is actuated along the x-axis (i.e. to the left in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) so that the finger <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is positioned over the slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is then actuated along the z-axis (i.e. downward in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) so that the male tab <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> enters the slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is then once again moved to the left to lock the male tab <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> in the slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, with the tab <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> engaging the exterior surface of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for stabilization purposes. The arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is then lifted upward, thereby lifting the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> off of the conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is then actuated to the right to bring the cassette to a position above the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is then lowered until the removal finger <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is next to the inside surface of the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, between the post <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and the tooling ball <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Then, by moving the z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> to the left, the finger <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> forces the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in the opposite direction about the post <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can then be lowered onto the face plate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by lowering the arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> further. Once the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is fully lowered, the z-axis slide <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is moved slightly to the right and the arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is then raised, thereby removing the male tab <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> from the slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. As this occurs, the finger <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> disengages from the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, and the biasing force F of the lever arm forces the cassette against the stop <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the pin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, thereby firmly retaining the cassette on the rotary table for subsequent scanning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Removal of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> from the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> after scanning occurs in a similar fashion to the mounting of the cassette. The finger <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> removes the force of the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> as the male tab <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is being locked into the slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. When the lever arm <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> has been moved sufficiently and the male tab <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is firmly secured in the slot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be moved slightly to the left and lifted upward, thereby removing the cassette. The cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is then carried to the conveyor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, or other suitable discharge location, for conveyance away from the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> It is to be realized that the x-axis slide <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> must be of sufficient dimensions so as to be able to reach the two conveyors <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. When side-by-side conveyors <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> are used, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the x-axis dimensions of the x-axis slide <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> are generally increased. For the case of a conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> that is used as both the infeed and the outfeed, the x-axis dimensions of the x-axis slide <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the arm <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> need not be as large. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As was described above, a suitable method for achieving an accurate bite registration of the images that result from the scanned study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> is needed. FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> illustrate one embodiment of how an accurate bite registration can be achieved. This method can be used with study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> that have roughly formed (i.e. not machined to precise geometric specifications) bases. In this method, the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> are initially mounted on the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in known locations relative to each other, prior to placement of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> onto the conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for conveyance to the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Because the positioning of each study cast relative to the other is known, once scanning is complete, the scanned images can be brought into registration using predetermined reference points. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> illustrate the tooling and other apparatus used to implement this method. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> that is provided with a precision vertical slide <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> that is mounted so as to move vertically up and down relative to the tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>. The tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> and a vertical support <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> provided with a guide rail <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. The slide <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> that is slidable on the rail <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> and an arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> that overhangs the base <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. The arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> includes a pair of locating holes <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> on the bottom surface of the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> facing the base <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. In addition, the base <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> includes a pair of locating pins <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> upon which the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> are to be mounted. The study cast <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> is schematically illustrated in position on the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a ridge <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> that separates the cassette into two halves, the first half receiving the study cast <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and the second half receiving the study cast <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. A removable plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>, upon which the study cast <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is to be mounted, is provided on the second half of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. A pair of locating holes <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>&prime; are formed in the bottom of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> which interact with the locating pins <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>, respectively, so as to permit mounting of the cassette onto the base <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> of the tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>. In addition, the removable plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> includes a pair of locating pins <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>&prime; formed on the bottom thereof that are designed to fit within the locating holes <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>, respectively, on the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> of the slide <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>. The second half of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes holes (not visible) that receive the locating pins <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>&prime; when the plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> is disposed on the cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, in implementing this method, the study cast <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> is first fixed onto the first half of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> such as by using hot melt glue or other suitable temporary fastening means. The cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is then mounted onto the base <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> of the tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> via the locating pins <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> and locating holes <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>&prime;, with the study cast <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> disposed underneath the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> of the slide <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> A wax wafer <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>, or other similar impression material, which has been previously bit into by the patient corresponding to the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> to record the patient&apos;s bite registration, is then placed onto the study cast <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The wafer <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> is placed onto the study cast so that the impression that corresponds to study cast <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> fits onto the teeth of the cast <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The study cast <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is then placed on top of the wafer <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> with the teeth fitting into their corresponding impressions in the wafer. It should be realized that the wafer <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> permits the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> to be registered with each other while on the tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>. Once the study casts are registered, the plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> is fixed onto the bottom surface of the study cast <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> such as by using hot melt glue or other fixing means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The slide <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> is then slid downward, either manually using a knob <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> fixed to the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> or through suitable mechanical means (not illustrated), toward the plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>. The arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> then captures the plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>, with the locating pins <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>&prime; fitting into the locating holes <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>. A fastener <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight> connected to the plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> extends upwardly through a hole provided in the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> to permit the plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>, and the study cast <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> now fixed thereto, to be fixed to the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> so when the slide <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> is again raised, the study cast <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> and plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> are raised with the slide <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>. Raising the slide <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> separates the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> while precisely maintaining the relative positioning of the study casts so that the registration is maintained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> After the slide <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> is raised, the plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>, with the study cast <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> fixed thereto, is removed from the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight>, flipped over so that the study cast <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> faces upward, and mounted onto the second half of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> so that both study casts are now fixed on the cassette. The cassette can then be placed onto the conveyor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for transport to the scanner so that the study casts can be scanned to create scanned images. It should be realized that the study casts are mounted on the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in positions that maintain the bite registration of the patient. However, what is also needed are reference points so that the images resulting from the scan can be aligned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Reference points are used in this method to achieve alignment, with the reference points being determined in accordance with a calibration process illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The calibration process is performed prior to mounting the study casts on the cassette. To perform calibration, the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is provided with a removable plate <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight>, in place of the plate <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>. The plate <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of tooling balls <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> thereon. In the preferred embodiment, three tooling balls <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> are used, however a larger number of tooling balls could also be used. A layer of clay <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> or other impression material is placed on the other half of the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is then mounted on the tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> as discussed above, with the clay <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> located underneath the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight>, and the plate <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> is mounted on the arm <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> with the tooling balls <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> facing downward toward the clay <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight>. The slide <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> is then moved downward until the balls <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> move into the clay <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> in order to form tooling ball impressions <highlight><bold>296</bold></highlight>. The slide <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> is then moved upwardly and the plate <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> removed therefrom and remounted onto the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is then mounted onto the rotary table <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the scanner <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, as discussed above, and the scanner scans the tooling balls <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> and the impressions <highlight><bold>296</bold></highlight>. Mounting of the cassette can be done using the pick and place mechanism <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, or manually. By scanning the tooling balls <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> and impressions <highlight><bold>296</bold></highlight>, the computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> can find the centers of the balls <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> and impressions <highlight><bold>296</bold></highlight>, with the centers providing fixed reference points for use in aligning subsequently scanned study casts. These fixed reference points are retained within the memory device <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>, so that the computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> knows ahead of time the reference points to be used. Due to the construction of the tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the relative positions of the centers of the tooling balls <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> and the centers of the impressions <highlight><bold>296</bold></highlight> correspond to identical positions on the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. Therefore, once the images of the study casts are generated, the three fixed points can be aligned to register the scanned impressions. After the points are aligned, the scanned images can be brought together by the computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> to a position representative of the patient&apos;s actual bite registration. The reference points are fixed in system memory, so that once the study casts are properly positioned on the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the scanning and registration can be completed automatically by the computer <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, without requiring further operator input. It is further contemplated that the use of the tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and the related process of positioning the study casts on the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be automated as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Periodically, the calibration process should be repeated so as to obtain updated reference points. This is necessary due to loosening of tolerances and general degradation of equipment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As part of the automation of scanning, the system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> needs to know which of the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> being scanned belong to which patient, so that the scan data can be saved to the appropriate memory location belonging to that patient in the memory device <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. To accomplish this objective, the cassette <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be provided with a patient identification tag <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, such as a radio frequency tag, a bar code or other suitable means. The tag <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> can contain patient data such as the patient&apos;s name and address, as well as more extensive patient data pertaining to the patient&apos;s past medical history, such as previous dental procedures. A sensor <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> is provided at a suitable location, such as on the support <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, to read the tag <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The sensor <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, as is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, is connected to the central processor <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> of the computer so that the information that is read from the tag <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is provided to the computer. The sensor <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> can be located at any convenient point in the system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, such as on the tool <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. However, it is preferred that the sensor <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> be positioned at a location so that it performs a read of the tag <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> just prior to, or immediately after, scanning of the study casts <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiment of the invention has been described in relation to automated scanning of dental study casts. However, as discussed above, the concepts described herein can also be used in implementing automated scanning of a variety of other objects as well. For instance, automated scanning can be applied to parts that are to be mated together, such as molded housing shells for cellular phones, electronic organizers, pacemakers, and a host of other parts having complex geometries. When applied to mated parts, the accuracy of the parts, and the molds used to create the parts, can be verified by scanning the parts and determining from the scanned images whether a suitable fit between the parts will be achieved. This verification can be performed at the manufacturing level by the supplier of the molded parts as the molded parts are molded, or at an assembly level by the user of the molded parts to ensure the quality of received parts. Molded parts can include plastic molded parts, metal parts formed by metal molding techniques, and mating parts formed from other materials and other molding techniques suitable for those other materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates a pair of housing shells <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> that are to be mated together to form a housing for a device such as a cellular phone, electronic organizer or a pacemaker. The inside of each housing shell <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is schematically illustrated to show an example of the possible complex geometry inside each shell. In use, the shell <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is flipped over and mated with the shell <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> to enclose the electronics and other components of the device formed by the mated shells <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. The shells <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> can be scanned and images created from the scan data in order to display the mating relationship (i.e. &ldquo;verify&rdquo; the parts) to determine whether the shells fit together adequately. A plurality of reference points would have to be used to achieve alignment of the shell images once they are scanned. For instance, three points R, S, T on the shell <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, and three points R&prime;, S&prime;, T&prime; on the shell <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, corresponding to, for example, mounting posts on the shells <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, could be used to align the images once the shells are scanned. The method described above for registering the dental study casts could also be used to register the shells <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> In addition, automated scanning can be applied to single objects that are not mated or fitted with a corresponding object. For instance, single objects can be scanned for subsequent display of an image of the object created from the scan data, or the scan data can be used to fabricate a replica of the object based upon the scan data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> While a particular embodiment of the invention has been described, it will be understood that by those skilled in the art that the invention is not limited by the application, embodiment or the particular devices disclosed and described herein. It will be appreciated that other devices that embody the principles of this invention and other applications therefor other than as described herein can be configured within the spirit and intent of this invention. The system described herein is provided as only one example of an embodiment that incorporates and practices the principles of this invention. Other modifications and alterations are well within the knowledge of those skilled in the art and are to be included within the broad scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The above specification, examples and data provide a complete description of the manufacture and use of the composition of the invention. Since many embodiments of the invention can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention, the invention resides in the claims hereinafter appended. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A scanning system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a scanner; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveyor mechanism adjacent said scanner for delivering an object to be scanned to said scanner; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pick and place mechanism for taking an object from said conveyor mechanism and mounting it on said scanner. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said scanner is a laser scanner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said laser scanner is mounted for movement along at least two mutually perpendicular axes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein scanner includes a scanning table that is mounted for movement along an axis perpendicular to said two mutually perpendicular axes, and wherein said scanning table is rotatable. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said conveyor mechanism includes an infeed conveyor and an outfeed conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a cassette upon which the object to be scanned is mounted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, further including an identification tag fixed to said cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said identification tag includes information relating to the object. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including an operator input station adjacent said scanner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of scanning objects by a scanner having a scanning table, comprising: 
<claim-text>a) conveying one or more objects to be scanned to the scanner using a conveyor mechanism; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) picking an object from the conveyor mechanism and mounting the object on the scanning table of the scanner; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) scanning the object; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) removing the scanned object from the scanning table and delivering the scanned object to a discharge location. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further including: 
<claim-text>picking an additional object to be scanned from the conveyor mechanism, and mounting the additional object on the scanning table, and repeating steps c) and d). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the objects are dental study casts, and further including mounting maxilla and mandible study casts for a single patient on one cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising mounting the cassette on the scanning table, and scanning the maxilla and mandible study casts together. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further including mounting the maxilla and mandible study casts on the cassette in known positions relative to one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further including reading an identification tag fixed to said cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A system for mass, automated scanning of dental study casts, comprising: 
<claim-text>a scanner having a scanning table; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of cassettes, each said cassette having a maxilla and mandible study cast for a single patient mounted thereon in known positions relative to each another; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveyor adjacent the scanner for delivering the cassettes to the scanner; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pick and place mechanism engageable with said cassettes for picking one of said cassettes from said conveyor and mounting the picked cassette on said scanning table. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said scanner is a laser scanner.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002089A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
