<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002699A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002699A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002699A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002699A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002699A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002699A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002699A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002699A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002699</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10188124</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>101 31 964.9</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04R025/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>381</class>
<subclass>316000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method for the operation of a digital, programmable hearing aid as well as a digitally programmable hearing aid</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Herve</given-name>
<family-name>Schulz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Erlangen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tom</given-name>
<family-name>Weidner</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Nurnberg</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SCHIFF HARDIN &amp; WAITE</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>6600 SEARS TOWER</address-1>
<address-2>233 S WACKER DR</address-2>
<city>CHICAGO</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60606-6473</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method for operating a digital, programmable hearing aid is provided that uses both a transmission characteristic of a normal amplification as well as a transmission characteristic of a maximum amplification of an audio signal over a frequency range that can be nearly freely configured. Given a modification of the amplification by settings at the hearing aid as well as using parameters that result from the signal processing, the gain for the overall system is always calculated utilizing all parameters and is potentially limited to the maximum amplification at the respective frequency if this would otherwise be exceeded. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention is directed to a method for the operation of a digital, programmable hearing aid having an input transducer for picking up an input signal and converting it into an audio signal, having a signal processing unit for the processing and frequency-dependent amplification of the audio signal, and having an output transducer. The invention is also directed to a digital, programmable hearing aid for implementing the method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Acoustic feedback frequently occurs in hearing aid devices, particularly for hearing aid devices having a high gain. This feedback is expressed in strong, feedback-caused oscillations at a specific frequency (feedback). This &ldquo;whistling&rdquo; is usually extremely unpleasant both for the hearing aid user as well as for persons in the immediate proximity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Feedback can occur when sound that is picked up via the microphone of the hearing aid device, amplified by a signal amplifier and output via the earphone proceeds back to the microphone and is re-amplified. Two further conditions, however, must be met for the typical &ldquo;whistling&rdquo;&mdash;usually at a dominant frequency&mdash;to occur. The &ldquo;loop amplification&rdquo; of the system, i.e., the product of the hearing aid gain and the attenuation of the feedback path, must be greater than 1. Additionally, the phase shift of this loop amplification must correspond to an arbitrary, whole multiple of 360&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The simplest approach for reducing feedback-caused oscillations is the permanent reduction of the hearing aid gain, so that the loop amplification remains below the critical limit even in unfavorable situations. The critical disadvantage of this approach, however, is that the hearing aid gain required given a more pronounced hearing impairment can no longer be achieved as a result of this limitation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The whistling typical of feedback usually lies at comparatively high frequencies. Hearing aids with a volume adjustment actuatable by the hearing aid user are known in devices such as the &ldquo;Swing&rdquo; hearing aid model of Siemens Audiologische Technik GmbH, with which the gain of an audio signal can be varied. With this model, the boosting or lowering of the amplification of the audio signal ensues dependent on the frequency, where nearly the entire transmission range of the hearing aid is uniformly amplified given a low gain and higher frequencies are less amplified than lower frequencies given a high gain. The frequency-dependent amplification based on the measure of the volume control is thereby static. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> German patent document DE 196 24 092 A1 discloses an amplifier circuit for analog and digital hearing aids. For better adaptation to the hearing capability of a test subject, the circuit comprises at least two compression circuits as sub-circuits that superimpose differently, and by which a resulting gain characteristic V can be generated at which the compression ratio decreases with an increasing input level either in a lasting fashion or at defined time intervals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> German patent document DE 196 19 312 A1 discloses an amplifier circuit for a hearing aid in which an input signal exhibits a signal level that is divided into individual, frequency band-specific sub-signal paths (channels). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> European patent document EP 0 250 679 B1 discloses a hearing aid with a memory for storing coefficients with respect to a filter frequency response. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a method for operating a hearing aid as well as to provide a hearing aid that allows a broad frequency response. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> This object is achieved in a method for operating a digital, programmable hearing aid having at least one input transducer for picking up an input signal and converting it into an audio signal, having a signal processing unit for the processing and frequency-dependent amplification of the audio signal, and with an output transducer, in that a transmission characteristic of a maximum amplification of the audio signal over the frequency range can be set and in that advantageously least one amplification modification value is determined in at least one frequency range from a parameter that can be set by the hearing aid user and/or from a parameter that is automatically generated by the signal processing unit, by which a final amplification value is determined at the respective frequency for an initial amplification value, taking the amplification modification value into consideration, and this final amplification value is limited to the maximum gain, so that an effective system gain for the respective frequency results. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> That part of the object directed to a digital, programmable hearing aid is achieved in that that hearing aid comprises at least one memory for accepting amplification values for characterizing a transmission characteristic of a maximum amplification of the audio signal over the frequency range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The hearing aid of the invention is, for example, a hearing aid worn behind the ear, a hearing aid worn in the ear, an implantable hearing aid, a pocket hearing aid device, or any similar device. Furthermore, the hearing aid of the invention can also be part of a hearing aid system comprising a plurality of devices for supplying a hearing-impaired person, for example, part of a hearing aid system having two hearing aids worn at the head or part of a hearing aid system composed of a hearing aid worn at the head and a processor unit carried on the body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The hearing aid comprises an input transducer for picking up an input signal. A microphone normally serves as an input transducer, this picking up an acoustic signal and converting it into an electrical audio signal. However, the invention can use other types of input transducers such as those that comprise a coil or an antenna and that pick up an electromagnetic signal and convert it into an electrical audio signal. The hearing aid of the invention also comprises a signal processing unit for the processing and frequency-dependent amplification of the audio signal. The signal processing in the hearing aid ensues using a digital signal processor (DSP) whose operation can be influenced by programs or parameters that can be transmitted to the hearing aid. This permits the operation of the signal processing unit to be adapted to the individual hearing impairment of a hearing aid user as well as to the current auditory situation in which the hearing aid is operated at the moment. The audio signal varied in this way is finally supplied to an output transducer. This is usually fashioned as an earphone that converts the electrical audio signal into an acoustic signal. However, other embodiments are also possible here, for example, an implantable output transducer that is directly connected to an ossicle and causes it to oscillate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> An audio signal is construed in a narrower sense as an electrical signal that proceeds from the signal picked up by the input transducer and that is transmitted by the hearing aid. It usually contains information lying in the audible frequency range. The audio signal can be present in analog or digital form in the signal processing in the hearing aid, where both forms of signal can also occur simultaneously in the signal path of the hearing aid. An audio signal is construed in a broader sense as an electrical signal that proceeds from the audio signal in the narrower sense as a result of further-processing, for example, by filtering, transformation, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The invention provides that a transmission characteristic of a maximum gain of the audio signal can be set over a frequency range, i.e., it can be freely configured, for example, in the adaptation of the hearing aid by the acoustician. Furthermore, at least one initial amplification value is deposited in the hearing aid, this being likewise adjustable by the acoustician. The initial amplification value can be constant for the entire transmittable frequency range of the hearing aid or, alternatively, within a respective frequency band of the hearing aid. Advantageously (within certain limits), however, an arbitrary initial amplification value can be set for each frequency, so that a transmission characteristic of a normal amplification of the audio signal over the frequency range can be freely configured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The factor by which an input audio signal with a specific signal amplitude is amplified dependent on the frequency is determined when setting the normal amplification. When the hearing aid comprises a volume control that can be set by the hearing aid user, then this factor is preferably in a middle position for setting the normal amplification, so that the hearing aid user can uniformly increase or reduce the amplification, proceeding from this basic setting. The setting of the normal amplification as well as of the maximum amplification can consider both hearing aid-specific points of view as well as individualized user points of view. For example, when adapting a hearing aid to a user indicates that feedback whistling occurs more at a specific frequency and a specific gain, then the maximum amplification in this frequency range is set below this gain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The transmission characteristic can preferably be freely configured for a specific frequency range and for a specific value range of the amplification. The transmission characteristics can be set as such with suitable adaptation software and can be transmitted onto the hearing aid; however, these characteristics can also be fixed merely by specifying a few frequency and gain value pairs. In addition to a continuous curve, other curve shapes are also possible, including discontinuous curves. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In addition to being dependent on the frequency, the actual amplification of an audio signal in a hearing aid is also dependent on a number of other factors. Such factors can be parameters derived from the momentary setting of the volume control at the hearing aid, from the amplitude of the input signal or from a signal analysis in the signal processing unit of the hearing aid. The latter are determined, for example, by algorithms for situational analysis, for ridding (the signal) of unwanted noise or for automatic gain control (AGC). In general, thus, a number of control and regulating functions in modern hearing aids influence the momentary amplification. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The invention considers, proceeding from the initial amplification value or from the characteristic of the normal amplification over the frequency, all influencing factors with respect to the amplification for the respective frequency. When, for example, the current volume setting effects a boosting of the audio signal by 10 dB and an algorithm for suppressing unwanted noise effects a lowering by 15 dB, then an overall amplification modification value of &minus;5 dB results. In contrast, the amplification modification value can also be a factor by which the initial amplification value is multiplied. Taking all influencing factors on the amplification (amplification modification values) at the respective frequency into consideration, the final amplification value is determined from the initial amplification value. When the final amplification value at the respective frequency exceeds the pre-set maximum amplification, then this is limited to the maximum amplification. The effective system gain is thus always less than or equal to the maximum amplification. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The invention offers the advantage that a nearly arbitrary, normal amplification as well as a nearly arbitrary, maximum amplification for a specific hearing aid can be set as a result. The signal processing in the hearing aid can thus be adapted better both to hearing aid-specific conditions as well as to the individual hearing impairment of a hearing aid user. The invention also offers the advantage that a plurality of influencing factors that simultaneously influence the amplification (for example, current setting of the volume control, gain modification using a signal processing algorithm, maximum amplification that has been set) can be taken into consideration more effectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> One embodiment of the invention provides that the signal processing ensues in a plurality of parallel frequency channels of the signal processing unit, and the transmission characteristic of the normal amplification of the audio signal over the frequency range and/or the transmission characteristic of the maximum amplification of the audio signal over the frequency range can be separately set for the respective channel. The division of the audible frequency range into a plurality of channels facilitates the adaptation of a hearing aid when characteristic quantities relating to a specific channel (i.e., a specific frequency range) are viewed as being constant for this channel. Such characteristic quantities for a specific channel can be the hearing threshold, the discomfort threshold, but can also be the normal amplification or the maximum amplification. Only specifying a value for the appertaining channel is then required for the characterization.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Further details of the invention are described below on the basis of exemplary embodiments and the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating a roll-off circuit of an analog hearing aid of the Prior Art; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a graph illustrating the transmission characteristics of the amplification over the frequency range in an analog hearing aid of the Prior Art; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a graph illustrating the amplification over the frequency given a hearing aid of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic block diagram of a multi-channel hearing aid with roll-off logic in the individual channels; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic block diagram of a multi-channel hearing aid with an overall roll-off logic. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows the circuit-oriented realization of a roll-off circuit in a hearing aid with analog signal processing. This amplifier circuit comprises an operational amplifier OA that is wired with an input resistor R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as well as with an RC element composed of a potentiometer R<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and a capacitor C in the feedback branch. The gain and, thus, the volume setting at the hearing aid, can be modified with the potentiometer R<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Simultaneously with the gain, however, the limit frequency (the knee point) from which the gain decreases with increasing frequency also changes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the amplification V over the frequency f for different potentiometer settings of the amplifier circuit according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The characteristic <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> shows the amplification V over the frequency f at the maximum volume setting at which the resistance of the potentiometer R<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is at its highest value. The amplification is constant up to a limit frequency; the amplification decreases linearly with increasing frequency above the limit frequency. The characteristics <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> show the amplification over the frequency for the normal setting (characteristic <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) or the minimal setting (characteristic <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) of the volume control. As can also be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, as the amplification decreases, the limit frequency above which an amplification reduction of the higher frequencies increases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The reason setting the amplification in hearing aids in the way set forth above is that unwanted feedback whistling (feedback) occurs more often with high amplification and high frequencies. Reducing the amplification at high frequencies counteracts this. The probability for feedback whistling and, thus, the beginning of the reduction at lower frequencies is all the greater the higher the amplification is. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The above-described method for lowering amplification is comparatively rigid and offers only a small latitude for individual or device-specific adaptation. In modern hearing aids, the effective amplification is often also dependent on further factors in addition to the setting of the volume control. A signal analysis that is implemented in the signal processing unit can be based on a number of different algorithms that can also run in parallel. By analyzing the input signal, the algorithms lead to an automatic gain control (AGC) or influence the amplification by automatically setting an auditory program as a result of a situation analysis. For example, an algorithm for suppressing unwanted noise can also be provided in a hearing aid, this reducing the amplification broad-band by a specific amount when unwanted noise is recognized. This procedure is shown by way of example in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The reduction in gain by a specific amounts effects a parallel shift of the pre-set characteristic of the normal amplification <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by exactly this amount. This is illustrated by the characteristic <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the arrow <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Proceeding from the setting of the volume control in normal position (characteristic <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), the gain is automatically reduced by the signal processing unit, so that the effective system amplification illustrated by characteristic <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> results. As can also be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the amplification about the frequency F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> that has already been reduced before is reduced again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the amplification over the frequency given a hearing aid of the invention. A characteristic of the normal amplification <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> can thereby be largely freely configured in the frequency/amplification diagram. This characteristic can, for example, be defined by a hearing aid acoustician and transferred onto the hearing aid. When the appertaining hearing aid comprises a volume control, a middle position of the volume control is preferably allocated to this characteristic, so that the hearing aid user, proceeding from the normal amplification, can modify the amplification both toward higher amplifications as well as toward lower amplifications by actuating the volume control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> A characteristic of the maximum amplification <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> can also be deposited in the hearing aid of the invention. This, too, can be defined by the acoustician when adapting the hearing aid and can be transferred onto the hearing aid when it is programmed. When, proceeding from the pre-set, normal amplification, the amplification is varied given a hearing aid of the invention, then an effective amplification derives, as illustrated with the characteristic <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> by way of example in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Proceeding from the characteristic of the normal amplification <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, a parallel lowering of the amplification characteristic initially ensues by a specific amount (e.g., &minus;10 dB) and the lowered characteristic is then in turn limited to the characteristic of the maximum amplification beginning with a frequency F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. This results in only a one-time lowering of amplification, even at high frequencies, which differs from the situation illustrated by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> that shows the same situation given a traditional hearing aid and in which a two-time lowering in amplification ensued in the characteristic <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> above the frequency F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> By way of example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> show block circuit diagrams of hearing aids with a gain control according to the invention. A microphone <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> serves as input transducer in the hearing aid according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, this picking up an acoustic signal and converting it into an electrical signal. The resulting audio signal is first supplied to a pre-amplifier and A/D converter unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in which the initial analog audio signal is converted into a digital audio signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> For further-processing in a plurality of parallel channels of the hearing aid, the digital audio signal is divided into a plurality of frequency bands (channels) with the filter bank <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The audio signals of the individual channels are first supplied to signal processing units <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>E in which the audio signals are individually and possibly differently filtered, for example, for adaptation to the individual hearing impairment of a hearing aid user. The signal processing units <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>E also perform a signal analysis in order, for example, to determine the signal level, acquire the current auditory situation and/or detect the presence of unwanted noise. Parameters are derived from this signal analysis and supplied to roll-off logic units <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>E. Parameters deposited in a memory <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> also enter into the roll-off logic units <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>E, these parameters characterizing a normal amplification as well as a maximum amplification of the audio signal over the frequency for the respective channel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The normal amplification determines an initial amplification value for every frequency of the transmittable frequency range in the amplification calculation and can be determined both by the hearing aid manufacturer from a standard setting of the amplification as well as by the acoustician in the adaptation of the hearing aid. The maximum amplification can likewise be pre-set by the hearing aid manufacturer and be individually adapted by the acoustician. Nearly arbitrary curve shapes of the amplification over the frequency in the audible frequency range can be set for both amplifications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As shown in the exemplary embodiment, the roll-off logic units <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>E can also be supplied with the current setting of a volume control <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Using the parameters supplied to the roll-off logic units <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>E, these units determine a specific amplification for each frequency. For one channel, for example, the normal amplification might be 50 dB (initial amplification value), and this amplification may then be compressed with the factor 0.8 (1st amplification modification value) due to a very high signal input level, the signal can be boosted by 10 dB due to the volume control <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> (2nd amplification modification value), and, finally, can be lowered by 20 dB due to a detected noise signal (3rd amplification modification value), so that an overall amplification modification value of &minus;20 dB and, thus, a final amplification value of 30 dB finally results taking all amplification modification values into consideration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> When this final amplification value at the respective frequency is lower than or equal to the maximum amplification, then this amplification is also the effective system amplification. Otherwise, the resulting amplification is limited to the maximum amplification, so that the latter forms the effective system amplification. The effective system amplification determined for the individual channels now controls amplifier elements <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E for amplifying the processed audio signals in the individual channels. Subsequently, the audio signals of the individual channels are re-merged and supplied to an earphone <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, potentially following a signal post-processing in the signal processing unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> that may filter, provide a final amplification, and a D/A conversion. The earphone <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> re-converts the processed, electrical audio signal into an acoustic signal that is output into the auditory canal of the hearing aid user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The invention can be realized in a number of different ways in terms of circuit technology. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows another exemplary embodiment of the invention. In this exemplary embodiment and given a hearing aid <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, an acoustic input signal is picked up via a microphone <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and converted into an electrical audio signal that is supplied to a pre-amplifier and A/D converter unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Corresponding to the previous exemplary embodiment, the audio signal is also processed in a plurality of parallel channels that are separated with a filter bank <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. Differing from the above-described exemplary embodiment, however, the parameters determined in individual signal processing units <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>E are supplied to a common roll-off logic unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Parameters deposited in a memory <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> that characterize the normal amplification as well as the maximum amplification also enter thereinto again. The current setting of the volume control <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is likewise introduced. Using all of the parameters entering into the roll-off logic unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, the latter calculates parameters for the control of a variable filter <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, so that all amplification demands in this exemplary embodiment as well are initially met by the amplifier elements <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>E; differing from the previously mentioned exemplary embodiment, however, the limitation to the maximum amplification after the merging of the audio signals of the individual channels is realized with the variable filter <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, which is in turn controlled by the roll-off logic unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A signal post-processing in a signal post-processing unit <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>&mdash;as warranted&mdash;and the output of the processed audio signal via an earphone <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> also ensue in this exemplary embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> For the purposes of promoting an understanding of the principles of the invention, reference has been made to the preferred embodiments illustrated in the drawings, and specific language has been used to describe these embodiments. However, no limitation of the scope of the invention is intended by this specific language, and the invention should be construed to encompass all embodiments that would normally occur to one of ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The present invention may be described in terms of functional block components and various processing steps. Such functional blocks may be realized by any number of hardware and/or software components configured to perform the specified functions. For example, the present invention may employ various integrated circuit components, e.g., memory elements, processing elements, logic elements, look-up tables, and the like, which may carry out a variety of functions under the control of one or more microprocessors or other control devices. Similarly, where the elements of the present invention are implemented using software programming or software elements the invention may be implemented with any programming or scripting language such as C, C&plus;&plus;, Java, assembler, or the like, with the various algorithms being implemented with any combination of data structures, objects, processes, routines or other programming elements. Furthermore, the present invention could employ any number of conventional techniques for electronics configuration, signal processing and/or control, data processing and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The particular implementations shown and described herein are illustrative examples of the invention and are not intended to otherwise limit the scope of the invention in any way. For the sake of brevity, conventional electronics, control systems, software development and other functional aspects of the systems (and components of the individual operating components of the systems) may not be described in detail. Furthermore, the connecting lines, or connectors shown in the various figures presented are intended to represent exemplary functional relationships and/or physical or logical couplings between the various elements. It should be noted that many alternative or additional functional relationships, physical connections or logical connections may be present in a practical device. Moreover, no item or component is essential to the practice of the invention unless the element is specifically described as &ldquo;essential&rdquo; or &ldquo;critical&rdquo;. Numerous modifications and adaptations will be readily apparent to those skilled in this art without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">List of Reference Characters </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> resistor </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> R<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> potentiometer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> C capacitor </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> OA operational amplifier </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> characteristics </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>,F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> limit frequencies </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> hearing aid </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> microphone </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> pre-amplifier and A/D converter unit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> filter bank </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>A . . . <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>E, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A . . . <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>E signal processing units </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>A . . . <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>E,<highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> roll-off logic units </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> memory </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> volume control </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>A . . . <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E,<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>A . . . <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>E signal post-processing unit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> signal processing unit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> earphone </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> variable filter </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for operating a digital, programmable hearing aid, comprising: 
<claim-text>picking up an input signal with an input transducer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>converting the input signal into an audio signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing and performing a frequency-dependent amplification of the audio signal with a signal processing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>converting and outputting the audio signal with an output transducer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting a maximum-amplification transmission characteristic of a maximum amplification of the audio signal over a frequency range; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining at least one amplification modification value in at least one frequency range from a parameter that can be set by at least one of a hearing aid user and a parameter that is automatically generated by the signal processing unit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a final amplification value at a respective frequency for an initial amplification value, taking the amplification modification value into consideration, and the final amplification value being limited to a maximum gain to produce an effective system gain for the respective frequency. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising limiting a gain for higher frequencies utilizing the maximum-amplification transmission characteristic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising setting the parameter by the hearing aid user with a volume control. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising automatically generating the parameter by the signal processing unit with an algorithm configured to perform an operation selected from the group consisting of a situation analysis, unwanted noise suppression, and compression. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>setting a normal-amplification transmission characteristic of a normal amplification over a frequency range; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining an initial amplification value for each frequency utilizing the normal-amplification transmission characteristic. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising storing at least one of the maximum-amplification transmission characteristic and the normal-amplification characteristic in a memory. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>processing signals in a plurality of parallel frequency channels of the signal processing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>separately setting, in at least two of the frequency channels, a transmission characteristic selected from the group consisting of the maximum-amplification transmission characteristic and the normal-amplification transmission characteristic. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising separately setting at least one of a constant normal amplification and a constant maximum amplification for at least two of the frequency channels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A digital, programmable hearing aid, comprising: 
<claim-text>an input transducer configured to pick up an input signal and convert it into an audio signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a signal processing unit configured to process and perform a frequency dependent amplification of the audio signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory configured to hold amplification values characterizing a maximum-amplification transmission characteristic of a maximum amplification of the audio signal over a frequency range, the memory being connected to the signal processing unit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an output transducer configured to produce an output signal from an audio signal processed by the signal processing unit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The digital, programmable hearing aid according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a memory configured to hold amplification values characterizing a normal-amplification transmission characteristic of a normal amplification of the audio signal over a frequency range. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The digital, programmable hearing aid according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one volume control adjustable by a hearing aid user; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a signal processing unit comprising algorithms configured to perform an operation selected from the group consisting of situation analysis, unwanted noise suppression and compression; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one roll-off logic unit configured to determine an effective system amplification for a respective frequency from: 
<claim-text>the normal amplification; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the maximum amplification; </claim-text>
<claim-text>parameters associated with a volume control setting; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>parameters determined from the algorithms.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002699A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002699A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002699A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002699A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
