<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000585A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000585A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000585</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893232</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F16K011/048</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>137</class>
<subclass>625500</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Modular vacuum and low pressure valve assembly</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Cooper</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaPorte</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>G.</middle-name>
<family-name>Schultz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>New Buffalo</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Lefco CPS, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>R. Tracy Crump</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 604</address-1>
<city>New Carlisle</city>
<state>IN</state>
<postalcode>46552</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A modular valve assembly of this invention includes individual valve units and components, which can be selectively combined to form an integrated multi-port, multi-way valve assembly that is operated by a single common linear actuator is disclosed. The modular design of this invention is facilitated by the construction of valve housings and valve components of the individual valve units and assemblies of common plumbing pipes and fittings, such as, tee joints, threaded couplings, bushings and reducers. A single linear actuator, such as a conventional solenoid or piston cylinder mounted to the end of the valve housing, reciprocates an elongated shaft running axially through the valve interior to move various valve discs into and out of engagement with various internal valve seats, thereby controlling the valve assembly operation. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to control valves, and in particular, modular control valve assemblies for vacuum and low pressure pneumatic applications. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Control valves for vacuum and low pressure applications are well known in the field of pneumatics control systems. Many types and varieties of control valves have been developed to accommodate the wide range of application requirements. Some control valves are designed to be normally open or normally closed. Other valves have multiple inlet and outlet ports and others provide three and four way valving from a single valve. Typically, control valves are actuated by their own internal control mechanisms and are operatively connected to an electrical or pneumatic line, which controls the operation of the valves. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Conventional control valves have several design limitations and cost restrictions, particularly in low pressure and vacuum applications. The valve housings are constructed of cast metals, such as brass and aluminum which makes the valves heavy and expensive. In low pressure pneumatic applications, constructing valve housings of brass and aluminum is often unnecessary for fluid control or safety purposes and simply adds cost to the system. A simple plastic valve housing often would provide sufficient structural integrity to the valve. In addition, valve housings must also be cast or machined to enclose the internal valving components and intricate flow passages. Valves traditionally have complex internal actuation components, including springs, poppets, seals, and diaphragms incorporated into sophisticated metal valve housings. The internal passages and components are even more intricate in multi-port multi-way valves. These intricate internal components are often subject to wear and contamination failure, which require maintenance in order to ensure the longevity of the valve and pneumatic system. The integration of the actuation mechanism into the valve housing often makes it more cost effective to replace the valve than to repair it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventional control valves are not designed or well suited for integration into a wide range of pneumatic applications. Since plastic piping is cost effective for most pneumatic applications, conventional control valves must be connected to plastic pipe systems. Integrating conventional cast metal control valves into plastic piping systems is difficult and adds considerable fittings, supports, weight and cost to pneumatic applications. Because of the cost of cast or machined metal housings, the range of sizes of conventional control valves is often limited. The use of small control valves in many pneumatic applications creates flow restriction problems. Conventional control valves often require expensive filtration systems to reduce obstructed flow passages and prolong the life of the valves. Conventional control valves are also limited in the range of pipe fitting sizes. As a result, bushings and reducers must used to mate the control valves to larger piping systems, which adds to application costs. Furthermore, conventional control valves are also ill suited because of the type of application in which they are incorporated. For example, many pneumatic applications require the control of alternating positive and negative (vacuum) air pressures. In such applications, conventional valve designs are not well suited for dual purpose use with positive and negative pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Heretofore, control valves have not been developed that employ modular design systems, so that individual valve units and valving components can be selectively combined into a complex valve assembly that allows the individual valve unit to operate from a common actuation component. While individual valves can be employed in series and parallel connected by pipe sections, to create an infinite array of pneumatic systems, each valve must be individually controlled. Electrical or pneumatic control lines must be routed to each control valve in the system, which complicates the system. Multi-port, multi-way valves (3-way valves, 4-way valves, etc. . . ) provide greater design flexibility, but are generally more expensive and costly to maintain. A modularvalve system would allow low cost individual valve units and components to be conveniently interconnected into more complex valve assemblies for integration into any particular design application. A modular valve system would also reduce the number of control lines needed to control the valve assembly in a given application thereby reducing costs. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The modular valve assembly of this invention addresses many of the traditional shortcomings of conventional control valves, particularly in vacuum and low pressure pneumatic applications. The modular valve assembly of this invention includes individual valve units and components, which can be selectively combined to form an integrated multi-port, multi-way valve assembly that is operated by a single common linear actuator. The modular design of this invention is facilitated by the construction of valve housings and valve components of the individual valve units and assemblies constructed of common plumbing pipes and fittings, such as, tee joints, threaded couplings, bushings and reducers. Common tee joints provide the basic configuration of the individual valve units. A linear actuator, such as a conventional solenoid or piston cylinder mounted to the end of the valve housing, reciprocates an elongated shaft running axially through the valve interior to move a valve disc into and out of engagement with an internal valve seat. Because the valve housings and components are constructed from common plumbing pipes and fittings, individual valve units can be connected end to end along with other valve components to form an integrated multi-port, multi-way valve assembly. The multi-way valving for such valve assembly is accomplished connecting multiple valve discs to a common valve shaft reciprocated by a single actuator to seal against multiple internal valve seats. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, an advantage of the modular valve assembly of this invention over conventional control valves is that it allows individual valve units and components to be selectively combined and integrated into larger more complex valve assembles as required for any particular application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of the modular design of this valve assembly is that it allows individual valve units and components to be readily serviced and replaced with minimum labor, effort and disruption to the valve system in which it is incorporated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Another advantage is the construction of the valve assembly from common PVC plumbing pipes and fittings, which reduces the cost, weight and complexity of the individual valve units, valve components and integrated valve assemblies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of this valve assembly is that use of common plumbing joints and fittings as valve housings allows the valves to be readily connected to both pipe and hose lines of vacuum and pneumatic systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of this valve assembly is that it can tolerate extreme environments and be used with air flows containing high particulate counts, because the valve housings provide large open flow passages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Another advantage is that this modular valve assembly can be scaled up and down to accommodate any application consideration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Another advantage is that the design of this modular valve assembly reduces the cost of producing valve assembles for a wide range of pneumatic applications by eliminating the expense of tooling, castings and machining valve assembles in various configurations and scales. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Another advantage is that the design of this valve assembly provides for adjustable port orientations both radially and axially. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Other advantages will become apparent upon a reading of the following description.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A preferred embodiment of the invention has been depicted for illustrative purposes only wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of a first embodiment of an individual valve unit of this invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side sectional view of the valve unit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shown in a closed position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side sectional view of the valve unit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shown in an open position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a second embodiment of an individual valve unit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of the valve unit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> with a partial sectional view of the adjustable valve seat assembly, which shows the valve seat extending into the center of the valve interior; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side view of the valve unit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> with a partial sectional view of the adjustable valve seat assembly, which shows the valve seat position back off from the center of the valve interior; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a five-way valve assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a side sectional view of the five-way valve assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a partial exploded perspective view of the end valve units and couplings of the five-way valve assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a side sectional view of a three-way valve; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a schematic of a type pneumatic application using a three-way valve assembly to switch between positive and negative air flows.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiment herein described is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise form disclosed. It is chosen and described to best explain the invention so that others skilled in the art might utilize its teachings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The modular valve assembly of this invention includes individual valve modules or units and valve components, all of which can be combined and interconnected to form various integrated valve assemblies for use in low pressure vacuum and pneumatic applications. The valve assembly is designed and intended for low pressure pneumatic applications, but can be modified for high pressure or hydraulic applications. The valve assembly can be used equally with positive or negative (vacuum) air pressures. The figures illustrate the individual valve units and valve components as separate valves, component parts, and as integrated components of large valve assemblies. The different embodiments of the individual valve units, component parts, and valve assemblies are not intended to be exhaustive, but to illustrate the advantages, convenience and utility of this invention. The scope of this invention is not limited to the embodiments shown and described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As shown, most of the components (valve housings and seat assemblies) forming the individual valve units and the valve assemblies are constructed of common pipes and plumbing fittings. Ideally, the plumbing pipes and fittings are constructed of polyvinylchloride (PVC), chlorinated polyvinylchloride (CPVC) or other common plastics, but can also be constructed of suitable metals. PVC and CPVC pipes and plumbing fittings are well known in the plumbing industry. PVC and CPVC pipes and fittings are readily available and can be obtained commercially from various manufactures and suppliers. Valve housings and valve seats for the individual valve units are assembled by interconnecting various pipes, tee joints, couplings, bushings, collars, reducers and elbows. The pipes and fittings are held together by bonding conventional PVC and PVC compounds, which also provides an air tight seal between the pipes and fittings. The various embodiments of the valve units and valve assemblies described herein are assembled using various combinations of pipes and fittings. The use of common PVC and CPVC pipes and fittings allows the valve units to be scaled in size by the use of different sized pipes and fittings. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Individual Valve Units </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> illustrate the first embodiment of a single valve module or unit, designated by reference numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as a stand alone valve in a normally open configuration. Valve <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be readily modified for a normal closed configuration or for incorporation into an integrated valve assembly. FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are intended simply to illustrate the basic construction, assembly and operation of the valve unit as a stand alone valve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a side port <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and an end port <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, either of which can act as an inlet or outlet as required. As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a valve housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a fixed seat assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, a valve disc or gate <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, and a linear actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Valve housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is constructed of a tee joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, two end couplings <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and an end cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Tee joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is the principal body component of valve housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and generally defines the cylindrical valve interior <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the valve unit. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, end coupling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is fitted into one end of tee joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and end coupling <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is fitted to the other end of tee joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by a bushing <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Bushing <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> also forms part of seat assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. End cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is turned into the threaded throat of male coupling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to enclose one end of valve housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. While tee joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, couplings <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and bushing <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are constructed of PVC or CPVC, end cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is constructed of a metal, such as brass or aluminum, or other material suitable for supporting actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and enclosing one end of the valve housing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As shown, valve seat assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes bushing <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, pipe section <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and an annular seal <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Bushing <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> connects coupling <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and tee joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and provides the internal support for the valve seat <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Pipe section <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is seated within bushing <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and extends into valve interior <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Seal <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is a rubber <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>-ring or gasket bonded to the end pipe section <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, which forms valve seat <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> within valve interior <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Pipe section <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> provides an open flow conduit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> between valve seat <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and port <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is s a conventional spring return pneumatic piston cylinder mounted to the exterior of valve housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. While actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is illustrated as a piston cylinder, any suitable linearly reciprocating mechanism may be employed, such as a solenoid or other types of piston cylinders. Actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is operated by a pneumatic control line (not shown). As shown, actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes a cylinder body <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and an extensible piston shaft <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Cylinder body <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is mounted to end cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> so that piston shaft <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> extends into the valve interior <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and reciprocates along the longitudinal axis of the interior. Cylinder body <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is secured to the outside of end cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> by a hex nut <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. An elongated shaft extension <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is threaded onto the distal end of piston shaft <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A flat valve disc or gate <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is adjustably connected to the threaded distal end <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> of shaft extension <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> by two hex nuts <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, or other suitable fasteners. Preferably, valve disc <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is constructed of a suitable material, such as, steel, brass, aluminum or plastic. Threaded end <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> of shaft extension <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> extends through a central bore in valve disc <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, which allows hex nuts <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> to be turned to secure the disc in different positions along the length of the threaded end of the shaft extension. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the closed position. In the closed position (actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is activated), piston shaft <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is extending into valve interior <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and valve disc <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is pressed against valve seat <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, thereby preventing flow between side port <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and end port <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> through valve interior <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and passage <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the normally open position. In the open position (actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is deactivated), piston shaft <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is retracted into cylinder body <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and valve disc <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is spaced from valve seat <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, thereby permitting air flow between side port <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and end port <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> show a second embodiment of the valve unit, designated as reference number <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Valve unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has an adjustable seat assembly <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, which allows the position of the valve seat to be adjusted within the valve interior. Valve unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is illustrated as a component part to be integrated into a larger valve assembly of the type described hereafter. As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, valve unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has an open valve interior, which allows it to be readily connected to other valve units (not shown). It should be noted that valve unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> could be modified to function as a stand alone valve in the same manner as valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> described above. FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are intended simply to further illustrate the basic construction, assembly and operation of this valve unit, as a component part of a larger valve assembly, and particularly, the construction and operation of the adjustable valve seat assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Valve unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> follows the same basic construction as valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment. As shown in the figures, valve unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes a valve housing <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, a valve disc or gate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, a threaded shaft <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, and an adjustable valve seat assembly <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Again, valve housing <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> includes a tee joint <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and two end couplings <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> fitted into the ends of the tee joint. Adjustable seat assembly <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> includes an adjustment coupling <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, lock ring <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, a reducer bushing <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, a pipe section <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and an annular seal <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Adjustment coupling <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> has a threaded neck, which is turned into the threaded throat of end coupling <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Reducer bushing <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is fitted into the distal end of adjustment coupling <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Pipe section <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is seated within bushing <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and extends into valve interior <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. Against, seal <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is a rubber O-ring or gasket bonded to the end pipe section <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, which forms valve seat <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> within valve interior <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, the position of valve seat <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> can be shifted longitudinally within valve interior <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, by turning adjustment coupling <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> into end coupling <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Once the desired position is obtained, lock ring <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> can be turned down against end coupling <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> to secure valve seat <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> in position. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Integrated Valve Assemblies </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrate two different embodiments of typical integrated valve assemblies created by connecting and integrating various individual valve units and valve components. The two embodiments are not intended to limit the scope of this invention, but simply to illustrate how the individual valve units and components can be interconnected and arranged into an integrated valve assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> show a first embodiment of an integrated valve assembly as a five-port five-way valve assembly, designated as reference numeral <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Valve assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is formed by five individual valve units <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The individual valve units are interconnected by various fittings, such as, pipe sections, reducers, bushings and threaded couplings. The interconnection of the individual valve units is readily understandable to one of ordinary skill in the art, and will not be described in detail herein, except to provide additional insight into the utility of this invention. The valve housings of valve units <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> are joined end to end, which creates an integrated valve interior <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> running the length of the valve assembly. Valve assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes five ports, <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight>, one for each individual valve unit. The valve units <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are interconnected together so that their side ports are fixed in any radial orientation to each other. As shown, ports <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> degrees opposed to port <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The radial orientation of the ports may vary as desired for connection into the particular vacuum or pneumatic system, without deviating for the teachings of this invention. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, valve unit <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and valve unit <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> are interconnected by a threaded coupling <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and bushing <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, which allows the radial orientation of port <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> to be readily adjusted with respect to the other ports. The interconnection can also provide a limited range of axial adjustment of the side ports. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, valve assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes four internal valve seats <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>, and two valve discs or gates <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> which provide its five way valving. Valve seat <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> is formed by a reducing bushing <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> fitted into one end of individual valve unit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Valve seat <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> is formed by a fixed seat assembly <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> fitted into the opposite end of individual valve unit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Valve seat <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> is formed by a second fixed seat assembly <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> fitted into one end of individual valve unit <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Both fixed valve seat assemblies <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> are of the type employed in valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which was described supra. Valve seat D<highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> is formed by an adjustable valve seat assembly <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> fitted into the opposite end of individual valve unit <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Adjustable valve seat assembly <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is of the type employed in valve unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, which was described supra. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The five way valving of valve assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is operated by a single actuator <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> mounted to the end cap <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> fitted into individual valve unit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. A long threaded shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is connected to the reciprocal piston shaft <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of actuator <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> by a shaft coupling <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. Shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> extends through the valve assembly interior along the longitudinal axis running the entire length of the valve assembly. The terminal end of shaft extension <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> extends through another end cap <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> fitted into valve unit <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Valve discs <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> are adjustably mounted to shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> by two sets of hex nuts <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> or other suitable fasteners. Valve disc <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is connected to shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> to be positioned between valve seat <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> and valve seat <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. Valve disc <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is adjustably mounted to shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> to be positioned between valve seat <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> and valve seat <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>. The location of the valve discs along the length of the shaft with respect to the valve seats can be finely adjusted by hex nuts <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> or other suitable fasteners or clamping devices. In addition, the adjustable valve seat assembly can be used to vary the longitudinal location of valve seat <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> within the valve assembly interior as desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The five way valving operation of valve assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is similar to the operation of a single valve unit. Actuator <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> linearly moves the valve discs within the valve assembly interior to abut against one the valve seats to seal off various ports from one another. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, when actuator <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is deactivated, shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> moves valve disc <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> against valve seal <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> and valve disc <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> against valve seal <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, thereby permitting air flow between ports <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>, and ports <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight>, respectively. When actuator <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is activated, shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> moves valve disc <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> against valve seal <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and valve disc <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> against valve seal <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>, thereby permitting air flow between ports <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>, and ports <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates a second valve assembly embodiment as a three-way valve assembly, designated by reference numeral <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Valve assembly <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is constructed of three individual valve units <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> interconnected by different fittings, which are pipe sections, reducers, bushings, and threaded couplings. Again, the interconnection of the valve housings of each valve unit is readily understandable to one of ordinary skill in the art, and will not be described in detail herein, except to provide additional insight into the utility of this invention. The valve housings of each valve unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> are joined end to end, which creates an integrated valve interior <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> running the length of the valve assembly. Valve assembly <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> includes three ports, <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight>, that is one port for each individual valve unit. As shown, the valve units are interconnected together so that the side ports are fixed in any radial orientation to each other; however, the valve units may be interconnected using the fittings of the type shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> so that the radial and axial orientation of the ports may be readily adjusted within the scope of this invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Valve assembly <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> includes two internal valve seats <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight> and two valve discs or gates <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> which provide its three-way valving. Valve seats <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight> are formed by two fixed seat assemblies <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. Both fixed valve seat assemblies <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> are of the type employed in valve unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which was described supra. The three-way valving of valve assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is operated by a single actuator <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> mounted to the end cap <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> fitted into valve unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. A threaded shaft <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> is connected to the reciprocal piston shaft <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> of actuator <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> by a shaft coupling <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. Shaft <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> extends through the valve interior along the longitudinal axis running the entire length of the valve assembly. The terminal end of shaft <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> reciprocally extends through an end cap <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> fitted into valve unit <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>. Valve discs <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> are adjustably mounted to shaft <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> by two sets of hex nuts <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> or other suitable fasteners. The location of valve discs <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> along the length of shaft <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> can be finely adjusted by hex nuts <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>, so that proper sealing against the valve seats can be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Again, the three-way valving of valve assembly <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is accomplished by the actuator <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> linearly moving the two valve discs between sealed engagements against the two valve seals within the valve interior. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, when actuator <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> is deactivated, shaft <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> moves valve disc <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> away form valve seat <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and valve disc <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> against valve seal <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight>, thereby permitting air flow between ports <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight>. When actuator <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> is activated (not illustrated in the figures), shaft <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> moves valve disc <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> against valve seat <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and valve disc <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> away from valve seat <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight>, thereby permitting air flow between ports <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Typical Valve Assembly Application </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates a three-way valve assembly <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in a simplified pneumatic system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, which requires both negative (vacuum) and positive airflow pressure. This illustration is intended to demonstrate an application of the valve assembly of this invention in a typical pneumatic system and is not intended to limit the scope of this invention. Valve assembly <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is of the type described supra. As shown, the system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes a blower <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, a vacuum pump <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, and an end user apparatus <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. The end user apparatus may include any equipment, instrument or device that selectively requires either a vacuum or positive air pressure. Blower <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> provides a positive low pressure air flow for the end user apparatus <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and vacuum pump <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> provides a negative low pressure air flow from end user apparatus <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. Valve assembly <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is selectively actuated between a first position, where blower <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> provides a positive pressure airflow to user apparatus <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and a second position, where vacuum pump <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> draws a negative pressure (vacuum) air flow from end user apparatus <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. One skilled in the art will note that the actuation of the valve assembly between its first and second positions can be controlled manually by the operator of the end user apparatus or controlled as part of an automated control system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Advantages </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> One skilled in the art will recognize that the modular valve assembly of this invention provides several practical advantages and improvements over conventional valves. Constructing the valve assembly from common plastic plumbing pipes and fittings provides cost savings, design flexibility and installation convenience. PVC and CPVC plumbing pipes and fittings are inexpensive and readily available. The modular nature of PVC plumbing fittings makes installing the valve system into existing pneumatic lines and fittings convenient and uncomplicated. Interconnecting the valve units with the various plumbing fittings requires minimal labor and technical skill. The PVC or CPVC construction makes the weight of the valve units and connection components much lighter in weight than similar conventional valves. Using plumbing fittings also allows the valve system to be scaled up and down as required in any particular system application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The modular design of the valve assembly allows sophisticated custom designed valve systems to be assembled from simple individual valve modules or units, valving components and common plumbing pipes and fittings. The individual valve units, valving components and plumbing fittings can be combined and modified, as needed to suit the design criteria for any low pressure pneumatic application. The multi-port valve assembles can be used simultaneously with both positive or negative (vacuum) air pressures. The modular design also provides an advantage in servicing the valve assembly. Since the actuator is a separate modular component and not enclosed or integrated into the valve housing, it can be readily serviced and replaced without disassembling or replacing the entire valve unit or assembly. Likewise, valve seat assemblies and valve discs often can be replaced and serviced without disassembling or replacing the entire valve unit or assembly. Since the modular valve systems do not rely on intricate internal valving components for actuation, they can tolerate extreme environments and be used with air flows containing high particulate counts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Individual valve units can be operated as either normally open or normally closed. In addition, individual valve units and assemblies can have any desired port configuration or orientation. The larger valve interior and <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> degree orientation of the ports provides a larger more direct flow passage than conventional valves, which makes the valve systems less susceptible to valve obstruction due to flow contamination or pressure drops. The modular design allows any valve assembly to be operated by a single common actuator. Multi-way valving can be controlled by the linear movement of the valve discs within the integrated valve interior. Unlike conventional valves, the position of the valve disc within the valve interior can be adjusted to ensure proper sealing against the valve seats and to accommodate seating variations caused by component wear and thermal expansion. In addition, the position of the valve seats within the valve interior can be adjusted to accommodate wear and thermal expansion. The design of this valve assembly also allows for radial and to a limited degree axial adjustment of the side ports. This feature allows the valve assembles to simplify the routing of the piping in any particular application. Another unique, but subtle feature, is that the valve assembly may use a &ldquo;soft seat&rdquo; valving design, wherein there is not metal to metal contact in seating the valve disc against the valve seat. The metal discs abut against a valve seat comprised of a rubber seal and PVC or CPVC pipe. The &ldquo;soft seat&rdquo; valving design allows the valve assembly to be used safely in volatile applications where spark and explosion are concerns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> It is understood that the above description does not limit the invention to the details given, but may be modified within the scope of the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A valve assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a valve housing defining a cylindrical housing interior, the housing including a tee part having a first open end, a second open end axially opposed to the first open end, and a side port located between the first open end and the second open end opening, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a valve seat disposed within the housing interior, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a disc disposed within the housing interior and axially shiftable within the housing interior between a first position where the disc sealingly abuts against the valve seat thereby preventing flow communication between the side port and the second open end of the first tee part and a second position where the disc is spaced from the valve seat thereby permitting flow communication between the side port and the second open end, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>actuation means sealingly fitted to the first end of the tee part and operatively connected to the disc for selectively reciprocating the disc within the housing interior between its first position and its second position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the housing also includes a second tee part interconnected end to end to the first tee part to form part of the valve housing, 
<claim-text>the second tee part having a first open end, a second open end axially opposed to the first open end, and a side port located between its first open end and its second open end opening, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first open end of the second tee part coupled to the second open end of the first tee part. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> and a second valve seat disposed within the housing interior and spaced from the first valve seat, 
<claim-text>the disc disposed between the first and second valve seats and also for sealingly abutting against the second valve seat, such that in its first position the disc sealingly abuts the first valve seat and is spaced from the second valve seat, thereby permitting flow communication between the side port of the second tee part and the second open end of the second tee part, and in its second position, the disc is spaced from the first valve seat and sealingly abuts the second valve seat, thereby permitting flow communication between the side port of the first tee part and the side port of the second tee part. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> and a second valve seat disposed within the housing interior and spaced from the first valve seat, 
<claim-text>a second disc disposed within the housing interior and axially shiftable within the housing interior between a first position where the second disc sealingly abuts against the second valve seat thereby preventing flow communication between the side port of the second tee part and the first open end of the second tee part </claim-text>
<claim-text>and a second position where the disc is spaced from the valve seat thereby permitting flow communication between the side port of the second tee part and the first open end of the second tee part, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the actuation means also operatively connected to the second disc for selectively reciprocating the second disc within the housing interior between its first position and its second position, such that the second disc is in its second position when the first disc is in its first position and the second disc is in its first position when the first disc is in its second position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the actuation means includes an end cap sealing mounted to the first open end of the tee part, a piston cylinder mounted to the end cap, and a reciprocating shaft part extending axially into the housing interior. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the actuation means also includes disc adjustment means for mounting the disc to the shaft part at selective locations along the length of the shaft part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> and a valve seat adjustment means interconnecting the valve seat and housing for selectively positioning the valve seat within the housing interior. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the valve seat adjustment means includes a collar part interconnected to the valve housing for shiftable movement within the second open end of the tee part, the valve seat fitted into the collar part and extending into the housing interior. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein one of the second open end of tee part and the collar part includes a threaded female part and the other of the second open end of tee part and the collar part includes a threaded male part turned into the threaded female part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seat adjustment means includes a lock ring turned only the male threaded part for securing the collar part at a fixed location within the second open end of the tee part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> and port adjustment means interconnecting the first tee part to the second tee part for adjusting the radial orientation of the side port of the second tee part with respect to the radial orientation of the side port of the first tee part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the port adjustment means includes one of the second open end of the first tee part and the first open end of the second tee part includes a threaded female part and the other of the second open end of the first tee part and the first open end of the second tee part includes a threaded male part turned into the threaded female part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the housing is constructed of plumbing fittings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the valve seat is constructed of plumbing fittings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the tee part is a plumbing tee joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The valve assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the collar part is a plumbing bushing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A valve assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a valve housing constructed of plumbing components and defines a cylindrical housing interior, the housing including a tee joint and an end cap, the tee part having a first open end, a second open end axially opposed to the first open end, and a side port located between the first open end and the second open end opening, the end cap sealingly fitted into the first open end of the tee joint, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated shaft part disposed for shiftable movement within the housing interior, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston cylinder mounted to the exterior of the end cap and operatively connected to the shaft part for reciprocating the shaft part axially within the housing interior, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a valve seat disposed within the housing interior, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a disc disposed within the housing interior and connected to the shaft part to be axially moved between a first position where the disc sealingly abuts against the valve seat thereby preventing flow communication between the side port and the second open end of the first tee part and a second position where the disc is spaced from the valve seat thereby permitting flow communication between the side port and the second open end. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A valve assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a valve housing constructed of plumbing components and defines a cylindrical housing interior, the housing including a first tee joint, a second tee joint, a third tee joint, a first end cap, and a second end cap, each of the first tee joint, the second tee joint and the third tee joint having a first open end, a second open end axially opposed to the first open end, and a side port located between the first open end and the second open end opening, the end cap sealing fitted into the first open end of the tee joint, the first open end of the second tee joint coupled to the second open end of the first tee joint, the first open end of the third tee joint coupled to the second open end of the second tee joint, the first end cap sealingly fitted into the first open end of the first tee joint, the second end cap fitted into the second open end of the third tee joint, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first valve seat constructed of plumbing components disposed within the housing interior between the first tee joint and the second tee joint, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second valve seat constructed of plumbing components disposed within the housing interior between the second tee joint and the third tee joint, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first disc disposed within the housing interior and shiftable axially within the housing interior for sealingly engagement against the first valve seat, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second disc disposed within the housing interior and shiftable axially within the housing interior for sealingly engagement against the second valve seat, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston cylinder mounted to the end cap and operatively connected to the first disc and the second disc for moving the first disc and the second disc between a first position where the first disc abuts against the first valve seat and the second disc is spaced from the second valve seat thereby permitting flow communication between the side port of the second tee joint and the side port of the third tee joint, and second position where the first disc is spaced from the first valve seat and the second disc abuts against the second valve seat thereby permitting flow communication between the side port of the second tee joint and the side port of the first tee joint. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A valve assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a valve housing constructed of plumbing components and defines a cylindrical housing interior, the housing including a plurality of tee joints interconnected end to end with each other, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of valve seats constructed of plumbing components disposed within the housing interior, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of discs disposed within the housing interior and shiftable axially within the housing interior for sealingly engagement against at least one of the plurality of valve seats, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston cylinder mounted to the valve housing and operatively connected to the plurality of discs for moving the plurality of discs between a first position where a portion of the plurality of discs sealingly abuts against a portion of the plurality of valve seats thereby permitting flow communication between selected ones of the plurality of tee joints and second position where another portion of the plurality of discs abuts against another portion of the plurality of valve seats thereby permitting flow communication between other selected ones of the plurality of tee joints.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>8</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030000585A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
