<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001751A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001751A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001751</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10169939</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020711</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-350906</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001117</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G08B007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>691600</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>701</class>
<subclass>050000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>425500</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Display device and display controller of construction machinery</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiroshi</given-name>
<family-name>Ogura</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ryugasaki-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiroshi</given-name>
<family-name>Watanabe</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ushiku-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kazuo</given-name>
<family-name>Fujishima</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Niihari-gun Ibaraki-ken</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sadahisa</given-name>
<family-name>Tomita</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ibaraki-ken</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MATTINGLY, STANGER &amp; MALUR, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1800 DIAGONAL ROAD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 370</address-2>
<city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22314</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/JP01/09804</doc-number>
<document-date>20011109</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A display unit for a construction machine is provided which allow for an operator to easily set a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control, and to freely change the contents to be displayed regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control, so that information which the operator wants to see can be promptly displayed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">A display <highlight><bold>41 </bold></highlight>of a display unit <highlight><bold>40 </bold></highlight>selectively displays a standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60 </bold></highlight>for displaying attitude information of a body, an excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61 </bold></highlight>for displaying the setting states of depth and gradient of a target excavation plane for automatic control, and an excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62 </bold></highlight>for displaying, in enlarged scale, the relative position of a bucket relative to the target excavation plane set on the excavation setting screen. Each of those screens has a menu area <highlight><bold>64 </bold></highlight>in which an item &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; and items corresponding to associated screen information are set. A desired one of the items in the menu area <highlight><bold>64 </bold></highlight>is selected by manipulating up and down selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight><highlight><bold>, 43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on an operating unit <highlight><bold>43 </bold></highlight>to move a cursor in the menu area vertically, and the contents of the item displayed in reverse video is executed by depressing a decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. It is hence possible to easily set a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control, to freely change the contents to be displayed regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control, and to promptly display information that the operator wants to see. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a display unit and a display control unit for a construction machine, each of which is provided in a cab of the construction machine and displays positional information of a front attachment, such as a bucket end position. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A hydraulic excavator is known as a typical example of construction machines. In the hydraulic excavator, an operator operates front members such as a boom, i.e., constituent members of a front attachment, with corresponding manual control levers. However, it is difficult for the operator to determine whether a trench with a predetermined depth or the face of a slope with a predetermined gradient is precisely excavated, only by visually observing the operation of the front attachment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> in Specification of U.S. Pat. No. 5,887,365 shows a monitoring unit, i.e., EX-200X Level Master made by Hitachi Construction Machinery Co., Ltd., which is a unit provided in a hydraulic excavator for displaying positional information of a bucket as a working device located at a fore end of a front attachment and for setting a preset target excavation plane when a bucket position is controlled so as not to protrude out of the preset target excavation plane. Such a monitoring unit displays just numerically the positional information of the bucket and setting information of the target excavation plane. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Also, a display unit disclosed in JP,A 10-103925 is known as a unit for entering setting values of depth and gradient for automatic control of a front attachment, and displaying a target excavation plane based on the setting values and the bucket position. The disclosed display unit is able to represent four kinds of setup screens for numerically displaying setting information of the target excavation plane, etc. corresponding to four kinds of control modes, and allows for an operator to set the target excavation plane using the setup screens. When a separately provided trigger switch is depressed in each of the setup screens, automatic control is started and the setup screen is changed to an under-control screen on which the bucket, the target excavation plane, etc. are displayed in the form of symbolic illustrations. Further, the display unit is constructed in the form of a touch panel, and the operator depresses the touch panel to change the setup screen from one to another and to enter numerical values on each of the setup screens. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DISCLOSURE OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The monitoring unit described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,887,365 displays numerically the positional information of the working device located at the fore end of the front attachment and the setting information of the target excavation plane. This gives rise to a problem that it is difficult for the operator to visually recognize the position of the working device located at the fore end of the front attachment and the setting state of the target excavation plane with the aid of display of the numerical values only. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The display unit disclosed in JP,A 10-103925 also has a similar problem because the setup screens used for setting the target excavation plane, etc. display numerically the setting information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Further, the disclosed display unit has the following problems because its primary object resides in making setting for automatic control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> 1) When automatic control is started, the setup screen is changed to the under-control screen on which the bucket, the target excavation plane, etc. are displayed in the form of symbolic illustrations. However, the display unit lacks flexibility in selection of the displayed contents. Once the under-control screen is displayed, a shift to another screen is not allowed until the relevant control comes to an end. Accordingly, the operator cannot see the positional information, such as the body tilt angle and the bucket end height, during the automatic control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> 2) During a period in which the automatic control is not performed, the setup screen is only displayed. Therefore, the operator cannot see the attitude of the body and the bucket or the target excavation plane during the period not under control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> 3) Entry of numerical values for the automatic control is made using the touch panel of the display unit. The site where hydraulic excavators are working, however, undergoes severe environmental conditions in points of, e.g., dust and temperature. Further, the operator often depresses the touch panel with a glove or the like put on the hand. This gives rise to a problem in operability and durability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A first object of the present invention is to provide a display unit and a display control unit for a construction machine, which allow for an operator to easily set a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control, and to freely change the contents to be displayed regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control, so that information which the operator wants to see can be promptly displayed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A second object of the present invention is to provide a display unit for a construction machine, which is superior in operability and durability in addition to the above advantages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> (1) To achieve the above first object, the present invention provides a display unit for a construction machine, the display unit being provided in a cab of the construction machine including a front attachment, and comprising a display portion for displaying positional information of the front attachment and setting information for automatic control of the front attachment, and an operating portion for instructing change of contents displayed on the display portion, thereby controlling the displayed contents in accordance with an instruction from the operating portion, wherein the display portion is capable of selectively displaying a first screen for displaying the setting state of a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, and at least one second screen for providing another display, each of the first and second screens having a menu area used for changing the first and second screens from one to the other in accordance with an instruction from the operating portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Since the display portion is capable of selectively displaying the first screen for displaying the setting state of the target plane or area in works by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, and at least one second screen for providing another display, various settings for the automatic control can be made by displaying the first screen. Also, since each of the first and second screens has a menu area for screen change, a screen image can be changed from the first screen to the second screen or vice versa by instructing screen change with manipulation made on the operating portion. Therefore, the screen image can be changed to the second screen even under control so that the operator can confirm positional information of the body, etc., and the screen image can be changed to the first screen even under not control so that the operator can set the automatic control or confirm the setting state. Thus, the contents to be displayed can be freely changed regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control, and the information that the operator wants to see can be promptly displayed. Hence, an improvement of the work efficiency is expected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> (2) To achieve the second object, in the present invention according to above (1), the operating portion includes selection keys, numerical value entry keys, and a decision key; the first screen changes display of the setting state upon manipulation of the numerical value entry keys; and the menu area in each of the first and second screens is used for changing the first and second screens from one to the other with manipulation of the selection keys and the decision key. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> With those features, the display portion is no longer required to use a touch panel, and operability and durability of the display unit can be improved even in any site where construction machines are working. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> (3) In above (1), preferably, when the automatic control is started, each of the first and second screens displays that the construction machine is under control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> With that feature, even when the screen image on the display portion is changed to any screen, the operator is able to know that the machine is currently under the automatic control, and hence to perform works without anxiety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> (4) In above (1), preferably, the second screen includes a screen for displaying, in enlarged scale, the positional relationship of a fore end of the front attachment relative to the target plane or area in the works by using a movable symbolic illustration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> With that feature, when works are performed in a location where the operator cannot visually confirm the position of the bucket fore end, the operator is able to perform the works while always confirming the position of the bucket fore end and the position of the target plane or area in the works by looking at the second screen. The excavation monitoring screen is effective. Further, since the screen image can be changed to the second screen even when the automatic control is turned OFF, excavation works to obtain the target plane or area can be performed with the operator&apos;s operation while looking at the second screen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> (5) In above (1), preferably, the menu area has a plurality of items including an item of screen change; the operating portion includes first entry means for selecting a desired one of the plurality of items in the menu area, and second entry means for deciding the selection made by the first entry means; and the display portion changes the first and second screens from one to the other when the item of screen change is selected by the first entry means and the selection of the item of screen change is decided by the second entry means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> With those features, the first and second screens can be changed from one to the other using the operating portion (first and second entry means) and the menu area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> (6) In above (1), preferably, the menu area of the first screen has an item of screen change and an item of automatic control ON/OFF; and the display portion changes the first and second screens from one to the other regardless of the selected state of the item of automatic control ON/OFF when selection of the item of screen change is instructed from the operating portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> With those features, the first and second screens can be freely changed from one to the other with the aid of the menu area regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> (7) In above (1), preferably, the menu area of the first screen has a plurality of items including an item of screen change and an item of automatic control ON/OFF; the menu area of the second screen has a plurality of items including an item of screen change; the operating portion includes first entry means for selecting a desired one of the plurality of items in the menu area, and second entry means for deciding the selection made by the first entry means; and when one item is selected by the first entry means and the selection of the one item is decided by the second entry means, the display portion executes the selected item. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> With those features, the first and second screens can be freely changed from one to the other with the aid of the menu area upon manipulation of the first and second entry means regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> (8) Also, to achieve the above first object, the present invention provides a display unit for a construction machine, the display unit being provided in a cab of the construction machine including a front attachment, and comprising a display portion for displaying positional information of the front attachment and setting information for automatic control of the front attachment, and an operating portion for instructing change of contents displayed on the display portion, thereby controlling the displayed contents in accordance with an instruction from the operating portion, wherein the display portion is capable of selectively displaying a first screen for displaying the setting state of a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, a second screen for displaying sates of a body of the construction machine and the front attachment by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, and a third screen for displaying, in enlarged scale, the positional relationship of a fore end of the front attachment relative to the target plane or area in the works by using a movable symbolic illustration, each of the first, second and third screens having a menu area used for changing the first, second and third screens from one to another in accordance with an instruction from the operating portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> With those features, as described in above (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), the target plane or area in the works to be performed under the automatic control can be easily set, and the contents to be displayed can be freely changed regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control. Hence, information that the operator wants to see can be promptly displayed, and the work efficiency can be improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> (9) Further, to achieve the above first object, the present invention provides a display control unit for a construction machine, the display control unit being provided in a cab of the construction machine including a front attachment and controlling, in accordance with an instruction from an operating portion, contents displayed on a display portion for displaying positional information of the front attachment and setting information for automatic control of the front attachment, the display control unit comprising first control means for causing the display portion to selectively display a first screen for displaying the setting state of a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, and at least one second screen for providing another display, and to display a menu area including an item of screen change in each of the first and second screens; and second control means for processing the item of screen change in accordance with an instruction from the operating portion and changing the first and second screens from one to the other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> With those features, as described in above (1), the target plane or area in the works to be performed under the automatic control can be easily set, and the contents to be displayed can be freely changed regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control. Hence, information that the operator wants to see can be promptly displayed, and the work efficiency can be improved.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view showing a layout in a cab of a hydraulic excavator provided with a display unit according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing the display unit according to one embodiment of the present invention along with a hydraulic excavator and a hydraulic circuit thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a configuration of a control unit for the hydraulic excavator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a configuration of a display control unit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a representation showing a standard monitoring screen displayed on the display unit according to one embodiment of the present invention, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is a representation for explaining the displayed contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> is a representation showing an excavation setting screen displayed on the display unit, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> is a representation for explaining the displayed contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> is a representation showing an excavation monitoring screen displayed on the display unit, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> is a representation for explaining the displayed contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a representation showing a transition among the screens displayed on the display unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when electric power is supplied to the display control unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when a cursor in a menu area of the standard monitoring screen is moved to &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor in the menu area of the standard monitoring screen is moved to &ldquo;0-POINT SETTING&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when a screen image is changed from the standard monitoring screen to the excavation setting screen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when a cursor in a menu area of the excavation setting screen is moved to &ldquo;DEPTH&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor in the menu area of the excavation setting screen is moved to &ldquo;GRADIENT&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor in the menu area of the excavation setting screen is moved to &ldquo;CONTROL ON/OFF&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when a screen image is changed from the excavation setting screen to the excavation monitoring screen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when a cursor in a menu area of the excavation monitoring screen is moved to &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo;.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Hereinbelow, an embodiment of the present invention will be described with reference to the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view showing a layout in a cab of a hydraulic excavator provided with a display unit according to the embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, numeral <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> denotes the entirety of the cab. Four sides of the cab <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are surrounded by corner flames a, b, c, d, side frames e, f, and windowpanes g to 1. An operator seat <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is provided inside the cab <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Also, inside the cab <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, control lever units <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>R for operating a front attachment and swinging a body are disposed on both side of a front portion of the operator seat <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, travel pedals <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>R and travel levers <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>R are disposed in front of the operator seat <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, and console boxes <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>R are disposed both sides of the operator seat <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. In the console boxes <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>R, there are provided a console panel <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>, an air conditioner unit <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>, a radio <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, and so on, the console panel <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> including monitors for indicating the temperature of a hydraulic working fluid (oil), the remaining amount of fuel, etc., and switches for setting an operating mode and an engine target revolution speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing the display unit according to one embodiment of the present invention along with a hydraulic excavator and a hydraulic circuit thereof. A hydraulic excavator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comprises a lower track structure <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, an upper swing structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and a front attachment <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The upper swing structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is driven to revolve by a swing motor (not shown) mounted on the lower track structure <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and the front attachment <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is vertically rotatably mounted to a front portion of the upper swing structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The upper swing structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> comprises an accommodating room <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, a counterweight <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the cab <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and so on. The front attachment <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is of a multi-articulated structure comprising a boom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, an arm <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and a bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The boom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the arm <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are driven to rotate by a boom cylinder <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, an arm cylinder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a bucket cylinder <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The boom cylinder <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the arm cylinder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the bucket cylinder <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are connected to a hydraulic pump <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> through control valves <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, respectively. The flow rates and directions of hydraulic fluids supplied from the hydraulic pump <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to the respective cylinders <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are adjusted by the control valves <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Though not shown for simplicity of the drawing, the hydraulic excavator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> further includes the swing motor and a corresponding swing control valve. The swing control valve controls the flow rate and direction of a hydraulic fluid supplied from the hydraulic pump <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to the swing motor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The control lever units <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>R are provided in association with the control valves <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the swing control valve. The control levers <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>R include respectively control levers <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and potentiometers <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. When the control lever <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is operated in a back-and-forth direction A, a stroke by which the control lever <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is operated is detected by the potentiometer <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which outputs an electrical operating signal X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> depending on the lever stroke. When the control lever <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is operated in a left-and-right direction B, a stroke by which the control lever <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is operated is detected by the potentiometer <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which outputs an electrical operating signal X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> depending on the lever stroke. When the control lever <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is operated in a back-and-forth direction C, a stroke by which the control lever <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is operated is detected by the potentiometer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which outputs an electrical operating signal X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> depending on the lever stroke. When the control lever <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is operated in a left-and-right direction D, a stroke by which the control lever <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is operated is detected by the potentiometer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which outputs an electrical operating signal X<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> depending on the lever stroke. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The operating signals X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> outputted from the potentiometers <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are sent to a control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> executes predetermined computations based on the operating signals X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and outputs control signals to solenoid proportional valves <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>R and a solenoid proportional valve provided in the swing control valve (not shown). The solenoid proportional valves <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>R are provided for hydraulic driving of the control valves <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> such that the shift directions and opening degrees of the control valves <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are regulated in accordance with respective pilot pressures instructed by the solenoid proportional valves <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>L. <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>L, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>R. The solenoid proportional valve provided in the swing control valve also operates in a similar manner. As a result, the directions and flow rates of the hydraulic fluids supplied from the hydraulic pump <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to the boom cylinder <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the arm cylinder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the bucket cylinder <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and the swing motor (not shown) are limited. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Also, a rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> for detecting the rotational angle of the boom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is disposed on the boom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, an arm rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> for detecting the rotational angle of the arm <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is disposed on the arm <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, and a bucket angle sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for detecting the rotational angle of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is disposed on the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The boom rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the arm rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, and the bucket rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> output electrical angle signals &agr;, &bgr;, &ggr;, respectively, depending on the attitude of the front attachment <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Further, a transverse tilt angle sensor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> for detecting the transverse tilt angle sensor of the body is disposed inside the cab <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> to output an electrical angle signal &sgr; depending on the transverse tilt angle of the body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The angle signals &agr;, &bgr;, &ggr;, &sgr; outputted from the boom rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the arm rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, the bucket rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the transverse tilt angle sensor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> are inputted to the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> computes the position of the fore end of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, etc. based on the angle signals &agr;, &bgr;, &ggr;, and outputs via a serial communication line <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> a computed result, as display data, to the display unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> according to this embodiment. Moreover, in accordance with an instruction (described later) to start automatic control, the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> executes, e.g., area limiting control in which the front attachment <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is controlled so as not to protrude out of the set range with the operation of the operator, area limiting excavation control in which when the front attachment <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is about to protrude out of the set range, it is controlled so as to operate along the set range, or locus control in which the front attachment <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is controlled so as to operate along the set locus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The display unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> comprises a display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, a display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and an operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The display data from the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is inputted to the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> displays the inputted display data on the display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and transmits data instructing the displayed contents and the contents of computation, which are required for the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, or numerical value data, such as the depth and gradient of the target excavation plane, for automatic control to the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> via the serial communication line <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> in accordance with an operating signal from the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Returning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is attached to the corner frame a diagonally to the left of the operator seat <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> inside the cab <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is housed in the console box <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>R on the right side, and the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is also provided in the console box <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>R on the right side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> includes, e.g., an LCD <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>serving as an image display portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> includes, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, up and down selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, numerical value increment and decrement entry keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, and a decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a configuration of the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> comprises a single-chip microcomputer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a nonvolatile memory (EEPROM) <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> for storing control constants, dimensional data, etc. for each model and each grade, and an amplifier <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. The single-chip microcomputer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes an A/D converter <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> for converting the angle signals &agr;, &bgr;, &ggr;, &sgr; inputted respectively from the boom rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the arm rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, the bucket rotational angle sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the transverse tilt angle sensor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and the operating signals X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> inputted respectively from the potentiometers <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>into digital signals; a central processing unit (CPU) <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>; a read only memory (ROM) <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> for storing programs for control procedures and constants necessary for control; a random access memory (RAM) <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> for temporarily storing numerical values given as computed results or obtained in the course of computation; a serial communication interface (SCI) <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> for communicating with the control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the display unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>; and a D/A converter <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> for converting digital signals into analog signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a configuration of the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the display unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> comprises a single-chip microcomputer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, a memory <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> used for drawing or processing the contents to be displayed on the display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, a display computing portion <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> for executing computation required for providing display, and an interface <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> for outputting the displayed contents, which are created by the display computing portion <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>. The single-chip microcomputer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes an interface (I/O) <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> for taking in the operating signal from the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>; a central processing unit (CPU) <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>; a read only memory (ROM) <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for storing programs for control procedures and constants necessary for control; a random access memory (RAM) <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> for temporarily storing numerical values given as computed results or obtained in the course of computation; a serial communication interface (SCI) <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> for communicating with the control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Next, the contents displayed on the display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A, 6A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A show three kinds of screen images selectively displayed on the LCD <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> shows a standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> for displaying attitude information of the body, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> shows an excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> for displaying the setting states of depth and gradient of the target excavation plane for automatic control, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> shows an excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for displaying, in an enlarged scale, relative positions of the target excavation plane set on the excavation setting screen and the bucket. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5B, 6B</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>B are representations for explaining the contents displayed as the respective screens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A, 6A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A, each of the screens <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> has a main screen area <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> in which objective information is displayed, and a menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> that is positioned on the right side of the main screen area <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and serves as a sub-screen area. In the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, a plurality of items are set depending on each type of screen information. Selection and execution of each item in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> are effectuated using the up and down selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. More specifically, a cursor for displaying items in reverse video one by one is disposed in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The subject represented by the item displayed in reverse video is executed by moving the cursor vertically to select a desired one of the items in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> with manipulation of the up and down selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, and then depressing the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Details of the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, and the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> will be described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>A, the main screen area <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> displays three kinds of information, i.e., the height of the fore end of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the transverse tilt angle of the body, and the bucket angle shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>B, which are computed by and sent from the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, in respective allocated areas by using numerical values and movable symbolic illustrations at the same time. The height of the fore end of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated by displaying a straight line indicating the ground surface, characters GL implying the ground level, and a bucket symbol indicating a height position, relative to the ground level, variable depending on the height of the fore end of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which is calculated by the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The transverse tilt angle of the body is illustrated by displaying a body symbol tiltable depending on the transverse tilt angle of the body, which is calculated by the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The bucket angle is illustrated by displaying a bucket symbol rotatable depending on the angle of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which is calculated by the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The angle of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is represented by an angle relative to the ground (i.e., an angle of the bucket rear surface relative to a horizontal plane). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> displays items &ldquo;0-POINT SETTING&rdquo;, &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; and &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo;. When &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is selected and executed using the up and down selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the angle unit of the transverse tilt angle and the bucket angle both displayed in the main screen area <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> can be changed in the order of &ldquo;&deg;&rdquo;&rarr;&ldquo;%&rdquo;&rarr;&ldquo;proportion&rdquo; in turn. When &ldquo;0-POINT SETTING&rdquo; is selected and executed, an arrow is moved to the current height position of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> calculates the bucket height with the current position being as a reference, and the calculated bucket height is displayed as a numerical value. When &ldquo;0-POINT SETTING&rdquo; is selected and executed again, the display reference is returned to an original one; namely, the bucket height position is displayed relative to the ground level GL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> When &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is selected and executed, the screen image is changed from the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A, the main screen area <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> displays not only the body in the form of a symbol, but also the setting states of depth and gradient of the target excavation plane for automatic control using numerical values and a straight line movable depending on the setting values. Further, in the case of using, as an external reference, a laser reference plane as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>B, the laser reference plane is displayed in the form of a broken line movable vertically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> displays items &ldquo;CONTROL ON/OFF&rdquo;, &ldquo;GADIENT&rdquo;, &ldquo;DEPTH&rdquo; and &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo;. The gradient of the target excavation plane can be set by selecting &ldquo;GRADIENT&rdquo; in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> with the selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, and by manipulating the numerical value entry keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and then depressing the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. On that occasion, with the manipulation of the numerical value entry keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, the numerical value of the gradient displayed on the screen is incremented or decremented, and the gradient of the straight line representing the target excavation plane is changed. Further, in the case of using the laser reference plane, the target excavation plane is displayed in parallel to the laser reference plane, and the gradient of the broken line representing the target excavation plane is also changed with the manipulation of the numerical value entry keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. The laser reference plane is set and displayed upon an external reference setting switch (not shown) being depressed when a predetermined position of the front attachment (in the illustrated embodiment, fulcrum at which the arm is rotatable relative to the boom) matches with the laser reference plane. In the case of not employing the laser reference plane, the gradient of the target excavation plane is set and displayed with the center of the underside of the body, for example, being as a reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Likewise, the depth of the target excavation plane can be set by selecting &ldquo;DEPTH&rdquo; with the selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, manipulating the numerical value entry keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, and then depressing the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. On that occasion, with the manipulation of the numerical value entry keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, the numerical value of the setting depth displayed on the screen is incremented or decremented, and the straight line representing the target excavation plane is moved vertically. Further, in the case of using the laser reference plane, the depth of the target excavation plane is set as a value from the laser reference plane, and the target excavation plane is vertically moved relative to the laser reference plane. In the case of not employing the laser reference plane, the depth of the target excavation plane is set and displayed with the ground level, for example, being as a reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Moreover, warning can be displayed, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A, by providing a hydraulic-working-fluid temperature sensor (not shown), taking in a signal from the temperature sensor to the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to determine the temperature state of the hydraulic working fluid, and transmitting, from the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, a command for displaying a message that arouses the operator attention to perform the warm-up operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> When &ldquo;CONTROL ON/OFF&rdquo; in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is selected and executed using the up and down selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, automatic control is started. During a period in which the automatic control is performed, &ldquo;UNDER CONTROL&rdquo; is displayed, as shown, on the screen. The display of &ldquo;UNDER CONTROL&rdquo; is continued even after change to another screen, i.e., even after the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is changed to the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> or the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, described later, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference>. Additionally, the setting of the target excavation plane can be made regardless of whether the automatic control is turned ON or OFF. When &ldquo;CONTROL ON/OFF&rdquo; in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is selected and executed again, the automatic control is brought into an end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> When &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is selected and executed, the screen image is changed from the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> to the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, the main screen area <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> displays, in an enlarged scale, the positional relationship between the target excavation plane set on the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>B, by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration. As with the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, the target excavation plane is displayed using a straight line movable depending on the setting state. The bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated by displaying a bucket symbol that is moved and rotated depending on the attitude of the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the positional relationship between the bucket and the target excavation plane, which are calculated by the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The operator is therefore able to perform works while always confirming the position of the bucket fore end and the position of the target excavation plane by looking at the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The excavation monitoring screen is effective when the operator performs works in a location where he cannot visually confirm the position of the bucket fore end. Further, the works under such conditions can be performed with the aid of the excavation monitoring screen even when the automatic control is turned OFF. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> displays items &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; and &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo;. When &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; is selected and executed, the angle unit can be changed in the same manner as with the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> When &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is selected and executed, the screen image is changed from the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows a screen transition among &ldquo;the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, &ldquo;the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, and &ldquo;the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>&rdquo; described above. The operator is able to freely change the displayed contents in sequence by selecting and executing &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, as described above, using the up and down selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Processing steps executed in the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to perform the above-mentioned display control will be described with reference to flowcharts shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. These processing steps are executed in accordance with programs stored in the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when electric power is supplied to the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Upon power-on of the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is displayed as an initial screen image, and the cursor initial position in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is set to &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>). At this time, the angle unit of the transverse tilt angle and the bucket angle both displayed on the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is given as an initial angle unit of &ldquo;&deg;&rdquo;. Subsequently, the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is depressed (step S<highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>), and then determines whether the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>). Upon the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>being depressed, the screen image is changed to the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> (step S<highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>). Upon the up selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>). Upon the down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;0-POINT SETTING&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is moved to &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. The display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is depressed (step S<highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>), and then whether the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>). Upon the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>being depressed, the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the current angle unit is &ldquo;&deg;&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>), and then whether the current angle unit is &ldquo;%&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>). Depending on the determination result, the angle unit is set to &ldquo;%&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>), &ldquo;proportion&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>), or &ldquo;&deg;&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>). On the standard setting screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, &ldquo;&deg;&rdquo; is displayed as the initial angle unit of the transverse tilt angle and the bucket angle. When the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>is depressed for the first time after the power-on, the determination in step S<highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is responded by Yes because the current angle unit is &ldquo;&deg;&rdquo;, and hence the angle unit is changed to &ldquo;%&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, when the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>is depressed again, the determination in step S<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is responded by No and the determination in step S<highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> is responded by Yes, whereupon the angle unit is changed to &ldquo;proportion&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, when the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>is depressed again, the determinations in steps S<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> are responded by No, and hence the angle unit is changed to &ldquo;&deg;&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Further, upon the up selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;0-POINT SETTING&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>). Upon the down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is moved to &ldquo;0-POINT SETTING&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. The display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is depressed (step S<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>), and then whether the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>). Upon the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> being depressed, 0-point setting processing is executed. More specifically, the current bucket height is assumed to be <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, and the bucket height is displayed thereafter on that assumption. Further, upon the up selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>). Upon the down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the screen image is changed to the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> in step S<highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. The display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is depressed (step S<highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>), and then whether the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>). At this time, the cursor in the menu area is set to &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo;. Upon the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> being depressed, the screen image is changed to the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> (step S<highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>). Upon the up selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;DEPTH&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>). Upon the down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;CONTROL ON/OFF&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is moved to &ldquo;DEPTH&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. The display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1512</bold></highlight>), and then determines whether the numerical value increment or decrement entry key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>153</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>). Upon the up selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;GRADIENT&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>), and upon the down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>). Further, upon the numerical value increment entry key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>being depressed, the numerical value of the depth setting is incremented (step S<highlight><bold>157</bold></highlight>), and upon the numerical value decrement entry key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>being depressed, the numerical value of the depth setting is decremented (step S<highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is moved to &ldquo;GRADIENT&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. The display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>), and then determines whether the numerical value increment or decrement entry key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>). Upon the up selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;CONTROL ON/OFF&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight>), and upon the down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;DEPTH&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>). Further, upon the numerical value increment entry key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>being depressed, the numerical value of the gradient setting is incremented (step S<highlight><bold>167</bold></highlight>), and upon the numerical value decrement entry key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>being depressed, the numerical value of the gradient setting is decremented (step S<highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor in the menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is moved to &ldquo;CONTROL ON/OFF&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. The display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>), and then determines whether the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>). Upon the up selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight>), and upon the down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;GRADIENT&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight>). Upon the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>being depressed, the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the machine is in the control status and &ldquo;UNDER CONTROL&rdquo; is displayed (step S<highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>). If the machine is in the control status, the display of &ldquo;UNDER CONTROL&rdquo; is turned off and a command instructing control OFF is sent to the control unit (step S<highlight><bold>177</bold></highlight>). If the machine is not in the control status, the display of &ldquo;UNDER CONTROL&rdquo; is turned on and a command instructing control ON is sent to the control unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (step S<highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the screen image is changed to the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> in step S<highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. At this time, the cursor is set to the position of &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo;. Also, the angle unit of the bucket angle displayed on the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is displayed as an initial unit of &ldquo;&deg;&rdquo;. Subsequently, the display control unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> determines whether the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is depressed (step S<highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight>), and then determines whether the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is depressed (steps S<highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>). Upon the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> being depressed, the screen image is changed to the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> (step S<highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>). Upon the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing processing steps when the cursor is moved to &ldquo;ANGLE UNIT&rdquo; in step S<highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. Steps S<highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> to S<highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> are the same as steps S<highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to S<highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of the flowchart shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. In the case of the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> being not depressed, if the up selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;0-POINT SETTING&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>), and if the up or down selection key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is depressed, the cursor is moved to &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; (step S<highlight><bold>199</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> This embodiment having the above-described construction can provide advantages given below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> 1) On the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, not only the setting states of depth and gradient of the target excavation plane for automatic control is displayed using numerical values, but also the setting state of the target excavation plane is displayed using a straight line movable depending on entered numerical values of the depth and gradient in relation to the body displayed in the form of a symbol. Therefore, the operator is able to easily make various settings for the automatic control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> 2) The menu area <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> including the item &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; is prepared in each of three kinds of screens <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, particularly including the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, and those screens are changed from one to another by selecting and executing the item &ldquo;SCREEN CHANGE&rdquo; with key manipulation on the operating unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the operator is able to freely change those screens regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control. For example, the operator can make setting for the automatic control on the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, perform works with the automatic control turned ON, and thereafter return to the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> for looking at the attitude information. Also, even under the automatic control, after performing works with the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, the operator can return to the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> to confirm the setting state and to change the setting. Thus, it is possible to promptly select and display the information required for the operator, and to improve the work efficiency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> 3) Even with the automatic control turned OFF, the screen image can be changed to the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, and the positional relationship between the target excavation plane and the bucket <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is displayed in enlarged scale on the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> using numerical values and a symbolic illustration. Accordingly, even when works are performed in a location where the operator cannot visually confirm the position of the bucket fore end, the operator is able to perform the works while confirming the target excavation plane and the bucket position by looking at the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. This results in an improvement of the work efficiency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> 4) Since entry of setting values and selection/execution of each of the items in the menu area are performed with key manipulation, the display unit can be more easily operated than a touch panel type display unit even in any site where hydraulic excavators are working. In addition, the life of the LCD used in the display unit can be prolonged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> 5) When the automatic control is turned ON, characters &ldquo;UNDER CONTROL&rdquo; are displayed on all the three kinds of screens. Therefore, even when the screen image is changed to any of the three kinds of screens, the operator is able to know that the machine is currently under the automatic control, and hence to perform works without anxiety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> While one embodiment of the present invention has been described above, the present invention is not limited to the embodiment, and various modifications and additions can be made without departing from the scope of the spirit of the present invention. For example, in the embodiment described above, the standard monitoring screen <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the excavation monitoring screen <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are prepared in addition to the screen (the excavation setting screen <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) on which the setting state of a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control is displayed using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration. Instead of or in addition to those monitoring screen, other screens may also be displayed. The other conceivable screens include, for example, a meter information screen for displaying information from meters such as a fuel meter, a hydraulic pressure/temperature meter and an engine cooling-water temperature meter, an abnormality alarm information screen for displaying a water temperature abnormality and an oil temperature abnormality, and an operation information screen for displaying operation information regarding the engine rotational load, the excavation load, the travel load, the swing load, etc. Anyway, each of those screens includes a menu area used for changing the screens from one to another in accordance with an instruction provided from the operating unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Further, while the operating unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is separate from the display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the above-described embodiment, it may be integral with the display <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. In addition, the arrangement and form of the up and down selection keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the numerical value increment and decrement entry keys <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, and the decision key <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>disposed on the operating unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be modified in various ways. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control can be easily set, and the contents to be displayed can be freely changed regardless of whether the machine is under the automatic control. It is hence possible to promptly display the information that the operator wants to see, and to improve the work efficiency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Also, according to the present invention, operability and durability of the display unit can be improved even in any site where construction machines are working. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Further, according to the present invention, when the automatic control is turned ON, characters &ldquo;UNDER CONTROL&rdquo; are displayed on all the three kinds of screens. Therefore, even when the screen image is changed to any of the three kinds of screens, the operator is able to know that the machine is currently under the automatic control, and hence to perform works without anxiety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Moreover, according to the present invention, even when works are performed in a location where the operator cannot visually confirm the position of the bucket fore end, the operator is able to perform the works while confirming the target excavation plane and the bucket position by looking at the screen. The works can also be performed even with the automatic control turned OFF. This results in an improvement of the work efficiency. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A display unit for a construction machine, said display unit being provided in a cab (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) of said construction machine including a front attachment (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>), and comprising a display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) for displaying positional information of said front attachment and setting information for automatic control of said front attachment, and an operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>) for instructing change of contents displayed on said display portion, thereby controlling the displayed contents in accordance with an instruction from said operating portion, 
<claim-text>wherein said display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) is capable of selectively displaying a first screen (<highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) for displaying the setting state of a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, and at least one second screen (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) for providing another display, </claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said first and second screens having a menu area (<highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) used for changing said first and second screens from one to the other in accordance with an instruction from said operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A display unit for a construction machine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>) includes selection keys (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), numerical value entry keys (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>), and a decision key (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>); 
<claim-text>said first screen (<highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) changes display of the setting state upon manipulation of said numerical value entry keys; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said menu area (<highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) in each of said first and second screens (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) is used for changing said first and second screens from one to the other with manipulation of said selection keys and said decision key. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A display unit for a construction machine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the automatic control is started, each of said first and second screens (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) displays that said construction machine is under control. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A display unit for a construction machine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second screen includes a screen (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) for displaying, in enlarged scale, the positional relationship of a fore end of said front attachment (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) relative to the target plane or area in said works by using a movable symbolic illustration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A display unit for a construction machine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said menu area (<highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) has a plurality of items including an item of screen change; 
<claim-text>said operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>) includes first entry means (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) for selecting a desired one of the plurality of items in said menu area, and second entry means (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>) for deciding the selection made by said first entry means; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) changes said first and second screens from one to the other when said item of screen change is selected by said first entry means and the selection of said item of screen change is decided by said second entry means. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A display unit for a construction machine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said menu area (<highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) of said first screen (<highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) has an item of screen change and an item of automatic control ON/OFF; and 
<claim-text>said display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) changes said first and second screens from one to the other regardless of the selected state of said item of automatic control ON/OFF when selection of said item of screen change is instructed from said operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A display unit for a construction machine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said menu area (<highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) of said first screen (<highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) has a plurality of items including an item of screen change and an item of automatic control ON/OFF; 
<claim-text>said menu area (<highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) of said second screen (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) has a plurality of items including an item of screen change; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>) includes first entry means (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) for selecting a desired one of the plurality of items in said menu area, and second entry means (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>) for deciding the selection made by said first entry means; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>when one item is selected by said first entry means and the selection of the one item is decided by said second entry means, said display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) executes the selected item. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A display unit (<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>) for a construction machine, said display unit being provided in a cab (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) of said construction machine including a front attachment (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>), and comprising a display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) for displaying positional information of said front attachment and setting information for automatic control of said front attachment, and an operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>) for instructing change of contents displayed on said display portion, thereby controlling the displayed contents in accordance with an instruction from said operating portion, 
<claim-text>wherein said display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) is capable of selectively displaying a first screen (<highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) for displaying the setting state of a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, a second screen (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>) for displaying sates of a body (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) of said construction machine and said front attachment (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, and a third screen (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) for displaying, in enlarged scale, the positional relationship of a fore end of said front attachment relative to the target plane or area in said works by using a movable symbolic illustration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said first, second and third screens having a menu area (<highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) used for changing said first, second and third screens from one to another in accordance with an instruction from said operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A display control unit (<highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>) for a construction machine, said display control unit being provided in a cab (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) of said construction machine including a front attachment (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) and controlling, in accordance with an instruction from an operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>), contents displayed on a display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) for displaying positional information of said front attachment and setting information for automatic control of said front attachment, said display control unit comprising: 
<claim-text>first control means (<highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>) for causing said display portion (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) to selectively display a first screen (<highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) for displaying the setting state of a target plane or area in works to be performed under automatic control by using numerical values and a movable symbolic illustration, and at least one second screen (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) for providing another display, and to display a menu area including an item of screen change in each of said first and second screens; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>second control means (<highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>) for processing said item of screen change in accordance with an instruction from said operating portion (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>) and changing said first and second screens from one to the other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030001751A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
