<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005345A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005345A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005345A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005345A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005345A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005345A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005345A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005345A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005345A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005345A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005345</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893871</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F001/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>713</class>
<subclass>401000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Multistage clock delay circuit and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Thomas</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Fletcher</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Giao</given-name>
<family-name>Pham</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KENYON &amp; KENYON</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1500 K STREET, N.W., SUITE 700</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A clock delay circuit has a plurality of outputs to provide a sequence of clock signals that togther constitute a multistage clock. The circuit further has a delay adjustment input to adjust the timing of the clock signals for at least one of the outputs relative to the clock signals at another of the outputs. In an embodiment, the circuit has a plurality of these delay adjustment inputs. In a further embodiment, the circuit has a plurality of buffer components to delay the clock signals. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the present invention relate to multistage clocks. In particular, embodiments of the present invention relate to the topology of circuits to delay a received clock signal into multiple clock stages. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Electronic systems such as micro-processors often use clock signals to synchronize operation of their various components. Such clock signals may be comprised of a stream of timing pules that occur at a particular rate which is known as the clock rate. In many systems, the operation of each of the components is timed from a single clock signal which may be referred to as the system clock. Some circuits have various stages, or sub-circuits, each of which is timed based upon a different clock. Such circuits may use multiple clocks that have the same rate (for example, the rate of the system clock) but with a delay between the clock signals. The different clock signals used by a circuit maybe referred to as different &ldquo;clock stages&rdquo; and a group of such signals may be referred to as a &ldquo;multistage clock.&rdquo; For example, a second clock stage may be a delayed version of a first stage, a third stage may be a delayed version of the second stage, etc. Circuits that use a multistage clock may have a clock delay circuit or block that is used to delay a received clock, such as the system clock, to provide the various clock stages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;domino circuit&rdquo; is one example of a type of circuit that uses a multistage clock. A domino circuit may be arranged with the outputs from one stage used as inputs into the next stage and with the clock delayed for each of the individual stages in order to provide a set-up time for the stages. Examples of domino circuits are self resetting domino circuits, single ended domino circuits, cascaded domino circuits, and zipper domino circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In many circuits, the differential delay between clock stages determines to a large extent the delay of the logic. For some circuits, such as a cascaded differential domino circuit, it is necessary to create clock signals that have a small difference in the relative delay between stages, which may be referred to as the differential delay. These circuits may not operate properly where there is a significant difference in the relative amount of delay in the clock signals provided to different stages of the circuit. Numerous factors may impact the differential delay for the clock signals. For example, variations in the effective channel length, threshold voltage, or width of transistors in the clock delay circuit may cause differences in the delay. Device mismatches and cross-capacitance in the clock delay circuit may cause clock skew, and the delay of particular size inverter that is to be used in the clock delay circuit may vary due to process variables. In addition, there may be variations in the delay of the logic being driven by the clock signals. These and other factors have made it difficult to design and manufacture a clock delay circuit that provides clock signals with small differences in the relative delay between stages.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a circuit that uses a multistage clock according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a partial block diagram of a clock delay circuit according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flow diagram of a method of providing a plurality of delayed clock signals according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a circuit that uses a multistage clock having programable adjustable delays according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention discloses topologies for clock delay circuits that provide a small differential in the delay between stages. Embodiments of the present invention reduce the number of elements from a common clocking point to the clock outputs, and thus reduce the number of devices mismatches and reduce the differential delay. For example, embodiments reduce the number of inverters used in the clock delay circuit. Embodiments also include delay adjustment blocks that allow for the adjustment of the relative delays. In further embodiments, the delay adjustment blocks are digitally adjustable. In still further embodiments, each stage of the clock is digitally controllable and these digital controls may be programmed to tune the differential delay provided at the clock stages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a multistage circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the present invention. Multistage circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a first logic stage <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> to an nth logic stage <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> as well as a clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that has outputs connected to each of the logic stages. As used herein, the phrase &ldquo;connected&rdquo; encompasses both direct connections and indirect connections. Each logic stage may be a logic gate such as, for example, an AND gate. First logic stage <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> receives data inputs <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and nth logic stage <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> provides data outputs <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>. Multistage circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may contain any number of stages, and in one embodiment has eight stages. In an embodiment, each logic stage <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> may perform a function on its inputs and may pass its outputs as inputs to the next stage. Multistage circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be, for example, a domino circuit, examples of which are discussed below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> receives a clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and provides delayed clock signals (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight>) that form a multistage clock. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the multistage clock is input to the logic stages <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>. In particular, clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> outputs a first stage clock signal <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> that is input to first stage <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, a second stage clock signal <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> that is input to second logic stage <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a third stage clock signal <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> that is input to third logic stage <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, and an nth stage clock signal <highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight> that is input to nth logic stage <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>. Clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may be, for example, the system clock. In an embodiment, each of the clock stages <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight> is a delayed version of the clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, and each successive clock stage is further delayed from clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. For example, there may be a delay of <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> picoseconds (ps) between each of the clock stages <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight>, with second stage clock <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> being <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> ps behind first stage clock <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, third stage clock <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> being <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> ps behind second stage clock <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, etc. This delay may provide set-up time for the logic stages <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>. In embodiments of clock circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, one example of which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the number of gates from a common clocking point to the clock outputs <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight> is reduced in order to reduce the differential delay between clock stages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> has a number of delay adjustment inputs <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> that may be used to adjust the relative amount of delay of clock stages <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight>. For example, a first delay adjustment input may delay the second stage clock <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> relative to the first stage clock <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, and a second delay adjustment input may delay the third stage clock <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> relative to both the second stage clock <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and first stage clock <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. In an embodiment, an adjustment of the delay of a clock stage will also adjust all following stages by the same amount. For example, the first delay adjustment input may delay the second stage clock <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and all following clock stages (e.g., third stage clock <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> to nth stage clock <highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight>) relative to the first stage clock <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. When this embodiment is employed, an adjustment that increases the amount of delay between the first clock stage <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> and second clock stage <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, for example, will not reduce the amount of delay between the second clock stage <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and third clock stage <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> because that adjustment will also increase the delay at the third clock stage (and all following stages) by the same amount. Clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may have any number of delay adjustment inputs. For example, clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may have one delay adjustment input or may have a delay adjustment input for every two adjacent clock stages. In an embodiment, delay adjustment inputs <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> are digital inputs, and thus the delay at the stages of the multistage clock is digitally controllable. An examples of the operation of delay adjustment inputs are described below with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In an embodiment, multistage circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is a cascaded differential domino circuit. A differential circuit may refer to a circuit that has two complimentary sets of input and output terminals, and one or more stages in multistage circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be a differential circuit. In a cascaded domino circuit, each sage may be an N-channel metal-oxide semiconductor (NMOS) domino gate and the outputs of each stage maybe directly connected to the inputs of the next stage. Individual domino logic stages (e.g.,<highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>) may have one or more precharge blocks, which force the circuit to a known state during one phase of a clock, and one or more evaluation blocks, which provide output values that are based on the input values. In an embodiment where multistage circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is a domino circuit, nth stage <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> maybe a converter that converts signals to static logic signals before they are output over outputs <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>. The present invention may be used with domino circuits such as self resetting domino circuits, single ended domino circuits, cascaded domino circuits, and zipper domino circuits. In addition, the present invention may be used in static circuits and, moreover, in any circuits that use multistage clocks. Thus, clock circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is not limited to use in domino circuits and may be used in any circuits where sequence of delayed clock signals is to be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a partial block diagram of a clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the present invention. Clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> has a clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to input a clock signal and a plurality of clock outputs <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> to output a multistage clock. The multistage clock in this example has eight stages, but in other embodiments may have more or less stages. Clock delay circuit contains a plurality of delay blocks (i.e., delay buffer components) <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> to delay the signals provided at the clock stage outputs and a plurality of delay adjustment blocks <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>273</bold></highlight> to adjust the amount these signals are delayed. Four of the delay blocks (<highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>) maybe referred to as common delay blocks in that the output of each of these delay blocks is used in providing two or more of the clock stage outputs. The other eight delay blocks (<highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>) may be referred to as stage delay blocks in that they each only delay the signal for a single clock stage output. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the outputs of each of the common delay blocks (e.g., <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>) is connected to two stage delay blocks (e.g., <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>) and maybe connected to another common delay block (e.g., <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>). The outputs of each of stage delay blocks <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> are connected respectively to the clock stage outputs <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, common delay blocks <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> and stage delay blocks <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> each comprise a chain of two inverters connected serially. In other embodiments, the delay blocks may contain other components that provide delay such as for example a NAND gate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> will now be described in more detail. Clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is connected to a first common delay block <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>, and the output of first common delay block <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> is connected through common point <highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight> as an input to each of first stage delay block <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> (chain of inverters <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>), second stage delay block <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>), and second common delay block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight>). First common delay block <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> comprises a NAND gate <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> connected serially to an inverter <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>. Thus, the output of NAND gate <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is input to inverter <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>, and the output of inverter <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> is the output of first common delay block <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. The inputs to NAND gate <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> are clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and circuit enable <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. When circuit enable <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is low, clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is disabled and, thus, the multistage clock is stopped. Other embodiments of clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may not contain a circuit enable input and/or may not contain a first common delay block <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. The output of first stage delay block <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> is connected to first stage output <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>, and the output of second stage delay block <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is connected to second stage output <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The output of second common delay block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is connected through common point <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> as an input to each of third stage delay block <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight>), fourth stage delay block <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight>), and third common delay block <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight>). Similarly, third common delay block <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> is connected through common point <highlight><bold>293</bold></highlight> as an input to each of fifth stage delay block <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>), sixth stage delay block <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight>), and fourth common delay block <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>259</bold></highlight>). Finally, fourth common delay block <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> is connected through common point <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> as an input to each of seventh stage delay block <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>261</bold></highlight>) and eighth stage delay block <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> (chained inverters <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>263</bold></highlight>). In other embodiments that have more than eight clock stages, fourth common delay block <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> may be connected to a fifth common delay block. Embodiments that have less than eight clock stages may have less than four common delay blocks. As discussed above, the outputs of third stage delay block <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> to eighth stage delay block <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> are provided to third stage clock output <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> to eighth stage clock output <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, there is a serial electrical connection path (&ldquo;path&rdquo;) from the clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to each of the clock outputs <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. In an embodiment, each of the delay blocks <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> are part of a single path from clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to only one of the clock outputs. For example, first stage delay block <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> is part of the path from clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to first stage clock output <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> but is not part of the path from clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to any other clock output. By contrast, each common delay block (e.g., <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>) in this embodiment is part of paths from the clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to at least two of the clock outputs (e.g., <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>). The clock signal provided at point <highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight> is used to provide each of the clock stage outputs <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>, the clock signal provided at point <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> is used to provide each of the clock stage outputs <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>, the clock signal provided at point <highlight><bold>293</bold></highlight> is used to provide each of the clock stage outputs <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>, and the clock signal provided at point <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> is used to provide each of the clock stage outputs <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. Points <highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> may therefore be referred to as common clocking points. This embodiment reduces the number of elements from each common clocking point to the clock outputs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In an embodiment, the clock outputs have a sequence (e.g., <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> is first, <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> is second, etc.) and there is a delay of approximately time t between each two adjacent clock signals in the sequence. In this embodiment, the amount of delay in the signal at each of the clock outputs differs from the amount of delay in the signal at the other clock outputs by approximately a multiple time t. In an embodiment, time t is approximately the high to low delay of an inverter with a fanout of 2. The time t could be faster or slower relative to an inverter with a fanout of 2 depending upon circuit complexity. A person of skill in the art would appreciate that an inverter has a fanout of 2 if the load on the output is two times the load on the input. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In an embodiment, the delay blocks delay the received clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> so that each of the clock outputs <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> outputs a delayed version of the signal received at clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, and the signal output at each of the clock outputs is delayed by more than the signal at the previous clock output. Thus, the second stage delay block <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> provides an additional delay t more than the first stage delay block <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>, and together the second common delay block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the third stage delay block <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> provide delay t more than the second stage delay block <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. In an embodiment, a common delay block such as <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> provides twice the differential delay between two adjacent stage delay blocks such as <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. For example, the invertors in the common delay blocks <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> (i.e., invertors <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>259</bold></highlight>) may each provide 12 ps of delay, the first invertors in stage delay blocks <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight> (i.e., invertors <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>) may each provide 12 ps of delay, the first invertors in stage delay blocks <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> (i.e., invertors <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>) may each provide 24 ps of delay, and the second invertors in the stage delay blocks (i.e., invertors <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>261</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>263</bold></highlight>) may each provide 20 ps of delay. In this embodiment, the differential delay between stages is 12 ps, and each of the common delay blocks provides 24 ps of delay. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may contain a plurality of delay adjustment blocks (<highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>273</bold></highlight>). Each delay adjustment block may be used to vary the difference in the amount of delay in the signal at one of the clock outputs compared to the signal at another of the clock outputs. In an embodiment, each of the delay adjustment blocks varies the delay between one clock output in the multistage clock and all of the clock outputs that sequentially follow that clock output in the multistage clock. Each delay adjustment block may have an input (<highlight><bold>281</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>) to adjust the timing of the clock signals for at least one of the outputs relative to the clock signals at another of the outputs. In an embodiment, these inputs may be used to digitally control the variation in the amount of delay, and the delay adjustment block may be a digital variable delay block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Details of the delay adjustment blocks of the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> will now be described. Of course, in other embodiments the delay adjustment blocks may have other topologies and may, for example, be analog adjustment blocks. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, each delay adjustment block comprises a chain of transistors connected serially having a drain connected to the output of one of the common delay blocks and a source connected to the ground. The gate of one of the transistors in each delay adjustment block is connected to a delay adjustment input, and the gate of the other transistor in the delay adjustment block is connected to a point between two inverters in one of the delay blocks. Thus, first delay adjustment block <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight> comprises a transistor <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> has a drain connected the output of second common delay block <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, a source connected to transistor <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight>, and a gate connected to first delay adjustment input <highlight><bold>281</bold></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> has a source connected to ground and a gate connected between inverters <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight>. Similarly, second delay adjustment block <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> comprises a transistor <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>277</bold></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> has a drain connected the output of third common delay block <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, a source connected to transistor <highlight><bold>277</bold></highlight>, and a gate connected to second delay adjustment input <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>277</bold></highlight> has a source connected to ground and a gate connected between inverters <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>259</bold></highlight>. Finally, third delay adjustment block <highlight><bold>273</bold></highlight> comprises a transistor <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>279</bold></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> has a drain connected the output of fourth common delay block <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, a source connected to the drain of transistor <highlight><bold>279</bold></highlight>, and a gate connected to third delay adjustment input <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>279</bold></highlight> has a source connected to ground and a gate connected between inverters <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>263</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The delay adjustment blocks may operate as follows. When the delay adjustment input (e.g., <highlight><bold>281</bold></highlight>) is low, the delay adjustment block (e.g., <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight>) is disabled in that current will not flow though the first transistor (e.g., <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>) in the delay adjustment block and, thus, the delay adjustment block does not have any impact on the clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. When the delay adjustment input (e.g., <highlight><bold>281</bold></highlight>) is high, the delay adjustment block (e.g., <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight>) is enabled in that current will flow from the output of a common delay block (e.g., <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>) though the first transistor (e.g., <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>) and the second transistor (e.g., <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight>) to the ground. The impact of the enabling of the delay adjustment block will therefore be the creation of a contention current on the output from the common delay block (e.g., <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>). This contention current will increase the time it takes for the output of the common delay block to drive the delay blocks that receive that output (e.g., <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>). Thus, the enabling of the delay adjustment block may cause an additional delay in each of the clock stages (e.g., <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>) that use the output from that common delay block. In an embodiment, this additional delay may be approximately 30% to 50% of the delay of an inverter with a fanout of 2. The second transistor in the delay adjustment block (e.g., <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight>) may be used to stop the effect of the contention current once the inverter being driven by the delay adjustment block (e.g., inverter <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>) reaches its threshold. Prior to reaching its threshold, the output of this inverter will be high, and thus the gate of the second transistor will receive a high input and the current will flow through the transistor to ground. When the inverter reaches its threshold, the output of this inverter will be low, and thus the gate of the second transistor will receive a low input and the contention current will no longer flow through the delay adjustment block to ground. By use of a delay adjustment block, the differential delay between a clock stage and all following clock stages may be adjusted. In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the differential delay may be increased. Embodiments of the present invention may use one or more delay adjustment blocks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flow diagram of a method of providing a plurality of delayed clock signals according to an embodiment of the present invention. This example method will be explained with reference to the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, but of course this method may also be used with other embodiments of the invention. A clock signal is received at a point in a circuit such as common point <highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>). The received clock signal is delayed by a first pair of inverters (<highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>) to provide a first clock output signal at <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>). In addition, the clock signal received at point <highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight> is delayed by a second pair of inverters (<highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>) to provide a second clock output signal at <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>). In an embodiment, the second clock output signal (at <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>) is delayed by a time t from the first clock output signal (at point <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>). In addition, the received clock of point <highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight> is delayed by a first delay block (<highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>) to provide a first internal clock signal at <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>). In an embodiment, the first delay block comprises a pair of inverters. In embodiment, the first internal clock signal is delayed by time 2t from the received clock signal. If a first delay adjustment enabled input is received at input <highlight><bold>281</bold></highlight> and delay adjustment is therefore enabled for the first delay block <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>), a contention current is created to further delay the first internal clock signal at <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>). In an embodiment, the contention current may be created by turning on a transistor (e.g., transistor <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>) to create a path to ground for the first internal clock signal (that is, the signal at <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>). According to this method, the first internal clock signal at <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> (which may or may not have been additionally delayed by the contention current) is then delayed using a third pair of inverters (<highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight>) to provide a third clock output signal (<highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>). In an embodiment, the third clock output signal at <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> is delayed by time t from the second clock output signal at <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. In an embodiment, the time t is approximately equal to the delay of an inverter with a fanout of 2. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The method described above may be repeated for additional clock stages. For example, in a further embodiment, the first internal clock signal is delayed using a fourth pair of inverters (<highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight>) to provide a fourth clock output signal that is delayed by time t from the third clock output signal. In a still further embodiment, the first internal clock signal is also delayed using a second delay block (<highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>) to provide a second internal clock signal at <highlight><bold>293</bold></highlight> that is delayed by time 2t from the first internal clock signal. In a still further embodiment, the second internal clock signal is delayed using a fifth pair of inverters to provide a fifth clock output signal that is delayed by time t from the fourth clock output signal. If a second delay adjustment enable input is received (e.g., at <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>), then delay adjustment is enabled for the second delay block and a contention current is created to further delay the second internal clock signal. In a further embodiment, the second internal clock signal is delayed using a sixth pair of inverters to provide a sixth clock output signal that is delayed by time t from the fifth clock output signal. In this same way, additional stages may also be included, some or all of which have delay adjustment blocks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a circuit that includes a clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> which has programable adjustable delays according to an embodiment of the present invention. As discussed above with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> having a clock input <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and a plurality of delay adjustment inputs <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, each of the delay adjustment inputs is connected (e.g., by a bus) to a non-volatile memory <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> such as a disk drive. Non-volatile memory <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of storage elements (e.g., a bits) for each of the delay adjustment inputs. For example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows non-volatile memory <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> as containing first adjustment enable storage location <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight> and second adjustment enable storage location <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>. In an embodiment, when a storage location corresponding to a enable adjustment input (e.g., <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>) is set, then the corresponding enable input will input an enable signal to clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and an appropriate adjustment will be made to the clock stages as discussed above. In an embodiment, a scan chain may be connected between the non-volatile memory <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> and the clock delay circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the bits of the scan chain may be loaded from the non-volatile memory during, for example, power up. In this embodiment, the scan chain provides the delay adjustment inputs. In another embodiment, the delay adjustment inputs <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> maybe connected to a control register and may be dynamically controlled. This embodiment may be useful, for example, in testing and debugging the circuit. In other embodiments the enable information may be hard-coded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the present invention reduce the number of devices from a common point in the delay circuit to the clock outputs of the delay circuit in order to reduce the number of device mismatches that may be present. Embodiments also allow for the digital adjustment of the delays at each clock stage so that these delays may be programmed to compensate for unwanted delay differentials. The variable delay elements allow for the selection of small delays with adequate self timed margins and thus compensate for device variations as well as cross-capacitance. In embodiments of the present invention, the inverters are tunned to provide a small delay. This aspect may cause a loss in gain and a reduction in the fanout. The present invention is constructed so that process variations in Leff, Vt and Z have a minimal effect on the differential delay by reducing the difference from the common clocking point while at the same time maintaining sharp edge-rates to preserve signal integrity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Several embodiments of the present invention are specifically illustrated and/or described herein. However, it will be appreciated that modifications and variations of the present invention are covered by the above teachings and within the purview of the appended claims without departing from the spirit and intended scope of the invention. For example, although <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the output of common delay blocks being connected to two stage delay blocks, in other embodiments the output of a common delay block may be connected to three or more stage delay blocks. In addition, the clock delay circuit may contain any number of stages and any number of delay adjustment blocks. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of outputs to provide a sequence of clock signals which together comprise a multistage clock; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a delay adjustment input to adjust the timing of the clock signals for at least one of the outputs relative to the clock signals at another of the outputs. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the delay adjustment input adjusts the timing of the clock signal at said one output and at all of the outputs that follow said one output in the multistage clock, wherein said adjustments are relative to the output that precedes said one output in the multistage clock. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the circuit has a plurality of said delay adjustment inputs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a clock input to receive a clock input signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of clock outputs to each provide a delayed version of the clock input signal, wherein the amount of delay in the signal at each of the clock outputs differs from the amount of delay in the signal at the other clock outputs by approximately a multiple of a time t; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a delay adjustment block to vary the difference in the amount of delay in the signal at one of the clock outputs compared to the signal at another of the clock outputs. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the delay adjustment block has an input to digitally control the variation in the amount of delay. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the circuit has a plurality of said delay adjustment blocks, wherein the clock outputs have a sequential order, and wherein each of the delay adjustment blocks varies the delay between a clock output and all of the clock outputs that follow that output in the sequential order. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the time t is approximately the delay of an inverter with a fanout of 2. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a clock input; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of clock outputs each connected by a path to the clock input; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of first delay blocks each of which is part of a single path from the clock input to one of the clock outputs; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of second delay blocks each of which is part of one of said paths from the clock input to a clock output through one of the first delay blocks and is part of another path from the clock input to another clock output through another first delay block; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an delay adjustment block connected to an output of one of the second delay blocks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first delay blocks and second delay blocks each comprise a pair of inverters connected serially. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the delay adjustment block comprises a pair of transistors connected serially. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the delay adjustment block is a digital variable delay block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method of providing a plurality of delayed clock signals, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>receiving a clock signal at a point in a circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the received clock signal using a first pair of inverters to provide a first clock output signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the received clock signal using a second pair of inverters to provide a second clock output signal that is delayed by approximately a time t from the first clock output signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the received clock signal using a first delay block to provide a first internal clock signal that is delayed by approximately time 2t from the received clock signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the first internal clock signal using a third pair of inverters to provide a third clock output signal that is delayed by approximately time t from the second clock output signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first delay block comprises a pair of inverters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein providing a first internal clock signal includes: 
<claim-text>receiving a first enable input signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the first internal clock signal by creating a contention current. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein creating the contention current comprises turning on a transistor to create a path to ground for the first internal clock signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>delaying the first internal clock signal using a fourth pair of inverters to provide a fourth clock output signal that is delayed by approximately time t from the third clock output signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the first internal clock signal using a second delay block to provide a second internal clock signal that is delayed by approximately time 2t from the first internal clock signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the second internal clock signal using a fifth pair of inverters to provide a fifth clock output signal that is delayed by approximately time t from the fourth clock output signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the second internal clock signal using a sixth pair of inverters to provide a sixth clock output signal that is delayed by approximately time t from the fifth clock output signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein providing a second internal clock signal includes: 
<claim-text>receiving a second enable input signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>delaying the second internal clock signal by creating a contention current. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the time t is approximately equal to the delay of an inverter with a fanout of 2. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a clock input; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first chain of two inverters having an input connected to said clock input and having an output connected to a first clock output; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second chain of two inverters having an input connected to said clock input and having an output connected to a second clock output; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third chain of two inverters having an input connected to said clock input and having an output; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth chain of two inverters having an input connected to the output of the third chain of inverters and having an output connected to a third clock output. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a first transistor connected to the output of the third chain of inverters and having a gate connected to a first enable input; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor connected to the first transistor and to ground. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a fifth chain of two inverters having an input connected to the output of the third chain of inverters and having an output connected to a fourth clock output; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sixth chain of two inverters having an input connected to output of the third chain of inverters and having an output; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seventh chain of two inverters having an input connected to the output of the sixth chain of inverters and having an output connected to a fifth clock output. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second transistor has a gate that is connected to a point between the inverters in the sixth chain of inverters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>an eighth chain of two inverters having an input connected to the output of the sixth chain of inverters and having an output connected to a sixth clock output; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ninth chain of two inverters having an input connected to output of the sixth chain of inverters and having an output; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tenth chain of two inverters having an input connected to the output of the ninth chain of inverters and having an output connected to a seventh clock output; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third transistor connected to the output of the ninth chain of inverters and having a gate connected to a second enable input. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A method of adjusting the delay of a clock signal in a multistage clock, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>determining that the delay between one stage of a multistage clock and the following stage of the multistage clock is too large; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting a first storage element which will later cause the input of a clock adjustment signal to a clock delay circuit and thereby reduce the delay between said one stage of the multistage clock and said following stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the method further comprises: 
<claim-text>determining that the delay between a third stage of the multistage clock and a fourth stage of the multistage clock is too large; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting a second storage element which value will later cause the input of a second clock adjustment signal to the clock delay circuit and thereby reduce the delay between said third stage and said fourth stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein setting the first storage element reduces the delay between said one stage and all following stages. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the delay is reduced by creating a contention current.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005345A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005345A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005345A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005345A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005345A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
