<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001284A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001284A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001284A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001284A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001284A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001284A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001284A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001284A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001284A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001284A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001284A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001284A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001284A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001284A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001284A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001284A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001284</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895362</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L029/40</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>778000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>613000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>396000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>779000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>On-die de-coupling capacitor using bumps or bars and method of making same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<middle-name>Scott</middle-name>
<family-name>List</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Beaverton</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bruce</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Block</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mark</given-name>
<middle-name>T.</middle-name>
<family-name>Bohr</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Aloha</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BLAKELY SOKOLOFF TAYLOR &amp; ZAFMAN</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>12400 WILSHIRE BOULEVARD, SEVENTH FLOOR</address-1>
<city>LOS ANGELES</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90025</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of fabricating an on-chip decoupling capacitor which helps prevent L di/dt voltage droop on the power grid for high surge current conditions is disclosed. Inclusion of the decoupling capacitor on die directly between the power grid greatly reduces the inductance L, and provides decoupling to reduce the highest possible frequency noise. This invention specifically describes the process flow in which the decoupling capacitor is located between the top layer metallization and the standard bump contacts which have either multiple openings or bar geometries to provide both power grid and top decoupling capacitor electrode contacts, </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to integrated circuit decoupling capacitors. More specifically, a decoupling capacitor stack that can be inserted between the top metal layer and a bump metal layer in the back end chip interconnection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Background </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The operation of low power, high speed integrated circuits can be affected by the electrical noise generated by the continuous switching of the transistors located in the circuit. It is well known that the inductive noise of an integrated circuit can be reduced by connecting decoupling capacitors to the circuit. Decoupling capacitors placed on power-consuming circuits are able to smooth out voltage variations with the stored charge on the decoupling capacitor. The stored charge is used as a local power supply to device inputs during signal switching stages, allowing the decoupling capacitor to mitigate the effects of voltage noise induced into the system by parasitic inductance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Typically, a decoupling capacitor is placed in the same package as the chip. Unfortunately, this arrangement is costly to manufacturer, and the long lead lines from the power-consuming circuit to the capacitor electrodes contributes a substantial inductance. Such off-chip decoupling capacitors, however, are not sufficient for very high speed microprocessor applications. The voltage drop across an inductor is L di/dt, where L is inductance and di/dt represents the change in current through a circuit over a period of time. Implicit in the di/dt is a frequency term omega, so as frequency goes up, inductance becomes more and more a factor for power distribution. The frequency dependent Ldi/dt voltage drop makes the off-chip capacitors unusable with gigahertz switching circuits unlike low frequencies for which voltage drops are dominated by resistance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Some efforts have been made to integrate decoupling capacitors as part of the gate dielectric processing step. A portion of the active silicon area is used to deposit the gate dielectric for use as a decoupling capacitor. An advantage to this is that there are no additional processing steps involved with it. The disadvantages include this decoupling capacitor takes up high-value real estate on the chip as the capacitors compete for valuable die area that could be used for building additional circuits. Also the capacitor made with a gate oxide designed for very high transistor performance has a great deal of leakage. These gate decoupling capacitors also have associated parasitic resistance from the relatively low Si conductivity which entail an additional RC time constant for charge extraction. Although it is possible to integrate gate capacitors within the chip&apos;s circuit elements, due to the limited area in which to build these capacitors, the overall capacitive decoupling that they provide is also limited. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Another approach to decoupling capacitor fabrication is a decoupling capacitor that may be fabricated between the metal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> (n-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) layer and the metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> (n) in an integrated circuit. The advantage to this embodiment is there is no additional real estate on the chip taken up for fabrication of the decoupling capacitor, and the decoupling capacitor directly bridges the on-die power grid being between 0 and 10 microns from the integrated circuit element it is supporting with a very low inductance per unit length due to the tight spacing of the power and ground lines. An off-chip decoupling capacitors are typically over a millimeter in distance from the circuit element it is supporting with a larger power to ground separation, with higher inductance per unit length. One problem with this technique is that only approximately 30 percent of the metal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> layer is devoted to power supply. This limits the total amount of decoupling capacitance that can be provided on-die per layer. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The invention is illustrated by way of example and not by way of limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings in which like references indicate similar elements. It should be noted that references to &ldquo;an&rdquo; or &ldquo;one&rdquo; embodiment in this disclosure are not necessarily to the same embodiment, and such references mean at least one. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of a bump connection to a decoupling capacitor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of a bump connection to a decoupling capacitor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of a planarized metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of blanket capacitor stack depositions; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of the capacitor stack depositions of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> patterned with photoresist; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of the capacitor stack after etch of stack layers; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of the capacitor stack of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference> after removal of the photoresist; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3F</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and capacitor stack of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E</cross-reference> after deposition of a passivation layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3G</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of the metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and capacitor stack of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3F</cross-reference> after patterning and fabrication of openings in the passivation layer for contact to the decoupling capacitor and metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3H</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic illustration of one embodiment of a bump contacting metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic top view illustration of one embodiment of bumps contacting metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic top view illustration of one embodiment of bump bars contacting metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flow diagram representing one method of fabricating one embodiment of the claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A method of fabricating an on-chip decoupling capacitor which helps prevent L di/dt voltage droop on the power grip for high surge current conditions is disclosed. Inclusion of a decoupling capacitor on-die directly between the power grid greatly reduces the inductance, L, and provides decoupling to reduce the highest possible frequency noise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In the following description, for the purposes of explanation, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the claims. It will be apparent, however, to one of ordinary skill in the art, that the present claims may be practiced without some of these specific details. The following description and accompanying drawings provide various examples for the purpose of illustration. However, these examples should not be construed in a limiting sense, as they are merely intended to provide examples of the claims rather than to provide an exhaustive list of all possible implementations of the claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made to drawings wherein like structures will be provided with like reference designations. In order to show the structures of the claims more clearly, the drawings included herein are diagrammatic representations of integrated circuit structures. Thus, the actual appearance of the fabricated structures, for example in a photomicrograph, may appear different while still incorporating essential structures of the claims. Moreover, the drawings show only the structures necessary to understand the claims. Additional structures known in the art have not been included to maintain the clarity of the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an illustration of one embodiment of a bump connection to a decoupling capacitor. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows the end result of a bump process performed on a metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> wherein the metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> includes decoupling capacitors. Metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> has three kinds of lines on it. The decoupling capacitor is fabricated on the metal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Bump metal connects to metal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> through the decoupling capacitor top electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> decoupling V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is coupled directly to bump <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> also includes a signal line <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. Between all of these metal lines is the interlayer dielectric <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The interlayer dielectric can be, but is not limited to, a Plasma Tetra Ethyl Ortho Silicate (PTEOS) oxide. The decoupling capacitor comprising layers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> separates metal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> from bump metallization <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is an optional bottom electrode fabricated on the top of metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is the high K dielectric material placed on top of the bottom electrode and layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is the top electrode placed on top of the high K dielectric layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A passivation layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is deposited over the decoupling capacitor stack and metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, this passivation layer can be silicon nitride. Openings are patterned in the passivation layer to allow an electrical contact to be made to the metal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> lines. In this figure, bump <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> can be seen to make a direct contact to metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and a decoupling capacitor connection to metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Thus bump <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is a power connection for V<highlight><subscript>ss</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> One advantage to the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is there is no additional real estate on the chip taken up for fabrication of the decoupling capacitor, and the decoupling capacitor is no more than 70 microns from the integrated circuit element it is supporting. An off-chip decoupling capacitors are typically a millimeter in distance from the circuit element it is supporting. Metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> typically has about 60% of its area dedicated to supplying power, and in some cases may have as much as 90% of its area dedicated to supplying power. Lower metal layers, for example layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, dedicate only about 30% of their area to supplying power. Thus the area available for decoupling capacitors on metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> may be two to three times the area available on metal layer <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, with essentially the same process cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> wherein bump <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> makes direct contact with metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and decoupling contact with metal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Thus bump <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is a power connection for V<highlight><subscript>cc</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> shows one embodiment of a method for fabricating the decoupling capacitor stack with a bump. Metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> comprising the V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and signal line <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> along with the interlayer dielectric <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is planarized using standard damascene process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> shows the blanket deposition of the decoupling capacitor stack layers including the optional bottom electrode layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the high K dielectric material layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and the top electrode layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A typical bottom electrode material can be, but is not limited to, tantalum nitride, titanium nitride, and tungsten nitride. The bottom electrode layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> typically includes a electrically conductive diffusion barrier to copper preventing the metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> copper from diffusing up through the high K dielectric during later processing steps. Layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> also prevents any chemical reactions between the copper and high K dielectric layer. If the high K dielectric layer is both a copper diffusion barrier and unreactive with copper, i.e. SiN, then the bottom electrode is not required. Bottom electrode layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can also include an oxygen diffusion barrier which will help prevent oxidation of the copper metal line beneath the bottom electrode during subsequent processing steps. In some instances, the oxidation diffusion barrier and the copper diffusion barrier can be the same material or they may be combined into one film. High K dielectric layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is next deposited on the bottom electrode layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Typically, the high K dielectric material comprises tantalum pentoxide (Ta<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>). However, the high K material can also be barium strontium titanate (BST) or silicon nitride or other materials. In the instance where BST film is used as the high K dielectric material, the electrodes must be made of metals which do not oxidize or if they do oxidize, the oxide is conductive. Platinum, ruthenium and iridium are the most common materials for electrodes to a BST stack capacitor. Next, top electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is blanket deposited on the high K dielectric material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Top electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> material may be, but is not limited to, tantalum nitride, tungsten nitride, and titanium nitride. Top electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> should be a material which does not oxidize during further process steps. Top electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> should also present a conductive barrier to copper for further process steps. The oxidation and diffusion properties of top electrode layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be combined into one film. The electrical resistivity of layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> should also be minimized to reduce RC delays in extracting the charge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> illustrates the spinning and patterning of photoresist <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> on top of the blanket decoupling capacitor stack above metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The capacitor stack is patterned with photoresist in areas where it is desired to retain the decoupling capacitor. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>C, the photoresist is remaining over V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. However, other areas of the die, for example V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the signal line <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, will not be covered by photoresist. In this figure, it is desired to have the decoupling capacitor between V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and metal bump <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> (not shown) while forming a direct connection between V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the aforementioned bump metal <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference> illustrates the process step after the blanket decoupling capacitor stack has been etched away except in those places where it is desired to retain the decoupling capacitor stack. Photoresist layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has acted as an etch mask over what is left of the decoupling capacitor stack layers. The process step has etched through the capacitor stack stopping on the planarized copper and interlayer dielectric metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E</cross-reference> illustrates the capacitor stack after the photoresist has been chemically stripped using a copper inert chemical. For this flow it is essential to use a copper inert stripping chemical for the photoresist in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E</cross-reference> because in this illustration, metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and signal line <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> are exposed to the photoresist stripping chemical. Typically metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> lines are made out of copper. It is also possible to only partially remove the high K/electrode stack during the patterned etch, then use an aggressive strip which sees no exposed copper, then perform a blanket copper friendly etch to finally remove the high K/electrode stack from areas where no decoupling capacitors are desired with a reduced top electrode thickness for the remaining decoupling capacitors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3F</cross-reference> illustrates the application of a thin passivation layer covering metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the decoupling stack capacitor. In one embodiment, the thin passivation layer may be a silicon nitride layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>G, the passivation material has been patterned and openings have been fabricated in the passivation layer to allow contact to the metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> lines where contact is desired. The opening in the passivation layer in this illustration for contact to the top electrode of the decoupling capacitor stack <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is designed to allow a V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>metallization bump to contact the top electrode of the stack enabling decoupling of the metallization bump and metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Passivation opening <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> over metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is designed to allow a direct connection between the metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>metallization bump <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3H</cross-reference> is an illustration demonstrating metallization bump <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> contacting both the top electrode to the decoupling capacitor stack on metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and making a direct contact to metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic top view of one embodiment of bumps contacting metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a small section of the area of the chip. This small section shows a part of <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> metal lines of which there are numerous multiple more on the same metal layer. In this illustration, all metal lines labeled <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> are V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>metal lines. All metal lines labeled <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> are V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> lines and all lines labeled <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> are metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> signal lines. The illustration in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> metallization bumps. The bumps labeled <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are designed to make a direct connection to metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>lines <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and make decoupling capacitor connections to metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> lines V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The direct connection between V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is made through openings in the not shown passivation layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The decoupling connection between V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>metal bump <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is made through openings in the not shown passivation layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. These openings connect to the top electrode of the stack decoupling capacitor. In this illustration, the top electrode of the stack capacitor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is shown throughout. Likewise, metallization bump V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is intended to make a direct connection to metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> line V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> through passivation openings <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is meant to make a coupled contact to the top electrode of the capacitor stack on metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> through passivation openings <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> These multiple opening bumps combined with the on-die decoupling capacitors provide a factor of two to three increase in decoupling capacitance. It is important to note that only the decoupling capacitor area located between overlapping layers has the fastest time constant. Decoupling capacitors in the wings have an additional parasitic RC delay which can be minimized by increasing the thickness of the top electrode, an option available on top of M<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> but not between M<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and M<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a top view schematic of one embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> wherein the metallization bumps are replaced with bars. In this figure, bar <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is designed to make direct contact with metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight>line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> through passivation openings <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>, and decoupled contact with V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> through passivation openings <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. Bar <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is designed to make direct contact with metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> V<highlight><subscript>cc </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> through passivation openings <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, and decoupled contact with V<highlight><subscript>ss </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> through passivation openings <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flow diagram representation of one method of the current claims. At block <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>, an integrated circuit having a top layer of metal is provided. This top layer of metal may be a metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> may have <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> percent approximately of its metal lines devoted to power distribution. On-chip decoupling capacitor stacks are fabricated on top of the top layer of metal of the integrated circuit at block <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight>. These decoupling capacitor stacks fabricated on the top layer of the metal greatly reduce the distance inductance has to build over an off-chip decoupling capacitor, thus reducing the inductance and do not compete for valuable real estate on the die as an 8 capacitor conductor might. A bump contact is fabricated contacting the capacitor stack and metal layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> lines at block <highlight><bold>630</bold></highlight>. Moving the decoupling capacitor stacks this close to fill up that portion of the integrated circuits that require power reduces the voltage droop on a power grid as at block <highlight><bold>640</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In the preceding detailed description, the invention is described with reference to specific embodiments thereof. It will, however, be evident that various modifications and changes may be made thereto without departing from the broader spirit and scope of the invention as set forth in the claims. Specification and drawings are, accordingly, to be regarded in an illustrative rather than restrictive sense. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing an integrated circuit having a top layer of metal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an on-chip decoupling capacitor stack on the top layer of metal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a bump contact contacting the capacitor stack; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>reducing a voltage droop on a power grid. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the capacitor stack comprises: a high coefficient of permittivity material, and a top electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of claims <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, wherein the capacitor stack further comprises a bottom electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom electrode and the top electrode comprise a material that acts as a diffusion barrier to the metal layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom electrode and the top electrode comprise a material that acts as a diffusion barrier to oxygen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the integrated circuit comprises six layers of metal and the top layer of metal is a seventh layer of metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising coating the capacitor stack and seventh layer of metal with a passivating layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing an integrated circuit with a top layer of metal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>planarizing the top layer of metal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a blanket bottom electrode material, </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a high K dielectric material, </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a blanket top electrode material, </claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning and etching the capacitor stack, </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing blanket passivation layer, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>proceeding with standard multiple opening bump process. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom electrode and the top electrode comprise a material that acts as an oxidation barrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom electrode and the top electrode comprise a material that acts as a diffusion barrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a planarized metal line coupled to the bottom electrode of an electrically decoupling capacitor wherein the top electrode of the electrically decoupling capacitor is coupled to a flip chip bump contact. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bump contacts the top electrode of the decoupling capacitor through multiple bumps. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom electrode and the top electrode comprise a material that acts as an oxidation and diffusion barrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a high K material used in the decoupling capacitor comprises one of tantalum pentoxide (Ta<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>), barium strontium titanate (BST) and silicon nitride (SiN). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom electrode and the top electrode material comprises one of tantalum nitrate (TaN), titanium nitrate (TiN), tungsten nitrate (WN). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the high K material is barium strontium titanate the bottom electrode and the top electrode material comprises one of platinum (Pt), ruthenium (Ru) and iridium (Ir). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an integrated circuit having a top metal layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the top metal layer having a plurality of lines with a plurality of purposes; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a decoupling capacitor coupled to a first top metal line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bump coupled to the decoupling capacitor and a second top metal line having a different purpose than the first top metal line coupled to the capacitor wherein the bump provides power to the second metal line and electrically decouples the first metal line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the decoupling capacitor comprises: 
<claim-text>a bottom electrode coupled to a top metal line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a high K dielectric material coupled to the bottom electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a top electrode coupled to the high K dielectric material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom electrode and the top electrode comprise a material that acts as an oxidation and diffusion barrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a high K material used in the decoupling capacitor comprises one of tantalum pentoxide (Ta<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>), barium strontium titanate (BST) and silicon nitride (SiN). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom electrode and the top electrode material comprises one of tantalum nitrate (TaN), titanium nitrate (TiN), tungsten nitrate (WN). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the high K material is BST the bottom electrode and the top electrode material comprises one of platinum (Pt), ruthenium (Ru) and iridium (Ir).</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3G</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001284A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001284A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001284A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001284A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001284A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001284A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001284A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001284A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
