<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001086A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001086A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001086A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001086A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001086A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001086A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001086</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10223470</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020820</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>0027431.6</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001109</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01J049/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>250</class>
<subclass>282000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Measurement method of the rate of transmission of a vapor through a sample</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10223470</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020820</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/JP01/09727</doc-number>
<document-date>20011107</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>UNKNOWN</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Holger</given-name>
<family-name>Noerenberg</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Oxford</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Andrew</given-name>
<family-name>Briggs</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Oxford</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>George</given-name>
<family-name>Smith</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Witney</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yusuke</given-name>
<family-name>Tsukahara</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Takashi</given-name>
<family-name>Miyamoto</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Toppan Printing Co., Ltd.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>STAAS &amp; HALSEY LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>700 11TH STREET, NW</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 500</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of measuring the rate of transmission of a vapor through a test sample using a mass spectrometer. The test sample is sealed to a gas cell defining a gas chamber, covering an opening in the gas chamber. A droplet of water including isotopes of mass number placed in the gas chamber and the gas cell is introduced into a vacuum chamber adjacent a mass spectrometer. After a sufficient time for evaporation of the liquid to saturate the gas chamber with vapor and for the output of the mass spectrometer to stabilize, the partial pressure of vapor in the vacuum chamber is measured using the mass spectrometer. The measure partial pressure is used to derive the rate of transmission of the vapor through the test sample. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This is a Continuation Application of PCT Application No. PCT/JP01/09727, filed Nov. 7, 2001, which was not published under PCT Article 21(2) in English. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This application is based upon and claims the benefit of priority from the prior United Kingdom Patent Application No. 0027431.6, filed Nov. 9, 2000, the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to measurement method of the rate of transmission of a vapor through a sample, such as a film of a polymer, a ceramic or a composite or a biological sample. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Understanding of the transmission of gasses and vapors through materials of great importance in many fields, for example in medicine, food packaging and for chemical separation processes. Various techniques for measuring the rate of transmission of gasses and through a film are known. Some techniques are based on electrochemical principles, others use a sensor such as a modulated infra-red (IR) sensor. Other techniques measure the pressure increase caused by permeating gasses or vapors, for example using an ion gauge or a PIRANI gauge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> For example, a common known device for measuring rates of transmission of water vapor is the device sold under the Trade Mark PERMATRAN, which uses a modulated IR sensor. This known device uses samples having an area of the order of 100 cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and has a practical resolution of around 5 mg/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/day. However, it would be desirable to obtain a greater sensitivity to allow the measurement of lower absolute rates of transmission of vapor. This would allow, for example, the study of samples with a given transmission rate per unit area having a smaller effective area or samples having a lower transmission rate per unit area, than is possible with the known IR sensor devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is also known to measure the rate of transmission of various gases through a sample using a mass spectrometer to measure the partial pressure of the various species of gas molecule transmitted from a gas chamber through the sample into a vacuum chamber under vacuum. In some known mass spectrometer techniques, the partial pressure in the vacuum chamber decays exponentially over time. This creates difficulties in measuring gas transmission rates, because of difficulties in both (i) modeling the decay to relate the decay to a transmission rate, and (ii) accurately extracting the decay co-efficient from the data, especially at low absolute transmission rates. This is a particular problem for larger molecules which exhibit exponential behavior, that is the measured particular pressure is the sum of two different exponential decay curves having a different magnitudes and time constants. This even further complicates any model used to extract coefficients. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> There are also known mass spectrometer techniques in which the test sample is fixed in the apparatus separating the gas chamber from the vacuum chamber and the gas chamber is supplied with gas at a constant pressure from an external source. However, such an apparatus presents a number of practical difficulties. It is necessary to have a pressurized source of the gas. It is cumbersome to change the test sample. Also, it is impractical to use the apparatus at Ultra High Vacuum, because the evacuation process including baking risks damage or destruction of the test sample. Consequently the sensitivity to low absolute transmission rates is reduced because the background measurements are high. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention is intended to provide a method of measuring the rate of transmission of vapors, such as water vapor through a test sample that alleviates the problems with the known techniques discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to a first embodiment of the present invention, there is provided a method of measuring the rate of transmission of a vapor through a test sample, comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> providing an amount of liquid in a gas chamber; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> arranging the gas chamber to communicate through a test sample with a vacuum chamber under vacuum; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> using a mass spectrometer to measure the partial pressure in the vacuum chamber of the vapor of the liquid after a sufficient time for evaporation of the liquid to saturate the gas chamber with vapor; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> deriving the rate of transmission of the vapor through the test sample from the measured partial pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> With the first embodiment of the present invention, the use of a mass spectrometer provides increased sensitivity as compared to the known IR sensor techniques, thereby allowing measurement of a lower absolute gas transmission rate. This allows study of, for example, samples having a lower gas transmission rate per unit area or samples with a given gas transmission rate per unit area of smaller area, as compared to the IR sensor techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In addition, in the first embodiment of the present invention, there are advantages in generating the vapor by providing an amount of liquid in a gas chamber. The liquid evaporates to fill the gas chamber with vapor. After a time, the vapor saturates the gas chamber. Once saturated, the vapor in the gas chamber will remain at a constant pressure, namely the vapor pressure of the liquid. Consequently, after saturation of the gas chamber, the rate of transmission through the test sample into the vacuum chamber occurs at a constant rate and consequently the partial pressure measured by the mass spectrometer is also a constant value. This simplifies measurement and calibration of the measured partial pressure to derive the rate of transmission. In particular, this represents an improvement over the known techniques where the mass spectrometer measures a partial pressure that decays exponentially. Furthermore, the generation of a vapor in the gas chamber by the provision by an amount of liquid provides the advantage of great simplicity as compared to the known techniques using an external gas source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Advantageously, the gas chamber is formed in a gas cell having an opening, the test sample being sealed to the gas cell covering the opening, and the step of arranging the gas chamber to communicate through the test sample with the vacuum chamber comprises introducing the gas cell into the vacuum chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> This provides a number of advantages. The gas cell may be easily filled outside the vacuum chamber. A succession of measurements for different samples and/or different vapors may be performed by introducing successive gas cells into the vacuum chamber without the need to re-establish the vacuum for each measurement. The temperature of the gas cell may be easily changed without the need to change the temperature of the entire apparatus including the vacuum chamber, thereby allowing study of the change in transmission rate with temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> According to a second embodiment of the present invention, there is provided a method of measuring the rate of transmission of water vapor through a test sample, comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> arranging a gas chamber containing water vapor including isotopes of mass number 20 to communicate through a test sample with a vacuum chamber under vacuum; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> using a mass spectrometer to measure the partial pressure of isotopes of mass number 20 of water vapor in the vacuum chamber; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> deriving the rate of transmission of water vapor through the test sample from the measured partial pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> With the second embodiment of the present invention, by measuring the partial pressure of isotopes of water vapor of mass number 20, it is possible to achieve a high degree of sensitivity. This allows measurement of lower absolute gas transmission rates than is possible by measuring the partial pressure of ordinary water of mass number 18. This is because the background pressure within the vacuum chamber is much lower for water of mass number 20 than for water of mass number 18, because naturally occurring water of mass number 20 is in far less abundance. Therefore, lower amounts of transmitted vapor can be distinguished against the background. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A method that embodies the present invention will now be described by way of non-limitative example. The method embodies both aspects of the present invention that may be combined together. The method is described with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Additional objects and advantages of the present invention will be set forth in the description which follows, and in part will be obvious from the description, or may be learned by practice of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The objects and advantages of the present invention may be realized and obtained by means of the instrumentalities and combinations particularly pointed out hereinafter.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of the specification, illustrate embodiments of the present invention and, together with the general description given above and the detailed description of the embodiments given below, serve to explain the principles of the present invention in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view of the apparatus used in the method; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a gas cell used in the method; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a graph showing an example of results obtained with the method; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a first alternative gas cell; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a second alternative gas cell.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Embodiments according to the present invention will now be described with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The method is performed using the apparatus illustrated in diagrammatic from in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The apparatus includes a standard vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> capable of withstanding Ultra High Vacuum (UHV). The vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is pumped by a main turbo-molecular pump <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a load lock chamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> acting as an air lock in a conventional manner and pumped by a further turbo-molecular pump <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has two transfer arms <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The first transfer arm <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is arranged to transfer objects through the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The second transfer arm <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is arranged to transfer objects introduced by the first transfer arm <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> through the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Disposed within the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is a quadrupole mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> arranged to detect vapor in the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is of conventional construction having an SEM detector. Any type of mass spectrometer could be used, although a quadrupole mass spectrometer is preferred because its relatively small size assists mounting in the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The sensitivity of the method can be improved by using a mass spectrometer of higher sensitivity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The output of the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is fed to a conventional personal computer <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> for data processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The apparatus further includes a gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of a sufficiently small size to be introduced into, and removed from, the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be moved using the two transfer arms <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> to a position adjacent the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated in cross-section in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is formed from a stainless steel body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> having a cylindrical hole <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> drilled therein to form a gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with an opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A test sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> covers the opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and is sealed to the block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> by an adhesive <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is filled before the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is sealed to the block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> by placing a droplet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of liquid into the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Subsequently the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is sealed to the block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The area of the opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is the effective area of the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for transmission of gas. The effective area may be of any size. However, it is easy to form the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to provide low effective areas, of say around 1 cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>or less. This compares favorably with the PERMATRAN device mentioned above which uses samples having an area of the order of 100 cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The present invention is particularly suitable for a sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> consisting of a thin film, for example of a polymer, a ceramic or a composite. In this case, the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is sufficiently thin that transmission through its minor edges is negligible compared to transmission through its major faces extending across the opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In this case, the measured rate of transmission of vapor may be expressed as a rate per unit area of the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The present invention is also suitable for a sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that is a biological sample. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The method for measuring the rate of transmission of vapor through the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> using the apparatus described above will now be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Initially, the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is evacuated to UHV, typically at a pressure of the order of 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;8 </superscript></highlight>Pa or below, using known techniques involving pumping and baking of the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is maintained at UHV by the turbo-molecular pump <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The evacuation process is performed while the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is disposed outside the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. This prevents the evacuation process, in particular the baking, from damaging the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Outside the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the gas cell is filled by placing a droplet of liquid <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> into the chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is sufficiently deep that the droplet of liquid <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> does not lie in opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> or contact the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Then the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is sealed to the block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> by the adhesive <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The filled gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is introduced into the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> using the two transfer arms <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned opposite the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> with the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> a few millimeters or closer, say 0.5 mm, from the entrance of the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which may be an aperture of, say, 1 mm diameter in a metallic plate. As a result, the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> communicates with the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Vapor transmitted through the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is detected by the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which outputs, in respect of each mass number (or strictly speaking the charge-to-mass ratio), a signal representative of the partial pressure of the corresponding constituent of the vapor in the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The output signal is analyzed on the personal computer <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The liquid in the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> evaporates to form vapor in the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. After a sufficient period of time, the vapor saturates the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, the pressure in the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> remains at a constant value, namely the vapor pressure of the liquid until all the liquid in the droplet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has evaporated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> After insertion of the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the output of the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in respect of each constituent of the liquid rises from the background level for that species. Eventually it stabilizes at a constant value. Typically this takes several hours. In this state, the system is in equilibrium with the vapor in the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> at a constant pressure being transmitted through the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at a constant rate. The partial pressure for each constituent measured by the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is proportional to the gas transmission rate of that constituent. Therefore, a measurement of the partial pressure is taken during this stable period of the output of the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The equilibrium remains until all the liquid in the droplet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has evaporated (or the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is removed from the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, if sooner). After that, the pressure in the chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> decays exponentially as vapor is transmitted out of the chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> without being replaced. This causes a corresponding decay in the rate of transmission and the output of the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The measured partial pressures are used to derive the rate of transmission of the vapor through the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. This is done by calibrating the measurement of partial pressure for a sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> constituting a test sample against of partial pressure measured for a further sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> constituting a reference sample. The reference sample has 9 rate of transmission of the vapor that is known, for example from another technique. The partial pressure measurements for the test sample and the reference sample may both be obtained using the same method, as described herein. Alternatively, the rate of transmission could be derived from the measured partial pressure based on a theoretical analysis of the transmission. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The measurements of partial pressure and derived rates of transmission may be considered for individual constituents of the vapor or for all the constituents of the vapor in summation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As the measurement of partial pressure is taken during the stable equilibrium state of the apparatus, it is particularly easy to take an accurate measurement and to derive the rate of transmission. In particular, this is easier than in techniques where the partial pressure measured by a mass spectrometer decays exponentially. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the present invention provides significant advantages of simplicity. The gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be filled outside the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the method may be repeated for different samples <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and/or different vapors simply by replacing one gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with another without the need to evacuate the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> each time, although throughput is limited by the time taken to restore the background level of the vapor in the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> after an experiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The method may be repeated for a given sample and a given vapor at different temperatures to investigate changes in the rate of transmission with temperature and hence derive the activation energy of the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. It is easy to change the temperature of the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, using any known technique, because it is only necessary to change the temperature of the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, not the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as a whole. The temperature of the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be measured using a thermocouple. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The present method may be used to measure the rate of transmission of any vapor, but is particularly suitable for measuring the rate of transmission of water vapor. In this case, to enhance sensitivity, the partial pressure of isotopes of water of mass number <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be measured by using a droplet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of liquid water that includes, or consists essentially of, isotopes of mass number <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The background pressure within the vacuum chamber for water of mass number <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is less than for water of mass number <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> because naturally occurring water of mass number <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is in far less abundance. Therefore, the use of water of mass number <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> allows lower measurements of partial pressure corresponding to lower transmission rates to be measured without being obscured by the background pressure. In the described embodiment the personal computer <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in its analysis of the output of the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> derives the ratios of transmission and so effectively selects the partial pressure of isotopes of mass number <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Water of mass number 20 can be comprised of oxygen of mass number 18 (0.2% natural abundance) instead of 16 or by using hydrogen of mass number 2 (0.015% natural abundance) instead of 1. Either source of water of mass number 20 may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> To illustrate its effectiveness, an example of measurements obtained using the present method are illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. These measurements were obtained for a sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> consisting of a film of oriented polypropylene (OPP) of thickness 20 &mgr;m and having effective area of 0.126 cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. The liquid used was water including isotopes of mass number 20. In fact the experimental results show that the water contained approximately equal amounts of isotopes of mass number 20 and isotopes of mass number 18. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a graph of the measured partial pressure for each isotope of water against time. The measurements for mass number 20 are shown by the dark line and the measurements for mass number 18 are shown by the fainter line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> was introduced into the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> after four hours on the time scale at the position A. Prior to this, the partial pressures readings output by the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are the background pressures. It will be seen that the background pressure is much lower for mass number 20, than for mass number 18. This is because the background pressure in the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> at UHV is formed in part by naturally occurring water which contains an abundance of water of mass number 20 at several orders of magnitude below that of water of mass number 18. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> After the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is introduced into the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> at position A, the partial pressure of both isotopes of water rise, stabilizing at a constant value at position B. This is where the measurement of partial pressure is taken. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The stable partial pressure is maintained for a period of time. At position C the gas cell was removed from the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Subsequently the output of the mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> decayed exponentially down to background levels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In fact, the partial pressure for each species of water was around 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;9 </superscript></highlight>mbar. Therefore, the total pressure for the transmitted water vapor is 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;9 </superscript></highlight>mbar. In the present case, this calibrates the apparatus, because the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of OPP has a known rate of transmission of approximately 3 g/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/day as measured by the PERMATRAN device as discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> If water consisting solely of isotopes of mass number 18 were used, this gives a theoretical lower detection limit of roughly 0.1 mg/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/day for the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> having an effective area of 0.126 cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. In practice, this lowermost detection limit will probably not be achievable because of problems such as achieving a sufficient seal, but the achievable sensitivity to low absolute rates of transmission compares favorably with the PERMATRAN device which uses samples having an area of the order of 100 cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and has a lower detection limit of around 5 mg/m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/day. The sensitivity of the techniques to absolute detection rate may be compared by multiplying the lower detection limit of the measurable rate of detection per unit area by the size of the sample used. It is expected that the present method could achieve a sensitivity to low absolute detection rates as compared to the PERMATRAN device around three orders of magnitude better, if water of mass number 20 is used. Such higher sensitivity to low transmission rates is advantageous. It allows, for example, the study smaller samples being a given transmission rate per unit area or of samples having a low transmission rate per unit area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The experiments described above were performed with a quadrapole mass spectrometer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> having 6 mm rods in analogue mode. Another order of magnitude in the detection range can be obtained if larger rods, say of 9 mm or 12 mm, were used. Signal detection may also be improved by improving existing amplifiers or using new amplifiers and using pulse counting techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Of course, various modifications may be made to method described above without department from the scope of the present invention. For example the method steps may be performed in a different order or a different apparatus may be used. In particular, the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be replaced by a gas cell of an alternative construction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a gas cell <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> having a first alternative construction. The gas cell <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> has in most part an identical construction to the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> (so a description is not repeated), except for the provision of a refill port <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The refill port <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is a bore drilled through the block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> into the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and formed with an internal thread <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. To close the refill port <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, a cylindrical, externally threaded copper plug <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is screwed into the internal thread <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the port <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The plug <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is removable to allow filling of the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> through the refill port <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to insert a droplet <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of liquid. Subsequently the plug <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is screwed back into the thread <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to close the refill port <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The refill port <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> allows the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the gas cell <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to be refilled without the need to remove the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and re-seal it to the block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, as is necessary with the gas cell <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. This provides the possibility of refilling the gas cell <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> when in the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or in another vacuum chamber which is desirable if the vapor is hazardous or to prevent harm to the vacuum in the vacuum chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The use of closable refill port such as the refill port <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in the gas cell <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> also has the advantages of permitting the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to be filled with vapor at a temperature above boiling point, which is condensed to a smaller amount of liquid at a lower investigation temperature. It also allows the introduction of a solid at a lower temperature that is investigated at a higher temperature above its melting point to provide liquid in the vacuum chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a gas cell <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> having a second alternative construction. The gas cell <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is formed from a stainless steel block <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> having a cylindrical hole <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> drilled therein. An annular Teflon seal <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is inserted into the hole <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to form, inside the annulus of the seal <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, a gas chamber <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> having an opening <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The sample <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is positioned on the end of the seal <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> to cover the opening <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The sample <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is sealed by the clamping action of an annular lid <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> positioned across the sample and secured to the body <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> by screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The lid <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> has a circular aperture <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> having the same shape as, and aligned with, the opening <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The area of the opening <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and the aperture <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> define the effective area of the sample <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The gas cell <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is filled by removing the sample <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and lid <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, placing a droplet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of liquid in the chamber <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and clamping the sample <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> over the chamber <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> using the lid <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In any case cells <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the sample <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be reinforced by a metal grid (not shown) similar to those used in electron microscopy to prevent bulging due to the one atmosphere pressure differential between the vacuum chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the gas chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> While the description above refers to particular embodiments of the present invention, it will be understood that many modifications may be made without departing from the spirit thereof. The accompanying claims are intended to cover such modifications as would fall within the true scope and spirit of the present invention. The presently disclosed embodiments are therefore to be considered in all respects as illustrative and not restrictive, the scope of the invention being indicated by the appended claims, rather than the foregoing description, and all changes that come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are therefore intended to be embraced therein. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of measuring the rate of transmission of a vapor through a test sample, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing an amount of liquid in a gas chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>arranging the gas chamber to communicate through a test sample with a vacuum chamber under vacuum; </claim-text>
<claim-text>using a mass spectrometer to measure a partial pressure in the vacuum chamber of a vapor of a liquid after a sufficient time for evaporation of the liquid to saturate the gas chamber with vapor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>deriving the rate of transmission of the vapor through the test sample from the measured partial pressure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>the gas chamber is formed in a gas cell having an opening, the test sample being sealed to the gas cell covering the opening, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the step of arranging the gas chamber to communicate through the test sample with the vacuum chamber comprises introducing the gas cell into the vacuum chamber. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of providing the amount of liquid in the gas cell is performed before the step of introducing the gas cell into the vacuum chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the test sample is sealed to the gas cell by adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the test sample is sealed to the gas cell by clamping </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas cell has a closable refill port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the method is repeated for the test sample at different temperatures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the vacuum chamber is under Ultra High Vacuum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an effective area of the test sample is around 1 cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>or less. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the test sample is a film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film is a polymer, a ceramic or a composite. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of using the mass spectrometer to measure the partial pressure in the vacuum chamber is performed after the output of the mass spectrometer stabilizes to a constant value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rate of transmission of the vapor through the test sample is derived from the measured partial pressure by calibrating the measure partial pressure with a partial pressure measured for a reference sample having a known rate of transmission of the vapor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the liquid is water and the vapor is water vapor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the liquid water includes isotopes of mass number 20 and the step of measuring the partial pressure of the vapor comprises measuring the partial pressure of the isotopes of mass number 20 of the vapor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method of measuring the rate of transmission of water vapor through a test sample, comprising: 
<claim-text>arranging a gas chamber containing water vapor including isotopes of mass number 20 to communicate through a test sample with a vacuum chamber under vacuum; </claim-text>
<claim-text>using a mass spectrometer to measure the partial pressure of isotopes of mass number 20 of water vapor in the vacuum chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>deriving the rate of transmission of water vapor through the test sample from the measured partial pressure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas chamber is formed in a gas cell having an opening with the test sample sealed to the gas cell covering the opening, the step of arranging the gas chamber to communicate through the test sample with the vacuum chamber comprising introducing the gas cell into the vacuum chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein water vapor is introduced into the gas cell before the step of introducing the gas cell into the vacuum chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method according to claims <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, wherein the test sample is sealed to the gas cell by adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method according to claims <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, wherein the test sample is sealed to the gas cell by clamping </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas cell has a closable refill port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas cell has a closable refill port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the vacuum chamber is under Ultra High Vacuum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the effective area of the test sample is around 1 cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>or less. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the test sample is a film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film is a polymer, a ceramic or a composite. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of using a mass spectrometer to measure the partial pressure of isotopes of mass number 20 in the vacuum chamber is performed after the output of the mass spectrometer stabilizes to a constant value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rate of transmission of water vapor through the test sample is derived from the measured partial pressure by calibrating the measured partial pressure with a partial pressure measured for a reference sample having a known rate of transmission of water vapor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for measuring rate of transmission of water vapor, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a vacuum chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas chamber provided in the vacuum chamber, the gas chamber having an opening for transmitting gas through a test sample; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mass spectrometer for measuring partial pressures of isotopes of water vapor of mass numbers 18 and 20 in the vacuum chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for selecting the partial pressure of isotopes of water vapor of mass number 20 to derive the rate of transmission of water vapor through the sample. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an amount of liquid water in the gas chamber, whereby evaporation of the liquid saturates the gas chamber with vapor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas chamber is formed in a gas cell which is removable from the vacuum chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the test sample is sealed to the gas cell covering the opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the test sample is sealed to the gas cell by adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the test sample is sealed to the gas cell by clamping. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas cell has a closable refill port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the vacuum chamber is under Ultra High Vacuum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the effective area of the test sample is around 1 cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>or less. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the test sample is a film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film is a polymer, a ceramic or a composite. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the selecting means is arranged to select the partial pressure after the output of the mass spectrometer stabilizes to a constant value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising means for deriving the rate of transmission of the vapor through the test sample. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to claim <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, wherein the deriving means is arranged to derive the rate of transmission by calibrating the measured partial pressure with a partial pressure measured for a reference sample having a known rate of transmission of the vapor.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001086A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001086A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001086A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
