<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003961A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003961A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003961</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896080</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010630</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04M001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>455</class>
<subclass>562000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>455</class>
<subclass>012100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Sequential signal selection system and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kuo-Hui</given-name>
<family-name>Li</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Redmond</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>Stevenson</middle-name>
<family-name>Kenney</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Atlanta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mary</given-name>
<middle-name>Ann</middle-name>
<family-name>Ingram</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Decatur</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>THOMAS, KAYDEN, HORSTEMEYER &amp; RISLEY, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>100 GALLERIA PARKWAY, NW</address-1>
<address-2>STE 1750</address-2>
<city>ATLANTA</city>
<state>GA</state>
<postalcode>30339-5948</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The sequential signal selection system and method is generally related to communication systems and more particularly to a system and method for sequentially selecting signals from a set of signal(s). The sequential signal selection comprises a processor, a memory device that is coupled to the processor, at least one radio/transceiver that is coupled to the processor, and an analog pre-selection network that is coupled to the at least one radio/transceiver. Moreover, the sequential signal selection method comprises the steps of pre-selecting at least two signals from a set of signals based on a pre-selection method, and selecting at least one signal from the at least two signals based on a selection method. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention is generally related to communication systems and, more particularly, is related to a system and method for sequentially selecting signal(s) from a set of signals. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Conventional signal selection systems and methods typically use one radio/transceiver or receiver for each signal to validate the signal. Beam validation analyzes the signal to decide whether the signal contains useful information or interference. Using one radio/transceiver for validating each signal is inefficient and cost prohibitive since a high number of signals generally require a corresponding large number of radios. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Moreover, other conventional signal selection systems and methods such as the receive signal strength indicator (RSSI) system and method, typically select signals based only on power. Hence, there is no validation of the signals to decide whether the signals contain useful information or interference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Thus, a need exists in the industry to address the aforementioned deficiencies and inadequacies. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a sequential signal selection system and method for pre-selecting at least two signals from a set of signals and then selecting at least one signal from the at least two signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Architecturally, one embodiment of the sequential signal selection system comprises a processor, a memory device that is coupled to the processor, at least one radio/transceiver that is coupled to the processor, and an analog pre-selection network that is coupled to the at least one radio/transceiver. Furthermore, the sequential signal selection method comprises pre-selecting at least two signals from a set of signals based on a pre-selection method, and selecting at least one signal from the at least two signals based on a selection method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Other features and advantages of the present invention will be or become apparent to one having ordinary skill in the art upon examination of the following drawings and detailed description. It is intended that all such additional features and advantages be included with this description, be within the scope of the present invention, and be protected by the accompanying claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The invention can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily to scale, emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present invention. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating an exemplar sequential signal selection system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a first embodiment of the sequential signal selection system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a second embodiment of the sequential signal selection system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a third embodiment of the sequential signal selection system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a first embodiment of an analog pre-select system located within the embodiments of the sequential signal selection illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a second embodiment of an analog pre-select located within the embodiments of the sequential signal selection system illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a third embodiment of an analog pre-select located within the embodiments of the sequential signal selection system illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a flow chart of a sequential signal selection method that illustrates the functionality of the sequential signal selection system illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The sequential signal selection system and method overcomes the above-mentioned inadequacies and deficiencies since the number of radios need not be equal to the number of signals that are received by the sequential signal selection system. The sequential signal selection system and method uses a two step approach to reduce the number of radios relative to the number of signals received. First, there is a pre-selection of at least two signals from a set of signals that are received by the sequential signal selection system. The numbers of radios are equal to the number of signals that are pre-selected. Hence, there are at least two radios. The second step is to select at least one signal from the at least two signals that are pre-selected. Hence, the number of radios in the sequential signal selection system and method may not be equal to the number of signals in a set of signals that is received by the sequential signal selection system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the sequential signal selection system and method overcomes the inadequacies and deficiencies when using only the RSSI system and method since it may pre-select at least two signals, from a set of signals, based on power. It may then select one signal from the at least two signals based on whether or not the at least one signal contains useful information or merely interference. Hence, the sequential signal selection system and method may obtain a signal that not only has the highest power among a set of signals but also contains useful information and not interference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating an exemplar sequential signal selection system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprises an analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, a radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, a processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and a memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> comprise a radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and a radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> could comprise any number of radios/transceivers, where the number of radios/transceivers correspond to the number of signals that the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> pre-selects. A line <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> couples the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and line <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> couples the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. A line <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> couples the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and line <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> couples the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The number of lines coupling the radios/transceivers in the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is the same as the number of lines coupling the radios/transceivers in the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. A line <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> couples the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and a line <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> couples the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to the memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> It should be noted that each radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> include devices, such as, but not limited to, an analog-to-digital converter, one or more filters, a digital-to-analog converter, and other devices known to those having ordinary skill in the art. Moreover, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> can be any processor known to those having ordinary skill in the art, and preferably, is a digital signal processor (DSP). Additionally, the memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> can be any device, including, but not limited to, a register, a random access memory (RAM), or any other memory device that stores information and is known to those having ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In operation, the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> receives a set of signals from a transmission medium, and produces a corresponding set of signals, where each signal in the corresponding set of signals is a different linear combination of signals in the set of signals. The analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> then pre-selects at least two signals from the corresponding set of signals based on a pre-selection method such as, but not limited to, the RSSI method. The analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, however, may pre-select any number of signals from the set of signals. The radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> receives the at least two signals from the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. For instance, the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> receives a first signal, among the at least two signals, via the line <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, receives a second signal, among the at least two signals, via the line <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> converts the first signal from an analog format to a digital format, and the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> converts the second signal from an analog format to a digital format. The radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, may also perform other functionality on the first signal, and the second signal, including but not limited to, filtering the first signal and the second signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> receives the at least two signals from the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. For instance, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> receives the first signal, from the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, via line <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and receives the second signal, from the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, via line <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> then selects two signals from the at least two signals, received from the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, based on a selection method. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may, alternatively, select two signals, from the set of signals, based on the selection method. The memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> stores the selection method. It should be noted that the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may select any number of signals based on the selection method. It should also be noted that the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can receive any type of signals, known to those having ordinary skill in the art, including, but not limited to, radio/transceiver frequency (RF) signals, acoustic signals, optical signals, or infrared signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a first embodiment of the sequential signal selection system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Specifically, the first embodiment comprises the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) and the memory <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). The analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> further comprises an antenna array (AA)<highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> that includes antennas <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>, a beamforming network (BFN) <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, a switching network (SN) <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, and an analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The AA <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may comprise any number of antennas and any kind of antennas known to those having ordinary skill in the art. The book, Robert J. Mailloux, <highlight><italic>Phased Array Antenna Handbook, </italic></highlight>423-445 (1<highlight><superscript>st </superscript></highlight>ed. 1994) illustrates a detailed description of an embodiment of the BFN <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is a switching network that is known to those having ordinary skill in the art. In its simplest form, the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> comprises five switches, where the five switches are coupled to the lines <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the five switches are coupled to both the lines <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> can comprise of any number of switches, where the number of switches are the same as the number of lines coupling the BFN <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The lines <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> couple the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, to the BFN <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Lines <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> couple the lines <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. A line <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> couples the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, and a line <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> couples the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The line <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> couples the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and the line <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> couples the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The number of lines coupling the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is the same as the number of radios/transceivers in the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, where the number of radios/transceivers in the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> corresponds to the number of signals that the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> pre-selects. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is coupled to the two radios/transceivers <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, and to the memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> in the same manner as described in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The antennas <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> in the AA <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> receive a set of signals. The AA <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> can receive any number of signals, where the number of signals corresponds to the number of antennas in the AA <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. The BFN <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> changes the phase and/or amplitude of one or more signals in the set of signals and produces five signals, where each of the five signals is a different linear combination of signals in the set of signals. The BFN <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may produce any number of signals and the number of lines <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> correspond to the number of signals that the BFN <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> produces. The number of lines <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> corresponds to the number of lines <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> receives the five signals via the lines <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> pre-selects at least two signals by calculating a first metric for each of the five signals, and then sorting at least two signals that have the best first metrics among the five signals. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may pre-select any number of signals. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> then manipulates the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> so that the at least two signals, among the five signals on lines <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>, pass through the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> receives the at least two signals from the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. For instance, the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> receives a first signal, among the at least two signals, via the line <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, and receives a second signal, among the at least two signals, via the line <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> converts the first signal from an analog format to a digital format, and the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> converts the second signal from an analog format to a digital format. The radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, may also perform other functionality on the first signal, and the second signal, including but not limited to, filtering the first signal and the second signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> receives the at least two signals from the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. For instance, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> receives the first signal, from the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, via line <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and receives the second signal, from the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, via line <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> calculates a second metric for each of the at least two signals. The second metric can be based on correlating a code of each of the at least two signals to a pre-determined code, comparing the frequency of the envelope of each of the at least two signals to a pre-determined frequency, or calculating the bit error rate of each of the at least two signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> A general goal of the sequential signal selection system and method is for the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to find a certain minimum number of signals that have an acceptable value of the second metric and then stop. Preferably, the minimum number of signals is two. The goal can be achieved by comparing the values of the second metric to a threshold. As soon as the minimum number of signals that meet the threshold, are found, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> commands the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to pass the minimum number of signals, and the sequential signal selection method ends. If the minimum number of signals that meet the threshold cannot be found, the desired minimum number of signals with the best values of second metrics are selected. A description of the sequential signal selection method that achieves the goal with a limited number of radios/transceivers within the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, follows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> stores the second metrics of each of the at least two signals in the memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and tests the at least two signals by comparing the second metrics of each of the at least two signals to a certain threshold. If the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> determines that at most one signal, of the at least two signals, has a second metric that meets the threshold, it sends a command via line <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to again pre-select at least two signals from the corresponding set of five signals. For instance, if the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> calculates a bit error rate of a signal, meeting the threshold means that the bit error rate of the signal is lower than a threshold bit error rate. If the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> compares the frequency of a signal to a pre-determined frequency, meeting the threshold can mean that a value representing the comparison is less than a threshold frequency value. If the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> obtains a correlation of code of a signal to a pre-determined code, meeting the threshold can mean that the correlation of the signal is lower than a threshold correlation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> After the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> sends the command, if the number of signals in the set of signals that are received by the AA <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, less the number of signals that have been tested by the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, is not greater than one, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> simply commands the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to pass the untested signal in the set of five signals, and computes its second metric. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> then chooses two signals that have the best second metrics among the set of signals. Alternatively, if the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> determines that the second metric of two or more signals among the at least two signals meets the threshold, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> selects two signals that have the best second metrics among the second metrics of the two or more signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a second embodiment of the sequential signal selection system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The second embodiment comprises the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), and the memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). The analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> comprises a first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, a second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, and a third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>. The first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> comprises an SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight>, a BFN <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, an AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, and an analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> comprise five antennas <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight> that are each coupled to the BFN <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Lines <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> couple the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> to the BFN <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Additionally, lines <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> couple the lines <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> located in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. Lines <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> couple the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> to an SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight>. The number of lines that couple the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> is the same as the number of signals that the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, pre-selects. Line <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> couples the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> and a line <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> couples the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The second analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> comprises an SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight>, a BFN <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>, an AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>, and an analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> comprise five antennas <highlight><bold>327</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> that are each coupled to the BFN <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>. Lines <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> couple the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight> to the BFN <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, lines <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight> couple the lines <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> located in the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>. Lines <highlight><bold>345</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>346</bold></highlight> couple the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight>. The number of lines that couple the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> is the same as the number of signals that the analog pre-select, in the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, pre-selects. Line <highlight><bold>358</bold></highlight> couples the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, located in the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, to the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight>, and line <highlight><bold>347</bold></highlight> couples the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, located in the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, to the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight> comprises the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight>, and an analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. Line <highlight><bold>354</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight> couple the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, located in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, to the lines <highlight><bold>345</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>346</bold></highlight>. Lines <highlight><bold>356</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>357</bold></highlight> couple the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, located in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, to the lines <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight>. A line <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight> couples the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> and a line <highlight><bold>353</bold></highlight> couples the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, located in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, to the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. A line <highlight><bold>349</bold></highlight> couples the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> to the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and a line <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> couples the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> to the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The number of lines that couple the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> to the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is the same as the number of signals that the analog pre-select, in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, pre-selects. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is coupled to the radios <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, and to the memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> in the same manner as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> It should be noted that any number of antennas and any kind of antennas known to those having ordinary skill in the art, can be used in the AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and in the AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the BFN <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and the BFN <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> may have the same structure as the BFN <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). Additionally, the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight>, SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight>, and SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> may have the same structure as of the SN <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). However the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> comprises four switches, where the four switches are coupled to the lines <highlight><bold>345</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>346</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight>. Moreover, the four switches are coupled to both the lines <highlight><bold>349</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. The number of switches in the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> are the same as the total number of lines coupling the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> and the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight> to the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The antennas <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight> in the AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> receive a first set of signals. The AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> can receive any number of signals, where the number of signals received corresponds to the number of antennas in the AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. The BFN <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> changes the phase and/or amplitude of one or more signals in the first set of signals and produces a corresponding first set of five signals, where each signal, in the corresponding first set five of signals, is a different linear combination of signals in the first set of signals. The BFN <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may produce any number of signals, the number of lines <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> correspond to the number of signals that the BFN <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> produces, and the number of lines <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> correspond to the number of lines <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight>. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, receives the five signals, in the corresponding first set of five signals, via the lines <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, pre-selects at least two signals by calculating a first metric for each of the five signals, and sorting at least two signals from the five signals. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, may sort any number of signals. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, then manipulates the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> so that the at least two signals, among the five signals on lines <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>, pass through the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> performs in similar fashion as the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, but on a second corresponding set of five signals that the BFN <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> produces and that correspond to a second set of signals that the AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> receives. The number of signals that the antennas in the AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> receive corresponds to the number of antennas in the AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, selects at least two signals from the second corresponding set of five signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight> receives at least four signals, which include at least two signals sent from the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight>, and at least two signals sent from the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight>. For instance, assuming that the at least two signals sent from the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> comprise a first signal and a second signal, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, receives the first signal via the line <highlight><bold>345</bold></highlight>, and receives the second signal via the line <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight>. Moreover, assuming that the at least two signals sent from the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight> comprise a third and a fourth signal, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, receives the third signal via the line <highlight><bold>345</bold></highlight>, and receives the fourth signal via the line <highlight><bold>346</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, pre-selects at least two signals from the at least four signals, by calculating a first metric for each of the at least four signals based on a method, including, but not limited to, the RSSI method, a correlation method, or a frequency comparison method. The correlation method compares codes, such as, but not limited to, bit patterns, of each signal among the at least four signals, to a pre-determined code. The frequency comparison method compares frequency of the envelope of each signal among the at least four signals to a pre-determined frequency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, continues to pre-select by sorting at least two signals, from the at least four signals, based on first metrics. The at least two signals that are sorted from the at least four signals have the best first metrics among the first metrics of the at least four signals. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, then manipulates the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> so that only the at least two signals having the best first metrics from the at least four signals pass through the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight>. The radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> receives the at least two signals from the SN <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight>. For instance, the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> receives a signal, via the line <highlight><bold>349</bold></highlight>, among the at least two signals sent from the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight>. Moreover, the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> receives a signal, via the line <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, among the at least two signals sent from the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight>. The radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> converts the signal that it receives, via line <highlight><bold>349</bold></highlight>, from an analog format to a digital format, and the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> converts the signal that it receives, via line <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, from an analog format to a digital format. The radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, may also perform other functionality on the signals that they receive, including but not limited to, filtering the signals. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> receives the at least two signals from the at least four signals via the lines <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. For instance, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> receives a signal sent from the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> via line <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and receives a signal sent from the radio/transceiver <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> via line <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> receives the at least two signals from the radio/transceiver device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, and selects two signals from the at least two signals. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> calculates second metrics for the at least two signals. The second metrics can be based on correlating a code of each of the at least two signals to a pre-determined code, comparing the frequency of the envelope of each of the at least two signals to a pre-determined frequency, or computing bit error rates of each of the at least two signals. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> stores the second metrics of the at least two signals in the memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> then tests the at least two signals by comparing the second metrics of the at least two signals to a certain threshold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> If the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> determines that at most one signal of the at least two signals has a second metric that meets the threshold, it sends a command via line <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, to again pre-select at least two signals from the corresponding first set of five signals. Furthermore, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> also sends the command via line <highlight><bold>347</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, to again pre-select at least two signals from the corresponding second set of five signals. Moreover, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> sends a command via line <highlight><bold>353</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, to again pre-select at least two signals from the at least four signals that the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the third analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight>, receives via lines <highlight><bold>354</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>357</bold></highlight>. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> could send commands to any one or more of the analog pre-selects <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in the first, second and third analog pre-selection sub-networks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> After the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> sends the commands via the lines <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>347</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>353</bold></highlight>, if the total number of signals, in the corresponding first and second sets of five signals, which are received by the AAs <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>, less the number of signals that have been tested by the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is not greater than one, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> simply commands the SNs <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> to pass the untested signal in the corresponding first and second sets of five signals, and computes its second metric. Then the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> chooses two signals that have the best second metrics among the signals in the corresponding first and the second sets of five signals. Alternatively, if the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> determines that the second metrics of two or more signals among the at least two signals meets the threshold, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> selects two signals that have the best second metrics among the two or more signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a third embodiment of the sequential signal selection system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Structurally, the sequential signal selection system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is similar that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, except for the following. In the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, the lines <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> directly couple the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight> to the antennas <highlight><bold>327</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> in the AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>. Moreover, the lines <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight> couple the lines <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> located in the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, the lines <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> directly couple the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> to the antennas <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight> in the AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the lines <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> couple the lines <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> located in the first analog pre-select sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The third embodiment of sequential signal selection system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> has the same functionality as the second embodiment of the analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) except for the following changes. There is no manipulation of the phase and/or amplitude of a first set of signals received by the AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> since there is no BFN coupled to the AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the first set of signals that are received by the AA <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> go directly to the SN <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> and to the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. Moreover, a second set of signals that are received by the AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> go directly to the SN <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight> and the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, in the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, since there is no BFN coupled to the AA <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> to manipulate the phase and/or amplitude of each signal in the second set of signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a first embodiment of the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> of FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> comprises detectors <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight>, amplifiers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, bandpass filters <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> and a sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>. Lines <highlight><bold>521</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight> are represented as lines <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, as lines <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, and as lines <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Any number of detectors, amplifiers and bandpass filters can be used in the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The number of detectors, amplifiers and bandpass filters are the same as the number of signals that the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> receives. For instance, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, as located within the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, within the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, or within the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, receives five signals. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, therefore, includes five detectors, five amplifiers, and five bandpass filters. Alternatively, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> as located within the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, receives four signals, and therefore includes four detectors, four amplifiers, and four bandpass filters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Lines <highlight><bold>531</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight> couple the bandpass filters <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> to the amplifiers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, respectively. For instance, the line <highlight><bold>531</bold></highlight> couples the bandpass filter <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> to the amplifier <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, lines <highlight><bold>541</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> couple the amplifiers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> to the detectors <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight>, respectively. As an example, line <highlight><bold>541</bold></highlight> couples the amplifier <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> to the detector <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>. Additionally, lines <highlight><bold>551</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>555</bold></highlight> couple the detectors <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight> to the sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the line <highlight><bold>551</bold></highlight> couples the detector <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight> to the sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>. Line <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight> couples the sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> to the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Line <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight> corresponds to line <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, line <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, and line <highlight><bold>347</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. Line <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> couples the sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> to an SN. To explain, line <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> corresponds to line <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, and to lines <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>358</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> pre-selects at least two signals from a set of signals as follows. Each of the bandpass filters <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> receives a signal from the set of signals and filters the signal. The bandpass filters <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> can be any filter, including but not limited to, a high pass filter, a low pass filter, or any other filter known to those having ordinary skill in the art. Each of the amplifiers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> receives a signal, from the set of signals, via lines <highlight><bold>531</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight> and amplifies the signal. Each of the detectors <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight> receives a signal, among the set of signals, via lines <highlight><bold>541</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> and creates a first metric of the signal by rectifying the signal. The first metric is an approximation of amplitude of a signal, among the set of signals, and the amplitude provides an indication of signal strength. Each of the detectors <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight> can be any device that is known to those having ordinary skill in the art and that rectifies a signal such as, for instance, a diode. The sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> receives the set of signals, via lines <highlight><bold>551</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>555</bold></highlight>, and sorts at least two signals that have the best first metrics, such as, for instance, the highest amplitude among the signals in the set of signals. The sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> manipulates an SN via the line <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> so that the SN allows only the at least two signals that are pre-selected, to pass through. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a second embodiment of the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The second embodiment of the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is similar to the first embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, except that the analog correlation receivers <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>615</bold></highlight> replace the detectors <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). Any number of analog correlation receivers can be used. The number of analog correlation receivers are the same as the number of signals in the set of signals that the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> receives. For instance, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, as located within the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, within the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, or within the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, comprise five analog correlation receivers. Alternatively, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, as located within the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, comprise four analog correlation receivers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> A description of the functionality of the second embodiment of the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> follows. Each of the bandpass filters <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> and the amplifiers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> receive a set of signals comprising five signals and perform the same functions as described in the first embodiment of the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Each of the analog correlation receivers <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>615</bold></highlight> receives a signal among the set of signals and calculates a first metric for the signal. The first metric for each signal among the set of signals represents a correlation of a code, such as, but not limited to, a bit pattern, of each signal among the set of signals, to a pre-determined code. The sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> receives the set of signals and pre-selects at least two signals having a higher correlation among the signals in the set of signals. The sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> then manipulates an SN via the line <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> so that only the at least two signals that are pre-selected from the set of signals, pass through the SN. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a third embodiment of the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Structurally, the third embodiment of the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is similar to the first embodiment of the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, except that the third embodiment includes modulated frequency sorters <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>715</bold></highlight>. Lines <highlight><bold>721</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>725</bold></highlight> couple the modulated frequency sorters <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>715</bold></highlight> to the detectors <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight>. For instance, line <highlight><bold>721</bold></highlight> couples the modulated frequency sorter <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight> to the detector <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>. Moreover, lines <highlight><bold>731</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>735</bold></highlight> couple the sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> to the modulated frequency sorters <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>715</bold></highlight>. As an example, the line <highlight><bold>731</bold></highlight> couples the sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> to the modulated frequency sorter <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Any number of modulated frequency sorters can be used. The number of modulated frequency sorters is the same as the number of signals that the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> receives. For instance, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, as located within the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, within the first analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, or within the second analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, comprise five modulated frequency sorters. Alternatively, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, as located within the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, comprise four modulated frequency sorters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> pre-selects as follows. Each of the bandpass filters <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>, the amplifiers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, and the detectors <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight> perform the same operation, as described in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, on each signal in a set of signals that are received by the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. Additionally, each of the modulated frequency sorters <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>715</bold></highlight> receives each signal among the set of signals via lines <highlight><bold>721</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>725</bold></highlight> and calculates a first metric based on a comparison of frequency of the envelope of each signal to a pre-determined frequency. The sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> receives each signal among the set of signals via lines <highlight><bold>731</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>735</bold></highlight> and sorts at least two signals from the set of signals based on the first metric. In other words, the sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> sorts at least two signals whose envelopes have frequencies that are closest to the pre-determined frequency, among the frequencies of signals in the set of signals. The sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> then manipulates an SN via line <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> so that the SN allows only the at least two signals to pass through. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> However, if the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is located within the third analog pre-selection sub-network <highlight><bold>359</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> pre-selects at least two signals from at least four signals that are pre-selected within the first pre-selection subnetwork <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> and within the second pre-selection subnetwork <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> as illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> can be implemented in hardware, software, firmware or a combination thereof. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) can be implemented in software or firmware that is stored in a memory and that is executed by suitable instruction execution system. The analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) can be implemented, preferably in hardware, with any or a combination of the following technologies which are well known in the art: a discrete logic circuit(s) having logic gates for implementing logic functions upon data signals, and applications specific integrated circuit (ASIC) having appropriate combinational logic gates, a programmable gate array(s) (PGA), a field programmable gate array (FPGA), etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a sequential signal selection method for selecting two signals from a set of more than two signals that are received by the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). N represents the total number of signals that are received by the analog pre-selection network <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). The sequential signal selection method starts with a step <highlight><bold>810</bold></highlight>, where j&equals;0, and j is a total number of signals that the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) has tested from the at least two signals received via lines <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). The starting step <highlight><bold>810</bold></highlight> also comprises an i&equals;0, where i is a total number of signals among j that pass the test. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The following step <highlight><bold>820</bold></highlight> determines whether or not N less j is greater than 1. In other words, step <highlight><bold>820</bold></highlight> determines if there are two or more signals that are left to be tested by the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). If there are two or more signals left to be tested by the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>), in block <highlight><bold>830</bold></highlight>, at least two signals are pre-selected from the N&minus;j signals. However, any number of signals can be pre-selected from the N&minus;j signals. The at least two signals that are pre-selected in the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) have the best first metrics among the first metrics of the N&minus;j signals. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the analog correlation receiver <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>615</bold></highlight> calculates the first metric that represents a correlation between a code of each signal in the N&minus;j signals, and a pre-determined code, and then the sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) sorts at least two signals from the N&minus;j signals, where each of the at least two signals, among the N&minus;j signals, have the highest correlation to the pre-determined code. Alternatively, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, modulated frequency sorters <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>715</bold></highlight> calculate a first metric of each of the N&minus;j signals, where the first metric represents the nearness of the frequency of the envelope of each of the N&minus;j signals to a pre-determined frequency. The sorting device <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) sorts at least two signals from the N&minus;j signals, where each of the at least two signals have the best first metrics among the N&minus;j signals. Moreover, any method that is known to those having ordinary skill in the art can be used to calculate the first metrics, or to sort the at least two signals from the N&minus;j signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Once the analog pre-select <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) pre-selects at least two signals from the N&minus;j signals, in block <highlight><bold>840</bold></highlight>, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) computes a second metric for each of the at least two signals and stores the second metric in the memory device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) computes the second metric based on for instance, a correlation of a code of each of the at least two signals to a pre-determined code, a comparison of frequency of the envelopes of each of the at least two signals to a pre-determined frequency, a computation of bit error rate of each of the at least two signals, or any other method of comparison known to those having ordinary skill in the art. Thereafter, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) tests the at least two signals by comparing the second metrics to a threshold. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) updates j so that j represents the total number of signals that have been tested among the N signals. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) also updates i so that i represents the total number of signals among the j signals that pass the test administered by the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The step <highlight><bold>860</bold></highlight> determines whether the total number of signals i that pass the test administered in the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>), is greater than 1. If so, in step <highlight><bold>870</bold></highlight>, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) chooses two signals among the i signals, where each of the two signals have the best second metrics among the i signals. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) may choose any number of signals among the i signals. Once the two signals that have the best second metrics among the i signals, are chosen in step <highlight><bold>870</bold></highlight>, the sequential signal selection method ends in step <highlight><bold>880</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> If the total number of signals i that pass the test that is administered in the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) is not greater than 1, the step <highlight><bold>860</bold></highlight> loops back to the step <highlight><bold>820</bold></highlight>. The step <highlight><bold>860</bold></highlight> keeps on looping back to the step <highlight><bold>820</bold></highlight> till i, which is the total number of signals that pass the test, is greater than 1. If the total number of signals N less the total number of signals that have been tested, j, is not greater than 1, step <highlight><bold>890</bold></highlight> follows from step <highlight><bold>820</bold></highlight>. In step <highlight><bold>890</bold></highlight>, the processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) chooses two signals among the N signals, where the two signals have the best second metrics among the second metrics of the N signals. The processor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) may choose any number of signals among the N signals. The sequential signal selection method then ends in the step <highlight><bold>880</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Any process descriptions or blocks in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> should be understood as representing modules, segments, or portions of code which include one or more executable instructions for implementing specific logical functions or steps in the sequential signal selection system and method, and alternative implementations are included within the scope of an embodiment of the sequential signal selection system and method in which functions may be executed out of order from that shown or discussed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, including substantially concurrently or in reverse order, depending on the functionality involved, as would be understood by those reasonably skilled in the art of the sequential signal selection system and method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> It should be emphasized that the above-described embodiments of the sequential signal selection system and method, particularly, any &ldquo;preferred&rdquo; embodiments, are merely possible examples of implementations, merely set forth for a clear understanding of the principles of the sequential signal selection system and method. Many variations and modifications may be made to the above-described embodiment(s) of the sequential signal selection system and method without departing substantially from the spirit and principles of the sequential signal selection system and method. All such modifications and variations are intended to be included herein within the scope of this disclosure and the sequential signal selection system and method and protected by the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">Therefore, having thus described the invention, at least the following is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A sequential signal selection system comprising: 
<claim-text>a processor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory device coupled to the processor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one radio/transceiver coupled to the processor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an analog pre-selection network coupled to the at least one radio/transceiver. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the analog pre-selection network comprises: 
<claim-text>a beam forming network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an antenna array coupled to the beam forming network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switching network coupled to the beam forming network; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an analog pre-select coupled to the switching network, and to the beam forming network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the analog pre-selection network comprises: 
<claim-text>a first analog pre-selection sub-network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second analog pre-selection sub-network; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third analog pre-selection sub-network coupled to the first analog pre-selection sub-network, and to the second analog pre-selection sub-network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the third analog pre-selection sub-network comprises: 
<claim-text>a third switching network coupled to the at least one radio/transceiver; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third analog pre-select coupled to the third switching network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second analog pre-selection sub-network comprises: 
<claim-text>a second switching network coupled to the third switching network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beamforming network coupled to the second switching network, the second beam forming network coupled to a second antenna array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second analog pre-select coupled to the second beam forming network, to the second switching network, and to the processor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first analog pre-selection sub-network comprises: 
<claim-text>a first switching network coupled to the third switching network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first beam forming network coupled to the first switching network, the first beam forming network coupled to a first antenna array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first analog pre-select coupled to the first beam forming network, to the first switching network, and to the processor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second analog pre-selection sub-network comprises: 
<claim-text>a second switching network coupled to the third switching network, the second switching network coupled to a second antenna array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second analog pre-select coupled to the second antenna array, and to the second switching network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second analog pre-select is coupled to the processor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first analog pre-selection sub-network comprises: 
<claim-text>a first switching network coupled to the third switching network; the first switching network coupled to a first antenna array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first analog pre-select coupled to the first antenna array, to the first switching network, and to the processor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the analog pre-select comprises: 
<claim-text>a band pass filter, the band pass filter coupled to the beam forming network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an amplifier coupled to the band pass filter; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector coupled to the amplifier; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sorting device coupled to the detector, to the processor, and to the switching network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the analog pre-select comprises: 
<claim-text>a band pass filter coupled to the beam forming network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an amplifier coupled to the band pass filter; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an analog correlation receiver coupled to the amplifier; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sorting device coupled to the analog correlation receiver, to the processor, and to the switching network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the analog pre-select comprises: 
<claim-text>a band pass filter, the band pass filter coupled to the beam forming network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an amplifier coupled to the band pass filter; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector coupled to the amplifier; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a modulated frequency sorter coupled to the detector; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sorting device coupled to the modulated frequency sorter, to the switching network, and to the processor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A sequential signal selection method, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>pre-selecting at least two signals from a set of signals based on a pre-selection method; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting at least one signal from the at least two signals based on a selection method. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pre-selection method is a receive signal strength indicator method. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pre-selection method comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>filtering the set of signals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>amplifying the set of signals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>rectifying the set of signals; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sorting the set of signals to obtain the at least two signals. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pre-selection method comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>filtering the set of signals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>amplifying the set of signals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing a code of each signal in the set of signals to a pre-determined code; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sorting the set of signals to obtain the at least two signals. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pre-selection method comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>filtering the set of signals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>amplifying the set of signals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing frequency of envelope of each signal in the set of signals to a pre-determined frequency; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sorting the set of signals to obtain the at least two signals. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the set of signals comprises a set of radio frequency signals, a set of acoustic signals, a set of optical signals, and a set of infrared signals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The sequential signal selection method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the selection method comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>comparing the at least two signals to a threshold; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sorting the at least two signals to obtain the at least one signal, wherein the at least two signals meet the threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A sequential signal selection system, comprising: 
<claim-text>means for pre-selecting at least two signals from a set of signals based on a pre-selection method; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for selecting at least one signal from the at least two signals based on a selection method.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003961A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
