<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003425A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003425A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003425A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003425A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003425A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003425A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003425A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003425A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003425A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003425A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003425A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003425A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003425</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10178674</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020624</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F41G003/26</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>434</class>
<subclass>023000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>434</class>
<subclass>019000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Training device and method for training a shooter to shoot with improved accuracy</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301397</doc-number>
<document-date>20010627</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Fay</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Frigon</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Garland</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Steven W. Smith</name-1>
<name-2>Attorney at Law</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 120</address-1>
<address-2>840 Central Parkway East</address-2>
<city>Plano</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75074-5569</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A device and method for training a shooter to shoot with improved accuracy. A picture of a target is fixedly mounted in front of a sight on a bow or gun. The picture is mounted in a stationary position which visually aligns an aiming point in the sight with the center of the picture when the shooter is in a shooting position. The shooter then shoots a plurality of shots in a safe direction while looking through the sight and focusing on the stationary mounted picture. In this manner, the shooter&apos;s subconscious mind is trained to keep the sight aligned with an actual target while shooting. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">PRIORITY STATEMENT UNDER 35 U.S.C. &sect;119(e) &amp; 37 C.F.R. &sect;1.78 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This nonprovisional application claims priority based upon the prior U.S. provisional patent application entitled, &ldquo;Training Device and Method for Archery and Gunnery,&rdquo; application No. 60/301,397, filed Jun. 27, 2001 in the name of Fay F. Frigon.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Technical Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to archery and gunnery training devices. More particularly, and not by way of limitation, the present invention is directed to a training device and method for training an archer or gunner to shoot with improved accuracy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Over the years, many advances have been made in the sport of archery to improve accuracy. Improvements in bow design, the addition of sights, and the use of release mechanisms to release the bow string have all contributed to greater accuracy. For example, the bow has evolved from the long bow to the compound bow. The compound bow uses a cam to increase arrow speed and improve accuracy. Sights and/or scopes are mounted on bows, and may have a plurality of sight pins that are adjustable for different target distances. Release mechanisms assist the archer by enabling the archer to release the bow string with a trigger device. Releasing a bow string with fingers increases string oscillation, thereby reducing accuracy. Release mechanisms reduce string oscillation, with a resultant increase in accuracy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Despite the technical improvements in archery equipment described above, accuracy is still limited by the human operator. One limitation is known as &ldquo;target panic&rdquo;. All shooters (archers and gunners) experience target panic to some degree. This is a condition at the moment of shooting a bow or firing a gun when, having made the decision to release the bow string or press the trigger, the shooter&apos;s mind freezes and no longer makes corrections if the sight drifts off the target. For example, with a fully drawn bow, if the pin in the sight drifts off the target, the archer&apos;s mind does not recognize the error, and no correction is made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Target panic is an unconscious condition which often goes undiagnosed as the source of a shooter&apos;s accuracy problem because the shooter is not aware that it is happening. It is thought that target panic occurs because the mind is overloaded, and cannot simultaneously perform another task. In archery, for example, archers are simultaneously performing the tasks of holding back the bow string, making corrections to hold the bow vertical, judging the wind, judging the distance to the target, selecting a sight pin appropriate for the distance, and moving the bow to optically align the selected sight pin with the target. Competition archers use from 9 to 15 steps to complete a shot. When the additional mental task of deciding to shoot is added, or if a thought enters the mind raising a fear about the accuracy of the coming shot, the mind overloads and stops making corrections. This causes the archer to squeeze the release mechanism when the sight pin is not aligned with the target. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An existing method of overcoming target panic is to train a shooter to squeeze the release mechanism or trigger so slowly that the shooter himself is surprised when the weapon fires. The reasoning is that the shooter&apos;s mind will continue to make corrections up until the moment of shooting since a mental decision to fire is never made. However, this technique presumes that the shooter&apos;s mind is not already overloaded from other tasks, and that it is the decision to shoot that causes the overload and the target panic. This may not be the case. In addition, this technique has several other disadvantages. First, being uncertain when the weapon is going to fire may be uncomfortable for many shooters. Second, since an archer must maintain considerable force to hold back the bow string, his shot may get less accurate if this position must be held for a longer period of time. The same is true for a gunner if he is shooting a fairly heavy rifle or pistol. Third, archers and gunners engaged in shooting competitions may have to shoot rapidly, and it is not realistic to squeeze the release mechanism or trigger so slowly that the shooter is surprised when the weapon fires. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Thus, in order to overcome the disadvantage of existing solutions, it would be advantageous to have a training device and method for training an archer or gunner to overcome the mental problem of target panic that effectively eliminates the problem of target panic regardless of other tasks being performed. The present invention provides such a device and method. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, the present invention is directed to a training device for training a shooter to shoot with improved accuracy. The device includes a picture of a target, and means for mounting the picture on an opposite side of a sighting mechanism from the shooter&apos;s eye. The picture is mounted in a position in which the picture is visually aligned with the sighting mechanism when the shooter is in a shooting position. By shooting shots while looking through the sighting mechanism and focusing on the stationary picture, the shooter&apos;s subconscious mind is trained to maintain a sight-picture in which the sighting mechanism remains aligned with the target while shooting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, the present invention is directed to a method of training a shooter to shoot with improved accuracy. The method begins by fixedly mounting a picture of a target on an opposite side of a sighting mechanism from the shooter&apos;s eye, the picture being mounted in a stationary position in which the center of the picture is visually aligned with the sighting mechanism when the shooter is in a shooting position. This is followed by shooting a plurality of shots by the shooter while looking through the sighting mechanism and focusing on the stationary picture of the target. In this manner, the shooter&apos;s subconscious mind is trained to maintain a sight-picture in which the sighting mechanism remains aligned with the target while shooting.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The invention will be better understood and its numerous objects and advantages will become more apparent to those skilled in the art by reference to the following drawings, in conjunction with the accompanying specification, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a first embodiment of the training device of the present invention mounted on an archery pin sight; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a second embodiment of the training device of the present invention mounted on an archery scope sight; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternative embodiment of the training device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a third embodiment of the training device of the present invention illustrating an alternative mechanism for mounting the device on a bow; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an illustrative drawing of a view through an archery pin sight when utilizing the training device of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an illustrative drawing of a view through a gun sight when utilizing the training device of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating the steps of the preferred embodiment of the training method of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to a training device and method for training an archer or gunner to overcome the mental problem of &ldquo;target panic&rdquo; at the moment of shooting. During shooting practice, the invention trains the shooter&apos;s subconscious mind to hold the sight on the center of the target until the shot is completed. Thereafter, when the shooter shoots at a real target, target panic is overcome, and accuracy is improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a first embodiment of the training device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention mounted on an archery pin sight <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> with, for example, a mounting bracket <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A picture <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> (for example, a drawing or photograph) of a target is mounted in a position in which the pin sight is visually aligned with the picture. The picture may be mounted by any suitable means such as, for example, hook-and-pile material (i.e, Velcro), clamps, screws, tape, adhesive, and the like. The mounting bracket allows the position of the picture to be adjusted horizontally and vertically so that the center of the target is visually aligned with a selected pin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The pin sight <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> mounts to a bow (not shown) with a pin sight mounting bracket <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The entire apparatus (pin sight <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and mounted training device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) is thus held in a stationary position on the bow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The picture <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is stationary relative to the pin sight <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, and thus the sight cannot drift off of the pictured target. The shooter then practices shooting in a safe direction while &ldquo;aiming&rdquo; at the pictured target. This process trains the subconscious mind to maintain the image that the shooter sees (i.e., the sight pin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> aligned with the target and not moving). Thereafter, when shooting at an actual target, the mind is conditioned, and the mind will not allow the sight to drift off the actual target when shooting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a second embodiment of the training device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention mounted on an archery scope sight <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The configuration of the scope sight <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is different from the pin sight <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), thereby requiring a mounting ring <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for mounting the training device to the scope sight. A set screw <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> or other suitable mechanism such as Velcro, clamps, tape, or adhesive may be utilized to secure the mounting ring to the scope sight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The operation of the training device in this embodiment is substantially unchanged from the first embodiment. The scope sight uses an aiming point <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in the center of the scope field of view. The picture <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the target is therefore mounted in a position in which the aiming point <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is visually aligned with the center of the target. The scope sight mounts to a bow (not shown) with a scope sight mounting bracket <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The entire apparatus (pin sight <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and mounted training device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) is thus held in a stationary position on the bow. Once again, the picture <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is stationary relative to the scope sight <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and thus the sight cannot drift off of the pictured target. The shooter then practices shooting in a safe direction while &ldquo;aiming&rdquo; at the pictured target. Again, the subconscious mind is trained to maintain this image while shooting at actual targets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternative embodiment of the training device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In this embodiment, the training device includes a plurality of cut-off mounting rings <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of varying diameters. For example, the rings may range from one inch to two inches in diameter. Scope sights are manufactured in varying diameters, and the diameters of the cut-off mounting rings may be sized to match the most common scope diameters. In use, therefore, the shooter selects the size that matches his scope, and cuts off the smaller sized mounting rings. The selected mounting ring is then utilized to mount the training device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the scope sight <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The device is then used as described above to overcome target panic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a third embodiment of the training device <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the present invention illustrating an alternative mechanism for mounting the device on a bow. In this embodiment, the device mounts directly to the bow (not shown) rather than to the sight. A picture-mounting bracket <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is used to mount the picture <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the target in the shooter&apos;s line of view. The picture-mounting bracket accepts one end of an adjusting rod <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in an aperture formed in the mount. A bow-mounting bracket <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> attaches to the bow, and accepts the other end of the adjusting rod in an aperture formed in the mount. The position of the picture, may be adjusted by sliding and/or rotating the adjusting rod in the aperture in either the picture-mounting bracket or the bow-mounting bracket. Set screws <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be utilized to fix the position of the picture such that it is visually aligned with whatever type of sight the shooter chooses to use. The device is then used as described above to overcome target panic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an illustrative drawing of a view through an archery pin sight <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> when utilizing the training device of the present invention. The position of the picture <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> has been fixed so that the center pin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is held stationary in the center of the picture. With this configuration, the shooter then practices shooting in a safe direction while &ldquo;aiming&rdquo; at the pictured target. As noted above, this process trains the subconscious mind to maintain the image that the shooter sees (i.e., the sight pin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> aligned with the target and not moving). Thereafter, when shooting at an actual target, the mind is conditioned, and the mind will not allow the sight to drift off the actual target when shooting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an illustrative drawing of a view through a gun sight when utilizing the training device of the present invention. Although the preferred embodiments are described herein for use in archery training, the present invention is equally applicable to gunnery training. In this configuration, the training device may be mounted on the gun barrel, and the picture may be positioned above the path of any bullet that is fired. Alternatively, the picture may be mounted in front of the gun barrel, and may have a hole in it for the bullet to pass through. As illustrated, the position of the picture has been fixed so that when the front sight <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is aligned with the rear sight <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, the center of the picture <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is visually aligned with the gun sight. With this configuration, the shooter then practices shooting in a safe direction while &ldquo;aiming&rdquo; at the pictured target. As noted above, this process trains the subconscious mind to maintain the image that the shooter sees (i.e., the gun sight aligned with the target and not moving). Thereafter, when shooting at an actual target, the mind is conditioned, and the mind will not allow the sight to drift off the actual target when shooting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating the steps of the preferred embodiment of the training method of the present invention. The method is described in archery terms, but as noted above, may also be utilized for gunnery training. At step <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, the training device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is mounted to the sight, or directly to the bow, depending on the shooting configuration. At step <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, the picture <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the target is mounted in the training device so that the target is visible through the sight, and the sighting mechanism (e.g., sight pin, aiming point, etc.) is centered on the target. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The shooter is then ready to practice, and at step <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> loads (nocks) an arrow. At step <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, the shooter raises and draws the bow in a safe direction. For safety reasons, since the shooter cannot actually see where he is aiming, it is recommended that this procedure be performed only at a controlled archery range, and at a distance of no more than five yards from a safe arrow impact zone. At step <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, the shooter then looks through his peep sight and through his pin or scope sight, and focuses on the mounted picture and the stationary sight pin positioned in the center of the target. The shooter then executes the shot at step <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> while remaining focused on the mounted picture of the target. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> At step <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>, the shooter repeats the training method as often as he is able, and preferably at least once daily, for a training period of four to six weeks. With repetition, this process trains the subconscious mind to maintain this &ldquo;sightpicture&rdquo; all the way through the shooting process. It is also recommended at step <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> that the shooter abstain from shooting at real targets and concentrate his training solely on this process for at least the first three weeks of the four to six week training period. Training the subconscious mind takes dedication, requiring many hours of practice and repetition. For those willing to make the effort, test results of the present invention have shown remarkable improvement in shooting accuracy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> It is thus believed that the operation and construction of the present invention will be apparent from the foregoing description. While the training device and method shown and described has been characterized as being preferred, it will be readily apparent that various changes and modifications could be made therein without departing from the scope of the invention as defined in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A training device for training a shooter to shoot with improved accuracy, said device comprising: 
<claim-text>a picture of a target; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for mounting the picture on an opposite side of a sighting mechanism from the shooter&apos;s eye, said mounting means mounting the picture in a position in which the picture is visually aligned with the sighting mechanism when the shooter is in a shooting position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The training device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the means for mounting the picture includes a mounting bracket that holds the picture of the target and connects to the sighting mechanism. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The training device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mounting bracket connects to an archery pin sight and holds the picture of the target in a position where a sight pin is visually aligned with the center of the pictured target. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The training device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mounting bracket connects to an archery scope sight and holds the picture of the target in a position where an aiming point in the scope is visually aligned with the center of the pictured target. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The training device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the means for mounting the picture includes a mounting bracket that holds the picture of the target and connects to a bow. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The training device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the means for mounting the picture includes a mounting bracket that holds the picture of the target and connects to a gun. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The training device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mounting bracket connects to the gun barrel and holds the picture of the target in a position where a gun sight is visually aligned with the center of the pictured target. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The training device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mounting bracket holds the picture of the target above a path followed by a bullet fired from the gun. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The training device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mounting bracket holds the picture of the target in front of the gun, the picture having an aperture therein that allows a bullet fired from the gun to pass therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of training a shooter to shoot with improved accuracy, said method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>fixedly mounting a picture of a target on an opposite side of a sighting mechanism from the shooter&apos;s eye, said picture being mounted in a stationary position in which the center of the picture is visually aligned with the sighting mechanism when the shooter is in a shooting position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>shooting a plurality of shots by the shooter while looking through the sighting mechanism at the stationary picture of the target; </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby the shooter&apos;s subconscious mind is trained to maintain a sight-picture in which the sighting mechanism remains aligned with the target while shooting. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of training a shooter of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising repeating the steps of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> at least once daily for a training period of approximately four to six weeks. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of training a shooter of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of repeating the steps of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> at least once daily for a period of approximately four to six weeks includes abstaining from shooting at real targets for approximately the first three weeks of the training period.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003425A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003425A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003425A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003425A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003425A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003425A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
