<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001411A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001411A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001411A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001411A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001411A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001411A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001411A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001411A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001411A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001411A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001411</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894761</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B60N002/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>296</class>
<subclass>192000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Gas-assisted two-shot injection molding process</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>Anthony</middle-name>
<family-name>Gedritis</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Grand Rapids</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kevin</given-name>
<middle-name>Allen</middle-name>
<family-name>Bull</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Cedar Springs</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>WARNER NORCROSS &amp; JUDD LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>900 FIFTH THIRD CENTER</address-1>
<address-2>111 LYON STREET, N.W.</address-2>
<city>GRAND RAPIDS</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>49503-2487</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A process for injection molding a composite of rigid thermoplastic and soft thermoplastic, the soft thermoplastic including a cavity established with pressurized assist gas or an assist liquid. The process includes the steps of: injecting a hard molten thermoplastic into a first mold chamber; injecting a soft molten thermoplastic into a second mold chamber; establishing communication between the first chamber and the second chamber so that the rigid thermoplastic and soft thermoplastic integrally bond; and injecting an assist fluid into the soft thermoplastic to form a cavity. In a preferred embodiment, the formed composite is an automotive cowl where the rigid thermoplastic forms the rigid body portion of the cowl and the integrally bonded soft thermoplastic forms a compressible bulb seal. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to injection molding a composite article including a rigid thermoplastic and a soft thermoplastic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In many industries, it is desirable to combine the structural characteristics of a rigid thermoplastic with the sealing abilities of a soft and flexible thermoplastic. For example, in the automotive industry, a cowl&mdash;the transition trim part between the hood and windshield&mdash;typically includes a rigid piece of plastic and a soft, blade-like seal bonded to an edge of the rigid piece. The rigid piece forms the body of the cowl and is secured to a body panel of the automobile. The blade seal engages the hood, providing an interface between the cowl and the hood to prevent water from leaking into the engine compartment and to suppress engine noise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Conventional rigid/soft thermoplastic composites such as cowls are made with a &ldquo;two-shot&rdquo; injection molding process. This process uses a mold that is initially separated by a retractable mold insert into two chambers&mdash;a body chamber corresponding to the body of the cowl, and a seal chamber corresponding to the blade seal. In the process, molten structural or &ldquo;hard&rdquo; thermoplastic is injected into and fills the body chamber. Next, the mold insert is retracted to expose an edge of the structural thermoplastic to the seal chamber. Then, a molten soft thermoplastic is injected into and fills the seal chamber, and simultaneously bonds to the exposed edge to form a rigid/soft thermoplastic composite cowl. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Although the resultant rigid/soft composite cowl includes the desired structural rigidity and sealing capability, it suffers a significant shortcoming. Due to repeated contact with the hood and exposure to excessive heat from the engine, the blade seal deforms from its original shape, and becomes incapable of satisfactorily engaging the hood to provide the required seal. This loss of sealing ability of the blade seal is common in many other rigid/soft thermoplastic composite applications as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In an unrelated field, pressurized gas conventionally is used to add rigidity to hard thermoplastic bodies. In one application, pressurized gas is injected into molten hard thermoplastic resin as the resin is injected into a mold. The gas pushes resin out of its way to form cavities within the hard resin. When the hard resin cools, the completed hard plastic body includes cavities that enhance the rigidity and structural strength of the body. This use of pressurized gas provides a way to increase rigidity of hard plastic bodies; however, many opportunities exist to use pressurized gas in novel applications. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The aforementioned problems are overcome in the present invention that provides a single mold injection process in which a rigid thermoplastic is bonded to a soft thermoplastic and pressurized assist gas is injected into the soft thermoplastic to establish a cavity and thereby form a compressible bulb seal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, the present invention generally includes the steps of: injecting a molten rigid thermoplastic into a first mold chamber; injecting a molten soft thermoplastic into a second mold chamber; establishing fluid communication between the first and second mold chambers so that the rigid and soft thermoplastics bond to one another along an edge; and injecting pressurized assist gas or liquid into the soft thermoplastic to establish a cavity in the soft thermoplastic. Preferably, the pressurized gas pushes molten soft plastic out of the gases&apos; way and the space occupied by the gas forms the tube-like cavity through the soft plastic. After the thermoplastics cool, the resultant composite is removed from the mold. With the cavity formed in the soft thermoplastic, the soft thermoplastic portion of the composite forms a compressible and resilient seal with a cross section resembling a light bulb-hence the name &ldquo;bulb seal.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present inventive process provides an efficient and economical way to integrally bond a rigid thermoplastic to a soft thermoplastic that includes a bulb seal in a single mold process. With the process, resilient bulb seals may now be integrated into a variety rigid/soft thermoplastic composite articles including automotive trim pieces, such as cowls, doors and door jambs; household appliance trim; construction materials, such as doorways and windows; and the like. Accordingly, these composite articles offer improved sealing capabilities because the integral bulb seal is less prone to deformation over time due to repeated contact with an item against which it interfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the present invention provides a novel use of assist gas. Rather than use assist gas to make hard thermoplastic parts more rigid and strong, the present invention uses assist gas to make soft plastic bodies more supple and resilient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> These and other objects, advantages and features of the invention will be more readily understood and appreciated by reference to the detailed description of the preferred embodiments and the drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view of an automotive cowl composite formed according to a process of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a mold used in the process of the present invention as hard thermoplastic is injected into the mold; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the mold when the hard thermoplastic has been injected into the mold; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the mold as a core is retracted and soft thermoplastic is injected into the mold; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the mold as pressurized assist fluid is injected into the soft thermoplastic; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a completed composite cowl within the mold.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment, the present invention is described in connection with the manufacture of injection molded thermoplastic automotive trim cowls. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, cowl <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, formed according to the process of the present invention, includes body <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and bulb seal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Body <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is constructed of a rigid or hard thermoplastic or resin and bulb seal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is constructed of a supple or soft thermoplastic or resin. The rigid thermoplastic <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the body <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is integrally bonded to the soft thermoplastic <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the bulb seal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at interface <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the hard thermoplastic or resin is polypropylene (PP) and the soft resin a thermoplastic elastomer (TPE). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Optionally, the hard thermoplastic may be any commercially available hard or rigid thermoplastic including but not limited to the following: polyethylene (PE), acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene (ABS), polystyrene (PS), polycarbonate (PC), thermoplastic olefin (TPO), nylon (PA), polyacetal (PMMA), polyethylene terephthalate (PET), polybutylene terephthalate (PBT), acrylonitrile styrene acrylate (ASA), polybutylene terephalate (PBT) and polyester. Optionally, mineral, glass fiber or synthetic fiber-filled versions of rigid thermoplastic, including those above, may be used. Further, commercially available blends of rigid thermoplastic may be used, such as ABS-ASA, ABS-PA, ABS-PBT, and the like. The soft thermoplastic may be any commercially available soft or supple thermoplastic including but not limited to the following: thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU), polyvinyl chloride (PVC), thermoplastic olefin (TPO) and ionomers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The cowl body <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes top surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, bottom surface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, side edge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (opposite side edge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> not shown), an elongated back edge <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and an elongated front edge&mdash;not visible as it is coincident with the interface <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the rigid thermoplastic <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the soft thermoplastic <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The elongated back edge <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> abuts the windshield <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the automobile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> With further reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the bulb seal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes cavity or void <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extending therethrough. As used herein, &ldquo;bulb seal&rdquo; refers to an article constructed of soft thermoplastic including an internal cavity of any size, shape or dimension formed using a gas or liquid assist process. The bulb seal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> engages the hood <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to form a seal when the hood <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is in a closed position as depicted. Because bulb seal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is constructed of soft thermoplastic <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and includes cavity <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> therein, it is compressible and resilient, and thereby capable of enduring repeated and continuous sealing engagement with the hood over the useful life of the vehicle without deforming. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the injection molding equipment <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment will now be described. The injection molding equipment <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> generally includes upper <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and lower <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> mold halves operatively movable between open (not shown) and closed positions with commercially available hydraulic, pneumatic, or electric systems. In the closed position, the upper <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and lower <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> mold halves meet together along mold interface <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The mold halves <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> define first mold cavity <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and second mold cavity <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A mold insert or slide core <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is adapted to slide in channel <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, which is defined by the upper mold <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Slide core <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> includes a block, plate or member which prevents materials in the first mold cavity <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> from communicating with materials in the second mold cavity <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> when it is in its extended or protracted position as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Optionally, the slide core is of any size, shape or dimension. The slide core <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is movable from the protracted position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> to a retracted position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, preferably by a hydraulic cylinder <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Hydraulic cylinder <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is in fluid communication with a control pump (not shown) via hydraulic supply line <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The hydraulic cylinder <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is optionally controlled by a microprocessor (not shown) to move the slide core <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> as desired. Optionally, the slide core is moveable by any commercially available actuating mechanism, for example, an electric servo motor, pneumatic drive, gear drive, rack and pinion drive, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> With further reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the upper mold <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> further includes rigid resin injection barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, which is in fluid communication with a rigid resin supply (not shown) via supply line <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The hard resin injection barrel is preferably located in the first mold chamber to deliver a shot or predetermined quantity of rigid or hard thermoplastic resin&mdash;in molten or liquid form&mdash;into the first mold chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The upper mold <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> also includes a soft resin injection barrel <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, which is in fluid communication with a soft resin supply (not shown) via supply line <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The soft resin injection barrel <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is preferably located in the second mold chamber to deliver a shot of soft thermoplastic resin&mdash;in molten or liquid form&mdash;into the second mold chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Additionally, a gas injection port <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is disposed in the upper mold, in communication with second mold chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and further in communication with a gas supply (not shown) via gas supply line <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The gas injection port is capable of injecting pressurized gas into the soft thermoplastic resin as that resin is injected from soft resin injection barrel <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> into the second mold chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Optionally, the gas injection port may be disposed in the lower mold. As will be appreciated by those skilled in the art, other gas injection systems may be substituted for the injection ports to inject gas into the mold. For example, the gas may be injected directly into a resin feed machine (not shown) used to deliver resin to the mold. Optionally, in cases where resin is injected through a runner system (not shown) into the mold, the gas may be injected directly into the runner system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the pressurized inert gas is nitrogen, however any commercially available assist gas may be used. Optionally, any commercially available assist liquid, for example water, may be used as well. In such an option, the assist liquid would be injected through the port <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> into the soft thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and operate under principles similar to that of an assist gas. As used herein, assist fluid refers to any commercially available assist gas or assist liquid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Additionally, temperature and pressure sensors (not shown) may be distributed throughout the upper and lower <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> mold halves to monitor temperature and pressure within the chambers <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> at preselected locations. These sensors can be employed with supply sensors (not shown) monitoring the amount of materials injected through the hard resin injection barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, the soft resin injection barrel <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and the gas injection port <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, to input information to a microprocessor (not shown) which consequently controls the injection molding process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As will be appreciated, the hard resin injection barrel, soft resin injection barrel, gas assist injection port <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, slide core <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and hydraulic cylinder <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> may be disposed in any combination in either the upper <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> or lower mold <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Optionally, additional molds and slide cores may be combined with the upper <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and lower <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> molds to create the desired configuration of the hard resin/soft resin composite. Further, a commercially available cooling system may be integrated into the upper <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and lower <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> molds to facilitate cooling of injected resins. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Method of Manufacture </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the preferred process of the invention will now be described in connection with the manufacture of injection molded thermoplastic automotive trim cowls. When the slide core <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is moved to its protracted position as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the mold halves <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> are clamped together with suitable clamping pressure to define first mold chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and second mold chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The first mold chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> corresponds to the rigid body of the cowl and the second mold chamber corresponds to the bulb seal of the cowl. At this time, a first molten thermoplastic resin, preferably a rigid thermoplastic <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is injected into the first mold chamber through to hard resin injection barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> until the first mold chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is satisfactorily filled as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the clamping pressure between the upper <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and lower mold halves <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> may then be relieved. The slide core <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is then retracted in the direction as indicated by the arrow by hydraulic cylinder <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> into the channel <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> to expose the rigid thermoplastic body <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which still may be partially molten, to the second mold chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> With further reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, after the slide core <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is retracted, the upper and lower molds <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> are again clamped together with pressure. As will be appreciated, this may not be necessary if pressure between upper and lower mold halves is not relieved. A soft thermoplastic resin shot is injected through soft thermoplastic resident barrel <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> into the second chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Almost simultaneously, pressurized assist gas from a gas supply (not shown) is pumped through line <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and into the second mold cavity <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> via gas injection port <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the soft resin shot <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> continues to pump into the second mold chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> through soft resin injection barrel <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. As the soft resin fills the second mold chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, the innermost portion of the soft resin <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> remains heated and viscous. Accordingly, when pressurized assist gas is injected into the second mold chamber <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> via gas injection port <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, the gas pushes the soft thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> outwards (as depicted by the arrows) to form an expanding cavity <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As further depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the soft thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> begins to fuse and integrally bond to the rigid thermoplastic <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at interface <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Injection of the soft thermoplastic <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and pressurized assist gas into second mold cavity <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> continues at a rate and for a duration of time experimentally determined until the cavity <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is expanded to desired dimensions and the soft thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> bonds to rigid thermoplastic <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> along interface <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Optionally, assist liquid, rather than assist gas, may be injected into the soft thermoplastic <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> to form the cavity <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In another step, the soft thermoplastic is allowed to cool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Upon cooling, the soft thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is fully bonded with interface <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to the rigid thermoplastic <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Cavity <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is formed so that the soft thermoplastic <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> defines a bulb seal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. At this point, any excess pressure within the cavity <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> caused by the pressurized assist gas or assist liquid therein may be relieved through an exhaust port (not shown) or back through assist gas injection port <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. After cooling and release of pressure from the cavity <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the clamping pressure is relieved, and the mold halves <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> are separated. The completed cowl is removed from the mold halves <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The completed cowl is composite in nature, including rigid thermoplastic body <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and soft thermoplastic bulb seal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which is bonded at interface <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to the rigid thermoplastic body <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The completed cowl preferably has an appearance of cowl <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The above descriptions are those of the preferred embodiments of the invention. Various alterations and changes can be made without departing from the spirit and broader aspects of the invention as defined in the appended claims, which are to be interpreted in accordance with the principles of patent law including the doctrine of equivalents. Any references to claim elements in the singular, for example, using the articles &ldquo;a,&rdquo; &ldquo;an,&rdquo; &ldquo;the,&rdquo; or &ldquo;said,&rdquo; is not to be construed as limiting the element to the singular. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">The embodiments of the invention in which an exclusive property or privilege is claimed are defined as follows: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A process for fluid-assist injection molding and composite article comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a mold; </claim-text>
<claim-text>injecting a shot of hard thermoplastic resin in molten form into the mold; </claim-text>
<claim-text>injecting a shot of soft thermoplastic resin in molten form into the mold, a first portion of the soft thermoplastic resin bonding to the hard thermoplastic resin, a second portion of the soft thermoplastic resin having a viscous interior; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>injecting assist fluid into the heated viscous interior to establish a cavity in the second portion of the soft thermoplastic resin. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the step of allowing the hard thermoplastic and soft thermoplastic to cool and solidify. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the hard thermoplastic is polypropylene and the soft thermoplastic is a thermoplastic elastomer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mold defines a first chamber and a second chamber selectively separated by a core slide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the core slide is moveable between a protracted position and retracted position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the soft thermoplastic is prevented from bonding to the hard thermoplastic when the core slide is in a protracted position and wherein the soft thermoplastic and hard thermoplastic bond to one another when the core slide is in a retracted position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A process for injection molding a composite article comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>injecting a hard thermoplastic into a first mold chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>injecting a soft thermoplastic into a second mold chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>establishing communication between said first mold chamber and the second mold chamber so that the hard thermoplastic and soft thermoplastic bond to one another; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>introducing a pressurized gas into said soft thermoplastic whereby a cavity is formed in the soft thermoplastic. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the soft thermoplastic with the cavity therein forms a bulb seal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second mold chambers are selectively separated by a retractable mold insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said establishing step includes retracting the mold insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the soft thermoplastic is chosen from the group consisting of thermoplastic elastomer, thermoplastic polyurethane, polyvinyl chloride, thermoplastic olefin and ionomers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the hard thermoplastic is chosen from the group consisting of: polypropylene, polyethylene, acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene, polystyrene, polycarbonate, thermoplastic olefin, nylon, polyacetal, polyethylene terephthalate, polybutylene terephthalate, acrylonitrile styrene acrylate, polybutylene terephalate and polyester. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A automotive cowl formed by the process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A cowl for use in a vehicle between a windshield and a hood of the vehicle, the cowl comprising: 
<claim-text>a rigid thermoplastic body including a top surface, a bottom surface, an elongated front edge, an elongated back edge, sides extending from said back edge to said front edge; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a compressible bulb seal integrally molded to said rigid thermoplastic body along said front edge, said seal formed from a material that is soft relative to said rigid thermoplastic body and adapted to provide an interface between the cowl and the vehicle hood. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The cowl according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said rigid thermoplastic body is constructed of materials chosen from: polypropylene, polyethylene, acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene, polystyrene, polycarbonate, thermoplastic olefin, nylon, polyacetal, polyethylene terephthalate, polybutylene terephthalate, acrylonitrile styrene acrylate, polybutylene terephalate and polyester. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A cowl according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the bulb seal is constructed from materials chosen from thermoplastic elastomer, thermoplastic polyurethane, polyvinyl chloride, thermoplastic olefin and ionomers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for injection molding composite articles comprising: 
<claim-text>a mold including a first chamber and a second chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a retractable insert capable of selectively separating said first chamber from said second chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for injecting a hard thermoplastic shot into said first chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for injecting a soft thermoplastic shot into said second chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for retracting said insert so that the hard thermoplastic and soft thermoplastic communicate with and bond to one another; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for injecting an assist fluid into the soft thermoplastic in the second chamber to form a cavity in the soft thermoplastic. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first mold chamber is in of a shape corresponding to an automotive cowl body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second mold chamber is of a shape corresponding to an exterior of a bulb seal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001411A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001411A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001411A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001411A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001411A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
