<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003747A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003747A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003747A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003747A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003747</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10096266</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020312</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-38114</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/4763</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>693000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Chemical mechanical polishing slurry for ruthenium titanium nitride and polishing process using the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jae Hong</given-name>
<family-name>Kim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Sungnam-shi</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sang Ick</given-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ichon-shi</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MARSHALL, GERSTEIN &amp; BORUN</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>6300 SEARS TOWER</address-1>
<address-2>233 SOUTH WACKER</address-2>
<city>CHICAGO</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60606-6357</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A CMP slurry for ruthenium titanium nitride and a polishing process using the same. In a process technology below 0.1 &mgr;m, when a capacitor using a (Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;x</subscript></highlight>Sr<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>)TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>film as a dielectric film is fabricated, the slurry is used to polish a ruthenium titanium nitride film deposited as a barrier film according to a CMP process. The CMP process is performed by using the slurry, to improve a polishing speed of ruthenium titanium nitride under a low polishing pressure. In addition, the CMP process is performed according to an one-step process by using one kind of slurry. As a result, defects on an insulating film are reduced and a polishing property is improved, thereby simplifying the CMP process. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Technical Field </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A chemical mechanical polishing (abbreviated as &lsquo;CMP&rsquo;) slurry for ruthenium titanium nitride (abbreviated as &lsquo;RTN&rsquo;), and a polishing process using the same are disclosed. In particular, a slurry is disclosed that is used when a RTN film deposited as a barrier film is polished according to a CMP process in forming a capacitor using a (Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;x</subscript></highlight>Sr<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>)TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>(abbreviated as &lsquo;BST&rsquo;) film as a dielectric film in a process technology below 0.1 &mgr;m. A polishing process using the same is also disclosed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> RTN is a precious material which has excellent mechanical and chemical properties and which is essential to form a high performance capacitor. RTN is used as a barrier film. According to the present invention, a CMP process is employed to polish RTN. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Here, the CMP process is a purification process mostly used for a semiconductor wafer manufacturing process over 64M requiring high accuracy, and the slurry is a chemicals for planarizing various insulating films on a silicon substrate. In general, the slurry consists of a solvent, a compound and an abrasive. Mostly, a surfactant is added in a small volume to improve a CMP property. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A compound and an abrasive are dependent upon a kind of a film to be polished. For example, an alkali solution such as KOH or NH<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>OH is used as a compound for polishing an oxide film, and SiO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is used as an abrasive for polishing the oxide film, and an oxidizer such as hydrogen peroxide is used as a compound for polishing a metal film, H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>, HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>or HCl is added in a small volume to adjust the slurry to acidity, and Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>is used as an abrasive for polishing the metal film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The CMP process is performed by combining a chemical reaction and a mechanical reaction. The chemical reaction implies a chemical reaction between a compound contained in the slurry and a film. In the mechanical reaction, a force applied by a polishing device is transmitted to the abrasive in the slurry, and the film receiving the chemical reaction is mechanically separated by the abrasive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> That is, in the CMP process, a rotating polishing pad and a substrate are directly pressure-contacted, and the polishing slurry is provided to an interface thereof. Thus, the surface of the substrate is mechanically chemically polished and planarized by the polishing pad coated with the slurry. Accordingly, a polishing speed and a defect and erosion of the polished surface vary with a composition of the slurry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> An appropriate slurry is not provided in polishing RTN according to the CMP process, and thus a slurry for tungsten or aluminum is employed. In this case, the polishing speed of RTN is very low, and thus the CMP process is performed for a long time under a high polishing pressure. Therefore, scratches and impurities are seriously generated on an insulating film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> And because RTN must be polished for a long time under a high polishing pressure, dishing which is polished more than the peripheral insulating film and erosion are generated on RTN adjacent to the insulating film, which deteriorate the properties of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> It will now be explained in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a semiconductor device where RTN is deposited as a barrier film. A gate oxide film <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a gate electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a mask insulating film <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are formed on a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An oxide film spacer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is formed at the side walls of the resultant structure. An interlayer insulating film is formed over the resultant structure. A presumed capacitor contact region is removed according to a photolithography process, thereby forming a interlayer insulating film pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, a stacked layer of polysilicon <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and buffer film <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> fills up the contact hole as a contact plug and a RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is formed on the whole surface of the resultant structure. A RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is patterned and planarized according to the CMP process, thereby forming a barrier film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view in a state where the CMP process is performed on the RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> by using the general slurry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The general conditions of the CMP process include a polishing pressure of 4 to 7 psi, a table revolution number of 80 to 100 rpm by a rotary type system, and a table movement speed of 600 to 700 ft/min by a linear type system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> However, the polishing speed of RTN is very low under the general conditions, and thus the CMP process is not successfully performed. So as to increase the polishing speed of RTN, the CMP process should be performed for an extended period of time, increasing a supply amount of slurry and a polishing pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> As a result, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, scratches <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are generated on the interlayer insulating film pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> due to the high polishing pressure, impurities such as slurry residuals or particles <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> remain thereon, the RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is polished more than the interlayer insulating film from a time of exposing the interlayer insulating film to cause a dishing phenomenon, and the peripheral interlayer insulating film is seriously eroded. Moreover, a slurry for the interlayer insulating film is required to remove the scratches <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the particles <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> generated after the CMP process of the RTN thin film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> That is, the RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is polished in a first step, and the surface of the interlayer insulating film pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is slightly polished by using a specific slurry in a second step, thereby preventing generation of the particles <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, a CMP slurry and a CMP process using the same are disclosed which can improve a polishing speed of RTN under a low polishing pressure and polish RTN according to an one-step process by using one kind of slurry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In addition, a method for manufacturing a semiconductor device according to a CMP process using a slurry, and a semiconductor device manufactured according to the method are also disclosed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> More specifically, a CMP slurry for RTN, containing ceric ammonium nitrate &lsqb;(NH<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Ce(NO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>&rsqb;, a CMP process using the same, a method for manufacturing a semiconductor device according to the CMP process using the slurry, and a semiconductor device manufactured according to the method are disclosed.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The disclosed slurries, processes, methods and devices will be better understood with reference to the accompanying drawings which are given only by way of illustration and thus are not limitative, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a semiconductor device where a RTN is deposited as a barrier film; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a semiconductor device where a RTN is patterned by using a known slurry; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a semiconductor device where a RTN is patterned by using a disclosed slurry.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PRESENTLY PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> First of all, a disclosed CMP slurry for RTN contains ceric ammonium nitrate &lsqb;(NH<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Ce(NO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>&rsqb;. The CMP slurry for RTN comprises distilled water, nitric acid (HNO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>), ceric ammonium nitrate and an abrasive. Preferably, HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>is used in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 10% by weight of the slurry, ceric ammonium nitrate is used in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 10% by weight of the slurry, and the abrasive is used in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 5% by weight of the slurry. Here, HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate are used in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 10% by weight of the slurry, thereby stabilizing and easily handling the slurry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>maintains pH of the slurry ranging from about 1 to about 7, preferably from about 1 to about 3 for strong acidity. H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>, HCl or H<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>PO<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>may be used instead of HNO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. However, HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>is most efficient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Ceric ammonium nitrate serves as an oxidizer for extracting electrons from ruthenium atoms. The more HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate are used, the more the polishing speed of RTN can be increased under the identical pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In more detail, the slurry containing about 2 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and about 2 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate has a polishing speed of about 450 &angst;/min under a polishing pressure of about 1 psi; the slurry containing about 2 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and about 6 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate has a polishing speed of about 700 &angst;/min under a polishing pressure of about 1 psi; the slurry containing about 2 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and about 10 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate has a polishing speed of about 950 &angst;/min under a polishing pressure of about 1 psi; the slurry containing about 6 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and about 2 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate has a polishing speed of about 550 &angst;/min under a polishing pressure of about 1 psi; and the slurry containing about 10 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and about 2 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate has a polishing speed of about 650 &angst;/min under a polishing pressure of about 1 psi. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As compared with the fact that the slurry containing about 2 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and about 2 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate has a polishing speed of about 1000 &angst;/min under a polishing pressure of about 4 psi, a polishing speed over 1000 &angst;/min even under a polishing pressure of about 1 psi can be obtained, by slightly increasing a content of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> However, when HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate are used in an amount over 10% by weight of the slurry, the slurry is not stabilized, and a polishing property of a pattern wafer is deteriorated. Accordingly, the content of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate should be maintained to a range from about 1 to about 10% by weight of the slurry. In addition, the process should be performed under a low polishing pressure to improve the polishing property of the pattern wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The abrasive is used to improve a mechanical operation of the slurry. In the present invention, CeO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, ZrO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>having a grain size below 1 &mgr;m is used as the abrasive to minimize scratches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the slurry of the present invention contains a buffer solution to constantly maintain pH. Here, a mixture of organic acid and organic acid salt (1:1), preferably acetic acid and acetic acid salt (1:1) is used as the buffer solution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As described above, the slurry of the present invention has strong acidity and reduces adhesion and density of ruthenium atoms by eroding or melting the surface of RTN. Therefore, a chemical property of RTN is so varied that RTN can be easily polished according to the CMP process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> That is, a mixture of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate added in the slurry increases an erosion and melting speed of RTN, to improve the polishing speed of RTN. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A method for preparing the CMP slurry for RTN in accordance with the present invention will now be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> CeO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, ZrO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>which is an abrasive is added to distilled water. Here, CeO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, ZrO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>is added in a stirring speed of about 10000 rpm so that abrasive particles can not be agglomerated. Thereafter, HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate are added thereto. The resulting mixture is stirred for about 30 minutes so that it can be completely mixed and stabilized. Therefore, the slurry of the present invention is prepared. Here, the abrasive is used in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 5% by weight of the slurry, and HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate are used in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 10% by weight of the slurry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In addition, another aspect of the present invention provides a CMP process using the CMP slurry for RTN. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> A method for forming a RTN pattern includes: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> (a) preparing a semiconductor substrate where a RTN thin film is formed; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> (b) patterning the RTN thin film according to the CMP process using the CMP slurry composition for RTN. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> A method for forming the pattern of the RTN thin film will now be explained in more detail. The semiconductor substrate where the RTN thin film is formed is pressure-adhered to a polishing pad formed on a rotary table of a CMP system. The slurry is supplied to an interface of the polishing pad and the RTN thin film, thus performing the CMP process. In the CMP process, a polishing pressure ranges from about 1 to about 4 psi, a table revolution number of a rotary type system ranges from about 10 to about 80 rpm, and a table movement speed of a linear type system ranges from about 100 to about 600 ft/min in consideration of the polishing speed of RTN thin film and the polishing property of the interlayer insulating film and the pattern wafer. An end-point detector is used to sense a time point of exposing the interlayer insulating film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The exposure time of the interlayer insulating film is sensed by using the end-point detector, and thus the RTN thin film is not more polished than the interlayer insulating film, thereby preventing the dishing phenomenon and the erosion of the peripheral interlayer insulating film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> A semiconductor device where RTN is patterned by using the CMP slurry for RTN will now be explained with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating the semiconductor device where RTN is patterned by using the slurry of the present invention. The CMP process is performed on the RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, by employing the slurry of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, when the CMP process is carried out in the process conditions of the present invention, defect generation on the interlayer insulating film pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and separation of the RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are prevented to improve the polishing property. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> That is, when the CMP process is performed under a minimum polishing pressure ranging from about 1 to about 4 psi which is generally allowable in any system, the RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is closely adhered to the interlayer insulating film pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and defects and scratches are prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In addition, when RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is polished according to the CMP process using the slurry of the present invention, a slurry for the interlayer insulating film is not required, and RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is polished according to an one-step process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> A method for manufacturing a semiconductor device includes patterning RTN by using the CMP slurry for RTN. The method for manufacturing the semiconductor device comprises: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> (a) forming an interlayer insulating film on a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having a predetermined lower structure <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> (b) patterning the interlayer insulating film to form an interlayer insulating film pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> having a contact hole; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> (c) filling up the contact hole with conducting material and performing over-etch to form a recess contact plug; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> (d) depositing a RTN thin film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> on the whole surface of the resultant structure; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> (e) forming a RTN thin film pattern on the recess contact plug by performing a CMP process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> gate oxide film <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a gate electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a mask insulating film <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are formed on the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having the predetermined lower structure in step (a), an oxide film spacer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is formed at the sidewalls of the resultant structure and the conducting material of step (c) is polysilicon <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The method further comprises forming silicon nitride on the interlayer insulating film at the step (a) and forming a buffer film <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> between the contact plug and RTN film pattern. Preferably, the buffer film <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is titanium silicide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Moreover, in addition to the step (a) through (e), the following steps (f) through (h) can be included, thereby finishing fabrication of the capacitor: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> (f) forming a sacrificial insulating film pattern which opens the contact plug; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> (g) forming a lower electrode film on the resultant structure and performing a CMP process using the sacrificial insulating film pattern as an etch barrier to obtain a lower electrode pattern; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> (h) sequentially forming a dielectric film and an upper electrode on the resultant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The lower electrode is a ruthenium film which is patterned by performing a CMP process using the slurry of this present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> A semiconductor device can be manufactured according to the method described above. The following examples are not intended to be limiting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> I. Preparation of Slurry </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> CeO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>having a grain size below 1 &mgr;m was added to 10 L of distilled water. Here, CeO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>was added in a stirring speed of about 10000 rpm so that particles cannot be agglomerated. Thereafter, HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate were added thereto. The resulting mixture was stirred for about 30 minutes so that it could be completely mixed and stabilized. Therefore, the slurry of the present invention was prepared. Here, CeO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>was used in an amount of about 1% by weight of the slurry, and HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate were used in an amount of about 2% by weight of the slurry, respectively. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The procedure of Example 1 was repeated but using about 6 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate, instead of using about 2 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 3 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The procedure of Example 1 was repeated but using about 10 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate, instead of using about 2 wt % of ceric ammonium nitrate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 4 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The procedure of Example 1 was repeated but using about 6 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>, instead of using about 2 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 5 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The procedure of Example 1 was repeated but using about 10 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, instead of using about 2 wt % of HNO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> II. CMP Process Using Slurry </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 6 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> A table revolution number and a wafer revolution number were respectively set up to be about 20 rpm and about 80 rpm, by using a rotary type system. Here, the CMP process was performed on the RTN thin film under a polishing pressure of about 1 psi by using the slurry prepared in Example 1 (polishing speed: about 450 &angst;/min). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> An end-point detector is used to sense a time point of exposing the interlayer insulating film. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 7 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The procedure of Example 6 was repeated but using the slurry prepared in Example 2, instead of using the slurry prepared in Example 1 (polishing speed: about 700 &angst;/min). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 8 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The procedure of Example 6 was repeated but using the slurry prepared in Example 3, instead of using the slurry prepared in Example 1 (polishing speed: about 950 &angst;/min). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 9 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The procedure of Example 6 was repeated but using the slurry prepared in Example 4, instead of using the slurry prepared in Example 1 (polishing speed: about 550 &angst;/min). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 10 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The procedure of Example 6 was repeated but using the slurry prepared in Example 5, instead of using the slurry prepared in Example 1 (polishing speed: about 650 &angst;/min). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 11 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> A table movement speed and a wafer revolution number were respectively set up to be about 500 ft/min and about 20 rpm, by using a linear type system. Here, the CMP process was performed on the RTN thin film under a polishing pressure of about 1.5 psi by using the slurry prepared in Example 1 (polishing speed: about 500 &angst;/min). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">COMPARATIVE EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> A table revolution number and a wafer revolution number were respectively set up to be about 20 rpm and about 80 rpm, by using a rotary type system. Here, the CMP process was performed on the RTN thin film under a polishing pressure of about 4 psi by using a slurry for tungsten (SSW2000 slurry of CABOT) (polishing speed: about 350 &angst;/min). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">COMPARATIVE EXAMPLE 2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> A table revolution number and a wafer revolution number were respectively set up to be about 20 rpm and about 80 rpm, by using a rotary type system. Here, the CMP process was performed on the RTN thin film under a polishing pressure of 4 psi by using a slurry for aluminum (EPA5680 slurry of CABOT) (polishing speed: about 500 &angst;/min). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate are added to distilled water to prepare the slurry composition. However, other additives may be further added. Moreover, HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and ceric ammonium nitrate may be added to the general slurry composition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> As discussed earlier, the CMP process is performed by using the slurry containing ceric ammonium nitrate, thereby improving the polishing speed of RTN under a low polishing pressure. In addition, the CMP process is performed according to an one-step process by using one kind of slurry. As a result, defects on the insulating film are reduced and the polishing property is improved, thereby simplifying the CMP process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, a process margin and a process yield are improved due to the simplified CMP process. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A slurry used in a chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) process for ruthenium titanium nitride (RTN) thin film, the slurry comprising: ceric ammonium nitrate &lsqb;(NH<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Ce(NO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>&rsqb;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an abrasive and an acid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein ceric ammonium nitrate is present in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 10% by weight of the slurry composition. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the acid is selected from the group consisting of HNO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>, HCl, H<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>PO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>, and mixtures thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein HNO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>is present in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 10% by weight of the slurry. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the abrasive is selected from the group consisting of CeO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, ZrO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and mixtures thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, wherein the size of the abrasive is below 1 &mgr;m. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The slurry composition according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, wherein the abrasive is present in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 5% by weight of the slurry. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The slurry composition according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein pH of the slurry ranges from about 1 to about 7. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The slurry composition according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein pH of the slurry ranges from about 1 to about 3. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a buffer solution. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the buffer solution comprises a mixture of organic acid and organic acid salt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The slurry according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the buffer solution comprises a mixture of acetic acid and acetic acid salt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method for forming a RTN pattern comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) preparing a semiconductor substrate where a RTN thin film is formed; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) patterning the RTN thin film according to a CMP process using a slurry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein RTN thin film is a barrier film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein step (b) is performed under a polishing pressure ranging from about 1 to about 4 psi. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein step (b) is performed by using a rotary type CMP system, and a table revolution number thereof ranges from about 10 to about 80 rpm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein step (b) is performed in a linear type CMP system where a table movement speed ranges from about 100 to about 600 ft/min. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method for manufacturing a semiconductor device comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) forming an interlayer insulating film on a semiconductor substrate having a predetermined lower structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) patterning the interlayer insulating film to form an interlayer insulating film pattern having a contact hole; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) filling the contact hole with conducting material and performing over-etch to form a recess contact plug; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) depositing a RTN thin film on the surface of the resultant structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) forming a RTN thin film pattern on the recess contact plug by performing a CMP process using a CMP slurry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conducting material of step (c) is polysilicon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of forming silicon nitride on the interlayer insulating film at the step (a). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of forming a buffer film between the contact plug and RTN film pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the buffer film is titanium silicide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>(f) forming a sacrificial insulating film pattern which opens the contact plug; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) forming a lower electrode film on the resultant structure and performing a CMP process using the sacrificial insulating film pattern as an etch barrier to obtain a lower electrode pattern; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) sequentially forming a dielectric film and an upper electrode on the resultant. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lower electrode is a ruthenium film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the dielectric film is a (Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;x</subscript></highlight>)TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ruthenium film is patterned by performing CMP process using the slurry of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device manufactured according to a method of claim <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003747A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003747A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
