<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001041A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001041A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001041A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001041A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001041A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001041A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001041A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001041A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001041</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10102618</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020319</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-39320</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B60R022/46</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>242</class>
<subclass>382600</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>242</class>
<subclass>374000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Pretensioner structure for a safety belt of an automobile</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jong-Young</given-name>
<family-name>Yoon</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyoungki-Do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Pennie &amp; Edmonds, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>3300 Hillview Avenue</address-1>
<city>Palo Alto</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94304</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Disclosed is a seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle wherein a spool is mounted in such a way that it cannot be further released at the onset of a car accident but can push itself downwardly in a fixed state along the length-wise direction of a retractor and thus can effectively rewind a seat belt with ease. To serve this purpose the seat belt pretensioner of the present invention comprises a retractor cover wherein sliding guides are mounted both on right and left sides, a spool mounted in such a manner that a seat belt is wound up with an elastic support and is able to slide along the sliding guide, and a piston structure, being mounted on the upper part of said cover, pushes said spool downwardly by the explosion force of explosives. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle, and more particularly, to a seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle wherein a spool onto which a seat belt is wound is pulled downwardly at the onset of a car accident by means of an explosive force. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A vehicle seat belt is a crucial part of a vehicle provided with a view to securing the safety of the driver and passengers at the onset of car crash and it has now become mandatory for vehicles to have seat belts. Seat belts, once fastened, preferably do not create unnecessary discomfort for a driver nor restrict too tightly the body of a driver and passengers to minimize bodily damage incurred from car accidents. For this purpose, there has been introduced a pretensioner on the retractor which is wound up by the elastic support of a seat belt. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>shows the structure of a conventional pretensioner wherein a clutch <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is mounted on a cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> so that a seat belt is located at one end of a spool and this clutch rewinds said seat belt while reversely rotating it due to a piston structure <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> which slides by the explosive force of explosive powder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows the structure of another type of a conventional pretensioner. The structure of the pretensioner in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is such that one end of a spool, wherein a seat belt is wound up by the elastic support, is protruded outwardly and home gear <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is mounted on one end of said protruded end, and ball supply line <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> is established to wrap around said home gear <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> thereby enabling said balls <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, which fill along said ball supply line <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, to reversely rotate said home gear <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>shows the structure of still another type of a conventional pretensioner. The structure of the pretensioner in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is such that a seat belt extends one end of wound up spool <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and at said extended end is installed clamp wire <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> so that the friction force generated while said clamp wire <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> is being pulled up by the explosive force of explosive powder at the time of car accident can rotate said spool <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>also shows the structure of another type of a conventional pretensioner disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,248,110. The structure of the pretensioner in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is such that a gear <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is mounted on the spool <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and said gear <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is rotated by the explosive force of explosive powder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> However, the spools to wind up or release a seat belt in these conventional pretensioners are disadvantageous in that they are forced to rotate and therefore the spool structures become rather complex and their manufacturing cost also becomes very high. Further, they are not advantageous in that there is required an enormous power to rotate a spool where a belt is wound up. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle wherein a spool is mounted in such a way that it cannot be further released at the onset of a car accident, but can push itself downwardly in a fixed state along the length-wise direction of a retractor and thus can effectively rewind a seat belt with ease. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A seat belt pretensioner according to an embodiment of the present invention comprises a retractor cover wherein sliding guides are formed on both right and left sides; a spool mounted in such a manner that a seat belt is wound up with an elastic support and is able to slide along the sliding guide; and a piston structure, mounted on the upper part of said cover, pushes said spool downwardly by the explosion force of explosives. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The sliding guides of the present invention are preferably mounted in parallel with the direction the seat belt is wound up or released. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The spool of the present invention is preferably equipped with a latch to prevent the release of a seat belt at the onset of a car accident. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The piston structure of the present invention preferably comprises an explosive powder chamber, which is mounted on the upper part of said cover and provides explosion gas to both left and right, and a pair of cylinders connected to said explosive powder chamber wherein each cylinder is positioned on the sides of said cover to be in parallel with said sliding guides, wherein the internal end of said each cylinder is connected to said spool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> According to another preferred embodiment of the invention, a seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle comprises a support member having a top and bottom, a seat belt spool having ends slideably supported by the support member, and a piston system acting on said spool to force the spool toward the bottom of the support member in response to a vehicle accident. Preferably, the support member comprises a retractor cover of a seat belt retractor mechanism. In a further preferred embodiment, a seat belt extends the spool in a predetermined orientation toward the spool ends, with the guide members being oriented at least substantially in parallel with the seat belt orientation. The piston system preferably comprises an explosive chamber, first and second cylinders communicating with the explosive chamber on opposite sides of the support member, and first and second pistons. Each piston is disposed in one cylinder and each is linked to an end of the spool. When an explosion is triggered in the explosive chamber, the explosive force communicates with the cylinders to act on the pistons to force the spool down, away from the extension of the seat belt.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are the cross-sectional views of a seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is a perspective view of a conventional seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are the cross-sectional views of conventional seat belt pretensioners for a vehicle.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The present invention is explained in more detail with reference to the drawings as set forth hereunder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> seat belt pretensioner according to the invention is so designed that it can wind up a seat belt at the onset of car accident; in particular, spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, in a state where no more rotation is possible, can be lowered at the onset of a car accident to generate the effect of rewinding the seat belt <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The pretensioner of the present invention includes a conventional retractor cover <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and on both sides of said retractor cover <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are mounted vertical sliding guides <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Sliding guides <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are where both sides of spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are moveably supported. Guides <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may be oriented in a straight line with a right angle or at varying degrees of angles with respect to the surface of said retractor cover <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment of the present invention, said sliding guides <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> preferably line up in parallel with the direction from which the seat belt <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is released. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which is mounted on the conventional retractor and also serves as a place to wind up said seat belt <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, is supported elastically. Spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> extends out on both ends and is mounted on the cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> so that said extended ends protrude outside of the sliding guides <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Specifically, spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is provided with a latch <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> as in the case with the conventional pretensioners in order to prevent further release of said seat belt <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Here, said latch <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> does not have to be the one with a special feature but any type of conventional latches can be used as long as they can serve the role of fixing said spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for seat belts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Piston structure <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> provides operational force so that spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be slid into a lower position in a fixed state. Piston structure <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> comprises an explosive powder chamber <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, which is mounted on the upper part of cover <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and cylinder parts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, each of which is mounted on both sides of cover <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, respectively. In particular, explosive powder chamber <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> contains explosive powder <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> so that it can explode upon sensing a car accident and cylinder parts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are designed to expand from the explosive gas as the explosive powder <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> explodes to both left and right directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Cylinder parts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are installed on sides of cover <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and are preferably lined up in parallel with sliding guides <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. In addition, cylinder parts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are preferably installed with an upper portion connected to both ends of explosive powder chamber <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> so that they are simultaneously provided with explosive gas. Each cylinder <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, established inside of cylinder parts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, is connected to the extended ends of spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> so that it can rotate in its designated location. Therefore, spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be prevented from rotating by latch <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> upon the occurrence of a car accident and at the same time cylinders <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> move downwardly from the explosion of explosive powder <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, which then results in lowering spool <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to a fixed state position, thus pulling said belt <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The present invention thus provides a number of advantages. For example, although being simple in its structural features, the pretensioner directly delivers explosive force to the spool for a seat belt and pulls up the seat belt. Also, because the explosive gas directly acts on the spool, the effect of lowering the spool (i.e., equivalent to the effect of rotating the spool in the conventional pretensioner) can be more effective. In addition, because its structure is so simple the total number of parts can be reduced thus reducing unit production cost as well as enhancing product quality. These and other advantages will be apparent to persons skilled in the art based on the preferred embodiment of the present invention described herein, the scope of the invention being defined by the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle, comprising: 
<claim-text>a retractor cover wherein sliding guides are formed on both right and left sides; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a spool mounted to slide along the sliding guides in such a manner that a belt is wound up with an elastic support; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston structure, being mounted on an upper part of said cover, pushing said spool downwardly by the explosion force of explosives. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sliding guides are mounted in such a way that they lie in parallel with a direction in which said seat belt is wound up or released. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said spool is equipped with a latch which prevents the release of a belt in a car accident. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said piston structure consists of: 
<claim-text>an explosive powder chamber which is mounted on the upper part of said cover and provides explosion gas to both left and right sides; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of cylinders connected to said explosive powder chamber wherein each cylinder is positioned on a side of said cover in parallel with said sliding guide, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the internal end of said each cylinder is connected to said spool. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A seat belt pretensioner for a vehicle, comprising: 
<claim-text>a support member having a top and bottom; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a seat belt spool having ends slideably supported by the support member; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston system acting on said spool to force said spool toward the bottom of the support member in response to a vehicle accident. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The pretensioner of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said support member comprises a retractor cover of a seat belt retractor mechanism. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The pretensioner of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a seat belt extends from said spool in a predetermined orientation toward the top of the support member and said support member includes guide members slideably receiving said spool ends, the guide members being oriented at least substantially in parallel with said seat belt orientation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The pretensioner of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pistons system comprises: 
<claim-text>an explosive chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second cylinders communicating with said chamber on opposite sides of the support member; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second pistons, one disposed in each said cylinder and each being linked to and end of said spool, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an explosion triggered in said chamber communicates with the cylinders to act on the pistons to force said spool down, away from the extension of the seat belt.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2B</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001041A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001041A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001041A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001041A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
