<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002181A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002181A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002181</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10170810</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020613</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B007/182</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>877000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Actuator assembly for tilting a mirror or like object</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60298488</doc-number>
<document-date>20010614</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shahab</given-name>
<family-name>Hatam-Tabrizi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Wei-Hung</given-name>
<family-name>Yeh</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BURGESS &amp; BEREZNAK LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>800 WEST EL CAMINO REAL</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 180</address-2>
<city>MOUNTAIN VIEW</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94040</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An actuator for tilting a moveable object such as a mirror includes a base and a coil-object assembly that includes first and second pairs of coils each of which is attached to the object, the first pair of coils being arranged along a longitudinal axis, and the second pair of coils being arranged along a transverse axis substantially orthogonal to the longitudinal axis. A gimbal has an attachment section attached to the object, and mounting sections connected via a plurality of beams to the attachment section, the mounting sections being attached to the base. A permanent magnet is positioned adjacent a corresponding one of each of the coils such that when current flows through the coils a rotational force is generated that causes the coil-object assembly to rotate about an axis. It is emphasized that this abstract is provided to comply with the rules requiring an abstract that will allow a searcher or other reader to quickly ascertain the subject matter of the technical disclosure. It is submitted with the understanding that it will not be used to interpret or limit the scope or meaning of the claims. 37 CFR 1.72(b). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is related to co-pending applications: Ser. No. ______, filed ______, entitled, &ldquo;GIMBAL FOR SUPPORTING A MOVEABLE MIRROR&rdquo;; and Ser. No. ______, filed ______, entitled, &ldquo;PHOTONIC SWITCH FOR AN OPTICAL COMMUNICATION NETWORK&rdquo;; both of which are assigned to the assignee of the present application.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to apparatus and methods for movement of objects; specifically, objects such as mirrors that direct light beams in optical systems and networks. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Fiberoptic technologies and systems have been widely deployed in recent decades. However, certain key components remain expensive and inefficient, which hinders the expansion of optical systems and optical communication networks. One of these components is the wavelength switch, which routes and redirects a light beam from one fiber to another fiber so that the signal can be provisioned and managed according to the demand. A typical wavelength switch used today converts the input light signal into an electronic signal to detect the routing information, switches the electronic signal, and then eventually reconverts it back into a light signal for further transmission. This device, commonly referred to as an Optical-Electrical-Optical (OEO) switch, not only depends on current semiconductor technologies and processes, but also requires a transmitter and a receiver for each transmission port. These factors cause OEO switches to be large in size (e.g., occupying two or more 7-foot tall racks), to have high power consumption (e.g., kilowatts), to be network protocol and transmission rate dependent, to lack scalability, and to be costly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Thus, there is a need for an alternative apparatus for directing a light beam in an optical system that can be manufactured efficiently and provide improved performance in optical systems and fiber optic-based networks. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be understood more fully from the detailed description that follows and from the accompanying drawings, which however, should not be taken to limit the invention to the specific embodiments shown, but are for explanation and understanding only. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A &amp; 1B</cross-reference> are top views of a gimbal used in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a platform that mounts to the gimbal of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A &amp; 4B</cross-reference> in an actuator-mirror assembly according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a bottom perspective view of an integrated mirror/pedestal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> utilized in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates an actuator-mirror assembly at an intermediate point of construction according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates an actuator-mirror assembly at a further point of construction according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an actuator-mirror assembly according to another embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A &amp; 7B</cross-reference> are top and side views of a magnet-housing arrangement for an actuator-mirror assembly in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a top view of a magnet-housing arrangement for an actuator-mirror assembly in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view of an actuator-mirror assembly according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10A &amp; 10B</cross-reference> are cross-sectional side views of an actuator-mirror assembly tilted in two different directions in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A &amp; 11B</cross-reference> show top and side views of a bobbin coil assembly utilized in accordance with an alternative embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates the relative position of a coil and magnet assembly in accordance with an alternative embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a top view of a gimbal utilized in accordance with an alternative embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view of an actuator-mirror assembly in accordance with an alternative embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> An actuator and a mirror assembly to guide a light beam for a variety of applications is described. In the following description numerous specific details are set forth, such as angles, material types, configurations, etc., in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. However, persons having ordinary skill in the opto-mechnical arts will appreciate that these specific details may not be needed to practice the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> According to one embodiment of the present invention, a tilting actuatormirror assembly is provided to control the path of a light beam. The present invention has numerous consumer, medical, and/or industrial applications. For example, laser marking, laser display, optical scanning devices, windshield auto projection, helmet display, personal digital assistant (&ldquo;PDA&rdquo;), fiber optic communication network (e.g., an all-optical switch), and mobile phone projection display, to name a few, can all benefit from the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In a particular embodiment, a dual-axis tilting actuator is provided as a rotary moving coil actuator suspended by a flexing, electrically conductive gimbal component. The gimbal is comprised of a pair of beams that move about the axis of rotation under the influence of an electromagnetic actuator. The conductive connections in the rotary moving coil actuator are integrated with the flexing part of the gimbal. In various embodiments, the actuator may rotate about either a single axis or a dual axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A &amp; 1B</cross-reference>, there is shown a top plan view of a gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> utilized in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. Gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is made from a single, integral sheet of thin metal. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> shows gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> after removal of the &ldquo;cutout&rdquo; areas from the sheet metal. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> shows the gimbal after removal of the end section and perimeter material, which step is performed during the construction of the actuator-mirror assembly according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The sheet metal used for gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is preferably a fully hardened material, such as stainless steel, having high fatigue strength. Other materials providing similar properties may also be used. The material selected should allow the gimbal to rotate the attached mirror (or mirror-coil assembly) with a high rotational angle (e.g., &plus;/&minus;15 degrees) over millions of movement cycles. The material may also be heat-treated. The sheet metal material is also preferably non-magnetic to prevent reluctance forces induced by the magnets in the actuator. In some cases, the sheet metal may also be coated with a corrosion-resistant material, such as titanium-nickel or gold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> comprises four attachment pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> that are centrally located symmetrical about the x-axis (i.e., longitudinal axis) and y-axis (i.e., transverse axis). A mirror, or mirror-pedestal assembly, is adhesively attached to pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. Thus, in the completed assembly, pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> are all affixed in a rigid plane, remaining stationary or moving in unison, depending on the particular embodiment of the final actuator-mirror assembly. Thin, elongated beams <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> support each of pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, respectively. In operation, pairs of adjacent beams <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>193</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> each twist longitudinally about the x-axis to permit the mirror (attached to pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>) to rotate about the x-axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, beams <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> are shown being integrally connected to end section <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> through respective intermediate sections <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. Similarly, beams <highlight><bold>193</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> are integrally connected to end section <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> through intermediate sections <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, respectively. Intermediate sections <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> are also integrally connected with thin, elongated beams <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight>, respectively, which permit rotation of the mirror about the y-axis. During rotation of the mirror about the x-axis, pairs of adjacent beams <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>197</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> remain substantially rigid. Similarly, during rotation of the mirror about the y-axis, pairs of adjacent beams <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>197</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> twist longitudinally about the y-axis, while pairs of adjacent beams <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>193</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> remain substantially rigid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Beams <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> being connected to end section <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> via respective L-shaped mounting sections <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>. Likewise, beams <highlight><bold>197</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> are both integrally connected to end section <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> through respective L-shaped mounting sections <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>. All of the end sections <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> are attached together through a set of perimeter connecting sections <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight>. For example, end section <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> attaches to end sections <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> via connecting sections <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight>, respectively. End section <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> attaches to end sections <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> via connecting sections <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>, respectively. In this embodiment, end sections <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> (beyond dashed lines <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>) are removed along with the perimeter connecting sections during the assembly process. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> shows gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> after these metal sections have been removed. This assembly process of this embodiment is described in more detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Each of the mounting sections <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is fixedly mounted (e.g., with adhesive) to a stationary point or platform mount of the actuator-mirror assembly. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows one possible implementation of a platform <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> that may be used for this purpose. Platform <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> comprises a base <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight> that supports four rigid posts <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> of equal height. Each of the posts <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> has a flat end surface <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>285</bold></highlight>, respectively. The dimensions of end surfaces <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>285</bold></highlight> and the position of posts <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> is such that end surfaces <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>285</bold></highlight> align with the rectangular surface areas of mounting sections <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference>) in a corresponding manner. This permits the mounting sections <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> to be adhesively attached to corresponding end surfaces <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>285</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> also shows a set of four thin wires <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>295</bold></highlight>, each of which is adhesively bonded to respective posts of platform <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>285</bold></highlight>. These wires connect with the coils that comprise the actuator of the final assembly. Two of the wires are used to energize the coils disposed about the x-axis, and the other two are used to energize the coils disposed about the y-axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> After gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> has been mounted to platform <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> each of the wires <highlight><bold>292295</bold></highlight> are soldered to corresponding tabs of the mounting sections <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>. For example, if surface <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> is attached to mounting section <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, wire <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> may be soldered to tab <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. Continuing with this example, with surfaces <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>285</bold></highlight> respectively attached to mounting sections <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>, wires <highlight><bold>293</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>295</bold></highlight> may be soldered to tabs <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>, respectively. Note that in gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> each of tabs <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> provides separate electrical connection with respective pads <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>. This feature is utilized to establish electrical connection to the coils of the actuator-mirror assembly, as discussed in more detail shortly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Metal may be removed from a single piece of thin sheet metal to achieve the gimbal cutout patterns shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A &amp; 1B</cross-reference> using a variety of conventional methods, such as chemical etching, press cutting, milling, etc. Although a specific rectilinear cutout pattern is shown in these figures, it is understood that other embodiments may have different patterns or a different arrangement of beams, pads, etc., yet still provide rotational movement along the x and y axes in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment illustrated by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A &amp; 1B</cross-reference>, beams <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> are each about 0.05 mm wide, mirror-attachment pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> are each about 0.4 mm&times;0.6 mm in dimension, and the thickness of the single piece of sheet metal is about 0.0254 mm. Wires <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>295</bold></highlight> are also about 0.0254 mm thick. In certain embodiments, beams <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> may be partially etched to make them thinner than the rest of the sheet metal material. For example, beams <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> may be chemically etched to a thickness less than 0.0254 mm to increase flexibility and thus achieve a higher degree of rotation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a bottom perspective view of an integrated mirror/pedestal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> utilized in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. In the drawing, the polished, reflective surface of mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> faces down and into the page. Integrated mirror/pedestal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may be manufactured from a single piece of material such as silicon, Pyrex&reg;, quartz, sapphire, aluminum, or other types of suitable materials. Integrated mirror/pedestal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> includes a pedestal portion <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> having a flat surface <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. The length and width of surface <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> is such that it matches or fit within the combined area of pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference>). During the assembly process, surface <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> is adhesively bonded to one side of pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Integrated mirror/pedestal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> also includes a base plate <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> between pedestal portion <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the back of mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. Base plate is sized smaller than mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> such that a step <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, comprising a peripheral area of the back of mirror <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, is realized. It is appreciated that other embodiments may be constructed from discrete parts (e.g., separate mirror, base plate, and pedestal) rather than being manufactured in integral form. In either approach, the mirror may be about 0.25 mm thick and 2&times;2 mm in area. The mirror surface may be lapped to a highly polished optical-flat surface. A reflective surface can also be applied by numerous methods, including plating or sputtering gold, silver, or aluminum on a layer of nickel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a bottom perspective view of an actuator-mirror assembly after pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> have been bonded to surface <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> of integrated mirror/pedestal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> also shows four coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> adhesively bonded to step <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> around the side back surface of mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. Thus, coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>, mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, and pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> are all rigidly coupled together, and move as a single unit, in the actuator-mirror assembly according to one embodiment of the present invention. Note that although <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the end sections of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> before removal at this stage of the assembly process, this is not required. That is, the end and peripheral connecting sections of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be removed either before or after attachment to the mirror/pedestal assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is another view of the assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> after soldering of pairs of coil wires to the back of pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. (Note that not all of the cutout portions of the gimbal are shown in this view for clarity reasons.) For example, wires <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight> of coil <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, and wires <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> of coil <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, are shown soldered to pads <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, respectively. Similarly, wires <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>229</bold></highlight> of coil <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>, and wires <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> of coil <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>, are soldered to pads <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Upon removal of the end sections of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, each of the pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is electrically connected to a separate one of the mounting sections <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>. In other words, removal of the end sections of the gimbal creates four distinct conductive paths in the remaining sheet metal material from each of the four mounting sections to a corresponding one of the pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. According to one embodiment of the present invention, current flows through these four paths to control movement of the attached mirror via coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. This embodiment therefore utilizes the metal of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to conduct electrical current delivered to the moving coil. That is, the electrical connections to the coil wires are integrated with the flexing part of the gimbal. This arrangement thereby eliminates movement of wires during operation of the mirror-gimbal assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Following attachment of the gimbal to platform <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) wires <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>295</bold></highlight> may be soldered to tabs <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> to establish an electrical connection to coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. Thus, the conductive paths provided through the flexing beams of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be used to energize the coils in order to control tilting of the mirror along the x-axis and the y-axis. By way of example, one pair of wires <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>295</bold></highlight> may be used to energize one pair of opposing coils (i.e., coils <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>) to control rotation of the mirror about the x-axis, with the remaining pair of wires <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>295</bold></highlight> being used to energize the other pair of opposing coils (i.e., coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>) to control rotation of the mirror about the y-axis. In the final assembly, permanent magnets are attached within the central opening of each of the coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Torque is developed on the mirror-coil assembly upon application of an appropriate current through the coils, in the presence of the permanent magnetic field. The direction of the force is made to be opposite on each side of the mirror-coil assembly such that the resulting torque rotates or tilts the mirror attached to the top of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Since the mirror-coil assembly is fixedly attached to gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, gimbal pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> rotate together as the mirror-coil assembly rotates. When the applied current is interrupted or halted, the restoring spring force of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> returns the assembly to a rest position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of another embodiment of an actuator-mirror assembly according to the present invention. The actuator-mirror assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> rotates about a single axis. In this embodiment, two coils <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> are adhesively attached to step <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> on opposite sides of mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and base plate <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>. The gimbal for this embodiment comprises two rectilinear, or I-bar, shaped members <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of thin sheet metal. Ends <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of respective I-bar members <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are bonded to surface <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> of pedestal <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. Wires <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of coil <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are soldered to ends <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. Likewise, wires <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of coil <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> are also soldered to ends <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. A stationary platform similar to that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, but having two posts, supports the assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, with the end surfaces of the posts being bonded to ends <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of I-bar members <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>A wire attached to each of the mounting posts may be soldered to ends <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to provide electrical connection through the gimbal members <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>&amp; <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to energize coils <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A &amp; 7B</cross-reference> show top and side views of a magnet-housing arrangement for a single actuator-mirror assembly in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. This magnet-housing arrangement, for example, may be utilized in the actuator-mirror assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Magnets <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are bonded on the side surfaces of steel returns <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, attached to a base <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. Magnets <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are positioned adjacent the moving coils (e.g., coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>). The polarities of the magnets are shown by conventional nomenclature for north (N) and south (S). In one embodiment, the magnet material is Neodymium-Iron-Boron. Of course, other types of magnetic materials may be used as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows a top view of a larger magnet-housing arrangement for use with multiple actuator-mirror assemblies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view of an actuator-mirror assembly utilizing gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> according to one embodiment of the present invention. A pair of magnets <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is shown attached to a steel return on opposite sides of the mirror-coil-gimbal assembly. One pair of magnets <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> are positioned adjacent coil <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, and the other pair of magnets <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> are positioned adjacent coil <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. Each of the coils is bonded to a notched edge surface of mirror plate <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. A pedestal <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is shown attached to the back of mirror plate <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and also to pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The end surfaces of posts <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> are shown respectively bonded to mounting sections <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>, with wires <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> soldered to sections <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> in accordance with the wiring scheme described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Also included in the cross-section of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an optional balancing plate <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> attached to the bottom of the coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. Balancing plate <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> acts to counterbalance the weight of the mirror so that the center of rotation is at the center of gravity. This feature improves external shock and dynamic settling of the actuator. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, balancing plate <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> comprises a solid, flat metal plate with several openings that allow the stationary posts to attach to the gimbal and also permit the gimbal-mirror-coil assembly to move. Instead of having several openings to accommodate mounting of the mirror-coil-gimbal onto stationary posts, balancing plate <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> may also be implemented with a single, centrally located opening. For instance, balancing plate <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> may comprise a rectangular frame having its sides adhesively attached to the coils, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10A &amp; 10B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> further illustrates the use of an optional damper coating <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>, which covers beams <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> and gimbal pads <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. Damper coating <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> comprises a low viscosity polymer (e.g., an ultraviolet curing resin) that becomes a flexible gel upon curing. Damper coating <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> acts to damp gimbal resonances and improve the settling time of the actuator; yet, because coating <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> is flexible, it does not appreciably affect the stiffness of the gimbal. Damper coating <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> also improves reliability by minimizing the effect of external shock and vibration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10A &amp; 10B</cross-reference> are cross-sectional side views of an actuator-mirror assembly with appropriate current applied to coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> to tilt mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> in two different directions along a single longitudinal axis of movement. Note that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10A &amp; 10B</cross-reference> only the rigid sections of gimbal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> are shown for clarity reasons. Precise movement of mirror <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> along both the x-axis and y-axis is achieved by controlling the current applied to the four coils <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> for the embodiments described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A &amp; 11B</cross-reference> show top and side views of a bobbin-coil assembly utilized in accordance with an alternative embodiment of the present invention. In this embodiment, the coils <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> are made from fine copper wire with single-built insulation, and are each wrapped around a post member on a side of bobbin <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. Coils <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> are physically located between one or more permanent magnets (not shown in this view) in the final assembly. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> shows the relative position of a coil and magnet assembly in accordance with this alternative embodiment. The coil windings are supported by and encircle the protruding side members of bobbin <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, shaped in accordance with the dimensions of the permanent magnets. Bobbin pedestal <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> provides a surface for bonding (e.g., adhesive attachment) to a gimbal that suspends bobbin <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> between the permanent magnets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> By way of example, in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A &amp; 11B</cross-reference>, each coil may include approximately 48 turns made from 6 layers, with each layer having 8 turns. The number of turns and layers may vary based on the type of coil used, the application, etc. Bobbin <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> may be made from a variety of machined materials (e.g., polymers) as is known in the art. In operation, application of current through the coils generates a magnetic field that interacts with the field of the permanently mounted magnets to torque to tilt the actuator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The bobbin coil assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A &amp; 11B</cross-reference> may be bonded to a variety of conventional gimbals. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> shows a top view of a conventional gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> of a type well known in the industry, which may be used to suspend the bobbin-coil assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A &amp; 11B</cross-reference>. Gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is formed of a single sheet of material (e.g., sheet metal) that provides for dual-axis rotation of the bobbin-coil assembly. Bobbin pedestal <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may, for instance, be bonded to central area <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> of gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> shows a cross-sectional side view of an actuator-mirror assembly in accordance with an alternative embodiment of the present invention. In this view, permanent magnets <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>397</bold></highlight> are positioned on steel returns <highlight><bold>395</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>394</bold></highlight> adjacent coils <highlight><bold>381</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight>, respectively. Coils <highlight><bold>381</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> are located on opposite sides of a bobbin <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, which is bonded to the center of a gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, such as that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. In this example, gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is secured to stationary steel returns <highlight><bold>394</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>395</bold></highlight>. A mirror <highlight><bold>391</bold></highlight> is secured on the center-top area of gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Torque is developed on the bobbin-coil assembly upon application of an appropriate current through coils <highlight><bold>381</bold></highlight> &amp; <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight>, in the presence of the permanent magnetic field. The direction of the force is made to be opposite on each side of bobbin <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> such that the resulting torque rotates or tilts mirror <highlight><bold>391</bold></highlight> attached to the top of gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. The bobbin-coil assembly is attached to a gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> and therefore the gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> and the mirror <highlight><bold>391</bold></highlight> will rotate as the bobbin-coil assembly rotates. When the applied current is interrupted or halted, the restoring spring force of gimbal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> returns the assembly to the rest position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An actuator for tilting an object about an axis, comprising: 
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gimbal having first and second attachment areas connected by two or more beams, the second attachment area being bonded to the base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an assembly that includes the object and a pair of coils, each coil being attached to an opposing side of the object, with the object being mounted to the first attachment area of the gimbal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of magnets, each magnet being positioned adjacent a corresponding one of the coils such that when current flows through the coils a rotational force is generated that causes the coil assembly to move about the axis, the beams of the gimbal flexing in response to movement of the assembly. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises a translationally stiff, yet rotationally flexible material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises sheet metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises a pair of beam members, with the first attachment area being located at one end, and the second attachment area being located at another end, of each beam member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each beam member has a rectilinear shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the coil assembly further comprises a pedestal member having a first end attached to the object and a second end attached to the first attachment area of the gimbal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the base includes a pair of mounting posts, each mounting post being attached to the second attachment area of a corresponding one of the beam members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each of the beam members includes a conductive path for the current. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the object comprises a mirror. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a damper coating applied to at least the beams of the gimbal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An actuator for tilting an object, comprising: 
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a coil-object assembly that includes first and second pairs of coils each of which is rigidly attached to the object, the first pair of coils being arranged along a longitudinal axis, and the second pair of coils being arranged along a transverse axis substantially orthogonal to the longitudinal axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gimbal having an attachment section, a mounting section, and a plurality of beams, the coil-object assembly being attached to the attachment section, with the attachment section being connected via a plurality of beams to the mounting section, the mounting section being attached to the base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of magnets, each magnet being positioned adjacent a corresponding one of the coils such that when a first current flows through the first pair of coils a first rotational force is generated that causes the coil-object assembly to rotate about the transverse axis, and when a second current flows through the second pair of coils a second rotational force is generated that causes the coil-object assembly to rotate about the longitudinal axis. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises a translationally stiff, yet rotationally flexible material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises sheet metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the object comprises a mirror mounted to one end of a pedestal, the pedestal having another end that is attached to the attachment section of the gimbal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mirror is rectilinear in shape, each of the first pair of coils being attached to first and second opposing sides of the mirror, and each of the second pair of coils being attached to third and fourth opposing sides of the mirror. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises: 
<claim-text>first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material, each of which includes: 
<claim-text>a first beam with first and second ends, the first beam extending along the longitudinal axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an attachment pad for bonding to the moveable mirror, the attachment pad being connected to the first end of the first beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam with first and second ends, the second beam extending along the transverse axis, the first end of the second beam being coupled with the second end of the first beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting member for bonding to a stationary mount, the mounting member being connected to the second end of the second beam; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material being arranged such that when the coil-object assembly rotates about the longitudinal axis the first beams twists, and when the coil-object assembly rotates about the transverse axis, the second beam twists. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the substantially planar material comprises an electrically conductive material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the attachment pads are centrally located on the gimbal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material each further comprises an intermediate section connected between the first end of the second beam and the second end of the first beam. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the base includes first, second, third, and fourth mounting posts, each mounting post being attached to a corresponding one of the mounting members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a plate member, each of the coils having a first side attached to the object, and a second side attached to the plate member, the second side being opposite to the first side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a plate member, each of the coils having a first side attached to the object, and a second side attached to the plate member, the second side being opposite to the first side, the plate member having an opening, the first, second, third, and fourth mounting posts extending through the opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a damper coating applied to at least the beams of the gimbal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An actuator for tilting an object, comprising: 
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a coil-object assembly that includes first and second pairs of coils each of which is rigidly attached to the object, the first pair of coils being arranged along a longitudinal axis, and the second pair of coils being arranged along a transverse axis substantially orthogonal to the longitudinal axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gimbal that includes: 
<claim-text>an attachment section bonded to the coil-object assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second pairs of beams extending along the longitudinal axis, the first and second pairs of beams being respectively connected to opposite ends of the attachment section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>third and fourth pairs of beams extending along the transverse axis, the third and fourth pairs of beams being respectively disposed on opposite sides of the attachment section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first one of the third pair of beams being connected with a first one of the first pair of beams, a second one of the third pair of beams being connected with a first one of the second pair of beams, a first one of the fourth pair of beams being connected with a second one of the first pair of beams, and a second one of the fourth pair of beams being connected with a second one of the second pair of beams; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second mounting sections bonded to the base, the first and second mounting sections being connected to the third and fourth pairs of beams, respectively; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of magnets, each magnet being positioned adjacent a corresponding one of the coils such that when a first current flows through the first pair of coils a first rotational force is generated that causes the coil-object assembly to rotate about the transverse axis, and when a second current flows through the second pair of coils a second rotational force is generated that causes the coil-object assembly to rotate about the longitudinal axis. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first mounting section comprises first and second mounting members respectively connected with the first and second ones of the third pair of beams, and the second mounting section comprises third and fourth mounting members respectively connected with the first and second ones of the fourth pair of beams. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises sheet metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the attachment section is divided into first, second, third, and fourth attachment pads. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first attachment pad is connected to the first one of the first pair of beams, the second attachment pad is connected to the first one of the second pair of beams, the third attachment pad is connected to the second one of the first pair of beams, and the fourth attachment pad is connected to the second one of the second pair of beams. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a first electrically conductive path is provided between the first attachment pad and the first mounting member, a second electrically conductive path is provided between the second attachment pad and the second mounting member, a third electrically conductive path is provided between the third attachment pad and the third mounting member, and a fourth electrically conductive path is provided between the fourth attachment pad and the fourth mounting member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first current flows through at least the first electrically conductive path. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second current flows through at least the third electrically conductive path. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first, second, third, and fourth electrically conductive paths respectively comprise first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material, the first piece of substantially planar material integrally including the first attachment pad and the first mounting member, the second piece of substantially planar material integrally including the second attachment pad and the second mounting member, the third piece of substantially planar material integrally including the third attachment pad and the third mounting member, and the fourth piece of substantially planar material integrally including the fourth attachment pad and the fourth mounting member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein when the coil-object assembly rotates about the longitudinal axis the first and second pair of beams twist about the longitudinal axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein when the coil-object assembly rotates about the transverse axis the third and fourth pair of beams twist about the transverse axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the object comprises a mirror. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a damper coating applied to the first and second pairs of beams and the attachment section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. An actuator for tilting an object, comprising: 
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a coil-object assembly that includes first and second pairs of coils each of which is rigidly attached to the object, the first pair of coils being arranged along a longitudinal axis, and the second pair of coils being arranged along a transverse axis substantially orthogonal to the longitudinal axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gimbal comprising first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material, each of the pieces including: 
<claim-text>a first beam that extends along a longitudinal axis having first and second ends; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an attachment pad bonded to the object, the attachment pad being connected to the first end of the first beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam that extends along a transverse axis, the second beam having first and second ends, the first end of the second beam being coupled with the second end of the first beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting member bonded to the base, the mounting member being connected to the second end of the second beam; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of magnets, each magnet being positioned adjacent a corresponding one of the coils such that when a first current flows through the first pair of coils a first rotational force is generated that causes the coil-object assembly to rotate about the transverse axis, and when a second current flows through the second pair of coils a second rotational force is generated that causes the coil-object assembly to rotate about the longitudinal axis, the first current flowing through the first pair of coils via at least the first piece of conductive material and the second current flowing through the third piece of conductive material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the object comprises a mirror. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the object further comprises a pedestal, the pedestal having one end attached to the mirror and another end attached to each attachment pad of the first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a plate member, each of the coils having a first side attached to the object, and a second side attached to the plate member, the second side being opposite to the first side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the base comprises first, second, third, and fourth mounting posts, each of which is bonded to the mounting member of a respective one of the first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a plate member having an opening, each of the coils having a first side attached to the object and a second side attached to the plate member, the second side being opposite to the first side, with the first, second, third, and fourth mounting posts passing through the opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material each further comprises an intermediate section connected between the first end of the second beam and the second end of the first beam. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a damper coating applied to at least the first and second beams of the first, second, third, and fourth pieces of substantially planar material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. An actuator for tilting a mirror, comprising: 
<claim-text>a coil-mirror assembly that includes a plurality of coils each of which is rigidly attached to the mirror; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gimbal having one or more mounting sections for bonding to a base, and an attachment section bonded to the coil-mirror assembly, the attachment section being supported by a plurality of beams that flex when the coil-mirror assembly tilts, the coil-mirror assembly tilting in response to a current applied to the coils when each of the coils is in the presence of a magnetic field. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises a plurality of conductive paths, the current flowing through the conductive paths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises a conductive material, the conductive paths being integral with the material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the material comprises sheet metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each coil comprises a pair of coil wires, each coil wire of the pair being coupled to a different one of the conductive paths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. An actuator for tilting a mirror, comprising: 
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>coil-mirror assembly that includes a plurality of coils each of which is rigidly attached to the mirror; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gimbal having one or more mounting sections bonded to the base, and an attachment section bonded to the coil-mirror assembly, the attachment section being supported by a plurality of beams that flex when the coil-mirror assembly tilts; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of magnets, each of which is positioned adjacent one of the coils such that when a current is made to flow through the coils, a force is generated that causes the coil-mirror assembly to tilt. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises a plurality of conductive paths, the current flowing through the conductive paths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gimbal comprises a conductive material, the conductive paths being integral with the material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the material comprises sheet metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each coil comprises a pair of coil wires, each coil wire of the pair being coupled to a different one of the conductive paths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The actuator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the magnets are attached to the base.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>9</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030002181A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
