<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002992A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002992A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002992A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002992A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002992A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002992A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002992A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002992A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002992A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002992A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002992</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10235212</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020905</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F04B039/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>417</class>
<subclass>228000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Oil utilized as motor protector trip for scroll compressor</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10235212</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020905</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09690275</doc-number>
<document-date>20001017</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jason</given-name>
<family-name>Hugenroth</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lafayette</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CARLSON, GASKEY &amp; OLDS, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>400 WEST MAPLE ROAD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 350</address-2>
<city>BIRMINGHAM</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48009</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A scroll compressor has lubricant flow which communicates lubricant onto a motor protector when adverse conditions are present causing the motor protector to trip the motor and stop further rotation. The lubricant is returned to an oil sump through a normal return path. The normal return path outlet may be positioned above the motor protector such that lubricant will contact the motor protector when adverse conditions are present, or the outlet may be remote from the protector. When the outlet is remote from the protector, a funnel and tubing divert the oil to the motor protector under adverse conditions. Alternatively, a passage communicating with the normal return path is selectively blocked when an adverse condition is present. At that time, lubricant is forced into an alternative oil path, which is positioned above the motor protector. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation in part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/690,275; filed Oct. 17, 2000.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a system which optimizes the flow of a lubricant over portions of a scroll compressor which become hot during reverse rotation or loss of charge, and then selectively passes the heated lubricant onto a motor protector under certain conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Scroll compressors are becoming widely utilized in refrigerant compression applications. In a scroll compressor, a first scroll member has a base and a generally spiral wrap extending from the base. The wrap of the first scroll member interfits with the wrap from a second scroll member. The second scroll member is caused to orbit relative to the first, and refrigerant is entrapped between the scroll wraps. As the second scroll members orbits, the size of the compression chambers which entrap the refrigerant are reduced, and the refrigerant is compressed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> There are certain design challenges with a scroll compressor. As an example, while the scroll compressor efficiently compresses refrigerant when rotated in a proper forward direction, there are undesirable side effects if the scroll compressor is driven to rotate in a reverse direction. Moreover, if the level of refrigerant or charge level being passed through the compressor is lower than expected, there may also be undesirable side effects. Among the many undesirable side effects is an increased heat level at the scroll compressor members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> One safety feature incorporated into most sealed compressors is the use of a motor protector associated with the electric motor for driving the compressor. The same is true in a scroll compressor, wherein a motor protector is typically associated with the stator for the electric motor. The motor protector operates to stop rotation of the motor in the event there is an electrical anomaly, or if the motor protector senses an unusually high temperature. However, the problems mentioned above with regard to reverse rotation and loss of charge typically cause heat to increase at the compressor pump set which is relatively far from the motor. Thus, it may take an undue length of time for the additional heat being generated in the compressor pump set to pass to the motor protector. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In the disclosed embodiment of this invention, lubricant is caused to flow over a motor protector of a compressor pump set in sufficient quantities to cause the motor protector to trip the motor and stop further rotation when adverse conditions are present in the compressor pump set. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In one general type of embodiment of the disclosed invention, the lubricant is directed to a normal return path wherein the lubricant passes over a heated portion of the compressor before returning to an oil sump. In this type embodiment, lubricant is directed to the motor protector only if adverse conditions are present. Some automatic feedback, such as the refrigerant volume flow, achieves the selective control. In preferred embodiments, the heated portion of the compressor over which the lubricant is passed is the non-orbiting scroll. Alternatively, in some embodiments the heated lubricant can pass over the orbiting scroll. In a second general type embodiment of the disclosed invention, the flow of lubricant back to the motor protector is selective, and will only occur if adverse conditions are present. In this type of embodiment, the normal return path does not include the motor protector. Instead, a passage communicating with the normal return path is selectively blocked when an adverse condition is present. At that time, lubricant is forced into an alternative oil path, which is positioned over the motor protector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> These and other features can be best understood from the following specification and drawings, the following which is a brief description.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view through a scroll compressor pump set; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a first embodiment compressor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a second embodiment compressor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is another cross-sectional view of the second embodiment compressor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a third embodiment compressor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a fourth embodiment compressor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view through a fifth embodiment compressor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a modification to the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is another modification to the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is yet another modification to the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> embodiment; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view through yet another embodiment. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a cross-section of a scroll compressor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> having a compressor pump set which incorporates an orbiting scroll <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and a non-orbiting scroll <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. This is a schematic view of one embodiment from the parent application. A motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, as known, is associated with a motor stator <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A lubricant level (not shown) is positioned beneath the motor. An oil feed tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extends through drive shaft <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Downstream fluid flow portions <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, shown schematically, pass over the non-orbiting scroll <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. An outlet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> returns the heated lubricant to the lubricant sump. While <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts the oil feed obtained directly from the sump, the oil feed may also be obtained from elsewhere as known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In a first general type of embodiment of the present invention, the feed tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, downstream portions <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, and outlet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> comprise a normal oil return path wherein, under normal conditions, the oil does not contact motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. However, lubricant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is directed to the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> if adverse conditions are present. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 6</cross-reference> show a first type embodiment of the disclosed invention wherein the normal return path avoids the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Under normal operating conditions, the lubricant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> passes over a heated portion of the compressor before returning to the oil sump as above. While a minimal amount of oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> may contact the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> under normal operating conditions, the amount is insufficient to activate the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. As will be explained, under adverse running conditions, the lubricant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is directed to the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to trip the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and stop further rotation of the motor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In a first embodiment <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is returned toward the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> but only trips the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> under adverse conditions which significantly decrease the mass flow rate of refrigerant (represented by arrows <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>) through the compressor pump set <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. During normal operation, the refrigerant rotates through the set <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the same direction as the shaft <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, carrying oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> exiting from the outlet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> so that it does not contact the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, other than in small amounts, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Adjusting distance d ensures that the oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> does not contact the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> during normal operation. However, should mass flow of refrigerant within the set <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> drop due to adverse conditions such as loss of charge or indoor fan failure, the lower mass flow rate will allow the oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to drip onto the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, thereby stopping further rotation of the motor. That is, the mass flow rate of refrigerant <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> will be lower such that heated oil contacts the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in greater quantities. One advantage of this embodiment <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is the decreased amount of time it takes to trip the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> after adverse conditions are realized. While some motor protection systems require the reduced mass flow in the system to heat the oil, and then that the heated oil contact the protector, this embodiment relies solely on the reduced mass flow of the system to trip the protector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> show a second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> which also relies on the mass flow rate of the refrigerant to trip the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, a diversion flap <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is located at outlet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. During normal operating conditions, the mass flow rate of the refrigerant pushes the flap <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to partially block the outlet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and redirect the oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> such that it does not contact the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. As with embodiment <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, when the mass flow rate of the refrigerant slows due to an adverse condition, the flap <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> returns to a non-deflecting position, allowing the oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to trip the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The flap <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be substantially vertical when in the non-deflecting position, requiring placement of the outlet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> substantially above the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In another embodiment, <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, the flap <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be biased toward the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in the non-deflecting position using a spring <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> or other biasing means, allowing placement of the outlet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> some distance from the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a further embodiment <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the present invention wherein a funnel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> captures oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> from the outlet <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and directs it toward the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> much like the diversion flap <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> described above. A tube <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> attached to the funnel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> diverts the oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> toward the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The diverter mechanism can be utilized to take the return oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and move it circumferentially such that it is in the proper position relative to the protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, this diverter concept can be utilized to move oil completely independent of any protection feature. The funnel concept allows the incorporation of the movement of the oil circumferentially without the necessity of redesign of housing or compressor pump unit detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 through 11</cross-reference> show the second general type of embodiment of the present invention. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> normal oil return path does not include the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Instead, a passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> communicates with a normal oil return path tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Oil will return from passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> back downwardly through tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> under normal operating conditions, avoiding the motor protector. Communication between the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is selectively blocked when an adverse condition is present. At that time, lubricant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> within a chamber <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> will no longer move into the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The lubricant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> will then be forced upwardly into a passage <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, and from the passage <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> it will communicate with an alternative oil path. An alternative oil return tube <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is positioned over the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, thereby tripping the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to stop further rotation of the motor. Positioning the orbiting scroll (not shown) closer to the alternative passage <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> than to the normal passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> will ensure that better heat transfer is achieved. As with the first general type of embodiment, a funnel or other means may be used to direct the oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> from the alternative oil return tube <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> to the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> embodiment <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> has a float ball <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> which floats in the oil returning through the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. An opening <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> in the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> allows some oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to escape the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, thereby preventing the ball <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> from floating high enough to block the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. When the oil becomes excessively heated during an abusive running condition, a bimetal clip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> snaps to cover the opening <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, increasing the amount of oil in the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and forcing the ball <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> upwardly to close communication between the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. At that time, oil is forced into the alternative oil path <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> to trip the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows embodiment <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, wherein the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> includes a piston <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> with an associated spring <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> that selectively closes the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> when an adverse condition is present. Under normal operating conditions, intermediate pressure from a compressor chamber C compresses the spring <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> such that the piston <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> remains depressed, thereby allowing oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to flow through passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and downwardly through tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. During adverse running conditions which tend to cause intermediate pressure to drop, such as indoor fan failure, the spring <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> releases and the piston <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> moves upwardly to block communication between passages <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. When this occurs, the oil is forced through the alternative oil path to trip the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as described above. A worker in this art would recognize how to provide communication to an intermediate pressure chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows embodiment <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> which only slightly differs from embodiment <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In embodiment <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, bimetal clips <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> positioned in mating grooves <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> maintain a piston <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> in an upward position allowing oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to flow through the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and downwardly through the tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. When the compressor pump set <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> becomes heated to a predetermined temperature during adverse running conditions, the clips <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> snap clear of the grooves <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. This allows intermediate pressure to drive the piston <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to move downwardly, blocking communication between passages <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Similar to previous embodiments of this type, oil is then forced through the alternative oil path to activate the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and stop rotation of the motor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> shows embodiment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, wherein a piston <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> associated with a spring <highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight> selectively closes passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. Suction pressure is communicated both below and above the piston <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. The spring <highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight> thus maintains the piston in an upward position, allowing passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to communicate with oil return tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. A bimetal clip <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> covers an opening in the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> above the piston <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> which communicates with intermediate pressure at C. The clip <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> normally blocks intermediate pressure from reaching the piston <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. When an adverse running condition causes the temperature to exceed a predetermined level, the clip <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> snaps allowing intermediate pressure to contact the piston <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> forcing it downwardly to block communication between passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. At this time, oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is forced through the alternative oil path to trip the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows another embodiment <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> of the present invention, wherein a mechanism <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> connects the oil return passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the normal oil return tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. A plug <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> selectively closes communication between the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> by blocking access to the tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The plug is attached to a shape memory alloy spring <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> housed within the mechanism <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. As this spring <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> increases in temperature, it contracts in length or size. A second spring <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> applies a biasing force to hold the spring <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> in a predetermined position under normal operating conditions, thereby preventing the plug <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> from blocking the tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. However, should adverse running conditions cause the oil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> flowing through the mechanism <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> to become sufficiently heated, the spring <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> will contract. As the spring <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> contracts in size, it overcomes the force from the spring <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> and the plug <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> attached to the spring <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> is pulled to block tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. At that time, the lubricant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> within the mechanism <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> will no longer exit through the tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Instead, the lubricant <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> will be forced to exit the mechanism <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> through the alternate oil path return tube <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, thereby tripping the motor protector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to stop rotation of the motor. This embodiment differs from the embodiments in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 through 10</cross-reference> largely in the fact that the passage <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> leads directly to both the normal oil return tube <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and the alternative oil return tube <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> through the mechanism <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> It should be understood that while the invention has been disclosed for reacting to a predetermined high temperature or loss or gain of pressure within the compressor pump set, other conditions could cause the actuation. Although preferred embodiments of this invention have been disclosed, a worker in this art would recognize that certain modifications would come within the scope of this invention. For this reason, the following claims should be studied to determine the true scope and content of this invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor comprising: 
<claim-text>a compressor pump unit having a first scroll member having a base and a generally spiral wrap extending from said base, a second scroll member having a base and a generally spiral wrap extending from said base, said spiral wraps of said first and second scroll members interfitting to define compression chambers, and a crankcase for supporting said second scroll member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shaft for driving said second scroll member to orbit relative to said first scroll member, and compression chambers between said wraps of said first and second scroll member decreasing in size as said second scroll member orbits to compress an entrapped refrigerant; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor for driving said shaft to cause said second scroll member to orbit, said motor having a rotor and a stator, and a motor protector associated with said motor stator, said motor protector being operable to stop further operation of said motor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first passage for passing lubricant into an oil sump at an end of said compressor remote from said compressor pump unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing mechanism for actuating said motor protector when a predetermined amount of lubricant contacts said motor protector; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said lubricant being directed toward said motor protector when an undesired condition exists. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first passage includes an outlet positioned to communicate lubricant onto said motor protector only when an undesired condition exists. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, having a normal mass flow of refrigerant through said compressor pump unit under conditions other than said undesired conditions sufficient to carry lubricant exiting from said first passage away from said motor protector such that said lubricant does not contact said motor protector in sufficient quantities to actuate said motor protector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said undesired condition is a decreased mass flow rate, thereby allowing said predetermined amount of lubricant to contact said motor protector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said outlet includes a diversion flap. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said diversion flap is biased. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said outlet communicates oil into a diversion mechanism for communicating oil from said oil return passage onto said motor protector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said diversion mechanism includes a funnel and a diversion tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first passage includes a valve, said valve movable to block said first passage in the event said undesired condition exist. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, said compressor further including a second oil return passage for passing lubricant over a portion of said compressor pump unit when said valve closes at said first passage, said second passage being positioned to return lubricant from said portion of said compressor pump unit onto said motor protector in sufficient quantities to actuate said motor protector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said portion of said compressor pump unit is said first scroll member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second passage is positioned at a vertically higher location than said first passage such that said second passage is closer to said second scroll, and further presents more resistance to flow or lubricant to said first passage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said undesired condition is a predetermined temperature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said valve includes a plug connected to a temperature sensitive spring, said plug being movable to block said first passage in the event said predetermined temperature is reached. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said temperature sensitive spring includes a pair of springs with at least one of said springs being temperature sensitive, said plug being movable for blocking said first passage based upon movement of said temperature sensitive spring in the event said predetermined temperature is reached. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor comprising: 
<claim-text>a compressor pump unit having a first scroll member having a base and a generally spiral wrap extending from said base, a second scroll member having a base and a generally spiral wrap extending from said base, said spiral wraps of said first and second scroll members interfitting to define compression chambers, and a crankcase for supporting said second scroll member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an oil return passage for passing lubricant from said compressor pump unit to an oil return tube; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said oil return tube communicating lubricant into a diversion mechanism for diverting lubricant from said oil return passage to a desired location. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein lubricant is communicated to said oil return passage only when an undesired condition exists. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said diversion mechanism includes a funnel and a diversion tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A scroll compressor as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said desired location is onto said motor protector.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002992A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002992A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002992A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002992A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002992A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
