<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000199A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000199A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000199A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000199A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000199A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000199A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000199A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000199A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000199A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000199A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000199A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000199A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000199A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000199A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000199</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10190683</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020709</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-192651</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000622</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F02C009/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>060</class>
<subclass>039240</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Power plant operation control system and a power plant maintaining and managing method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10190683</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020709</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09791703</doc-number>
<document-date>20010226</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Naoyuki</given-name>
<family-name>Nagafuchi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokai</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yasushi</given-name>
<family-name>Iwai</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Hitachi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiraku</given-name>
<family-name>Ikeda</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Hitachinaka</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MATTINGLY, STANGER &amp; MALUR, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1800 DIAGONAL ROAD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 370</address-2>
<city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22314</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Quick recovery or recovery support of a faulty power generating facility by real time diagnoses such as facility failure diagnosis, supervision for failure symptoms, facility diagnosis by evaluation of performance using databases between said power generating facilities and an operation control system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">An operation control system comprising </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0003" lvl="2">means for transferring information on operating status and secular characteristic changes of apparatus from power generating facilities or information from operators of selected power generating facilities, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0004" lvl="2">means for processing and diagnosing information transferred by said transferring means, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0005" lvl="2">means for weighting the level of a failure of a power generating facility which has a failure according to the information sent from said processing and diagnosing means, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0006" lvl="2">means for automatically creating repairing information (e.g. recovery procedures, processes, required parts, inventory of the parts, possible failure causes, etc.) from repairing information prepared for each weight in advance and sending it to the operation section and the operation supporting section of said power generating facility. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an operation control system and a maintaining and managing method for power generating facilities fit for maintenance/management services of a power network group consisting of a plurality of power supplying facilities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Related Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Technologies on management of power generating facilities have been disclosed in Japanese Non-examined Patent Publications No. 10-301621 (1998), No. 11-3113 (1999), No. 7-152984 (1995), and No. 5-284252 (1993). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> However, these technologies are all related to processing in the inside of a power generating facility such as instructions of operations, provision of work information, and so on and do not include centralized control and management of a plurality of power generating facilities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Real time diagnoses of a plurality of power generating facilities such as facility failure diagnosis, supervision for failure symptoms, facility diagnosis by evaluation of performance using a database have been requested between said power generating facilities and an operation control system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide an operation control system and a maintaining and managing method for power generating facilities fit for maintenance/management services of a power network group consisting of a plurality of power supplying facilities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention is characterized by an operation control system for controlling a plurality of power generating facilities, comprising </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> means for gradually weighting the levels of failures of said power generating facilities according to operating status information of each of said power generating facilities and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> means for outputting preset information corresponding to each weighted failure level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Or the present invention is characterized by a method of maintaining and managing a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising a step of selecting a repairing period and procedure for a failure which occurred in at least one of said power supplying facilities from repairing periods and procedures which are predetermined according to levels of failures.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a power generation facility network to which the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an explanatory illustration of a general supervision/diagnosis system which is an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an explanatory illustration of a general supervision/diagnosis system and a repairing supporting function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an explanatory illustration of an optimum scheduling supporting function and a system stabilization supporting function </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an explanatory illustration of a status forecasting function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a power generation plant management system which shows a positional embodiment of the operating method of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a power supplying system comprising a plurality of power generating facilities which include a distributed power supply group which is an embodiment of the present invention. Below will be explained the present invention using the application to an arbitrary gas turbine combined power generating facility as an example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the system comprises a general supervision/diagnosis system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for managing a power supply system and a piece of control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which supplies process quality information of a selected power generating facility to the diagnosing system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> One of the power generating facilities is linked to a power system through a power regulator which regulates the voltage and power fluctuation of power generated by a generator <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and a transformer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> which regulates power from the power regulator <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into a voltage for the power system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> One of said power generating facilities consists of a compressor <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> which compresses air, a compressor inlet guide vane <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> which regulates the rate of an air flow fed to the compressor <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a fuel source regulating valve <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which regulates the rate of a fuel source sent from a fuel base <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, a diffusion fuel regulating valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a pre-mixed fuel regulating valve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> which regulate the flow rates of fuel from the fuel source regulating valve <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for diffusion and premixing, a burner <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which mixes and burns fuel sent from the diffusion fuel regulating valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the pre-mixed fuel regulating valve <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and a compressed air from the compressor <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and generates high-temperature combustion gas, a turbine <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> which recovers power from the combustion gas fed from the burner <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, a heat exchanging boiler <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> which recovers heat from the exhaust gas output from the turbine <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and generates superheated steam, a steam pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which transfers superheated steam from the heat exchanging boiler <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> to a steam turbine <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, and a rotary shaft <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> which transfers a turning effort of the compressor <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the turbine <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and the steam turbine <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to the generator <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Further, this system comprises another power generating facility <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> which is linked to the power system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the same power network, a non-utility power generator or IPP facility <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> which is a distributed power supply, a distributed power supply system <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> which is a local network connecting a power generating facility <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a circuit breaker <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which makes or breaks the connection between the power system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the distributed power supply system <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and a leased or satellite communication line <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> which transfers control signals from the general supervision/diagnosis system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the fuel base <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, another power generating facility <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, a distributed power facility <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and so on. Here, the leased or satellite communication line <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> used as a telecommunication means in this embodiment can be substituted by another communication means such as Internet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In the normal operation status of this system, the general supervision/diagnosis system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> usually monitors process quantities sent from said control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and provides the operation manager with daily management information required for operation, information about remaining service lives of expendables, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> When a failure occurs in this system, the general supervision/diagnosis system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> provides the operation manager with the level of the failure and information about possible causes of the failure. If the operation manager requires, this system secures the power quality of said power system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and provides information on operations to protect the power generating facility which has the failure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Further, if a fatal failure which damages a power generating facility occurs, this system provides information required to shorten the repairing period and minimizes the operating time of the power generating facility which has the failure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Below will be explained functions to materialize the above operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the content of the general supervision/diagnosis system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The general supervision/diagnosis system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is equipped with an error supervision/diagnosis function <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> which receives process supervision information and operation instruction information from the control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and diagnoses the operating status of target power generating facilities and failure level judges <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> which determine the level of the failure according to information sent from the error supervision/diagnosis function <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> This embodiment transfers operating status information from respective power generating facilities to the error supervision/diagnosis function <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> by a communication means. For easier judgment of fault levels (or failure levels), information on operating status and secular characteristic changes of apparatus or information from operators of selected power generating facilities are used as the operating status information from respective power generating facilities. The failure level judges receive information from the error supervision/diagnosis function <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and give stepwise weights to failures according to the degrees of failures in the power generating facilities. For example, the description of this embodiment assumes there are three failure levels: Fatal fault, Non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and Non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. These weights are given according to time periods and procedures required for repairing or correction. A repairing period and a repairing procedure are assigned to each failure (fault) in advance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In details, the fault level judge <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> judges whether the failure is fatal or non-fatal. A failure which does not require stopping of a power generating system is judged to be non-fatal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> When the fault level judge <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> judges it as a nonfatal failure, the fault level judge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> judges whether the failure is non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A failure which may cause device damages when left unrepaired is judged to be non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A failure which may cause no device damage when left unrepaired is judged to be non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Failure information judged to be non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is sent to the fault level judge <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> This embodiment comprises a status forecasting function <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> which forecasts the status of the power generating facility from information sent from the fault level judges <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> When the fault level judge <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> judges that the failure is a fatal fault which requires stopping of the power generating facility, the fault level judge <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> sends the failure information to the optimum scheduling supporting function <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. This embodiment is constituted so that information may be transferred from this optimum scheduling supporting function <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to the pumping-up power facility control function <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, the system stabilization supporting function <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, the fuel base control function <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, and so on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The status forecasting function <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> processes information as explained below. The information judged to be non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is evaluated by the fault level evaluating function <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> whether the failure may propagate into an apparatus damage. The fault level evaluating function <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> sends the information to the recoverability evaluator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Similarly, the information judged to be non-fatal fault <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is sent to the recoverability evaluator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The recoverability evaluator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> checks whether the status can be recovered by adjustment of control value settings, that is by changing control values. If it is possible, the information is sent to the control value adjusting function <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The function <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> performs remote tuning of control value settings and the like and adjusts the control quantities. If it is not possible, information is sent from the recoverability evaluator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to the fault propagation evaluating function <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The fault propagation evaluating function <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is so constituted to display information about occurrence of a failure and forecasted result of propagation of the failure, to send the information to the repairing supporting function <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, and to provide the operation manager with information about failure causes, repairing procedures, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> When a fatal failure which requires stopping of a facility occurs in a power generating facility, this embodiment can immediately inform to the power generating facility or stop the operation of the power generating facility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The optimum scheduling supporting function <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> processes information as follows. When the information is judged to be fatal by the fault level judge <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the automatic plant stopping function <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> stops the power generating facility which has the failure and automatically stops. In this case, the automatic plant stopping function <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can send process quantities to the repairing supporting function <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and provide the operation manager with information about failure causes, repairing procedures, etc. When a fatal failure which requires stopping of a facility occurs in a power generating facility, this embodiment can immediately inform to the power generating facility or stop the operation of the power generating facility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> At almost the same time, information to stop the power generating facility is sent from said automatic plant stopping function <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to the optimum scheduling supporting function <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The optimum scheduling supporting function <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> checks, by the operating status judge (in the identical system) <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, whether the other power generating facility in the system which contains the power generating facility which has stopped can take over the load of the faulty power generating facility. If the load can be taken over by the other power generating facility, the operation control function (in the identical system) <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> increases the load of a running power generating facility which does not have a failure and approximately at the same time, sends a &ldquo;Change in Total Fuel Amount&rdquo; signal for the fuel base <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to said fuel base control function <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Thus, if at least one of said power supplying facilities (power generating facilities) fails, it is possible to assure the steady power supply of the whole power system comprising a plurality of power generating facilities by selecting a repairing period and procedure for the failure from repairing period periods and procedures which are determined according to levels of failures and by controlling the operation of at least one of power supplying facilities except the faulty power supplying facility. It is also possible to control the power supplying facilities in the other power system, the power supplying facility in the stop status, or the distributed power source facilities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> If the operating status judge (in identical system) <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> judges that the load cannot be taken over by the other power generating facility, the information is sent to the operating status judge (in other power generating facility) <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> which judges whether the load of the faulty power generating facility can be taken over by a power generating facility in the other system. When the load can be taken over by a power generating facility in the other system, the operation control function (in other system) <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> increases the load of a running power generating facility and at the same time, sends a &ldquo;Change in Total Fuel Amount&rdquo; signal for the fuel base <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to said fuel base control function <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> If the operating status judge (in other power generating facility) <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> judges that the load cannot be taken over by any power generating facility in the other system, the information is sent to the operating status judge (in other power generating facility) <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> which judges whether a power generating facility in the stop status can be started immediately. If the power generating facility in the stop status can be started immediately, the information is sent to the operation control function (other power generating facility) <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and the power generating facility in the stop status is started. Approximately at the same time, the &ldquo;Change in Total Fuel Amount&rdquo; signal for the fuel base <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is sent to said fuel base control function <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> If the operating status judge (in other power generating facility) <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> judges that there is no power generating facility which can be started immediately, the information is sent to the operation status judge (decentralized power supply) <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> which judges whether the load can be taken over by a running or stopping distributed power source facility. If the load can be taken over by a distributed power source facility, the information is sent to the operation control function (distributed power supply) <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The operation control function <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> increases the load of the running distributed power source facility or starts a stopping distributed power source facility. Approximately at the same time, the &ldquo;Change in Total Fuel Amount&rdquo; signal for the fuel base <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is sent to said fuel base control function <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Information generated by said operation control functions <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are sent to said system stabilization supporting function <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> If the operation status judge (distributed power supply) <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> judges that there is no power generating facility which can be started immediately, the information is sent to the operation control function (pumping-up power station) <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and the load is taken by a pumping-up power generation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> As explained above, as failures of the power generating facilities are respectively given stepwise weights according to the operating status information of each power generating facility in the system, we can exactly grasp the level of a failure which occurred in one power generating facility and its location. Therefore, operations of a plurality of power generating facilities can be managed collectively, concentrating facilities and increasing the efficiency of management jobs. Particularly, this embodiment is suitable for collectively controlling power generating facilities which are remotely dispersed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Further, this embodiment is equipped with means for outputting preset information for each weighted failure level. So a proper repairing action can be taken for a power generating facility which has a failure. Therefore, for quick repairing, it is preferential to send said repairing information to the section in charge of the operation of the power generating facility or the operation supporting section and to dispatch service engineers to the facility. Further, as the repairing period and procedure fit for the failure can be obtained just by selection, quick and exact maintenance services can be done on the power supplying facility which has a failure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Referring <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, below will be explained the details of the error supervision/diagnosis function <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and said repairing supporting functions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the functional block diagram of said error supervision/diagnosis function <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and said repairing supporting functions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The error supervision/diagnosis function <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> performs as explained below. The error supervision/diagnosis function <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> receives a run command signal <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> from the control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and sends to the physical model simulator <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> which contains a set of tuning parameters <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> to eliminate a difference between the result of computation and the result of actual operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The physical model simulator <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> calculates normal-operation process quantities which are expected when a facility is operated by said run command signal <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and outputs the result to the subtractor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The process quantity measurement signal <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> sent from the control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is sent to the operation log database <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> which has a function to correct and update the normal/abnormal operation data by results of daily operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The operation log database <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> sends the information of measurement in the current operation status to said subtractor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The subtractor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> sends the resulting difference information to the switch <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The switch <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> sends the difference information to the fault diagnosing function <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> while the operation is normal or to the parameter adjusting function <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> when the difference between the result of computation and the result of actual operation exceeds a preset limit even in the normal operation. If the output of the subtractor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> exceeds a preset limit, the switch sends the signal to the fault diagnosing function <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The fault diagnosing function <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> compares the information from said switch <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> by data (normal operation data and abnormal operation data) from the operation log database <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and checks whether the operation is normal or abnormal. When assuming there may be a failure, the fault diagnosing function <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> outputs a Fault Detected signal <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> When the switch <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> switches to send a signal from said subtractot <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to said parameter adjusting function <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the function <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> outputs a signal which adjusts said tuning parameters <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> so that the difference between the result of computation by said simulator <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the normal operation data sent from said operation log database may be zero. An offline identifying function is provided so that said parameter adjustment may be carried out while the plant is not in operation for safety. In this way, this embodiment can perform fault supervision and diagnosis efficiently and accurately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The repairing supporting functions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> perform as explained below. When a plant has a failure, the fault locating function <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> locates a faulty part from the Fault Detected signal <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> and sends the resulting information to the fault cause diagnosing function <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and to the function <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for selecting the shortest repairing procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The fault cause diagnosing function <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> selects the most possible failure cause information from the fault factors database <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> which classifies the failure information from the operation log database by locations and causes for management and outputs cause display information <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The function <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for selecting the shortest repairing procedure selects and outputs information of parts and procedures required to repair the failure in a very short time period from the replacement part inventory database <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> having information of the inventory of replacement parts and the repairing procedure database <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> having repairing procedures that were actually carried out. This enables easy, accurate, and quick repairing of a faulty power generating facility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Next will be explained the optimum scheduling supporting function <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the system stabilization supporting function <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Operation information <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> from the control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, other facility operation information <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> sent from other power generating facilities <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> through information transfer means <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and information coming from the statistic model database <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> which simulates the operation characteristics of the other power generating facilities <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are fed to the operation schedule calculating function <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. The operation schedule calculating function <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> calculates the operation schedules of the target power generating facilities and sends the result to the optimizing function <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The optimizing function <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> includes an evaluating function <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and an adjusting function <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. The evaluating function <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> checks whether the entered information satisfies conditions by functions that the operation manager selects by the optimization evaluating function selecting function <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and sends the result (information of judgment) to the adjusting function <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. The adjusting function <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> feeds back a signal for re-scheduling or partial modification so that the result of operation by the operation schedule calculating function <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> may be optimum. The signal which is evaluated to be optimum by the evaluating function <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is output to a display unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> which displays the result of arithmetic operations. In this way, the operation schedule can be optimized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Next will be explained the status forecasting function <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The run command signal <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> from the control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is sent to a control system model <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> which contains an installation logic of the control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The control system model <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> contains a set of tuning parameters <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> to eliminate a difference between the result of computation and the result of measurement of actual control operation ends. The control system model <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> calculates a control operation end instruction signal which is expected when the facility is operated according to the operation instruction signal <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and sends the result to the physical model base dynamic characteristics simulator <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The physical model base dynamic characteristics simulator <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> calculates the process status quantity from the control signal and outputs the result to the subtractor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The process quantity measurement signal <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> sent from the control equipment <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is sent to the subtractor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> through the operation log database <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The resulting difference information is sent to the evaluating function <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The evaluating function <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> sends a switching signal to the switch <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and a signal to modify preset control values for control of said control operation ends to the parameter regulating function <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The parameter regulating function <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> outputs a signal to adjust tuning parameters <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> so that the subtractor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> outputs 0. This signal is fed to the switch <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and fed back as a signal for tuning the control setting by a switching signal sent from the evaluating function <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> when a failure occurs. An offline identifying function is provided so that said parameter adjustment may be carried out while the plant is not in operation for safety. In this way, this embodiment can forecast the status efficiently and accurately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Below will be explained a method of operating a plant to which the present invention is applied, referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Information from a power generation control panel <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> which controls and monitors the operating status of a power generation plant is coded and transmitted to the general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> which contains functions explained in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> through a communication line <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> which is a communication means. The coded information can protect the power generation control equipment <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> and the general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> from violating interference from the outside. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The communication line <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> has a firewall function <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> to protect the system against violating accesses on each end of the line. The coded information can protect the power generation control equipment <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> and the general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> from violating interference from the outside. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Further, the general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> has an intranet <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> for communication which connects a database of apparatus drawing and specification data <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, a database of performance and life cycle evaluation diagnosis data <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>, a database of auxiliary parts data, and a database of common data <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> for designing and manufacturing sections so that the engineers in the general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> may share the data. In other words, the engineers can use apparatus drawing and specification data <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, performance and life cycle evaluation diagnosis data <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>, auxiliary parts data <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, and common data <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> for designing and manufacturing sections through the general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. This provides an excellent facility maintenance/management service. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Operators and maintenance engineers <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of the power generation plant <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, the general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, and the service shop <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> which manages replacement parts are interconnected directly communication lines <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. This provides an excellent facility maintenance/management service. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> For example, when the power generation plant <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> has a failure, the power generation control panel <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> or the operator or maintenance engineer <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of the plant <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> sends information to the general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> sends plant recovery information obtained by functions in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> to said power generation control panel <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, to said operators and maintenance engineers <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, and to repairing instructors <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> who are dispatched upon request from said general control center <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. Said information is also sent to the service shop <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> In this way, this embodiment can monitor a plurality of remote power generation facilities and provide information for operators to control the operating status of the facilities if the facility has a possibility of failure. Further when one of the facilities fails, this embodiment can immediately support recovery of the facility. The security function when added to the communication means can prevent external interference by third parties. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> This embodiment is very effective for a power supplying system comprising a plurality of power generating facilities linked to a power system and distributed power source facilities such as non-utility power generator, IPP, and fuel cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The present invention can provide an operation control system and a maintaining and managing method for power generating facilities fit for maintenance/management services of a power network group consisting of a plurality of power supplying facilities. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An operation control system for controlling a plurality of power generating facilities, comprising 
<claim-text>means for gradually weighting the levels of failures of said power generating facilities according to operating status information of each of said power generating facilities and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for outputting preset information corresponding to each weighted failure level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An operation control system for collectively controlling a plurality of power generating facilities which are dispersed remotely or for supporting to control said distributed power generating facilities, comprising 
<claim-text>means for transferring information on operating status and secular characteristic changes of apparatus from said power generating facilities or information from operators of selected power generating facilities, </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for processing and diagnosing information transferred by said transferring means, </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for weighting the level of a failure of a power generating facility which has a failure according to the information sent from said processing and diagnosing means, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for selecting related repairing information from repairing information prepared for each of said failure weights and transmitting thereof to the related operation section and the operation supporting section of said power plant. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An operation control system in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising means for transmitting said repairing information to a location which requires repairing or to a repairing personnel when said power generating facility has a failure to be repaired. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An operation control system for power generating facilities comprising a control facility which maintains and controls a plurality of power supplying facilities, wherein said control facility selects from repairing period periods and procedures required to repair failures which occur in said plurality of power supplying facilities and performs maintenance and management of power supplying facilities which have failures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method of maintaining and managing a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising the steps of 
<claim-text>selecting a repairing period and procedure for a failure which occurred in at least one of said power supplying facilities from repairing periods and procedures which are predetermined according to levels of failures and </claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling the operation of at least one of power supplying facilities except the power supplying facility which has the failure according to the selected repairing period and procedure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method of maintaining and managing a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising the steps of 
<claim-text>selecting a repairing period and procedure for a failure which occurred in at least one of said power supplying facilities from repairing periods and procedures which are predetermined according to levels of failures and </claim-text>
<claim-text>instructing to repair the power supplying facility which has the failure according to the selected repairing period and procedure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method of maintaining and managing a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising the steps of 
<claim-text>selecting some possible causes for a failure which occurred in at least one of said power supplying facilities in the order of highest possibility to lowest possibility and information of a phenomenon which may extend or propagate if the failure is left unpaired, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>presenting the selected item information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method of maintaining and managing a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising the steps of 
<claim-text>receiving information of a failure which occurred in at least one of said power supplying facilities through communication means, </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a repairing period and procedure for a failure in the received information from repairing periods and procedures which are predetermined according to levels of failures and </claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting an instruction to control the operation of at least one of power supplying facilities except the power supplying facility which has the failure according to the selected repairing period and procedure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method of maintaining and managing a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising the steps of; 
<claim-text>receiving failure information of a power supplying facility which has a failure and checking whether the failure is a fatal fault which requires the power supplying facility to stop, </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the level of the non-fatal fault from said failure information when the failure is not a fatal fault, </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a period and a procedure to repair said failure from repairing periods and procedures which are predetermined according to levels of failures and </claim-text>
<claim-text>showing the selected repairing period and procedure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of maintaining and managing a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising the steps of; 
<claim-text>obtaining failure information of a power supplying facility which has a failure from an error supervision/diagnosis means, </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the level of said failure by a fault level judge, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>showing a predetermined repairing period and procedure according to the determined fault level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method of maintaining and managing a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising the steps of; 
<claim-text>comparing actual operation data of said power supplying facilities by normal and abnormal operation data which was stored in a database in advance, </claim-text>
<claim-text>checking for any operation error, </claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting failure information from said error supervision/diagnosis means when finding an operation error, </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the level of said failure by a fault level judge from said output failure information, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>showing a predetermined repairing period and procedure according to the determined fault level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An operation and management system for power generating facilities which maintains and manages a plurality of power supplying facilities which supply power to arbitrary power systems, comprising 
<claim-text>a database storing operation data obtained while the facilities are in normal operating states and operation data obtained while the facilities are in abnormal states, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an error supervision/diagnosis means which compares actual operation data of said power supplying facilities by operation data stored in said database, checks for any operation error, </claim-text>
<claim-text>and outputs failure information when finding an operation error, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fault level judge which determines the level of said failure from said output failure information, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation scheduling means which shows a predetermined repairing period and procedure selected according to the determined failure level.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000199A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000199A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000199A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000199A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000199A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000199A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000199A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
