<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001554A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001554A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001554</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10094639</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020312</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-38020</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G05F003/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>323</class>
<subclass>315000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Internal power voltage generator</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kee Teok</given-name>
<family-name>Park</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyoungki-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JACOBSON HOLMAN PLLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>400 SEVENTH STREET N.W.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 600</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An internal power voltage generator for achieving stable operation of a semiconductor device by selectively connecting an external power voltage terminal to a supply line of an internal power voltage in an operation power potential range of the semiconductor device, and generating a predetermined reference voltage in a reference voltage generator in accordance with the internal power voltage after a predetermined potential. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to an internal power voltage generator, and more specifically, to an internal power voltage generator of a current mirror type which converts an external power voltage into an internal power voltage by using a reference voltage. The internal power voltage generator generates a predetermined reference voltage by making use of an external power voltage during a specific power potential period, but generates the predetermined reference voltage by making use of the internal power voltage after the specific power potential period. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Semiconductor integrated circuits need to be operable with lower power consumption and to be hardly affected from external noises, accompanying with enhancement of reliability and stable operations thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In view of the above basic requirements, in order to drive internal circuits at stable operation states, it is customary to use an internal power voltage made in the semiconductor integrated circuits rather than an external power voltage dependent on external circumstances. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> There are various ways for generating a stable internal power voltage. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a conventional voltage down converter of a current mirror type in which an external power voltage VEXT is converted into a conventional internal power voltage QVint by using a reference voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The conventional voltage down converter usually comprises a differential amplifier. The first reference circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> receives the external power voltage VEXT and generates the first reference voltage Vr<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The first reference voltage Vr<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is potential-amplified by the second reference circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The second reference circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> generates the second reference voltage Vr<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A stress voltage circuit <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> loads a stress voltage on the second reference voltage Vr<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An internal power driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> generates the internal power voltage QVint with reference to output an voltage from the stress voltage circuit <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The internal power voltage QVint is provided to an internal circuit <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> However, since the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the conventional voltage down converter utilizes only the external power voltage VEXT as a power source, the first reference voltage Vr<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> may change when the external power voltage VEXT fluctuates due to external environments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In other words, in the conventional voltage down converter, the external power voltage VEXT applied to the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> may be easily variable in accordance with external temperature changes or noises. Accordingly, in special cases, the external power voltage VEXT of sufficient potential may be transferred to the current mirror loop in the voltage down converter. As a result, it would be difficult to obtain a reliable value of the first reference voltage Vr<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> It is, therefore, an object of the present invention to overcome the above problems encountered in the prior art and to achieve stable operation of a semiconductor device by selectively utilizing external or internal power voltages in accordance with an operation power potential period of the semiconductor device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the present invention, there is provided an internal power voltage generating unit including: a switch control means for connecting an external power voltage terminal to a internal power voltage supply line in an operation power potential range, and for cutting off the connection between the external power voltage terminal and the internal power voltage supply line if the external power voltage reaches a predetermined potential level; a first reference circuit for generating a predetermined first reference voltage by making the use of the internal power voltage; a second reference circuit for generating a second reference voltage by amplifying the first reference voltage supplied from the first reference circuit; and an internal power driver for generating the internal power voltage with the second reference voltage supplied from the second reference circuit, and for driving internal circuits with the internal power voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The foregoing features and advantages of the invention will be more fully described in the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects, features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a conventional internal power voltage generator according to the conventional art; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram showing an internal power voltage generator according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram showing a switch controller employed in the internal power voltage generator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram showing an internal power voltage generator according to another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram showing a switch controller employed in the internal power voltage generator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 through 8</cross-reference> are graphic diagrams showing operational characteristics evaluated by a simulation process for the internal power voltage generator of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing an internal power voltage generator according to still another embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> It should be understood that the description of the preferred embodiment is merely illustrative and that it should not be taken in a limiting sense. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram showing an internal power voltage generator according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the internal power voltage generator includes a switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, a switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the second reference circuit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a stress voltage circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and voltage driver <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> selectively connects the external power voltage terminal VEXT with the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of under the control of the switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> selectively receives the external power voltage VEXT or the internal power voltage QVINT from an internal power driver <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and then generates the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of a constant voltage level. The second reference circuit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> potential-amplifies the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and generates a second reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The stress voltage circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> loads a stress voltage on the second reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The internal power driver <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> generates the internal power voltage QVINT by making use of the output voltage from the stress voltage circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> as a reference voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to the aforementioned discussion of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> generates the first reference voltage from the internal power voltage QVINT having a changing range lower than that of the external power voltage VEXT when an initial drive voltage has a larger potential, than a predetermined potential, thereby minimizing variation of the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A detailed discussion of the above elements is herein explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes PMOS (P-channel metal-oxide-semiconductor) transistors P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> having a common source node connected to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Gates of the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are commonly connected a drain node of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An NMOS (N-channel MOS) transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, connected between the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a resistor R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, is connected to a ground voltage terminal QVSS through its bulk region. An NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected between an output terminal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (that is a drain node of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and the ground voltage terminal QVSS. The drain node of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to its gate node, which is connected together with a gate of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The bulk region of the NMOS transistor is connected to the ground voltage terminal QVSS. The first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is generated at the output terminal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The second reference circuit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&tilde;P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&tilde;N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The PMOS and NMOS transistors, P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&tilde;P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&tilde;N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, form a differential amplifier. Sources of the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&tilde;P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are connected to the external power voltage VEXT, together with their bulk regions. Gates of the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are in common coupled to a drain node of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A gate of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, which is connected between the external power voltage VEXT and an output terminal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, is coupled to a drain node of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The output terminal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is connected to the ground voltage terminal QVSS through the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The bulk region of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and a gate of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are in common coupled to the output terminal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The gate of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is in common coupled to a node <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> between the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is connected between the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a node <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, and the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is connected between the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the node <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Gates of the NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are coupled to the output terminal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the node <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, respectively. Bulk regions of the NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected to the ground voltage terminal QVSS. Between the node <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and the ground voltage terminal QVSS, the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> whose gate is coupled to the output terminal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is connected. The NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is connected between the node <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the ground voltage terminal QVSS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The stress voltage circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is comprised of PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, which are connected between the external power voltage VEXT and the output node <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the second reference circuit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Each gate of the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is coupled to its drain, and their bulk regions are in common coupled to the external power voltage VEXT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The internal power driver <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>&tilde;P<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>&tilde;N<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>&tilde;P<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>&tilde;N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, forms a differential amplifier. Sources of the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>&tilde;P<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are connected to the external power voltage VEXT, together with their bulk regions. Gates of the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are coupled to a drain node of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in common. The gate of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, connected between the external power voltage terminal VEXT and an output terminal <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the driver <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, is coupled to a common drain node of the PMOS and NMOS transistors, P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The bulk region of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is coupled to the external power voltage terminal VEXT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is connected between the drain of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and a drain of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> whose gate is coupled to the output terminal <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is connected between the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the drain of NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Gates of the NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are coupled to the output terminal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the second reference circuit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the output terminal <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, respectively. Bulk regions of the NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are connected to the ground voltage terminal QVSS. The bulk region of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is connected to the ground voltage terminal QVSS. The gate of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is coupled to the output terminal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, together with a gate of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> which is connected between the output terminal <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the ground voltage terminal QVSS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> operates to connect the external power voltage terminal VEXT to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line, in response to the switching control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> from the switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> serves to connect the external power voltage terminal VEXT to the supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the internal power voltage QVINT in a specific potential range between the ground voltage QVSS and the external power voltage, for the purpose of ensuring that the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not conductive until the external power voltage VEXT attains a predetermined level at an initial drive time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> comprises a PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> connected between the external power voltage terminal VEXT and the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The switching control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> supplied from the switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is applied to a gate of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The internal power voltage QVINT and the ground voltage QVSS may be global power source voltages used in a chip, or internal power source voltages partially used for driving internal circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> controls the operation of the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and inverters IV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and IV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, are connected in series between the external power voltage terminal VEXT and the ground voltage terminal QVSS. The gate of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is coupled to the ground voltage terminal. The bulk region of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is connected to the external power voltage terminal VEXT. The gate and drain of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are connected in common. The PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are connected in series between the external power voltage terminal VEXT and the ground voltage terminal QVSS. The bulk region of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is connected to the external power voltage terminal VEXT. Gates of the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are coupled to a common drain node <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> between the PMOS and the NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The inverters IV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and IV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are serially connected from a common drain node <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> between the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The inverters IV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and IV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> delay an out signal from the common drain node <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and output the delayed output signal (i.e., the switching control signal) S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> controls the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> which connects the external power voltage terminal VEXT to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> at a specific potential range between the ground voltage QVSS and the external power voltage VEXT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The operation of the switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> will be explained in conjunction with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>. When the external power voltage VEXT is turned on, the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> voltage-divide the external power voltage VEXT, and establish a predetermined reference voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> invert the reference voltage. The inverted reference voltage is converted into the switching control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> by being delayed by the inverters IV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and IV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> During a specific power potential period of an initial operation, the switching control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> goes to a low level when the external power voltage VEXT is lower than a predetermined voltage level. At this time, if the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is turned on, the external power voltage VEXT is connected to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. And then, a high voltage driven from the external power voltage VEXT is transferred to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> makes use of the high voltage as a power source. Then, when the external power voltage VEXT is higher than the predetermined voltage after the specific power potential period, the control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> goes to a high level. At this time, the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is turned off, and thereby the external power voltage VEXT is disconnected from the internal power voltage QVINT. Thus, only the internal power voltage QVINT is applied to the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Here, the switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> operates the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to connect the external power voltage VEXT to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> in a specific potential range, e.g., less than 2V, and to cut off the connection in a higher potential range than the specific potential range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Further, the switching control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may have the operational characteristics of an hysteresis loop while it is being conductive to control the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> For instance, the switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> operates the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to disconnect the external power voltage VEXT from the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> in a specific potential range higher than 2V, and to connect the external power voltage VEXT to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> in a potential range lower than 1V. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In other words, the connection of the external power voltage terminal VEXT and the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is cut off in a potential range higher than 2V when a power source is being supplied to a chip. When the power source is not being supplied to the chip, the external power voltage terminal VEXT is connected to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> in a potential range lower than 1V. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows another embodiment of an internal power voltage generator according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> A switch controller <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> generates a control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; in response to the first and second reference voltages VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which are each provided from the first and second reference circuits <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Here, the circuit constructions except the switch controller <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> are identical to those shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a detailed circuit construction of the switch controller <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the switch controller <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is comprised of PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&tilde;P<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&tilde;N<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&tilde;P<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&tilde;N<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> form a differential amplifier. The PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> respectively have source nodes connected to the external power voltage terminal VEXT, gates coupled to a drain node of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in common, and bulk regions connected to the external power voltage terminal VEXT. The NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> whose gate is coupled to the second reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected between the common drain node of the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a node <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> whose gate is coupled to the external power voltage terminal VEXT is connected between a node (an output of the differential amplifier) and the node <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. Bulk regions of the NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are connected to the ground voltage terminal QVSS in common. the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> whose gate is coupled to the first reference circuit VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected between the node <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and the ground voltage terminal QVSS. The PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> whose gate is coupled to the node <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> is connected between the external power voltage terminal VEXT and a node <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, and the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> whose gate is coupled to the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected between the node <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and the ground voltage terminal QVSS. The PMOS and NMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are connected between the external power voltage terminal VEXT and the ground voltage terminal QVSS and performs as an inverter. Gates of the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are coupled to the node <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> disposed between the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The switching control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; is generated from an output terminal <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> (or a common drain node) disposed between the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The switch controller <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> compares the external power voltage VEXT with the second reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by making use of the differential amplifier of a current mirror type enabled by the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and generates the switching signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; by inverting the compared out signal through the inverter formed of the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In other words, in a power potential range of initial operation, the control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is set on a low level if the external power voltage VEXT is lower than the second reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. At this time, the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is turned on, so that the external power voltage terminal VEXT is connected to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. And then a high voltage of VEXT is provided to the supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> which is connected to source nodes of the PMOS transistors, P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Afterwards, when the external power voltage VEXT is higher than the second reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> after a specific power potential range, the control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; goes to a high level. At this time, the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is turned off, so that the external power voltage terminal VEXT is disconnected from the supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the internal power voltage QVINT. Thus, only the internal power voltage QVINT is applied to the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Here, the switch controller <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> may be utilized as a general power-up circuit serving to initialize the chip. Or, it is possible to use the switch controller apart from the power-up circuit, or to employ it as a circuit having a similar function for another object. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the present invention is operable with the external power voltage when the external power voltage terminal VEXT is in a specific potential range connected to the internal power voltage QVINT supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> through the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, but is driven only with the internal power voltage QVINT when the connection is cut off in the other potential ranges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Since the internal power voltage QVINT is less changeable than the external power voltage VEXT, the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be stably established therein. The stabilized voltage level of the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> generates stable voltage levels for the second reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the internal power voltage QVINT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> show operational characteristics of the internal power voltage generator according to the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows all the features of voltage plots involved in the operation of generating the internal power voltage, including waveforms of the external power voltage VEXT, the internal power voltage QVINT and the conventional power voltage QVint, the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the conventional one Vr<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and the switching control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates close-up plots of the first reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the conventional reference voltage Vr<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates close-up plots of the internal power voltage QVINT of the conventional power voltage QVint. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the switching control signal S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (or S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime;) of the switch controller <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (or <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>) is established at about 2V to control a connection between the external power voltage terminal VEXT and the supply line <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the internal power voltage QVINT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the conventional reference voltage Vr<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> increases in accordance with an increase of the external power voltage VEXT while the present reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is constant in an operation period of forming the reference voltage with the internal power voltage QVINT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the conventional internal power voltage QVint is increased according as the increment of the external power voltage VEXT is increased. However, in the present invention, even though the external power voltage VEXT is increased, the internal power voltage QVINT is constant in the potential period of forming the reference voltage with the internal power voltage QVINT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Consequently, it is possible to generate the stable internal power voltage QVINT by using the constant reference voltage VR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as the reference voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Meanwhile, the present invention can add additional elements for the second reference circuit and the internal power driver, including the drive condition of the reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. The internal power voltage generator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> includes pairs of the second reference circuits and the internal power drivers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>/<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>/<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The second reference circuits <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>generate a pair of the second reference voltages VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and VR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the internal power drivers <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>generate a pair of internal power voltages, QVINT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and QVINT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, respectively. The internal power voltage QVINT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to the first reference circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the external power voltage terminal VEXT through the switch circuit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> As described above, the internal power voltage generator according to the present invention can achieve stable operation of a semiconductor device by generating the stable internal power voltage, resulting in improving the production yield. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been shown and described with reference to a certain preferred embodiment thereof, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes in form and details may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. For use with an integrated circuit having internal circuits, an external power voltage terminal, and an internal power voltage supply line, an internal power voltage generator unit comprising: 
<claim-text>switching control means for connecting the external power voltage terminal to the internal power voltage supply line in an operation power potential range, and for cutting off the connection between the external power voltage terminal and the internal power voltage supply line if the external power voltage reaches a predetermined potential level; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first reference circuit for generating a predetermined first reference voltage by making use of the internal power voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second reference circuit for generating a second reference voltage by amplifying the first reference voltage supplied from the first reference circuit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an internal power driver for generating the internal power voltage with the second reference voltage supplied from the second reference circuit, and for driving the internal circuits with the internal power voltage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The internal power voltage generator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switch control means comprises: 
<claim-text>a switch controller for providing a control signal to selectively connect the external power voltage terminal to the internal power voltage supply line in a specific potential range between a ground voltage and the external power voltage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch for connecting the external power voltage terminal to the internal power voltage supply line in response to a control signal from the switch controller. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The internal power voltage generator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switch controller comprises: 
<claim-text>a resistor element for reducing the voltage level from the external power voltage terminal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a diode element for generating a predetermined reference voltage through the resistor element in accordance with the reduced voltage from the external power voltage terminal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inverter unit for converting the reference voltage generated into the diode element; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a delay unit for delaying the output of the inverter unit and providing the control signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The internal power voltage generating unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switch controller comprises: 
<claim-text>a differential amplifier of a current mirror type for comparing the second reference voltage with the voltage from the external power voltage terminal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of switch elements for enabling an operation of the differential amplifying unit in response to an input of the first reference voltage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inverter unit for converting the output of the differential amplifying unit and providing the control signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The internal power voltage generating unit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switch is formed of a P-channel metal oxide semiconductor transistor that is a switch element for selectively connecting the external power voltage terminal to the supply line of the internal power voltage in response to the control signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001554A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
