<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001017A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001017A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001017A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001017A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001017A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001017A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001017A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001017A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001017A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001017A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001017A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001017A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001017A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001017A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001017A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001017A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001017</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10160041</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020604</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-180645</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010614</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06K007/10</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G06F017/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G06F019/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>235</class>
<subclass>462150</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Bar code reader</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kazuhiko</given-name>
<family-name>Konda</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chuo-ku</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>MEDIA PORTAL JAPAN CO., LTD.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Chuo-ku</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>OLIFF &amp; BERRIDGE, PLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 19928</address-1>
<city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22320</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention makes it possible to use a bar code-URL converting service with a simple operation on a cellular telephone. The bar code reader relating to the present invention comprises: a URL memory portion for storing server URLs in advance; a device type information memory portion for storing device type information relating to the connected cellular telephone; an operation command memory portion for storing operation commands for each type; a command generating portion for generating operation commands corresponding to the device type information on the basis of the contents stored in the operation command memory portion; and a combining portion for combining the output of the URL memory portion and the output of the command generating portion with the output of the bar code reading portion. The cellular telephone receives data comprising the bar code, URL, and command, and automatically shifts to Internet mode. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a bar code reader used for reading bar codes printed on newspapers, magazines, or advertising leaflets and accessing a prescribed server. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A large number of servers is connected to the Internet and provides an assortment of content. Various search engines are provided for selecting and accessing a desired one from among those servers. Apart from that, URLs are printed on newspapers magazines, and advertising leaflets apart from the Internet to appeal for access by users. In order to be actually accessed by users, the content on those servers (web sites) must be interesting and the sites must also-be easy to access. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The use of bar codes is a method for making it easy to access a prescribed URL Specifically, bar codes are printed on paper media such as newspapers, magazines, and advertising leaflets. These are read with a bar code reader connected to a personal computer and converted to URLs, and a browser is automatically started and jumps to the prescribed URLs. This is a simple and sure access method and is expected to become widely disseminated in the future. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A conventional method for accessing a prescribed server based on a bar code (bar code-URL conversion method) is a method wherein a personal computer sends a bar code number received from a bar code reader to a predetermined bar code-URL converting server, receives the converted URL, and accesses the prescribed web server on the basis thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is presently possible to access the Internet using cellular telephones as well as personal computers. In terms of the number of users, it is said that more users use cellular telephones than personal computers. Consequently, it would also be desirable to be able to access prescribed servers based on bar codes with cellular telephones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> However, accessing the Internet with a cellular telephone requires the user to press a number of buttons to display a menu screen for inputting URLs. While this type of operation is relatively easy for users accustomed to it, it is complicated for first-time uses and the operations must be performed with reference to an operations manual. The fact that operating procedures are different for each make of cellular telephone also complicates those operations. While inputting the URL itself can be easily performed with a bar code, the procedures for displaying the URL input screen are complex and annoying and the particular convenience of the bar codes is lost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A method enabling the use of a bar code-URL conversion service with simpler operations for cellular telephones is required. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, it is an object of the present invention to provide a bar code reader which can use a bar code-URL conversion service with simple operations for cellular telephones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The bar code reader relating to the present invention comprises: a bar code reading portion for reading bar codes; a URL memory portion for storing server URLs in advance; a device type information memory portion for storing device type information relating to the connected cellular telephone; an operation command memory portion for storing operation commands for each type; a command generating portion for generating operation commands corresponding to the abovementioned device type information on the basis of the contents stored in the abovementioned operation command memory portion; a combining portion for combining the output of the abovementioned URL memory portion and the output of the abovementioned command generating portion with the output of the abovementioned bar code reading portion; and a communications portion for sending the output of the abovementioned combining portion to the abovementioned cellular telephone.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a functional block diagram of a bar code reader relating to an embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flowchart for initializing the bar code reader relating to the embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flowchart of the procedure for adding commands and a URL to the bar code number in the bar code reader relating to the embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows sample commands; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows other sample commands; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows an example of a system to which this bar code reader is applied; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows an example of the processing procedures in this system.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments of the invention will be explained with reference to the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic of the bar code reader relating to a first embodiment of the invention. A bar code printed on a newspaper, magazine, or advertising leaflet is read with the bar code reading portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. To the bar code read, the URL of the bar code-URL converting server (discussed in detail below) from the URL memory portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is added in the combining portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and then commands corresponding to the type of cellular telephone (or portable terminal) connected to the bar code reader are added in the combining portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The data generated in the bar code reader (including whether to use a URL converting server, the URL of the URL converting server, the bar code number, and operation commands for the cellular telephone) are sent to the cellular telephone through the communications portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Upon receiving this data, the cellular telephone, not shown, automatically displays the URL input screen, receives the URL (including the bar code number) of the URL converting server, and accesses the URL converting server, and also receives the URL converted by the URL converting server, accesses this URL, and automatically displays the web screen. In this way, the desired web screen can be displayed on the screen of the cellular telephone with a single operation of reading a prescribed bar code with the bar code reader. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The commands for displaying the URL input screen vary among different types of cellular telephones. For this reason, functional blocks numbered 12 to 15 are established the type distinguishing portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> distinguishes the type of cellular telephone connected and stores those results in the device type information memory <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The command generating portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> generates commands for each type . on the basis of information in the memory <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The operation commands for each type are stored in advance in the memory <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the memory <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and URL memory portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can receive updated data from outside the system and automatically overwrite their contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> It is also necessary to consider that the URL of the URL converting server will be updated at the convenience of the service provider and that corresponding operation commands will be added if new cellular telephones are released. At such times, it would be very convenient for the user if it were possible to automatically update the contents of the bar code memory <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and advantageous with regard to maintaining bar codes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Those procedures are generally as follows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A cellular telephone sends a table update request to an information server, not shown. The timing for the update request may be, for example, at the initialization of the cellular telephone, when the telephone is powered on, when a prescribed operation is performed, periodically, after every given number of readings, before the second time the process is performed (the first time, a primary converting server is accessed, a secondary converting server is accessed for the second time and later). Moreover, the cellular telephone may also send an update request in response to a request from the bar code reader. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and (<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) show the procedures for distinguishing the type of cellular telephone connected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), the bar code reader in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is connected to a cellular telephone (S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), and then the bar code corresponding to the type of cellular telephone connected is read (S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). A sheet whereon bar codes for each type are printed is attached to the bar code reader. The following items, for example, are printed on this sheet.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="77PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="91PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Type A</entry>
<entry>Bar code A</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Type B</entry>
<entry>Bar code B</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Type C</entry>
<entry>Bar code C</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> If the item connected is Type A, for example, the bar code A is read with the reading portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the data for that bar code A are stored in the memory <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> (S<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). The command generating portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> prepares corresponding commands on the basis of the contents of the memory <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> (s<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). When the data in the memory <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> comprise the bar Code A, the command generating portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> assembles commands stored in the operation command memory <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for type A and generates commands. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) shows the procedures for communicating with the cellular telephone and receiving the type code thereof instead of using a sheet whereon bar codes are printed. The processing other than Step S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is the same as the case discussed above * <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the procedures for generating data for accessing a prescribed UMM with the bar code reader. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>: A bar code printed on a newspaper, magazine, advertising leaflet, or the like is read with the bar code reader. The bar code number included in the bar code is output from the reading portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> For example, the following bar code number is output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> 4976680789305 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>: The command generating portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> generates corresponding commands. Moreover, it is also possible to generate commands in advance, store these in non-volatile memory, and read commands from the non-volatile memory each time the bar code is read. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The commands are as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows an example of commands corresponding to keys on the cellular telephone. The URL input screen can be displayed by adding the commands from S<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to S<highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>. Moreover, selection methods include using the scroll key (S<highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to S<highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>) as well as making a section selection directly with the number keys (S<highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>); either may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows an example of commands for direct input of commands and/or data from outside the system. The data embedded between the data header command S<highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and the data end command S<highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, S<highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> are interpreted either as a command S<highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> or URL data s<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> by the cellular telephone depending on the format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The abovementioned commands are represented as &lsqb;CM&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>: The URL for the URL converting server is added to the bar code. Here, this indicates the server which will convert the bar code. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The data, http://www.mediapj.com/i&equals;php&quest;k&equals;01&amp;s&equals;9&amp;b&equals;, are stored in advance to the URL memory portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In this case, the following data are generated in Step S<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> http://www.mediapj.com/i&equals;php&quest;k&equals;01&amp;s&equals;19&amp;b&equals;4976680789305 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Moreover, http://www.mediapj.com/ is the URL for the URL converting server. i&equals;php&quest;k&equals;01&amp;s&equals;19&amp;b&equals;is an option for requesting that the bar code be converted to a URL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>; The commands generated in step S<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are added. The following type of data is thereby attained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;CM&rsqb; http://www.mediapj.com/i&equals;php&quest;k&equals;01&amp;s&equals;19&amp;b&equals;4976680789305 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The data attained are sent to the cellular telephone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The cellular telephone receives data from the bar code reader, displays the URL input screen on the basis of the above-mentioned &lsqb;CM&rsqb; portion, and inputs the URL included in the data received to that screen, and accesses the URL converting server on the basis of the pertinent URL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows the overall constitution of a system to which this bar code reader is applied. This system has the purpose of reading a bar code and accessing the prescribed site. The bar code readers <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are connected to the cellular telephones <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and can read bar codes printed on media. A bar code printed on media such as a newspaper, magazine, or advertising leaflet is read by any of the bar code readers <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, then the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is accessed, and the URL corresponding to the bar code number is acquired. The client can access the desired server <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> on the basis of the acquired URL. The URLs corresponding to the bar codes printed on the media M are determined in advance and the correlations thereof are stored in advance in the bar code-URL converting table 2. For example, if a bar code showing the site of a company is printed in newspaper advertising, the user can be guided to that company&apos;s site with a simple operation. Moreover, &ldquo;URL&rdquo; is an abbreviation for &ldquo;uniform resource location&rdquo; and describes the locations and titles of resources present throughout the Internet in a uniform format. Specifically, the URL shows the addresses for resources present on a computer network. The cellular telephone <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> accesses a wireless gateway <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> through a protocol converting server <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which is established by the communications carrier, and then accesses the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a process flow chart for portions relating to the cellular telephone. As understood from this drawing, the processing procedures are different in the case where the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> first accesses the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (S<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>), and in the case where the cellular telephone accesses the server for the second and later times (S<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>). This is in order to reduce the load on the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and/or the wireless gateway <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and protocol converting server <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> when a large number of URL conversion requests is generated. In other words, the same type of URL converting servers <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> are provided on the communications carrier side and this causes the load to be distributed. Also, this makes it easy to protect the privacy of the cellular telephone users. By having users access the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> initially, the administrator of the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can manage the users of the bar code-URL converting server. An explanation for <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> follows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> First Time Access </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>: The scanned bar code number is sent to the cellular telephone 5. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>: A request to convert the pertinent bar code number to a URL is sent to the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for cellular telephones. As discussed above, the pertinent request is sent to the server appropriate tot the type of client. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>: The user is requested to register because this is a first time access. The user inputs information such as his or her name, address, telephone number, and email address. Afterwards, the bar code number sent is converted to a URL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>: The converted URL is sent to the cellular telephone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>: Contents are requested from the CHTML site on the basis of the URL received. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>: The CHTML site responds to the client and sends contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Second Time and Later Access </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>: The scanned bar code number is sent to the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>: A request to convert the pertinent bar code number to a URL is sent to the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for cellular telephones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>: The URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> rejects this request when this is a second time or later access, for example, when the user making the request is already registered. At the same time, notification may be made that the request should be submitted to the URL converting server <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the communications carrier. Moreover, Steps S<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are not necessarily required. For example, if it can be determined whether this is a first time access within the cellular telephone that is the client, the server <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the communications carrier may be accessed from the start. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>; The request to convert the pertinent bar code number to a URL is sent to the URL converting server <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the communications carrier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>: The bar code number sent is converted to a URL and the converted URL is sent to the cellular telephone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>: Contents are requested to the CHTML site on the basis of the URL received. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>: The CHTML site responds to the client and sends contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> S<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>: At a prescribed time, notification of access conditions is sent from the URL converting server <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the communications carrier to the URL converting server <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> With the preferred embodiment of the invention, as discussed above, it is possible to use a bar code-URL converting service with a simple operation just by connecting the bar code reader to a cellular telephone. The plurality of button operations, necessary before now, becomes unnecessary and the bar code-URL converting service can be used easily even by people unaccustomed to the operations. Also, no problems develop even when different types of cellular telephones are connected to the bar code reader. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Moreover, in the explanation above, the case of accessing a bar code-URL converting server with a cellular telephone is used as an example, but the present invention is not limited to this. For example, the present invention can also be applied in the case of accessing a prescribed server directly from a URL included in a bar code. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The present invention is not limited to the foregoing embodiment; various changes are possible within the scope of the invention noted in the claims and needless to say, these are also included in the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Also, in this specification, &ldquo;means&rdquo; does not necessarily mean physical means and includes cases where the functions of the means are achieved with software. Furthermore, the functions for one means may be achieved with two or more physical means, or the functions of two or more means may be achieved with a single physical means. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A bar code reader comprising: 
<claim-text>a bar code reading portion for reading bar codes; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a URL memory portion for storing server URLs in advance; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a device type information memory portion for storing device type information relating to the connected cellular telephone; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation command memory portion for storing operation commands for each device type; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a command generating portion for generating operation commands corresponding to said device type information on the basis of the contents stored in said operation command memory portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a combining portion for combining the output of said URL memory portion and, the output of said command generating portion with the output of said bar code reading portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a communications portion for sending the output of said combining portion to said cellular telephone. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The bar code reader according to claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>., wherein said operation command memory portion includes rewritable memory; and 
<claim-text>wherein said communications portion receives data relating to said operation commands and writes this to said memory. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The bar code reader according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said communications portion requests to update data at least at one of the following times or intervals at initialization, periodically, after every given number of readings, and after accessing a specified server. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The bar code reader according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said URL memory portion includes rewritable memory; and 
<claim-text>wherein said communications portion receives data relating to said URL and writes this to said memory. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The bar code reader according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said communications portion requests to update date at least at one of the following times or intervals: at initialization, periodically, after every given number of readings, and after accessing a specified server. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The bar code reader according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the URL for a URL converting server is attained from said UMM memory portion when reading a bar code for the first time, and subsequently the URL for the server of a communications carrier is attained. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The bar code reader according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a device type distinguishing portion for determining said device type information on the basis of a bar code read by said bar code reading portion, wherein said device type information memory portion stores said device type information determined by said device type distinguishing portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The bar code reader according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a device type distinguishing portion for determining said device type information on the basis of data from the cellular telephone attained through said communications portion, wherein said device type information memory portion stores said device type information determined by said device type distinguishing portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001017A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001017A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001017A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001017A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001017A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001017A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001017A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001017A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
