<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004650A1-20030102-M00001.NB SYSTEM "US20030004650A1-20030102-M00001.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030004650A1-20030102-M00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004650A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004650A1-20030102-M00002.NB SYSTEM "US20030004650A1-20030102-M00002.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030004650A1-20030102-M00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004650A1-20030102-M00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004650A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004650A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004650A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004650A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004650A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004650A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004650A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004650A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004650</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09883290</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010619</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F019/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G01N033/48</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G01N033/50</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>702</class>
<subclass>019000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and method for determining biological heat potential</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chow</given-name>
<middle-name>Feng</middle-name>
<family-name>Chiang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yeong</given-name>
<middle-name>Shing</middle-name>
<family-name>Wu</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Mingjian</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ROSENBERG, KLEIN &amp; LEE</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>3458 ELLICOTT CENTER DRIVE-SUITE 101</address-1>
<city>ELLICOTT CITY</city>
<state>MD</state>
<postalcode>21043</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A device and method to determine the biological heat potential consists of an acclimation apparatus for aerobic seed source, a reactor to carry out the desired biological reaction, an external temperature controller to control and heat the ambient air surrounding the reactor at a preset temperature, an oxygen controller to supply and record the oxygen depleted within the reactor with an output of oxygen uptake data, an internal heat controller to control and heat the reactor at a preset temperature with an output of heat compensation data. Based on the oxygen uptake data and heat compensation data, uses a specific biological heat potential evaluator to compute a specific biological heat potential and a heat loss flux. Then uses a heat compensation ratio evaluator to compute a transient heat compensation ratio and a minimal heat compensation ratio during the reaction period for evaluating the spontaneity of an ATAT system. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a device and method for determining biological heat potential, more specifically to the above-mentioned device and method concerning the autothermal thermophilic aerobic treatment (ATAT) system for wastewater and sludge treatment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The key problems encountered in the conventional biological wastewater treatment of high-strength wastewaters include high excess sludge yield, low degradation rate, and the low organic loading. An autothermal thermophilic aerobic wastewater treatment (ATAT) system can be used to solve these problems. The ATAT system is normally operated under the aerobic conditions and at temperatures of 45-65&deg; C., differing from those of mesophilic anaerobic treatment at 35&deg; C. or thermophilic aerobic treatment at 55&deg; C. According to the vant Hoff-Arrhenius&apos; law, reaction rates easily increase at high temperatures. Moreover, according to bioenergetics, the energy capture efficiency of biomass decreases as the temperature increases, thus increasing the biological reaction temperature will increase the energy part for cell maintenance and simultaneously decrease the part for cell synthesis. Thus, the high temperature of an ATAT can reduces the sludge yield and increase the heat released from maintenance energy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The current difficulties or misconception in the design of an ATAT system include: requiring costly supplemental heat if the reaction fails to be spontaneous, and limitation of oxygen transfer rate at high degradation rate as dissolved oxygen (DO) concentration decreases at high temperatures. However, in 1990, the United State Environmental Protection Agency (USEPA) reviewed 35 sets of full-scale operating data of autothermal thermophilic aerobic sludge digestion (ATAD) process in Europe and determined that the ATAD is a promising technology for municipal sludge. In Taiwan, ROC, we demonstrated the successful operation of a full-scale ATAT process treating food-processing oily wastewater. Therefore, the ATAT process of high strength wastewater in full-scale was evidenced. However, it requires a reliable device and method to accurately determine the biological heat potential of the wastewater (or sludge) for the successful design and operation of the ATAT process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> If a conventional chemostat is used to evaluate the heat potential of the ATAT process, the problems encountered are: 1. difficulty to evaluate the reaction spontaneity since the system normally results in a large amount of heat loss via poor insulation and aeration; 2. difficulty to overcome the high oxygen transfer rate required by the high degradation of substrate for the ATAT by using a conventional air diffusion system; 3. inaccuracy and time-consuming in the determination of monitoring parameters, such as chemical oxygen demand (COD), biological oxygen demand (BOD), and oxygen uptake rate (OUR) by conventional laboratory methods, particularly for on-line sensing. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention overcomes the difficulties as described above by providing a device and method for determining the biological heat potential and monitoring of heat flux and biological oxygen depletion, particularly for the application of the ATAT process. The invention is featured to provide a pure oxygen supply system, a high-strength mixing device, a surrounding temperature controlled system to minimize heat loss, and a programmable on-line real-time analyzer for transient oxygen uptake and heat supplemental data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention aims at providing a device to measure an on-line and real-time oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t) and a heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t) for a biological reaction system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention also aims at providing a data analysis method to determine the biological heat potential. The method uses a multiple linear regression algorithm with a heat balance model to determine a specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and a heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) of an ATAT system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The device and method used to determine the specific heat potential, as mentioned above, involves an acclimation apparatus for incubating an aerobic microorganism culture, a reactor inoculated by the culture to carry out the desired biological reactions, an external temperature controller to heat and control the ambient air surrounding the reactor at a preset temperature, an oxygen controller to supply and record the oxygen depleted within the reactor with an on-line and real-time output of oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t), an internal heat controller to control and heat the reactor at a preset temperature with an on-line and real-time output of heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t). Based on the above oxygen uptake data and heat compensation data, the method of this invention uses a specific biological heat potential evaluator to determine the specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>). The method also uses a heat compensation ratio evaluator to determine a transient heat compensation ratio (r) and a minimal heat compensation ratio (r<highlight><subscript>min</subscript></highlight>) during the reaction period for evaluating the spontaneity of an ATAT system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The device mentioned above for determining the biological heat potential mainly consists of six units: a reactor, an oxygen controller, an internal heat controller, an external temperature controller, a mixing controller, and a signal and data controller. The device focuses on the programmable on-line and real-time capability for monitoring a large set of transient oxygen uptake data, heat compensation data, and surrounding temperature data. It also provides a method to use the device as mentioned above to determine the specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) via the heat balance computer algorithm for the ATAT system.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The drawings disclose an illustrative embodiment of the present invention which serves to exemplify the various advantages and objects hereof, and are as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows the block diagram illustrating the main parts and their relations for the device of the present invention for determining the biological heat potential; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the diagram illustrating the acclimation apparatus of the present invention, which provides the necessary aerobic culture for the ATAT test; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the diagram illustrating the device of the present invention, used to determine the biological heat potential for the ATAT test; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the results of the oxygen uptake data fed on the glucose sample, obtained with the device of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows the results of heat compensation data fed on the glucose sample as the substrate (energy source), obtained with the device of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> According to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, it is shown that the present invention provides a device and method for determining the biological heat potential. The device consists of an acclimation apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for incubating an aerobic culture which is used as the source culture to a reactor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for carrying out the desired biological reactions, an external temperature controller <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>can used to control and heat the ambient air surrounding the reactor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> at a preset temperature for reducing the heat loss flux during the biological reaction, an oxygen controller <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to provide and control the oxygen depleted within the reactor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> with an on-line and real-time output of oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t), an internal heat controller <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to control and heat the content of the reactor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> at a preset temperature with an on-line and real-time output of heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t). Based on the above oxygen uptake data and heat compensation data, the method uses a specific biological heat potential evaluator <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to compute the specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and the heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>). The method also uses a heat compensation ratio evaluator <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to compute a transient heat compensation ratio (r), and a minimal heat compensation ratio (r<highlight><subscript>min</subscript></highlight>) for evaluating an ATAT system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Derivation of the Specific Biological Heat Potential Algorithm </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) of this invention is defined as the released heat of a biological reaction per unit of substrate degraded in terms of biological oxygen demand (BOD), in the unit of kcal/g BODr. It is an important parameter for the design and operation of an ATAT system. The parameter can be included into a heat balance mathematical analysis for evaluating the reaction spontaneity and operating temperature of an ATAT system. For a biological reaction system at steady-state (dT/dt&equals;0), with the use of the internal heat controller and the external temperature controller, the heat balance analysis around the system can be established by the reaction term, the heat loss term, and the heat compensation term, as follows:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<math>
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mn>0</mn>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>h</mi>
                    <mi>b</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&it;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>&dd;</mo>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>O</mi>
                        <mi>u</mi>
                      </msub>
                    </mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>&dd;</mo>
                      <mi>t</mi>
                    </mrow>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>reaction</mtext>
                </mstyle>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <msub>
                  <mi>J</mi>
                  <mn>0</mn>
                </msub>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>loss</mtext>
                </mstyle>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
          <mo>+</mo>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>&dd;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>H</mi>
                      <mi>c</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>&dd;</mo>
                    <mi>t</mi>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>compensation</mtext>
                </mstyle>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00001" file="US20030004650A1-20030102-M00001.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00001" wi="216.027" he="31.9221" file="US20030004650A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> where h<highlight><subscript>b </subscript></highlight>being the specific biological heat potential in the unit of kcal/g BODr, O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>being the accumulated oxygen uptake in the unit of g BODr, J<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>being the heat loss flux in the unit of kcal/min, and H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>being the accumulated heat compensation data in the unit of kcal. Using an initial condition: at t&equals;0, O<highlight><subscript>u&equals;</subscript></highlight>0 and H<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>&equals;0, Equation (1) can be integrated into </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>H</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&equals;J</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>t&minus;h</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>O</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>u</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(2)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Using the device of the present invention, the on-line real-time oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t) and the heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t) can be measured. These data can be incorporated into Equation (2) and analyzed by a multiple linear regression method based on the least-squared method for determining the specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and the heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>). During the period of reaction, a heat compensation ratio (r) can be defined as follows:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>r&equals;H</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>/J</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>t</italic></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(3)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The magnitude of the r ratio is an indication of reaction spontaneity for the ATAT system. The smaller the r, the larger the extent of reaction spontaneity can be evidenced with the lab-scale ATAT system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Acclimation Apparatus </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides an acclimation apparatus for incubating an aerobic culture, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. It consists of a 11 liter acclimation reactor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with a liquid volume of 10 liter, an air pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a diffuser <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to maintain the dissolved oxygen (DO) concentration at 1 to 2 mg/L, a temperature probe <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and a heater <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, incorporated with a proportional integrated derivative (PID) temperature controller <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to maintain the acclimation reactor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at 55&deg; C. with a precision of 0.1&deg; C., a heavy-duty magnate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> driven by a magnetic stirrer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to maintain a homogeneous content within the acclimation reactor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>a reflux condenser <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> connected to the top the acclimation reactor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to prevent the loss of liquid solution via vaporization, a 4 liter substrate vessel <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and a 4 liter nutrient vessel <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to avoid the undesired substrate spoiling, and a peristaltic pump <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to feed the acclimation reactor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>operated at a preset flow rate and sludge retention time (SRT) for a treatment efficiency. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Acclimation Operation </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Firstly, a 10 liter sludge is transferred from the aeration tank of a full-scale ATAT plant to the reactor of the acclimation apparatus. The reactor is fed on a glucose sample at a loading of 10 g/L COD and an SRT of 10 days. Effluent samples are periodically taken from the reactor for the analyses of COD, pH, and MLSS. Other performance characteristics are also observed for sludge settlability, culture color, forming, and microscope examination to determine the acclimation status. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The present invention allows for maintaining the normal acclimation operation to provide a stable source of seed culture required for the ATAT tests. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> ATAT Test </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The ATAT test, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, consists of a reactor, an oxygen controller, an internal heat controller, an external temperature controller, a mixing controller, and a signal and data controller capable of the on-line and real-time data acquisition of an oxygen uptake data and a heat compensation data. It can be used for an ATAT system and other biological reaction studies to obtain the specific biological heat potential based on the heat balance analysis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the oxygen controller provides pure oxygen to maintain the oxygen content of the headspace of the reactor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at a preset value. The oxygen supply is regulated by a computer program with an on/off control mechanism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The oxygen source <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> will be turned on if oxygen level determined by the oxygen probe <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is below the preset value and is turned off if above the preset value. Providing the oxygen is supplied at a constant rate, the on-time as recorded by the on-line and real-time computer program can be used to calculate the accumulated oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t). The carbon dioxide (CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) stripper <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is used to absorb the released CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>resulting from the aerobic reaction by strong basic solution, such as potassium hydroxide (KOH). The internal heat controller uses an on/off control system, referring to the internal temperature probe <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> and the internal heater <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to allow for operation of the reactor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at a constant temperature. Providing the heating power of the internal heater <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is kept at constant, the on-line and real-time computer program can record the on-time of the internal heater <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to calculate the heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t). The magnate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is driven by the magnetic stirrer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for high-strength mixing within the reactor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at a controllable speed to avoid spin-off. The signal and data controller, comprising a signal interface assembly <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and a signal and data processor <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, consists of an on-line and real-time computer program, which can be used to monitor, control, and exhibit dynamic plots of the mixing speed, the reactor and surrounding air temperatures, the oxygen uptake data, and the heat compensation data. The external temperature controller uses the temperature probe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> connected to the external heater <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to maintain at an appropriate constant surrounding temperature to reduce heat loss from the reactor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The ambient air surrounding the reactor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is circulated with a fan to maintain a homogeneous ambient temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> When operating the ATAT test, the seed culture is first transferred into the reactor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and then operated in a semi-continuous mode. The substrate (such as glucose) sample is daily fed after daily wasting of the excess sludge from the reactor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to control the ATAT test at a preset SRT. After reaching a steady state, a repeatable pattern of oxygen uptake data can be observed and the ATAT test is completed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Results and Discussion </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> show the O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>and H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>curves. It can be found that the O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>curve varied from day to day, and the H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>curve was more repeatable during one day of testing period. The O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>data and H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>data were analyzed with Equation (3) with a multiple linear regressed method to estimate the specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and the heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) for comparison. The regression results indicate that the h<highlight><subscript>b </subscript></highlight>normally ranges from 3.28-4.53 kcal/g BODr, with exception from the 3<highlight><superscript>rd </superscript></highlight>to 6<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>days. The R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>values of 0.92-0.95 for all the 8 testing days indicate good linearity, even for 3<highlight><superscript>rd </superscript></highlight>to 6<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>days. The reason for the wide variation of h<highlight><subscript>b </subscript></highlight>from the 3<highlight><superscript>rd </superscript></highlight>to 6<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>days remains to be further investigated. It was speculated that it might be due to the dynamic nature of the thermophilic microbial system associated with incomplete acclimation under the testing conditions. It was not likely due to the mechanical problems of the ATAT system since h<highlight><subscript>b </subscript></highlight>was automatically brought back to the base line values of the 1<highlight><superscript>st </superscript></highlight>to 3<highlight><superscript>rd </superscript></highlight>days at the 7<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>and 8<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>days. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The regression result also indicates that the heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) varies in a fairly narrow range of 0.43-0.55 kcal/min. The heat loss flux reduces about 10% when the system experienced lower biological heat on the 5<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>to 6<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>days. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Using the average h<highlight><subscript>b </subscript></highlight>value (4.28 kcal/g BODr) and the average heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) value (0.50 kcal/min), the heat compensation ratio can be determined to be with a minimum of 89.2% at 12 hours during the 24 hours of testing period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a device for determining the biological heat potential by measuring the on-line real-time oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t) and heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t) from an ATAT test. The present invention also provides a data processing method to calculate the biological heat potential. The method uses a multiple linear regression algorithm to solve a governing function based on a heat balance model to determine the specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and the heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) of the ATAT test. The results show that the present invention is a useful tool for an ATAT study. As the system is fed on 10-g COD/L glucose sample at an SRT of 10 days, the h<highlight><subscript>b </subscript></highlight>is determined to be 4.28 kcal/g BODr. Moreover, the heat loss flux (J<highlight><italic>o</italic></highlight>) of the ATAT system is determined to be 0.50 kcal/min and the minimal heat compensation ratio (r<highlight><subscript>min</subscript></highlight>) is 89.2%. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Many changes and modifications in the above described embodiment of the invention can, of course, be carried out without departing from the scope thereof. Accordingly, to promote the progress in science and the useful arts, the invention is disclosed and is intended to be limited only by the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for determining biological heat potential of biological reaction systems, particularly the ATAT system, which comprising the following steps: 
<claim-text>using an acclimation apparatus to incubate an aerobic culture and transferring the culture into a reactor for the biological reaction test; </claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling, heating, and recording an ambient air surrounding the reactor at a first preset temperature; </claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling and supplying a pure oxygen to maintain the oxygen level at a preset value in a headspace of the reactor, and recording an on-line and real-time oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t); </claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling and heating a content of the reactor at a second preset temperature, and recording an on-line and real-time heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t); </claim-text>
<claim-text>using the oxygen uptake data and the heat compensation data to compute a specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and a heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>); and </claim-text>
<claim-text>using the calculated specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and the heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) to compute a transient heat compensation ratio (r) and a minimal heat compensation ratio (r<highlight><subscript>min</subscript></highlight>) during a reaction period. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the on-line and real-time oxygen uptake data is obtained with an oxygen controller, which comprising means for controlling and providing the oxygen depleted in the reactor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the on-line and real-time heat compensation data is obtained with a heat compensation controller, which comprising means for controlling and heating the content of the reactor at the second preset temperature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the on-line and real-time oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t) and the heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t) are analyzed by a heat balance equation, considering a reaction term, a heat loss term, and a heat compensation term: </claim-text>
<claim-text> 
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<math>
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mn>0</mn>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mrow>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>h</mi>
                    <mi>b</mi>
                  </msub>
                  <mo>&it;</mo>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>&dd;</mo>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>O</mi>
                        <mi>u</mi>
                      </msub>
                    </mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mo>&dd;</mo>
                      <mi>t</mi>
                    </mrow>
                  </mfrac>
                </mrow>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>reaction</mtext>
                </mstyle>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <msub>
                  <mi>J</mi>
                  <mn>0</mn>
                </msub>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>loss</mtext>
                </mstyle>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
          <mo>+</mo>
          <mtable>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mfrac>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>&dd;</mo>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>H</mi>
                      <mi>c</mi>
                    </msub>
                  </mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>&dd;</mo>
                    <mi>t</mi>
                  </mrow>
                </mfrac>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
            <mtr>
              <mtd>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>compensation</mtext>
                </mstyle>
              </mtd>
            </mtr>
          </mtable>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00002" file="US20030004650A1-20030102-M00002.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00002" wi="216.027" he="31.9221" file="US20030004650A1-20030102-M00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
<claim-text>where h<highlight><subscript>b </subscript></highlight>being the specific biological heat potential in the unit of kcal/g BODr, O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>being the accumulated oxygen uptake data in the unit of g, J<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>being the heat loss flux in the unit of kcal/min, and H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>being the accumulated compensated heat in the unit of kcal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>integrating equation (1) with the initial conditions of t&equals;0, O<highlight><subscript>u</subscript></highlight>&equals;0, and H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>&equals;0 to obtain</claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>H</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&equals;J</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>t&minus;h</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>O</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>u</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(2).</in-line-formula></claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and the heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) are used to calculate a heat compensation ratio (r):</claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>r&equals;H</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>/J</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>t</italic></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(3).</in-line-formula></claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential comprising: 
<claim-text>an acclimation apparatus to incubate an aerobic seed culture; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reactor receiving the seed culture from the acclimation apparatus to carry out a biological reaction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an external temperature controller to control and heat an ambient air surrounding the reactor at a first preset temperature; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an oxygen controller to provide and record an oxygen depleted within the reactor with an on-line and real-time output of oxygen uptake data (O<highlight><subscript>u </subscript></highlight>vs. t); </claim-text>
<claim-text>an internal heat controller to control and heat the reactor at a second preset temperature with an on-line and real-time output of heat compensation data (H<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>vs. t); </claim-text>
<claim-text>a specific biological heat potential evaluator using the on-line and real-time data of oxygen uptake and heat compensation to determine a specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and a heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>); </claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat compensation ratio evaluator using the specific biological heat potential (h<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>) and the heat loss flux (J<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) to determine a heat compensation ratio (r) and a minimal heat compensation ratio (r<highlight><subscript>min</subscript></highlight>) during a reaction period. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the acclimation apparatus comprises an air pump for aeration via a fine-bubble diffuser on a bottom portion the reactor, a temperature probe connected to a heater and a proportional integrated derivative (PID) temperature controller to maintain the reactor at a constant temperature, a heavy-duty magnate on the bottom portion of the reactor driven by a magnetic stirrer for homogenous mixing, and two glass bottles for storing a substrate solution and a nutrient solution being fed simultaneously by a peristaltic pump at a preset flow rate to maintain at a preset sludge retention time (SRT) and substrate concentration (S) for the reactor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a reflux condenser is connected to a top portion of the acclimation reactor to prevent a loss of liquid solution via evaporation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein comprising means for evaluating the spontaneity of an autothermal thermophilic aerobic treatment system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential comprising a reactor, an oxygen controller, an internal heat controller, an external temperature controller, a mixing controller, and a signal and data controller with the following characteristics: 
<claim-text>comprising means for programmable on-line and real-time monitor and control of a transient oxygen uptake data and a heat compensation data, and using a heat balance analysis to process a specific biological heat potential algorithm for biological reaction thermodynamics and autothermal thermophilic aerobic treatment feasibility study. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxygen controller, according to the estimate by an oxygen probe, uses a computer program with an on/off control mechanism connecting to an oxygen source to provide a preset flowrate of oxygen per on-time, which can be recorded and calculated to be the oxygen uptake data, and a carbon dioxide formed during oxidation is absorbed by a strong basic solution within a CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>stripper. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the heat compensation temperature controller, according to the estimate of a temperature probe, uses a computer program with an on/off control mechanism connecting a heater with a fixed power to maintain the temperature of the reactor at a preset temperature, which can be recorded and calculated to be the heat compensation data. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the mixing controller comprises a magnate on a bottom portion of the reactor driven by a magnetic stirrer for high-strength mixing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the signal and data controller comprises a signal and data processor and a signal interface assembly and an on-line and real-time computer program, which contains means for monitoring, controlling, and showing dynamic plots of a mixing speed of the magnetic stirrer, an internal and external temperatures of the reactor, the oxygen uptake data, and the heat compensation data. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A device for determining biological heat potential as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the external temperature controller comprising an external temperature probe on an external portion of the reactor and an external heater can be incorporated to a computer program for maintaining the external portion of the reactor at a high temperature for reducing the heat loss.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004650A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004650A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004650A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004650A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
