<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005379A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005379A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005379A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005379A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005379A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005379A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005379A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005379A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005379A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005379A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005379A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005379A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005379</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895589</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01R031/28</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>714</class>
<subclass>726000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Comparison circuit and method for verification of scan data</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Darren</given-name>
<family-name>Slawecki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stephan</given-name>
<family-name>Rotter</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Kenneth B. Paley</name-1>
<name-2>BLAKELY, SOKOLOFF, TAYLOR &amp; ZAFMAN LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Seventh Floor</address-1>
<address-2>12400 Wilshire Boulevard</address-2>
<city>Los Angeles</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90025-1026</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An apparatus and a method are disclosed to save on the integrated circuit die(s) the state of the scan latches coupled to an integrated circuit in a memory unit during an exercise of the integrated circuit by a coupled tester, to compare on the die the saved states to the state of the scan latches in a subsequent exercise of the integrated circuit, and to transmit the result of the comparison to the tester, rather to have to transmit to the tester the scan latch states for a comparison analysis after each exercise of the integrated circuit. The apparatus and method include deriving on the die a signature of the saved scan latch states, and comparing on the die the signature of an exercise of the integrated circuit and subsequently exercise of the integrated circuit. The invention also includes generating on the die a scan latch latching clock for consecutively exercising the integrated circuit without determining off the die, and sending to the die, for each iteration, the latching clock. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This disclosure relates generally to integrated circuit testing, and particularly but not exclusively relates to a built-in test circuit for comparing a passing scan and a failing scan, and for selecting the clock pulse at which to latch a scan chain. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> An integrated circuit is functionally tested to ascertain the performance of the circuit at specified conditions, and to isolate any faults in the circuit at the specified conditions. The specified conditions may include core clock pulse frequency, signal level voltage, and ambient temperature. A test system for the functional test generally includes the circuit-under-test coupled to a tester that is itself coupled to a computing device workstation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In operation, the tester generates an at least one test-data sequence of pulses, and an at least one clock signal sequence of pulses, that are each sent to at least one port of the circuit-under-test die(s). Generally, the clock signal generated by the tester is at a lower frequency than the functional speed of the circuit-under-test, so the circuit-under-test die(s) includes a coupled frequency boosting circuit to receive the tester generated clock signal, raise the frequency of the pulses of the tester generated clock signal, and output a higher frequency clock signal to the circuit-under-test as the core clock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In operation, the circuit-under-test generates at least one functional output pulse in response to receiving the test data input and the core clock, that is sent to at least one port of the circuit-under-test die and received by the tester. The circuit-under-test die(s) generally also includes an at least one scan latch test circuit coupled to the circuit-under-test to save at least one signal state of the circuit-under-test that is not normally observable in a functional output pulse. At a specified time, in response to a scan clock signal, the scan latches collectively generate a pulse train, each pulse of the pulse train representing a signal state saved in a scan latch, to an at least one port of the circuit-under-test die(s), and received by the tester. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, the tester sends to the workstation the data received from the circuit-under-test. The workstation executes programs to analyze the data received from the tester, and to determine if the expected functional outputs from the circuit-under-test conform with expected values for each tester clock pulse of interest, and if the scan latch pulse train (or its signature) output conforms to the expected values, for each core clock pulse of interest. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, conventionally the workstation defines and sends to the tester an identification of each clock at which to latch the scan latches, for each new test of the integrated circuit-under-test, in a header preceding the clock signal or the data input to the integrated circuit die. Each new test, even if the clock signal and the data remains the same, the header must be sent to the circuit-under-test only because a new scan latch clock must be transmitted to the circuit test die for initialization of built in test circuitry on the die(s). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> What is needed is an apparatus and a method to compare the result of a test input with a passing or failing test exemplar result on the die and not to transmit for each iteration of the test the test data to the tester-workstation combination and analyze for each iteration of the test the data on the tester-workstation combination. What is needed is an apparatus and a method to change the scan latch timing of the clock signal automatically on the integrated circuit die(s) and not to generate the clock signal for each iteration of the test from the tester-workstation combination, and not to transmit for each iteration of the test the clock signal for each iteration.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Non-limiting and non-exhaustive embodiments of the present invention are described with reference to the following figures, wherein like reference numerals refer to like parts throughout the various views unless otherwise specified. The order of description should not be construed as to imply that these operations are necessarily order dependent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> portrays an embodiment of a functional block diagram of a test system to test an integrated circuit that includes a die having the circuit-under-test and a built-in-test circuitry, a tester; and a workstation computing device for deriving, storing, and analyzing latched circuit states. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> portrays an embodiment of a functional block diagram of a test system to test an integrated circuit that includes a die having the circuit-under-test and a built-in-test circuitry, a tester; and a workstation computing device for deriving, storing, and analyzing a signature of latched circuit states. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> portrays an embodiment of a scan latch pulse selection circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> portrays an embodiment of a pulse determination circuit of a scan latch pulse selection circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart of an embodiment of a method to compare on a die a scan latch unload or a signature of the unload with respectively a previous unload and a previous signature. The order of description should not be construed as to imply that these operations are necessarily order dependent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flow chart of an embodiment of a method to automatically change the time to clock the scan latches coupled to a circuit under test for latching the state of the circuit under test. The order of description should not be construed as to imply that these operations are necessarily order dependent.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of an apparatus and method for comparing the internal states of an integrated circuit under test, and automatically generating a scan latch clock for scan latches (or other storage elements) coupled to the integrated circuit under test, by on-die test circuitry are described herein. In the following description, numerous specific details are provided thoroughly understanding the embodiments of the present invention. One skilled in the relevant art will recognize, however, that the invention can be practiced without one or more of the specific details, or with other steps, methods, systems, components, materials, etc. In other instances, well-known structures, materials, system components, or steps of methods are not shown, or if shown are not described in detail, to avoid obscuring aspects of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Reference throughout this specification to &ldquo;one embodiment&rdquo; or &ldquo;an embodiment&rdquo; means that a particular feature, structure, step, or characteristic described in connection with the embodiment is included in at least one embodiment of the present invention. Thus, the appearances of the phrases &ldquo;in one embodiment&rdquo; or &ldquo;in an embodiment&rdquo; in various places throughout this specification are not necessarily all referring to the same embodiment. Furthermore, the particular features, structures, steps, or characteristics may be combined in any suitable manner in one or more embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Various operations will be described as multiple discrete steps performed in turn in a manner that is most helpful in understanding the present invention. However, the order of description should not be construed as to imply that these operations are necessarily order dependent, in particular, the order the steps are presented. Any necessary ordering is alternatively expressly mentioned or will be understood by those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> As used herein, a scan latch comprises a clocked memory element such as a latch to hold the binary output data from a coupled portion of a circuit under test. And as used herein, a circuit comprises an interconnection of electrical elements to form an at least one path for the flow of electrical current. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an integrated circuit on at least one die and coupled terminals <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> includes a circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and support and built-in test circuitry to be presently described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A terminal (or port) <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> is coupled to a tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> to conventionally receive clock signal sequence of pulses from the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. The clock signal from the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> is transmitted along a signal path <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to a coupled Phase Locked Loop (PLL) circuit <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>, or other circuit well know to those skilled in the art to at least raise the frequency of the clock signal from the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> to a preferred clock frequency, and/or assure a synchronized even duty cycle clock. The output of the PLL circuit <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> is a stable clock signal sequence of pulses at the preferred frequency for the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, that passes through the coupled signal path <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, to the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, as the core clock signal for the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Testing occurs at two different conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> A data input from the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> includes a header of information that is transmitted to the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The header information includes data to indicate the clock at which the built-in-test circuit is to latch (or capture) the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>. The header may be in the tester clock signal sequence of pulses input to the die(s) <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> on the terminal <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> as described above, and in at least one of the data inputs described below with reference to the terminals <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. It is within the specific contemplation of the present invention that the header information may be transmitted to the die <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> with another signal or by a different port than is described herein, as is well known to those skilled in the art. The header includes data to indicate the core time of a pulse at which the built-in-test circuit is to latch (or capture) the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>. The header information is transmitted illustratively along the signal path <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to a scan control circuit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. However, in the embodiment presented herein, a trigger signal is conventionally transmitted as well from the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>, to the die at a coupled illustrative terminal (or port) <highlight><bold>179</bold></highlight> to provide a tester clock reference for the core clock identified in the header. It is within the specific contemplation of the present invention that the trigger may be transmitted in another signal or along a different terminal as described herein as is well known to those skilled in the art. In an alternate embodiment, the trigger is specified or generated internally by an event or a sequence of events or state(s) inside the integrated circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In operation, the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> transmits to the terminal <highlight><bold>179</bold></highlight> the trigger signal, and the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> latches the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>by providing a scan clock pulse signal to each scan latch <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>along the circuit path <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight>. The scan clock pulse signal is provided to each scan latch <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>at the time of the clock pulse identified in the header after the trigger signal. The circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is coupled to built-in test circuitry that includes an at least one scan chain <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, each scan chain having coupled individual scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>or other memory elements that are each coupled (not shown) to a separate portion of the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, as is well known to those skilled in the art. Each scan latch <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>is to save a signal state of a coupled portion of the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in response to a latch command from the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> through the path <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight>, discussed with reference to the trigger signal above. Here, the latch command through the path <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> refers to multiple control signals to all the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>because typically both clocks and commands are sent to each scan latch <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>to control its operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The dies <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> includes a memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>. Under the control of the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, the scan chains <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> unload the state of the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>to the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>, and the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> stores the state of each transferred scan latch <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>as a corresponding high or low valued bit. The content of each bit of the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> is unloaded to the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> in synchronization with the unload of the scan chains <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> to the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> as described presently. It is within the specific contemplation of the present invention that the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> is distributed on the die(s), such as distributed to each of the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>where each scan latch <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>is capable if storing the first condition, as well as the second condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Under the control of the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, the scan chains <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> unload the state of each scan latch <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>to the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, in synchronization with the unload of the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> to the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, such that each bit of the scan latch state stored by the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> is compared to a state of the same scan latch unloaded to the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The output of the comparison circuit is a string of pulses, each pulse representing the result of the comparison of the state of a scan latch stored in the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> with the state of the same scan latch unloaded from the scan chain <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> to the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> performs an exclusive-or operation, or some other operation that will result in a single bit whose value indicates whether or not the two compared bits are of the same value or are not of the same value, such that the output of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is a string of pulses each representing an exclusive-or operation such that the low-valued pulses mean that the compared scan latch values are the same, and the high-valued pulses mean that the compared scan latch values are not the same. Therefore, a high-valued pulse in the output of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> means that the stored and the directly unloaded scan latch states do not correspond. In an alternate embodiment, the low-valued pulses mean that the compared scan latch values are not the same and high-valued pulses mean the compared scan latch values are the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In operation of the present invention, the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> exercises the circuit-under-test under a condition to operate properly and generate a &ldquo;passing result&rdquo; set of scan latch <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>states. Such a condition may be a core clock signal frequency adequately slow to result in a proper operation of the circuit-under-test. The passing result scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>are unloaded to the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> so that the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> thus stores a scan latch state passing result. Subsequently, the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is operated at a second condition that may (or may not) result in an improper operation, such as illustratively a core pulse signal higher frequency or an at least one pulse of the core clock signal having a higher frequency. The scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>containing the second condition results are unloaded to the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> in synchronization with the stored content in the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> for a comparison with the second condition result with the stored passing result in the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>. Alternatively in another usage model, the memory unit <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> may store a suspected failing test that is then compared to a known passing result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The output of the comparison circuit is passed to a terminal (or port) <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> that is conventionally implemented as a connection pin, and transmitted to the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> coupled to the terminal <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>, so that the tester has only to scan the output of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> for the presence of at least one high value bit to indicate a failing result (for the embodiment of an exclusive-or operation comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>), without the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> output, the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> would otherwise have to download from the integrated circuit die(s) <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> a passing result from the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>, transmit the passing result to a workstation <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight>, download a suspected failing result from the integrated circuit die(s) <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, transmit the suspected passing result to the workstation <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight>, the workstation <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> would have to perform a comparison of the passing result and suspected failing result to check for any mismatching bits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the built-in test circuit includes a circuit <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> referred to herein as a strobe circuit, to scan the pulse train that is output from the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and, in the example of an exclusive-or operation comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, upon identifying a high value pulse in the example of an exclusive-or comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, change all subsequent pulse values to high value pulses. The strobe circuit <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> is coupled to receive the output of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (rather than to be sent to the port <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>), and to transmit an output to the port <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. The output of the strobe circuit <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> in the case of the illustrative comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> exclusive-or operation embodiment is low value pulses until the first (if any) failing comparison, and thereafter high value pulses for the remainder of a comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> output. Therefore, the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> receiving the output of the strobe circuit <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> rather than the output of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, need only test on the last bit of the pulse train output on the terminal <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> for the presence of a high valued pulse to detect a failing result, rather than scan and test each pulse of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> output signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the built-in-test circuit includes a scan latch pulse selection circuit <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> to automatically change the timing of the scan clock latching signal relative to the core clock signal for each of a plurality of sequential tests from an initial core clock pulse defined by the workstation-tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> combination. It is specifically within the contemplation of the present invention that the initial core clock pulse location in an embodiment is also determined by selection circuitry within the die(s). Automatically herein means that the selection (or determination) of the scan latch pulse is selected (or determined) within the die and does not require a transmission from outside the die(s), such as from the workstation-tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> combination. The initial core clock pulse location has been illustratively described above as being determined by both a trigger signal and a core clock data in a header from the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. The scan latch pulse selection circuit <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> eliminates the need to derive and to transmit an identity of the scan clock pulse signal from the tester-workstation <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> combination in a header block for each time a test is executed after the initial header transmission. The scan latch pulse selection circuit <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> algorithmically selects the scan clock pulse for each test. In the preferred embodiment, the scan latch pulse selection circuit <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> auto-increments the initial scan clock pulse as will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. In an embodiment described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference> below, the header also includes a target pulse or number of generated pulses, as well as an initial pulse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is coupled to an illustrative two data input terminals (or ports) <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> to couple to the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. The tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> is to provide to the terminals <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> illustratively two input test data sequence of pulses that are transmitted respectively along the paths <highlight><bold>167</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> to the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> as input data signals to the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is further coupled to an illustrative two data output terminals (or ports) <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> to couple to the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> to provide illustratively two output pulse signals to the tester that are transmitted respectively along the path <highlight><bold>177</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, an integrated circuit die and coupled terminals <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> embodiment includes the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the PLL circuit <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>, the scan latch pulse selection circuit <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, the scan chain(s) <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, and the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The die <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> includes a signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to which the scan chains <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> unload the state of the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>in response to a signal from the scan-signature control circuit <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> algorithmically transforms the state of scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>received by the circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to a statistic of the state of the scan latches as is well known to those skilled in the art. The signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> transfers the signature of the state of the scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>to a memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>, and the signature memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> stores the transferred signature. Under the control of the scan-signature control circuit <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, the content of each bit of the signature stored in the memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> is unloaded to the signature comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> in synchronization with the unload of the signature generation circuit to the signature comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> as described presently. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Under the control of the scan-signature control circuit <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, the signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> unloads a signature to the signature comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, and the signature stored in signature memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> is compared to the signature unloaded directly from the signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to detect whether the two signatures are identical. Preferably, that each bit of the signature stored by the signature memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> is compared to a respective bit of the signature unloaded directly from the signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The output of the signature comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is a string of pulses representing the result of the comparison of the signature stored in the memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> and the signature of a scan latch state from the signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the signature comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> performs an exclusive-or operation, some other operation that will result in a single bit whose value indicates whether or not the two compared bits are of the same value or are not of the same value. For the exclusive-or operation, the output of the signature comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is a string of pulses each representing an exclusive-or operation such that the low-valued pulses mean that the compared bits of the signatures are the same, and the high-valued pulses mean that the compared bits of the signatures are not the same. Therefore, a high valued pulse in the output of the signature comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> means that the stored and the directly unloaded signatures do not correspond. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In operation of the present invention, the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> exercises the circuit-under-test under a condition to operate properly and generate a &ldquo;passing result signature&rdquo; that is unloaded to the signature memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. Such a condition may be a core clock signal frequency adequately slow to result in a proper operation. Subsequently, the circuit-under-test <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is operated at a second condition that may (or may not) result in an improper operation, such as illustratively a core pulse signal higher frequency or an at least one pulse of the core clock signal having a higher frequency. The scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>containing the second condition results are unloaded to the signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to produce a signature of the scan latch states, and the signature generation circuit <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is unloaded to the signature comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> in synchronization with the stored signature in the memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> for a comparison of the second condition result with the stored passing result in the memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. Alternatively in another usage model, the memory unit <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> may store a suspected failing test that is then compared to a known passing result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The built-in-test circuitry of the die <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> preferably includes a strobe circuit <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> to scan the pulse train that is output from the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> and, upon identifying a high value pulse in the example of an exclusive-or comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, change all subsequent pulse values to high value pulses. The strobe circuit <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> is coupled to receive the output of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> (rather than to be sent to the port <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>), and to transmit an output to the port <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. The output of the strobe circuit <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> in the case of the illustrative comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> exclusive-or operation embodiment is low value pulses until the first (if any) failing comparison, and thereafter high value pulses for the remainder of a comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> output. Therefore, the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> receiving the output of the strobe circuit <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> rather than the output of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, need only test on the last bit of the pulse train output on the terminal <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> for the presence of a high valued pulse to detect a failing result, rather than scan and test each pulse of the comparison circuit <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> output signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The conversion of the scan latch state to a signature is preferred because the signature will be represented by fewer bits than the number of scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>, for a signal generation circuit performing a compression algorithm and thus will reduce the amount of built-in-test circuitry on the die <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> to store the scan latch states, and the transmission time to transmit the result of the comparison to the tester/workstation <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> scan latch pulse selection circuit <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> intercepts the external trigger and delays the trigger to the built-in-test circuitry scan control circuit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The scan latch pulse selection circuit <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> includes a scan control circuit <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> to receive signals from outside the scan latch pulse selection circuit <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and to transmit signals to a scan latch clock determination circuit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> portrayed herein and in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In an embodiment the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> receives an external trigger data indicating a selected initial clock for latching the scan latches, and header data from the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> that includes both the initial scan latch clock displacement from the trigger and the target scan latch clock for the last scan latch clock to scan latches <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>. The scan control circuit <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> in response transmits an initial latch clock setting and a target latch clock setting to the pulse determination circuit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. The scan control circuit <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> receives an internal trigger from the scan latch clock determination circuit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>; and in response transmits a delayed scan latch clock indication signal to the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> preferred embodiment of a pulse determination circuit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is implemented as an auto-increment circuit in order to increase the determined scan latch pulse by a value of <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> each test iteration. The pulse determination circuit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> includes a target count register <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> to receive upon reset the initial clock setting signal from the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). The pulse determination circuit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> includes an adder circuit <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> preferably implemented as a down-counter, coupled to the current counter register <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> to decrement the current count register <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> by 1 after each core clock after the trigger signal. The pulse determination circuit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> includes a target count register <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> to receive the target setting from the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). The pulse determination circuit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> includes an adder circuit <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> preferably implemented as an up-counter, coupled to the target count register <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> to increment the target count register <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> by 1 after each scan latch load to realize an incrementing of the scan count by 1. The comparator circuit <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> is coupled to the current count register <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> to compare the content of the current count register <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> to zero, and signal a match when the current count has attained a zero value, and otherwise to issue the internal trigger to the scan control circuit <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). The target count register <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> additionally includes an optional output to the scan latches <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> to output to the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> through the scan latches <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> to enable observability by the tester/workstation of the scan latch clock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> It will be clear to those skilled in the art that a different circuit of the pulse determination circuit can be implemented to realize this algorithm or a different algorithm, such as an algorithm for decrementing down or incrementing up by any number of clocks, and that the present invention is not limited to the algorithm described herein. It will also be clear to those skilled in the art that a target condition is a quantifiable condition that in embodiments includes a specific clock identifier, a number of iterations, and the like. The present invention also specifically includes generating the initial clock from a default condition and/or generating a target condition from a default condition, in which a coupled external circuit such as the tester <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> does not supply an initial clock and/or a target condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> method includes in block <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> an integrated circuit that is disposed on at least one die is coupled to at least one storage element in a capture circuit, such with at least one scan latch with at least one scan chain, and the integrated circuit is to be functionally exercised. In an embodiment, the integrated circuit is to be functionally exercised by receiving functional data inputs at a port of the die, and by receiving a clocking signal from a port of the die, from a coupled tester. It is expected that the clocking signal will be converted into a higher frequency pulse signal and/or be cleaned and synchronized as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In block <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, the storage elements are to capture at a determined clock at least a first state of the integrated circuit in the storage elements during the functional exercising of the integrated circuit described with reference to block <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. Each storage element, such as a scan latch, is to capture a signal state of a coupled portion of the circuit, as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In blocks <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight>, a method is described of comparing on the die a signature of the captured integrated circuit states after the capturing described with reference to block <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. In blocks <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight>, a method is described of comparing on the die the captured integrated circuit states after the capturing described with reference to block <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Now, in block <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> for a method of comparing on the die a signature of the captured circuit states, the captured first states are to be transformed into a digital signature of the first states. In block <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> the digital signature derived in block <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> is to be stored in a storage unit. In block <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>, the integrated circuit is to be functionally exercised again, and in block <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> the storage elements are to once again capture at a determined clock at least a second state of the integrated circuit during the functional exercising of the integrated circuit described in block <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In block <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> the captured second state of the integrated circuit is to be transformed into a digital signature. The term &ldquo;second&rdquo; state is used herein to distinguish the captured data from the &ldquo;first&rdquo; state captured with reference to block <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. The data captured in the &ldquo;second&rdquo; state is for the same circuit portions as captured with reference to block <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, but the data to be captured after the circuit has been exercised a second time. In block <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight>, each bit of the first signature to be stored in the memory unit is to be compared to a respective bit of the second digital signature, so that the response of the integrated circuit from the first exercising is to be compared to the response of the integrated circuit to the second exercising. Here, even though the embodiment includes a comparison on a bit for bit basis, any other method of comparing the two signatures in order to determines whether the two signatures are or are not the same is specifically within the contemplation of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Now in block <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight>, the states to be captured with reference to block <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> are to be stored in a memory unit. In block <highlight><bold>555</bold></highlight> the integrated circuit is to be once again functionally exercised, and in block <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> at a determined clock, an at least one second state is to be captured in the storage elements. As described with reference to blocks <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight>, the term &ldquo;second&rdquo; state is used herein to distinguish the captured data from the &ldquo;first&rdquo; state, wherein the second state is for the same circuit portions but the data is captured after the circuit has been exercised a second time. In block <highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight>, for each storage element, the state in the memory is to be compared with the state in the capture circuit. Because each storage element stores a binary value, the comparison is to be on a bit for bit basis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In an embodiment the results of the comparing in both blocks <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight> are to be provided to an output port of the die, so that a coupled tester can receive the comparison result. It is preferred that the comparing includes an exclusive-or operation as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, or some other operation that will result in one or more bits whose value indicates whether or not the two compared bits are of the same value or are not of the same value. The method furthermore preferably includes automatically changing the clock capture signal to the storage elements based on an algorithm, at a time after capturing the second state, wherein a second iteration of the method defined herein in blocks <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight> includes as the determined clock the automatically changed clock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Now with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> step of the method described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> of automatically changing the clock capture signal of the storage elements is described independently. The method includes in block <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>, an integrated circuit that is disposed on at least one die is coupled to at least one storage element in a capture circuit disposed on the die, such with at least one scan latch with at least one scan chain, and the integrated circuit is to be functionally exercised. In an embodiment, the integrated circuit is to be functionally exercised by receiving functional data inputs at a port of the die, and by receiving a clocking signal from a port of the die, from a coupled tester. It is expected that the clocking signal will be converted into a higher frequency pulse signal and/or be cleaned and synchronized as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In block <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight>, the storage elements are to capture at a determined first clock at least a state of the integrated circuit in the storage elements during the functional exercising of the integrated circuit described with reference to block <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>. Each storage element, such as a scan latch, is to capture a signal state of a coupled portion of the circuit, as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In block <highlight><bold>618</bold></highlight>, a determined second clock at which to capture at least a state of the integrated circuit is to be calculated automatically, as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. The determination of the second clock is preferably based on an algorithm implemented by a circuit, and preferably by incrementing or decrementing monotonically from the first clock to a target clock, as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. In block <highlight><bold>624</bold></highlight>, the blocks <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> are repeated. Further repetitions of the blocks <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> are within the specific contemplation of the present invention, wherein each new clock is determined, until a specific clock or a specific target number of clocks are determined, the target number in an embodiment being input into the die and generated from a tester, and the first clock input into the die and generated from the tester. Therefore, the present invention includes starting on a specific clock (e.g. three clocks after the trigger signal), and stopping on a specific clock (e.g. 300 clocks after the trigger). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The above description of illustrated embodiments of the invention, including what is described in the Abstract, is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed. While specific embodiments of, and examples for, the invention are described herein for illustrative purposes, various equivalent modifications are possible within the scope of the invention, as those skilled in the relevant art will recognize. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> These modifications can be made to the invention in light of the above detailed description. The terms used in the following claims should not be construed to limit the invention to the specific embodiments disclosed in the specification and the claims. Rather, the scope of the invention is to be determined entirely by the following claims, which are to be construed in accordance with established doctrines of claim interpretation. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit that includes: 
<claim-text>a circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an at least one scan latch, each scan latch in communication with at least a portion of the circuit to retain a signal state of the portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory unit to retain a state of the at least one scan latch; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparison circuit to compare the state of the retained at least one scan latch in the memory unit to a state of the at least one scan latch and to save a result of the comparison. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a transmission circuit to transmit the result of the comparison to a port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the comparison circuit includes an exclusive-or operation comparison circuit to execute an exclusive or comparison between the retained at least one scan latch in the memory unit and the state of the at least one scan latch to generate a sequence of at least one bit, each bit representing the result of the comparison between a scan latch and a retained state of a scan latch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a strobe circuit to strobe the result of the comparison as a strobed signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a clock circuit to clock the scan latch to retain a signal state at a specified clock, to clock the memory unit to retain the state, to clock the scan latch to retain a signal state at a specified clock, and to clock the comparison circuit to compare the memory unit state with the scan latch retained signal state. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a first circuit to automatically define a time of a clock pulse to latch the scan latch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first circuit is to algorithmically define the time of the clock pulse. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit that includes: 
<claim-text>an at least one scan latch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a signature generator circuit to generate and to retain a signature of a content of the at least one scan latch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory unit to retain a signature generated by the signature generator circuit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparison circuit to compare a signature retained in the memory unit with a signature retained in the signature generator circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a transmission circuit to transmit the result of the comparison to a port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the comparison circuit includes an exclusive-or operation circuit to perform an exclusive-or operation between the signature retained in the signature generator circuit and the signature retained in the memory unit to generate a sequence of at least one bit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a strobe circuit to strobe the result of the comparison as a strobed signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a clock circuit to clock the at least one scan latch to retain a first signal state at a first clock, to clock the signature generator circuit to generate a first signature of the first signal state, to clock the memory unit to retain the first signature; to clock the scan latch to retain a signal state at a second clock subsequent to the first, and to clock the comparison circuit to compare the memory unit state with the scan latch retained signal state retained at the second clock. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a first circuit to automatically define a clock to latch the scan latch at a specific time. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first circuit automatically defines the clock based on an algorithm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit that includes: 
<claim-text>a circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an at least one scan latch, each scan latch in communication with at least a portion of the circuit to retain a signal state of the portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first circuit to generate a scan latch signal clock to latch each scan latch to retain a signal state at a selected clock during a first sequence of core clock pulses, and to generate a scan latch clock signal to latch the scan latch to retain a signal state at an automatically selected clock during an at least one other sequence of core clock pulses subsequent to the first sequence of core clock pulses. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first clock circuit generates the scan latch signal clock to retain a signal state at an automatically selected clock based on an algorithm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first circuit generates the scan latch signal clock to retain a signal state at an automatically selected clock by one of increasing the scan clock by one core clock for each sequence of core clock pulses and decreasing the scan clock by one core clock for each sequence of core clock pulses. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a transmission circuit to transmit each of the retained signal state to a port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes 
<claim-text>a memory unit to retain a state of the at least one scan latch at or after a scan clock pulse during a first identified sequence of clock pulses; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparison circuit to compare the state of the retained at least one scan latch in the memory unit to a state of the at least one scan latch and to save a result of the comparison. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a transmission circuit to transmit the result of the comparison to a port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a clock circuit to clock the memory unit to retain the state, and to clock the comparison circuit to compare the memory unit state with the scan latch retained signal state for a sequence of clock pulses subsequent to the first identified sequence of clock pulses. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes 
<claim-text>a signature generator circuit to generate and to retain a first signature of a content of the at least one scan latch at or after a scan clock pulse during a first identified sequence of clock pulses; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory unit to retain the first signature; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparison circuit to compare the first signature retained in the memory unit with a second signature retained in the signature generator circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a transmission circuit to transmit the result of the comparison to a port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> that further includes a clock circuit to clock the signature generator circuit to generate the first signature of the first signal state for a scan latch pulse during a first sequence of core clock pulses, to clock the memory unit to retain the first signature, to clock the signature generator circuit to generate and retain a second signature for a scan latch pulse during a sequence of core pulses subsequent to the first sequence, and to clock the comparison circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>functionally exercising an integrated circuit that is coupled to at least one capturing circuit storage elements; </claim-text>
<claim-text>capturing at a first determined clock an at least one first state of the circuit in the storage elements during the exercising; and one of </claim-text>
<claim-text>transforming the captured first states into a first digital signature, storing the signature in a memory unit, functionally exercising the integrated circuit that is coupled to the storage elements, capturing at a second determined clock an at least one second state of the circuit in the storage elements, transforming the captured second states into a second digital signature, and comparing the first signature stored in the memory unit to the second digital signature; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the states in a memory unit, functionally exercising the integrated circuit that is coupled to the storage elements, capturing at a second determined clock an at least one second state of the circuit in the storage elements; and for each storage element, comparing the state in the memory unit with the state in the capture circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> further including providing a result of the comparing to a terminal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the comparing includes performing an exclusive-or operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> further including automatically changing the second determined clock based on an algorithm at a time after capturing said second state, wherein a second iteration of the method defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> includes as the second determined clock the automatically changed clock. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method including 
<claim-text>functionally exercising an integrated circuit disposed on a die that is coupled to at least one storage elements disposed on the die; </claim-text>
<claim-text>capturing at a first determined clock an at least one first state of the circuit in the storage elements during the exercising; </claim-text>
<claim-text>automatically calculating on the die a second determined clock based on the first determined clock; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>repeating the exercising and the capturing using as the value of the first determined clock the automatically calculated second clock. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> further including before the repeating the following: 
<claim-text>transforming the captured first states into a first digital signature; </claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the signature in a memory unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>functionally exercising the integrated circuit that is coupled to the storage elements; </claim-text>
<claim-text>capturing at a determined clock an at least one second state of the circuit in the storage elements; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transforming the captured second states into a second digital signature; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing each bit of the first signature stored in memory unit to a respective bit of the second digital signature.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005379A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005379A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005379A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005379A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005379A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005379A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
