<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001233A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001233A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001233</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10171790</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020617</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-200583</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L029/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>550000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>semiconductor memory device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiroyuki</given-name>
<family-name>Yamauchi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Matsushita Electric Industrial Co., Ltd.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Jack Q. Lever. Jr.</name-1>
<name-2>McDERMOTT, WILL &amp; EMERY</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>600 Thirteenth Street, N.W,</address-1>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005-3096</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A semiconductor memory device of the present invention includes: a substrate; a plurality of memory cells arranged in a matrix pattern on a primary surface of the substrate; a sense amplifier provided in each column for detecting data of the memory cells that are arranged along the column; a plurality of wiring layers formed on the substrate; and a plurality of data lines provided in each column and connected to the memory cells that are arranged in the column, wherein the data lines are connected commonly to the sense amplifier but via different paths, and a data line having a longer path length is provided by using a wiring layer that is on a higher level. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a semiconductor memory device, and more particularly to a countermeasure to a signal delay in such a device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Japanese Laid-Open Patent Publication No. 10-178110 and Japanese Laid-Open Patent Publication No. 9-270468 each disclose a layout of a 6-transistor SRAM memory cell (i.e., a memory cell of an SRAM device including six transistors). Specifically, each of these publications discloses a method for reducing the aspect ratio (defined herein as the ratio of the dimension in the row direction in which word lines extend with respect to the dimension in the column direction in which bit lines extend) of a 6-transistor SRAM memory cell as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A, i</cross-reference>.e., a method for laying out the components of the memory cell so that the dimension of the memory cell in the row direction in which word lines extend is greater than that in the column direction in which bit lines extend. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Specifically, each of these publications discloses a layout in which P-wells <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are arranged on opposite sides of an N-well <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> so as to interpose the N-well <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> therebetween, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference>. In this layout, six transistors (MN<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, MN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, MN<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, MN<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, MP<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) are arranged substantially in point symmetry with respect to a central point P<highlight><subscript>100 </subscript></highlight>of the memory cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In the layout of a memory cell <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>B, bit lines BL and /BL are arranged on the P-well <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the P-well <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. The drive transistors MN<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which are NMOS transistors, are laid out substantially in point symmetry with respect to the central point P<highlight><subscript>100 </subscript></highlight>of the memory cell <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight> as described above, and are arranged over the P-well <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the P-well <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. The access transistors MN<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and MN<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, which are NMOS transistors, are also laid out substantially in point symmetry with respect to the central point P<highlight><subscript>100 </subscript></highlight>of the memory cell <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight> as described above, and are arranged over the P-well <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the P-well <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. Moreover, the load transistors MP<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which are PMOS transistors, are also laid out substantially in point symmetry with respect to the central point P<highlight><subscript>100 </subscript></highlight>of the memory cell <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight>, and are both arranged over the N-well <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The load transistors MP<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> extend in two lines parallel to each other in the direction in which bit lines extend, whereby the width of the PMOS region (the width of the N-well <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>) is increased accordingly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference> is a top view schematically illustrating a structure of an SRAM device in which the memory cells <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference> are arranged in a matrix pattern, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a bit line provided along line X-X shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</cross-reference> is a top view schematically illustrating a structure of another SRAM device in which high-aspect-ratio memory cells (longitudinal-type cells) are arranged in a matrix pattern, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a bit line provided along line Y-Y shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Assuming that the memory cells illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</cross-reference> are made with the same design rule, the SRAM device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>A, which uses the memory cells <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight>, has a smaller dimension in the column direction in which bit lines extend, as compared to the SRAM device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, which uses the longitudinal-type cells. Thus, as can be seen from a comparison between <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, the length of the bit line can be reduced in the SRAM device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>A, which uses the memory cells <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight>, as compared to the SRAM device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, which uses the longitudinal-type cells. In practice, the length of the bit line of the SRAM device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>A, which uses the memory cells <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight>, is about &frac13; of that of the bit line of the SRAM device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, which uses the longitudinal-type cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Each bit line provided in a semiconductor memory device includes a portion (&ldquo;extended portion&rdquo;) that extends in the column direction of the matrix pattern in which a plurality of memory cells are arranged, and another portion (&ldquo;contact plug&rdquo;) that is connected to an access transistor of each memory cell. Therefore, if the number of contact plugs increase along with an increase in the degree of integration of memory cells, the capacitance of the contact plugs increases, thereby increasing the total line capacitance of the bit line. For example, in SRAM devices, highly-integrated mask ROM device, etc., using memory cells having a small ratio of the dimension in the direction in which word lines extend with respect to the dimension in the direction in which bit lines extend (longitudinal-type cells), the proportion of the contact plug capacitance with respect to the total line capacitance of the bit line is particularly large, and thus the bit line delay is substantial. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> However, with the conventional method as described above, the length of a contact plug between a transistor and the extended portion of a bit line cannot be changed. Therefore, it is not very effective in reducing the total line capacitance of a bit line. In other words, it is not very effective in reducing the bit line delay. This will now be described in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Typically, the length of a contact plug running through one wiring layer is 1300 nm, and the total length of a contact plug running through three wiring layers is 3900 nm. In the SRAM device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>A, which uses longitudinal-type cells, the length of the extended portion of a bit line per two memory cells (the dimension in the column direction of the memory cells) is about 1700 nm. In a case where one bit line includes one contact plug per two memory cells, the total of the length of the extended portion of the bit line per two memory cells and the length of the contact plug is 5600 nm (1700 nm&plus;3900 nm). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Using the memory cell <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>A, if the length of a bit line is reduced to &frac13;, the total of the length of the bit line and the length of the contact plug will be about 4460 nm. Since the length of the contact plug does not change, the total of the length of the extended portion of the bit line and the length of the contact plug is reduced only by about 20%. Thus, the total line capacitance of the bit line is reduced only by about 20%. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The present invention, which has been made to solve the problem as described above, has an object to reduce a signal delay in a semiconductor memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A semiconductor memory device of the present invention includes: a substrate; a plurality of memory cells arranged in a matrix pattern on a primary surface of the substrate; a sense amplifier provided in each column for detecting data of the memory cells that are arranged along the column; a plurality of wiring layers formed on the substrate; and a plurality of data lines provided in each column and connected to the memory cells that are arranged in the column, wherein the data lines are connected commonly to the sense amplifier but via different paths, and a data line having a longer path length is provided by using a wiring layer that is on a higher level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> With the present invention, the number of memory cells connected to one data line is reduced. Therefore, the number of contact plugs for connecting memory cells and one data line is reduced. Thus, the total line capacitance of each data line including the contact plugs is reduced. Since the line capacitance is in proportion to the signal delay along the line, the signal delay along one data line is reduced by the reduction in the total line capacitance of the data line including the contact plugs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It is preferred that: the plurality of data lines each include contact plugs for connection to the plurality of memory cells that are arranged in one column; and a total line capacitance of each data line including the contact plugs is substantially equal to those of the other data lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In this way, the variations in signal delay time among different data lines are suppressed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> It is preferred that in two data lines that are provided by using an upper wiring layer and a lower wiring layer vertically adjacent to the upper wiring layer, among the plurality of wiring layers, a portion provided through the upper wiring layer is offset from another portion provided through the lower wiring layer as viewed from above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In this way, in the two data lines that are provided by using the upper wiring layer and the lower wiring layer vertically adjacent to the upper wiring layer, the distance between the portion provided through the upper wiring layer and the other portion provided through the lower wiring layer can be increased, thereby reducing the coupling capacitance occurring between the portion provided through the upper wiring layer and the other portion provided through the lower wiring layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> It is preferred that: the memory cells each include a memory cell transistor; and a larger cell current flows through the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is connected to a data line having a longer path length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A data line having a longer path length has a greater signal delay. Therefore, a memory cell of a higher driving power including a memory cell transistor through which a larger cell current flows is employed as a memory cell connected to such a data line having a longer path length. In this way, the signal delay can be compensated for. Thus, the signal delay can be made uniform among different data lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is connected to a data line having a longer path length may have a larger channel width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is connected to a data line having a longer path length may have a smaller channel length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is connected to a data line having a longer path length may have a lower threshold voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> An amplifier may be provided along the path of at least one of the plurality of data lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The plurality of data lines may be connected to the sense amplifier each via a column switch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Another semiconductor memory device according to the present invention includes: a substrate; a plurality of memory cells arranged in a matrix pattern on a primary surface of the substrate; a sense amplifier provided in each column for detecting data of the memory cells that are arranged along the column; and a data line provided in each column and connected to the memory cells that are arranged in the column, wherein the memory cells each include a memory cell transistor, and a larger cell current flows through the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A data line having a longer path length has a greater signal delay. Therefore, a memory cell of a higher driving power including a memory cell transistor through which a larger cell current flows is employed as a memory cell located farther from the sense amplifier. In this way, the signal delay can be compensated for. Thus, the signal delay can be made uniform between memory cells connected to a single bit line and the sense amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier may have a larger channel width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier may have a smaller channel length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier may have a lower threshold voltage. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating a structure of an SRAM device of Embodiment 1, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> shows a top view and a cross-sectional view illustrating a structure of bit lines of a memory cell group including a plurality of memory cells that are arranged along a column in the SRAM device of Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating a structure of bit lines provided in the SRAM device of Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> illustrates a structure of a bit line in a conventional SRAM device, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> illustrates a structure of a bit line in the SRAM device of Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating the line capacitance of a bit line of Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating a structure of the SRAM device of Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a top view illustrating a memory cell provided in the SRAM device of Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> are schematic diagrams each illustrating a structure of a bit line provided in the SRAM device of Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a structure of bit lines provided in an SRAM device of Embodiment 2. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating the line capacitance of a bit line of Embodiment 2. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference> is a graph illustrating the effect of reducing the bit line delay according to Embodiment 1 and Embodiment 2, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</cross-reference> is a graph illustrating the effect of reducing the power consumption according to Embodiment 1 and Embodiment 2. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference> illustrates a circuit diagram of a memory cell provided in a conventional SRAM device, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference> illustrates a schematic top view of a layout of the memory cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference> is a top view schematically illustrating a structure of an SRAM device in which the memory cells as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference> are arranged in a matrix pattern, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a bit line that is provided along line X-X shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</cross-reference> is a top view schematically illustrating a structure of an SRAM device in which high-aspect-ratio memory cells (longitudinal-type cells) are arranged in a matrix pattern, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a bit line that is provided along line Y-Y shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the present invention will now be described with reference to the drawings, in which like elements are denoted by like reference numerals throughout the embodiments for the sake of simplicity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Embodiment 1 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating a structure of an SRAM device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> shows a top view and a cross-sectional view illustrating a structure of bit lines of a memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including a plurality of memory cells arranged along a column in the SRAM device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, the SRAM device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment includes a plurality of memory cells arranged in a matrix pattern, word line drivers each connected to a word line (not shown) for performing a row addressing operation via the word line, sense amplifiers and I/O circuits each for exchanging signals with a bit line pair (not shown), and a control circuit for controlling the word line drivers and the I/O circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in the top view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B, two bit line pairs (BLUn, /BLUn) and (BLDn, /BLDn) are provided in the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including a plurality of memory cells arranged in a column. In each bit line pair, two bit lines are arranged in parallel to each other with a constant interval therebetween and are connected to a column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is connected to a sense amplifier <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and the sense amplifier <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is connected to an I/O circuit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Next, referring to the cross-sectional view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B, the structure of the bit lines BLUn and BLDn will be described. As illustrated in the cross-sectional view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B, the bit line BLUn includes extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B extending in the column direction along the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> each connected to an access transistor (not shown) of a memory cell formed on an Si substrate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The bit line BLDn includes an extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> extending in the column direction along the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> each connected to an access transistor (not shown) of a memory cell formed on the Si substrate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The bit lines /BLUn and /BLDn are structurally the same as the bit lines BLUn and BLDn, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The bit line pair (BLUn, /BLUn) is connected to the memory cells that are included in a region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A of the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and the bit line pair (BLDn, /BLDn) is connected to the memory cells that are included in a region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B of the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Thus, the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including memory cells that are located along the same column is divided into the two regions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B, and a bit line pair is provided for each of the regions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A of the bit line pair (BLUn, /BLUn) is provided in the region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A and in the same wiring layer as the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the bit line pair (BLDn, /BLDn) connected to the memory cells in the region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B. In the region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B, the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B of the bit line pair (BLUn, /BLUn) is provided in another wiring layer on a higher level than the bit line pair (BLDn, /BLDn) connected to the memory cells in the region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B, and the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B is connected to the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A of the bit line pair (BLUn, /BLUn) via a contact plug <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Note that in the present embodiment, the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B of the bit line BLUn is parallel to the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the bit line BLDn and is shifted from the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> as viewed from above, as illustrated in the top view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference>. In other words, the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B is offset from the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> as viewed from above. The extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B of the bit line /BLUn is provided in a similar manner. In this way, the distance between the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B and the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is increased, whereby it is possible to reduce the coupling capacitance occurring therebetween. Particularly, it is preferred that the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B is offset from the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> as viewed from above, by a distance that is one half of the distance between each pair of bit lines, as in the present embodiment, because in this way, the distance between the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B and the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is maximized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the bit line pair (BLUn, /BLUn) and the bit line pair (BLDn, /BLDn) are each connected to the column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> includes a switch G<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, a switch G<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a switch G<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and a switch G<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The bit line BLDn is connected to the switch G<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, the bit line /BLDn to the switch G<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the bit line BLUn to the switch G<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and the bit line /BLUn to the switch G<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Thus, by controlling the column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (i.e., by turning ON/OFF the switches G<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to G<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> provided in the column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>), it is possible to select one of the bit line pair (BLUn, /BLUn) and the bit line pair (BLDn, /BLDn) to which a selected memory cell is connected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Note that in the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including memory cells that are located along the same column, word lines for two memory cells will not be addressed at the same time. Therefore, the bit line pair (BLUn, /BLUn) and the bit line pair (BLDn, /BLDn) will not be addressed at the same time. Thus, the bit line delay is influenced by the line capacitance of one of the bit line pairs (one with the larger line capacitance). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> illustrates a structure of a bit line in a conventional SRAM device, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> illustrates a structure of a bit line in the SRAM device of the present embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> A comparison between <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> shows that the number of contact plugs for one bit line in the present embodiment is one half of that in the prior art. Thus, with the present embodiment, the number of contact plugs for one bit line can be reduced to half. Therefore, the line capacitance of each bit line can be reduced. Note that while the number of contact plugs for one bit line is set to be one half of that in the prior art in the present embodiment, the present invention is not limited to this, as long as two bit lines together include a number of contact plugs that are provided for one bit line in the prior art. In this way, the line capacitance of each bit line can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Particularly, an SRAM device using the low-aspect-ratio lateral-type cells has a contact plug density about three times that of an SRAM device using the longitudinal-type cells. Therefore, it is very effective to reduce the bit line delay by reducing the line capacitance of each bit line as in the present embodiment. The effect of reducing the line capacitance of each bit line in the present embodiment with respect to that in the prior art can be quantitatively represented by a model as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The line capacitance of the bit line BLUn of the present embodiment will now be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating the line capacitance of the bit line BLUn. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, N/2 contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are provided in the region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A of the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and each of the contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is connected to the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A of the bit line BLUn. Moreover, N/2 contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are provided also in the region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B of the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and each of the contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is connected to the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the bit line BLDn. Each contact plug <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is provided for two memory cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Where K denotes the line capacitance of the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B for two memory cells, and M denotes the line capacitance of the contact plug <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, with respect to the line capacitance of the extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> for one contact plug (for two memory cells) being 1, the line capacitance C<highlight><subscript>BLUn </subscript></highlight>of the bit line BLUn is represented by Expression 1 below. Note that the line capacitance of the contact plug <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is negligible and is thus ignored herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>C</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>BLUn</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&plus;<highlight><italic>K&plus;M</italic></highlight>)&times;<highlight><italic>N/</italic></highlight>2&emsp;&emsp;(Expression 1) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the line capacitance C<highlight><subscript>BL </subscript></highlight>of a bit line provided in the conventional SRAM device is represented by Expression 2 below. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>C</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>BL</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)&times;<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(Expression 2) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the ratio C<highlight><subscript>BLUn</subscript></highlight>/C<highlight><subscript>BL </subscript></highlight>of the reduced line capacitance of each bit line in the present embodiment with respect to that in the prior art can be represented by Expression 3 below. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>C</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>BLUn</subscript></highlight>/C<highlight><subscript>BL</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&plus;<highlight><italic>K&plus;M</italic></highlight>)&times;<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight>/(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)&times;2<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(Expression 3) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Note that the line capacitance of the bit line BLDn is (1&plus;M)&times;N/2, and is smaller than the line capacitance of the bit line BLUn. Therefore, the effect of reducing the line capacitance of each bit line in the present embodiment is dependent on the bit line BLUn. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Next, the effect of reducing the line capacitance of the present embodiment will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, the capacitance reduction rate is calculated for various values of M, used as a parameter, while assuming that K&equals;0.7. Note that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, it is assumed that the capacitance reduction rate is the same as the bit line delay reduction rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, the capacitance reduction rate is 64% to 62% for values of M in the range of 1.5 to 2, which is close to the value in the case of a 0.15 &igrave; m design rule. Therefore, if the bit line delay in the prior art is 1 nsec, it is expected that the bit line delay will be reduced to 0.64 to 0.62 nsec. Moreover, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>B, the power consumption can also be reduced in proportion to the reduction in the line capacitance of each bit line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, each data line is provided by using a bit line pair, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B, since the present embodiment is directed to an SRAM device. However, the present invention is not limited to this. For example, in a ROM device, each data line is basically provided by using a single bit line. Particularly, since a ROM device has a high degree of integration, the number of contact plugs per unit bit line length is several times that of an SRAM device. Therefore, when the present embodiment is applied to a ROM device, it is quite effective in reducing the line capacitance of each bit line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Particularly, in a semiconductor memory device used at a high operating speed, it is preferred that the variations in the bit line delay among different bit lines are as small as possible. In view of this, methods for making the bit line delay uniform will be shown below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Method 1 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> A comparison between the bit line BLUn and the bit line BLDn of the present embodiment shows that the line capacitance of the bit line BLUn is greater than the line capacitance of the bit line BLDn by the line capacitance of the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B. In view of this, according to the present method, the number of contact plugs to be provided for the bit line BLUn and that for the bit line BLDn are adjusted so that their line capacitances are equal to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Where N<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>denotes the number of contact plugs to be provided for the bit line BLUn, and N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>denotes that for the bit line BLDn. The ratio of the numbers of contact plugs at which the line capacitance C<highlight><subscript>BLUn </subscript></highlight>of the bit line BLUn and the line capacitance C<highlight><subscript>BLDn </subscript></highlight>of the bit line BLDn are equal to each other can be obtained as follows. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>C<highlight><subscript>BLUn</subscript></highlight>&equals;C<highlight><subscript>BLDn </subscript></highlight></in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)&times;<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&plus;K&times;N</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)&times;<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight></in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>/N</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)/(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M&minus;K</italic></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(Expression 4) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is preferred to arrange the bit lines so that the ratio N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>/N<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>is as shown in Expression 4 above. For example, N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>/N<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;1.39 where K&equals;0.7 and M&equals;1.5 in Expression 4 above. If the bit lines are arranged so as to satisfy N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>/N<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;1.39, the bit line delay can be reduced to be as small as 58%. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Method 2 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, the line capacitance of the bit line BLUn is greater than the line capacitance of the bit line BLDn by the line capacitance of the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B. In view of this, according to the present method, the structure of the present embodiment is adjusted so that a larger cell current flows through memory cells that are connected to the bit line BLUn. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Specifically, in a memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connected to the bit line BLUn (i.e., each memory cell included in the region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A of the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>), the channel width W of the transistors MN<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> may be increased, or the channel length L thereof may be reduced, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Specifically, the channel width W of the transistors MN<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connected to the bit line BLUn can be increased by adjusting the channel width W of the memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connected to the bit line BLUn (&ldquo;channel width Wa&rdquo;) and the channel width W of the memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>connected to the bit line BLDn (&ldquo;channel width Wb&rdquo;) so as to satisfy Wa&gt;Wb, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> In such a case, the area of each memory cell may need to be increased. In a case where the area of each memory cell needs to be increased, there may occur problems such as an increase in the total size of the SRAM device, or an increase in the total amount of leak current through the memory cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> However, according to the present method, only the channel width of the transistors MN<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is increased, whereby it is possible to make the bit line delay uniform while minimizing such problems as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Specifically, the channel length L of the transistors MN<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connected to the bit line BLUn can be reduced by adjusting the channel length L of the memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connected to the bit line BLUn (&ldquo;channel length La&rdquo;) and the channel length L of the memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>connected to the bit line BLDn (&ldquo;channel length Lb&rdquo;) so as to satisfy La&lt;Lb, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Note that the present method is not limited to the method of reducing the channel length L of the transistors MN<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and MN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the memory cell <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. As long as the threshold voltage of the transistors MN<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, MN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, MN<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and MN<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is reduced (e.g., by reducing the thickness of the gate insulating film, by increasing the doping amount for the channel region, etc.), a large cell current flows, whereby the bit line delay can be made uniform as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> In addition, the present invention is applicable to a structure in which the bit line is not divided into the bit line BLUn and the bit line BLDn. In so doing, the channel width, the channel length or the threshold voltage is adjusted between the transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier and the transistor of a memory cell that is located nearer to the sense amplifier so as to allow a larger cell current to flow through the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier, whereby it is possible to make the bit line delay uniform between memory cells connected to a single bit line and the sense amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Method 3 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The bit line delay can be made uniform also by employing a structure in which the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A of the bit line BLUn is connected to the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B of the bit line BLUn via an amplifier <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference>. The amplifier <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may be, for example, an amplifier including two MOS transistors, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Embodiment 2 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> An SRAM device of the present embodiment is different from the SRAM device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of Embodiment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> above in that four bit line pairs (BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, /BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), (BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, /BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), (BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, /BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and (BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, /BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) are provided in the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. In each bit line pair, two bit lines are arranged in parallel to each other with a constant interval therebetween and are connected to the column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a structure of bit lines provided in the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the present embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, in the SRAM device of the present embodiment, the bit line in the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is divided into four bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The bit line BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>D and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E extending in the column direction along the memory cell group <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and the contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> each connected to an access transistor (not shown) of one of the memory cells formed on the Si substrate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the bit line BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> includes extended portions <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>D and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E and the contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and the bit line BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> includes extended portions <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>D and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E and the contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The bit line BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> includes an extended portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and the contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected to the column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> through four different wiring layers that are provided on four different levels in the layered device structure. A bit line having a contact plug located farther away from the column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> than a contact plug of another bit line is connected to the column switch <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> through a wiring layer on a higher level. Note that the bit lines /BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, /BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, /BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and /BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> have the same cross-sectional structure as that of the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, the extended portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E is shifted from the extended portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> as viewed from above. In other words, the extended portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E is offset from the extended portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> as viewed from above. The extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E is also offset from the extended portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E as viewed from above, and the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E is also offset from the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E as viewed from above. Thus, as viewed from above the memory cell, the extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E and <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are arranged in parallel to one another with a constant interval therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> In this way, the interval between the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E and the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E, that between the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E and the extended portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E, and that between the extended portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E and the extended portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, are increased. Therefore, it is possible to reduce the coupling capacitance occurring between the extended portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E and the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E, between the extended portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E and the extended portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E, and between the extended portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E and the extended portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, the number of contact plugs for one bit line is reduced to &frac14; of that of the conventional SRAM device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>. Thus, with the present embodiment, the number of contact plugs for one bit line can be reduced to &frac14;. Therefore, the line capacitance of each bit line can be reduced. Note that while the number of contact plugs for one bit line is set to be &frac14; of that in the prior art in the present embodiment, the present invention is not limited to this, as long as four bit lines together include a number of contact plugs that are provided for one bit line in the prior art. In this way, the line capacitance of each bit line can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The line capacitance of the bit line of the present embodiment will now be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> each include N/4 contact plugs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. One contact plug <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is provided for two memory cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Where K denotes the line capacitance of the extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E for two memory cells, and M denotes the line capacitance of the contact plug <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, with respect to the line capacitance of the extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>D, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>D, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>D and <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> for one contact plug (for two memory cells) being 1, the line capacitance C<highlight><subscript>BL1 </subscript></highlight>of the bit line BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is represented by Expression 5 below. Note that the line capacitance of the contact plug <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is negligible and is thus ignored herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>C</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>BL1</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)&times;<highlight><italic>N/</italic></highlight>4&plus;<highlight><italic>K&times;</italic></highlight>3<highlight><italic>N/</italic></highlight>4&emsp;&emsp;(Expression 5) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the line capacitance C<highlight><subscript>BL </subscript></highlight>of a bit line provided in the conventional SRAM device is represented by Expression 2 below. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>C</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>BL</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)&times;<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(Expression 2) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the ratio C<highlight><subscript>BL1</subscript></highlight>/C<highlight><subscript>BL </subscript></highlight>of the reduced line capacitance of each bit line in the present embodiment with respect to that in the prior art can be represented by Expression 6 below. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>C</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>BL1</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>/C</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>BL</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)&times;N&plus;3<highlight><italic>KN</italic></highlight>/(1&plus;<highlight><italic>M</italic></highlight>)&times;4<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(Expression 6) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Note that the line capacitance of the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is always smaller than the line capacitance of the bit line BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the effect of reducing the line capacitance of each bit line in the present embodiment is dependent on the bit line BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Next, the effect of reducing the line capacitance of the present embodiment will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, the capacitance reduction rate is calculated for various values of M, used as a parameter, while assuming that K&equals;0.7. Note that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, it is assumed that the capacitance reduction rate is the same as the bit line delay reduction rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, the capacitance reduction rate is 46% to 43% for values of M in the range of 1.5 to 2, which is close to the value in the case of a 0.15 &igrave; m design rule. Therefore, if the bit line delay in the prior art is 1 nsec, it is expected that the bit line delay will be reduced to 0.46 to 0.43 nsec. Moreover, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>B, another significant effect is provided that the power consumption can also be reduced in proportion to the reduction in the line capacitance of each bit line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Also in the present embodiment, Methods 1 to 3 of Embodiment 1 above may be employed so as to further reduce the bit line delay. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Specifically, in the present embodiment, a comparison between the line capacitance of each of the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and that of the bit line BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> shows that the line capacitance of each of the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is larger than that of the bit line BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> by the line capacitance of the corresponding one of the extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E. Such line capacitance variations among these bit lines can be corrected by adjusting the number of contact plugs for each of the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> so that their line capacitances are substantially equal to one another as in Method 1 of Embodiment 1. In this way, the line capacitance of each bit line can be further reduced, and the bit line delay can be made uniform among different bit lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, Method 2 of Embodiment 1 described above may be employed as follows. As described above, the line capacitance of each of the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is larger than that of the bit line BL<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> by the line capacitance of the corresponding one of the extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E. In view of this, the structure of the present embodiment may be adjusted so that a larger cell current flows through memory cells that are connected to the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Particularly, in the structure of the present embodiment, the line capacitance increases from the bit line BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to the bit line BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Therefore, it is preferred that the cell current gradually increases from the memory cells that are connected to the bit line BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to the memory cells that are connected to the bit line BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, as in Method 3 of Embodiment 1 described above, the bit line delay can be made uniform by employing a structure in which the extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>D, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>D and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>D of the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are connected respectively to the extended portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>E and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E of the bit lines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> each via an amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> The present invention has been described above through Embodiments 1 and 2 with respect to the bit line structure of an SRAM device. However, the present invention is not limited thereto, but may alternatively be applied to semiconductor memory devices other than an SRAM device (e.g., a highly-integrated mask ROM device). Moreover, each data line is provided by using a bit line pair through Embodiments 1 and 2, since the embodiments are directed to an SRAM device. However, the present invention is not limited to this. For example, in a ROM device, each data line is basically provided by using a single bit line. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of memory cells arranged in a matrix pattern on a primary surface of the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sense amplifier provided in each column for detecting data of the memory cells that are arranged along the column; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of wiring layers formed on the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of data lines provided in each column and connected to the memory cells that are arranged in the column, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the data lines are connected commonly to the sense amplifier but via different paths, and a data line having a longer path length is provided by using a wiring layer that is on a higher level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the plurality of data lines each include contact plugs for connection to the plurality of memory cells that are arranged in one column; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a total line capacitance of each data line including the contact plugs is substantially equal to those of the other data lines. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein in two data lines that are provided by using an upper wiring layer and a lower wiring layer vertically adjacent to the upper wiring layer, among the plurality of wiring layers, a portion provided through the upper wiring layer is offset from another portion provided through the lower wiring layer as viewed from above. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the memory cells each include a memory cell transistor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a larger cell current flows through the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is connected to a data line having a longer path length. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is connected to a data line having a longer path length has a larger channel width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is connected to a data line having a longer path length has a smaller channel length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is connected to a data line having a longer path length has a lower threshold voltage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an amplifier is provided along the path of at least one of the plurality of data lines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of data lines are connected to the sense amplifier each via a column switch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of memory cells arranged in a matrix pattern on a primary surface of the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sense amplifier provided in each column for detecting data of the memory cells that are arranged along the column; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a data line provided in each column and connected to the memory cells that are arranged in the column, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the memory cells each include a memory cell transistor, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a larger cell current flows through the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier has a larger channel width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier has a smaller channel length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the memory cell transistor of a memory cell that is located farther from the sense amplifier has a lower threshold voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>11B</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030001233A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
