<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000530A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000530A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000530A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000530A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000530A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000530A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000530</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896750</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A62B007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61M016/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A62B018/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>128</class>
<subclass>205250</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>128</class>
<subclass>204180</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>SELF-ELONGATING OXYGEN HOSE FOR STOWABLE AVIATION CREW OXYGEN MASK</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Thomas</given-name>
<middle-name>K.</middle-name>
<family-name>McDonald</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Overland Park</city>
<state>KS</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gary</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hannah</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Shawnee</city>
<state>KS</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>BE INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY, INC.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HOVEY WILLIAMS TIMMONS &amp; COLLINS</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2405 GRAND BLVD., SUITE 400</address-1>
<city>KANSAS CITY</city>
<state>MO</state>
<postalcode>64108</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A supplemental gas assembly (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) such as used for aircraft crews is provided which includes a mask (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) adapted to fit over at least the nose and mouth of a wearer, together with a flexible, self-elongating hose assembly (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) and a stowage box (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) for receiving the mask(<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) and hose assembly (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>); the assembly (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) is designed so that when the mask (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) is pulled from the box (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>), pressurized gas passing through the hose assembly (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) serves to inflate and axially expand the assembly (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) to a deployed length greater than the relaxed length thereof. The assembly (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) preferably includes an inflatable elastomeric inner tube (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) together with an exterior sheath (<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>) of woven or braided material which restricts radial expansion of the tube (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) while permitting axial expansion thereof. In preferred forms, the deployed length of the assembly (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) is up to three times greater than the relaxed length thereof. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention is broadly concerned with supplemental gas assemblies such as supplemental oxygen units typically used in aircraft for supplying supplemental oxygen to aircraft crew in the event of a cabin depressurization or other emergency. More particularly, the invention is concerned with such assemblies wherein a self-elongating gas hose assembly is employed which, when pressurized, axially expands to a significant extent. This gives the user a relatively long effective hose length, while avoiding the problems of handling and stowage typical with conventional hoses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> During the course of aircraft operation, such as pilots, navigation officers and other crew personnel, may need supplemental gas (e.g., oxygen) to provide protection from smoke from onboard fires and other possible airborne eye and lung irritants which may enter the crew compartment. There is a requirement in the commercial aviation industry that crew masks be capable of donning in five seconds or less. The provision of crew mask assemblies is sensitive to both the quick-donning requirements and the very limited space and volume available in aircraft flight decks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The donning issue has been responded to by provision of crew oxygen masks having inflatable harnesses. In such designs (see U.S. Pat. Nos. 4,915,106 and 5,664,566), the harness straps expand upon introduction of pressurized gas to assume an enlarged configuration permitting easy donning. When vented, however, these harness assemblies contract and engage the wearer&apos;s head to firmly hold the mask in place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In recent years, available flight deck space has become even more precious, leaving to efforts to reduce the volume of components. However, very little reduction in mask stowage box volume has been achieved, owing to the fact that the oxygen delivery hoses coupled with the mask must be of a certain minimum length to allow and facilitate crew use. That is, these stowage boxes, because they must receive a relatively long length of hose, cannot be readily reduced in size. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> There is accordingly a need in the art for improved supplemental gas assemblies which can be made in a more compact design, while still achieving the degree of utility and rapid donning characteristics required for crew oxygen equipment. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention overcomes the problems outlined above and provides supplemental gas (e.g., oxygen) assemblies including a mask adapted to fit over at least the nose and mouth of a wearer, with a flexible hose coupled with the mask and a source of supplemental gas; at least a portion of the mask and the hose are received within a stowage box. In accordance with the invention, the hose assembly comprises a length-expandable hose which, when a user grasps the mask and pulls its from the stowage box, will inflate and axially expand to a deployed length greater than the relaxed length thereof. In this way, the stowage requirements for the hose assembly are reduced, or alternately a hose having a substantially longer effective length can be used in a standard stowage box designed to accommodate a much smaller length conventional hose assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In preferred forms, the hose assembly includes an inflatable elastomeric inner tube together with an exterior sheath formed of woven or braided material which in use restricts the radial expansion of the inner tube upon pressurization thereof, while allowing the tube to expand axially. The hose assemblies may have a deployed length of at least about 1.5 times the relaxed length thereof, and more preferably greater than about two times the relaxed length.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a vertical sectional view illustrating a supplemental gas assembly of the type used in aircraft, and including the self-elongating hose construction of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side view in partial vertical section illustrating the construction of a supplemental gas mask assembly in accordance with the invention, with the gas hose in its relaxed condition; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a view similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, but depicting the mask assembly in its elongated condition. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Turning now to the drawings, and particularly <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> supplemental gas assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> broadly includes a mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> adapted to fit over the nose and mouth of a wearer, together with an elongated, length-expandable hose assembly <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> coupled with the mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, the mask and hose are housed within a stowage box <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the type used for emergency crew oxygen equipment in aircraft. In use, the mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be grasped adjacent the upper end thereof and pulled from the box <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> so that the mask may be donned by a user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In more detail, the mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is of conventional design and includes a hollow flexible section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> having a soft, pliable, surrounding face seal <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the upper end of the mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a regulator <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and appropriate couplers <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> for the hose assembly <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and harness straps <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the latter permitting donning of the mask. The straps <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may optionally be of the inflatable variety as described in U.S. Pat. Nos. 4,915,106 and 5,664,566, incorporated by reference herein. Although a nose and mouth mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is depicted, it will be appreciated that full-face masks can also be used in the context of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The hose assembly <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is best illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference> and is designed so that the end thereof remote from mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be coupled with a conventional connector within box <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The assembly <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes an inner, resilient, expandable tube <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> secured to endmost threaded hose fittings <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, together with an outer sheath <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> formed of woven or braided material. The sheath <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is secured to the ends of the hose assembly by means of crimp ferrules <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Thus, the fitting <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is secured to coupler <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, whereas the opposite fitting <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is threaded onto the box-mounted gas fitting (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In more detail, the tube <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may be formed of an elastomeric material, and particularly those selected from the group consisting of silicone rubber materials. The sheath on the other hand is preferably formed of &ldquo;Nomex&rdquo; flexible fabric; the sheath could also be formed of other suitable materials such as Kevlar, Nylon, or monofilament. The sheath <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> has a length which is two to three times the length of the inner tube <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, in the relaxed condition of the assembly <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the sheath <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is in a gathered or shirred condition along the length of the unexpanded tube. However, as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, when a pressurized gas such as oxygen is delivered into the tube <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, it expands in both radial and axial directions. However, the presence of the sheath <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> serves to inhibit and restrict the extent of radial expansion of the tube <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, but permits axial elongation thereof. Preferably, the deployed length of the hose assembly <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is at least about 1.5 times the relaxed length thereof, and more preferably at least about two times the relaxed length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The box <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is itself entirely conventional, and includes bottom wall <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> upstanding sidewalls <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a hinged top cover <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The latter has an opening <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> formed therein which is designed to receive mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with the regulator end thereof protruding above the top cover. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The use of assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is similar to that of standard crew oxygen emergency equipment. That is, in the event of a cabin depressurization, the pilot may grasp the upper end of mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and pull it upwardly. This causes the hinge cover <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to open and facilitates easy removal of the mask. The pilot then pulls the mask to his or her face with seal <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> surrounding the nose and mouth area of the pilot&apos;s face, so that the mask may be quickly donned. In this connection, many such masks are equipped with gas-expandable harness assemblies which inflate and allow quick mask donning; thereafter, the harness assembly is fully or partially deflated, causing the mask straps to engage the pilot&apos;s head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In the present instance, however, during mask deployment the hose assembly <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> comes into play in order to self-elongate from a relaxed condition (e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) to a fully extended position (e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). This effectively gives the pilot an additional length of hose to facilitate donning of the mask. At the same time, the hose in its relaxed condition allows easy stowage of the mask assembly, both originally and after use of the mask. Furthermore, given that the hose is secured to a connector within the box <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, after use the hose will &ldquo;retract&rdquo; itself and the oxygen mask back into the box <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. This aids significantly in restowage, since the hose does not require the extent of gathering and coiling typical of conventional hose assemblies. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In a supplemental gas assembly including a mask adapted to fit over at least the nose and mouth of a wearer, a flexible hose operably coupled with said mask and source of supplemental gas and having a relaxed length, and a stowage box adapted to receive at least a portion of said mask and hose when the latter are not in use by said wearer, the improvement which comprises using as said hose a length-expandable hose which, when said wearer grasps said mask and pulls the mask from said box, will inflate and axially expand to a deployed length greater than said relaxed length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said length-expandable hose comprising an inflatable inner tube, and an exterior sheath which restricts the radial expansion of said inner tube which allowing said axial expansion during said hose inflation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, said inner tube formed of an elastomeric material, said sheath being a woven or braided material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, said inner tube formed of an elastomeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said deployed length being at least about 1.5 times said relaxed length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, said deployed length being greater than about 2 times said relaxed length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, said sheath formed of Nomex material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A supplemental gas mask assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a mask body adapted to fit over at least the nose and mouth of a wearer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated hose operably coupled with said hose for supplying supplemental gas to the mask body, and having a relaxed length, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said hose being a length-expandable hose which, when supplemental gas under pressure is directed through the hose, will inflate and expand in an axial direction to a deployed length greater than said relaxed length. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, said length-expandable hose comprising an inflatable inner tube, and an exterior sheath which restricts the radial expansion of said inner tube which allowing said axial expansion during said hose inflation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, said inner tube formed of an elastomeric material, said sheath being a woven or braided material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said inner tube formed of a material selected from the group consisting of silicone and nitrile materials. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, said deployed length being at least about 1.5 times said relaxed length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, said deployed length being greater than about 2 times said relaxed length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, the end of said hose opposite said mask body adapted for connection to a supplemental gas source.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000530A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000530A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000530A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
