<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003422A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003422A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003422A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003422A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003422A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003422A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003422A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003422A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003422</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09973879</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011011</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>BO2001 A 000418</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>IT</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61C005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61C003/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>433</class>
<subclass>217100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>433</class>
<subclass>032000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and device for preparing the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative materials</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Guido</given-name>
<family-name>Pasquantonio</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Roma</city>
<country-code>IT</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lorenzo</given-name>
<family-name>Breschi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Pianoro</city>
<country-code>IT</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Andrea</given-name>
<family-name>Petrone</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Roma</city>
<country-code>IT</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>The Law Offices of Timothy J. Klima</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 330</address-1>
<address-2>One Massachusetts Avenue NW</address-2>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method and device for preparing the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative materials, according to which, after a step of mechanical treatment to remove a layer of tissue from the hard structure of the tooth, at a given zone affected by a disorder, and after removing the debris generated by such treatment, a layer of an adhesive substance is spread over the zone using an application head connected by a wire in a support handpiece to a control power circuit able to generate electrical signals which subject the given zone to a difference in potential which subjects the adhesive substance to an electrokinetic force due to the passage of an electrical current able to move the adhesive substance in an even and deep way inside dentinal tubules and so that it occupies the irregular surface of the tooth enamel. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method for preparing the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The adhesion of the dental restorative materials to the hard structures of the tooth, mainly enamel and dentin, is of paramount importance for dental preservation techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The use, for example, of compound resins for tooth reconstruction has significantly increased due to the extremely high esthetic requirements of today&apos;s population. However, such resins have an unwanted secondary feature due to their polymerization, which is a significant contraction causing them to be detached from the tooth. For this reason or for obvious retention requirements in preparations which are not self-retaining, adhesive substances must be used, which allow a bond between the mineralized tissues of the teeth and the compound resins. Therefore, the adhesive should perform the essential function for the success of the reconstruction, guaranteeing a marginal seal for the restoration made of compound resin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> To increase the retentive capacity of the substrate, for many years the treatment of dentin and enamel with various acidic solutions (or gels) was recommended. Such a process is called acid-etching and has a variety of different functions, depending on the tissue to which it is applied. On enamel, acid-etching makes the surface more receptive to the above-mentioned adhesive, dissolving the mineralized surface layer and revealing a rough, uneven surface. This surface is characterized by alternating so-called &ldquo;enamel prisms&rdquo;, that is to say, crystalline structures with varying orientation which guarantee that the adhesive resin can penetrate in small grooves and form interdigitations which guarantee retention and sealing. In practice, the fluid resin of the adhesive fills the microporosities in the enamel, guaranteeing micro-mechanical retention which allows the seal. Moreover, acid-etching increases the wettability of the enamel and allows the adhesive an angle of contact optimum for complete integration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Dentin adhesion presents numerous problems because it has a different structure from enamel. Dentin consists not only of a mineral (hydroxyapatite) like enamel (in which 97% is mineral substance), but also an organic substance, that is to say, collagen fibrils which do not easily attach to acrylic hydrophobic resins. Moreover, dentin has a high water content, a factor which makes the sticking process even more complex. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In particular, dentin is a tissue characterized by a plurality of tubules which join the inside of the tooth (pulp) and the peripheral dentin. Inside these tubules there are the so-called &ldquo;odontoblastic processes&rdquo;, that is to say, the cellular extensions of pulp cells (odontoblasts) hydrated by the fluid from blood circulation. Each tubule is surrounded by a hood of hypermineralized dentin, called the peritubular dentin. The dentin between one tubule and another is called intra-tubular, is very fibrous and less mineralized. The tubules are arranged radially starting from the pulp and have a decreasing diameter, therefore, their density differs according to the dentinal zone in which they are located and, therefore, the adhesion substrate changes according to the zones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> When the dentin is treated at given affected zones by removing the layer of tissue affected by the disorder, for example it is treated with a manual or rotary instrument to remove the decayed process or to prepare a cavity, a layer of debris called the &ldquo;smear layer&rdquo; is produced, which occludes the orifices of the dentinal tubules and covers the intertubular dentin, reducing its permeability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The application of an etching acid on the dentin previously treated, therefore, removes the layer of debris, re-opening the dentinal tubules and demineralizing the top layer of dentin, removing the mineral part and leaving the organic matrix. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The process of demineralizing the surface of the dentin takes place both at intertubular and peritubular level, although the degree of incisiveness varies given the different levels of mineralization of the two structures. In particular, the tubules at the surface on which the etching acid was passed widen to a funnel shape and over the first 4 or 5 microns of thickness the intra-tubular tissues are completely demineralized, leaving only collagen fibrils. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> These collagen fibrils, when in their so-called wet state, are porous, whilst when they are dry they collapse upon themselves and are reduced to a compact tissue on which, in contrast to the porous tissue, it is extremely difficult for the adhesive substances to stick. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> At this point, the main problem of adhesion on the dentin is succeeding in completely penetrating the demineralized layer and entering several microns into the tubules so as to guarantee an effective seal. If part of the organic matrix is not reached by the fluid resin of the adhesive and remains exposed, it is rapidly degraded by salivary enzymes, forming a marginal gap at the sides of the restorative work. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Various methods of correctly infiltrating the dentin have been put forward, mainly aiming to keep the collagen fibrils (organic matrix exposed by acid-etching) from collapsing and to allow the adhesive to pass to the deepest zones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Adhesive substances have been used which consist mainly of an acid-etching solution (mainly phosphoric acid 30-40%) and a polymerizable solution of hydrophilic and hydrophobic monomers. When the acid is washed away from the surface of the enamel and dentin, the monomer solution is applied (even in several layers) to the etched surface of the tooth. The most modern adhesives use acetone or ethanol as a solvent. The function of the solvent is to remove and substitute the water from the demineralized dentinal matrix. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The adhesive molecules have two functional groups: one with a great affinity for the surface of the tooth (hydrophilic) and another with the resinous material (hydrophobic) which is put over the layer of adhesive. The hydrophilic monomer which constitutes the main part of the adhesives is able to create micro-mechanical retention by interpenetrating the collagen fibrils exposed by the acid-etching, forming a mixed structure of organic matrix, inorganic residues and resin called the hybrid layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Formation of the hybrid layer still appears essential in order to guarantee a good degree of sealing. Moreover, the adhesive which enters the tubules which are open and widened to a funnel shape by the acid-etching process guarantees retention by forming resin extensions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The absence of a seal can allow the infiltration of bacteria which may cause secondary decay under the reconstruction, which leads to rapid failure of the therapy. Also, it has been noticed that most breaks and yielding occur at the hybrid layer level, since complete impregnation with the resin is not achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> More specifically, the generation of zones which are not infiltrated seems to be the result of a variety of factors, including, for example, an acid-etching step which is too aggressive and demineralizes the fibrils too deep, so that where they are not reached by the resin, the fibrils are completely dried out and collapse, forming a compact layer which is difficult to infiltrate and an irreversible denaturation and, therefore, modification of the collagen fibrils following acid-etching or drying or cutter overheating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> All of these factors contribute to the creation of a layer which is not completely impregnated and with various microporosities which allow the passage of enzymes and bacteria. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> It is, therefore, evident how the weak point of the entire adhesive process is guaranteeing precision filling of the open tubules after the acid-etching and complete infiltration of the collagen fibril matrix for a correct seal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The aim of the present invention is to overcome the above-mentioned disadvantages to guarantee complete adhesion of the adhesive substances on the hard structures of the tooth. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present invention provides a method for preparing the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative material, characterized in that it comprises steps of treating at least one affected zone of the hard structure of the tooth, removing the layer of tissue affected by the disorder, applying a layer of adhesive substance at least in the zone treated, subjecting at least the adhesive substance to the action of an electrical field, applying the restorative material at least on the zone covered by the adhesive substance. The present invention also relates to a device for preparing the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, a device is provided which prepares the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative materials, characterized in that it comprises at least one handpiece connected to a control power circuit for applying an electrical field to at least one layer of adhesive substance, applied at least to an affected zone of the hard structure of the tooth, previously treated to remove the layer of tissue affected by the disorder, so as to apply the restorative material at least on the zone covered by the layer of adhesive substance.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The technical characteristics of the invention, in accordance with the aims, are clearly described in the claims herein and the advantages are apparent from the detailed description which follows, with reference to the accompanying drawings, which illustrate a preferred embodiment of the invention, without limiting the scope of application, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a device for preparing the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative materials; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a power and control circuit to which the device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is connected; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an exploded schematic side view of a first preferred embodiment of a handpiece which is part of the device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a second preferred embodiment of a detail from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic front view of the device in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> operating inside the mouth of a patient.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the numeral <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> denotes as a whole a device for preparing the hard structures <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of teeth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> for the application of dental restorative materials, such as monomers, compound resins and similar products of the known type and widely used in the sector of dental restoration and reconstruction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comprises a handpiece <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which has a substantially tubular central grip <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> with longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the outside made of an insulating material, for example silicone rubber and similar materials, which allows the operator a good grip. Inside the grip, in a substantially coaxial position, there is a wire <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> connected to the two opposite ends of the grip with a first and a second socket (female), respectively labeled <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, of the known type and designed to receive in a removable fashion, that is to say, in such a way that it can be easily attached and removed, a connector <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and a connection and application head <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> whose use and operation are described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The connector <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a plug <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> designed for insertion in the first socket <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and is electrically connected, by an electrical cable <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, to a control power circuit, labeled <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as a whole. The circuit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> comprises a control block <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> connected at its output to an amplifier block <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a signal generator <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, which is in turn connected at its output to the amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which leads back to the control block <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> input is connected to a battery <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> which is in turn connected to a command block <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, whilst the amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> output is connected directly to the connector <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The command block is connected to an electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which can be inserted in the patient&apos;s mouth. The latter is normally called an intra-oral electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The circuit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is designed to power the handpiece <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> with an operating voltage which may reach values of 200 Volts, and with a current which can reach values of around 40 A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Obviously, the electrical power supply may be direct or alternating. If alternating, the operating frequency may reach around 1 GHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The above-mentioned connection and application head <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, once applied to the end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of the handpiece is designed to be electrically connected to the circuit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and, therefore, is designed to become an electrical distributor of the electrical power sent from the block <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> which can send direct or alternating signals, of sinusoidal, square wave, triangular ramp, step, pulse train and similar types. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the head <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> comprises a metal insert <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, one end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of which is designed for insertion, like a plug, in the second socket <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, to guarantee an electrical contact with the wire <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in the grip <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, whilst the other end <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> supports means <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> for moving the adhesive substance which may be a sponge, a brush or similar item. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the means <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> for moving the substance consist of a sponge <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> or similar means able to retain a substance and then release it every time it makes contact with a surface. Once the circuit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> has been activated and when the head <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has been moved towards a given zone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the surface <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the hard structure <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of a tooth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can subject the zone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to an electrical field. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 5</cross-reference>, the method for preparing the hard structure <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of a tooth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, inside a patient&apos;s mouth <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> for receiving restorative materials, using the device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, comprises steps of treating at least the given zone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> which is obviously affected, for example attached by a bacterial and inflammatory process such as decay and similar disorders. The treatment is normally of the mechanical type, and is carried out using tools such as dental burrs and drills able to remove the layer of tissue, of the hard structure <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the tooth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, affected by the disorder. Once this treatment has been carried out, the layer of debris produced during the previous mechanical treatment step is removed, in order to re-open the dentinal tubules. At this point, the operator brings the end <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the metal insert <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in the head <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> into contact with the given zone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, taking care to first soak up a suitable adhesive substance with the sponge <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. When the sponge <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> arrives at the given zone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the surface <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the hard structure <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of a tooth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the operator uses the block <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to activate the circuit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, which uses the generator <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to send an electrical signal to the handpiece <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which, through the wire <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, reaches the insert <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. In this way, an electrical field is created on the zone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the adhesive substance is subjected to a difference in potential, after ensuring that the electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is positioned at a point <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on the patient&apos;s body, for example in the mouth <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. This creates an electrokinetic force at the zone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> covered by the layer of adhesive material, able to move the adhesive substance evenly and deeply towards the innermost layers of the hard structure <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the tooth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In this way, the adhesive substance, moved by the passage of electrical charges, is distributed deep down inside the dentinal micro-tubules and covers the irregular surface of the tooth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> enamel. At this point the operator distributes a layer of restorative material on the zone <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> on which the adhesive substance was distributed, forming a structure for retaining the restorative material, without the disadvantages previously mentioned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As indicated above, the electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be applied to any area of the patient&apos;s body. Advantageously, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be applied in the mouth <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, for a clearer description, the mouth <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is divided into two parts <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>by a substantially symmetrical plane <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be placed at a point <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in a position on the side opposite the handpiece <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. In other words, to work on a tooth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the part <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the mouth, the electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> must be placed at the point <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on the part <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Vice versa, to work on a tooth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the part <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the mouth, the electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> must be placed at the point <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on the part <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the head <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may be made in such a way that it has a connecting portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in the socket <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, a tank <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for holding a given amount of the adhesive substance, and a point <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> for distribution of the adhesive substance. The point constitutes the means <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> for moving the adhesive substance. The method for the application of the adhesive substance is identical to that previously described relative to the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> It must be emphasized that for both embodiments illustrated the head <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is of the single-use type and can be substituted for each application cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The invention described can be subject to numerous modifications and variations without thereby departing from the scope of the inventive concept. Moreover, all the details of the invention may be substituted by technically equivalent elements. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) a method for preparing the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative materials, comprising the steps of treating at least an affected zone of the hard structure of the tooth, removing the layer of tissue affected by the disorder, applying a layer of adhesive substance to the zone treated and subjecting at least the adhesive substance to the action of an electrical field. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of generating an electrical field includes the application of a difference in potential between the zone treated and covered by the adhesive substance and a given point of the patient&apos;s body so as to generate, at least at the zone treated, an electrokinetic force due to the passage of an electrical current able to move the adhesive substance in an even, deep way inside the dentinal tubules and such that it covers the irregular surface of the enamel on the tooth. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the steps of applying a layer of adhesive substance and subjecting the adhesive substance to the action of an electrical field take place simultaneously and the layer of adhesive substance is applied while subjecting the layer of adhesive substance to the electrical field. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) The method according to any of the claims from <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, further comprising a step of removing the layer of debris deriving from the treatment of the affected zone, so as to re-open the dentinal tubules. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of demineralizing the surface layer of the dentin on the tooth, removing the mineral part and leaving the organic matrix. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) The method according to any of the claims from <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, further comprising a step of applying the restorative material at least on the zone covered by the layer of adhesive substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) The method according to any of the claims from <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, wherein the electrical field is produced by a voltage whose value may reach 200 Volts. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) The method according to any of the claims from <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, wherein the electrical field is produced by a current whose value may reach 40 A. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, wherein the two electrical quantities, voltage and current, are direct. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, wherein the two electrical quantities, voltage and current, are alternating and have an operating frequency which may reach 1 GHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) The method according to any of the claims from <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein the step of subjecting the adhesive substance to the action of an electrical field is carried out using a handpiece connected to a control power circuit, also connected to an electrode designed to be placed at any given point on the patient&apos;s body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of applying the layer of adhesive substance is carried out using the handpiece comprising an application head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the application head comprises means for containing and distributing the adhesive substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the containing and distributing means comprise a metal insert, one end of which bears a means for moving the adhesive substance at least on the zone treated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for moving the adhesive substance comprises a sponge-like element designed to soak up the adhesive substance and to be passed over the zone treated in order to apply a layer of the adhesive substance at least on the zone treated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electrode is an intra-oral electrode and is designed to be placed in the side of the mouth opposite that of the tooth on which the adhesive substance must be applied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) The method according to any of the claims from <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, wherein the application head is of the single-use type. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>) A device for preparing the hard structures of teeth for the application of dental restorative materials, comprising at least one handpiece connected to a control power circuit for applying an electrical field to at least one layer of adhesive substance applied at least to an affected zone of the hard structure of the tooth previously treated to remove the layer of tissue affected by the disorder, so as to apply the restorative material at least on the zone covered by the adhesive substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>) The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an electrode connected to the control power circuit and designed to be placed at any given point on the patient&apos;s body and operating in conjunction with the handpiece to apply a difference in potential between the zone treated and covered with the layer of adhesive substance and the given point of application of the electrode, thus generating, at least at the zone treated, an electrokinetic force due to the passage of electrical current able to move the adhesive substance in an even, deep way within the dentinal micro-tubules, so that it covers the irregular surface of the enamel of the tooth. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the handpiece comprises an application head for the layer of adhesive substance able to subject the adhesive substance to the action of the electrical field during its application to the zone treated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the application head comprises means for containing and distributing the adhesive substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the containing and distributing means comprise a metal insert, one end of the insert bearing means for moving the adhesive substance at least on the zone treated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>) The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for moving the adhesive substance comprises a sponge-like element designed to soak up the adhesive substance and to be passed over the zone treated, applying a layer of adhesive substance at least on the zone treated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electrode is an intra-oral electrode and is designed to be placed in the side of the mouth opposite that of the tooth on which the dental restorative material must be applied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>) The device according to any of the claims from <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, wherein the application head is of the single-use type.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003422A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003422A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003422A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003422A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
