<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002255A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002255A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002255A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002255A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002255A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002255A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002255A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002255A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002255A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002255A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002255A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002255A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002255</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10021936</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011213</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05K007/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>361</class>
<subclass>688000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and method for providing auxiliary cooling and thermal stability to an opto-electronic component</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60276402</doc-number>
<document-date>20010316</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Parviz</given-name>
<family-name>Tayebati</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boston</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Brian</given-name>
<family-name>Cranton</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Haverhill</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Daryoosh</given-name>
<family-name>Vakhshoori</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Cambridge</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Masud</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Azimi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Belmont</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kevin</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>McCallion</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Charlestown</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Pandiscio &amp; Pandiscio</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>470 Totten Pond Road</address-1>
<city>Waltham</city>
<state>MA</state>
<postalcode>02451-1914</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Apparatus is disclosed for providing auxiliary cooling and thermal stability to a temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, the apparatus comprising a primary thermal control system having a first thermal connection with a primary structure supporting at least one component of an optical system and a second thermal connection being thermally connected with an external environment; and an auxiliary thermal control system having a first thermal connection being thermally connected with the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, and the auxiliary thermal control system having a second thermal connection being thermally connected with the primary thermal control system whereby the auxiliary thermal control system provides cooling to the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component and the primary thermal control system provides additional cooling to the auxiliary thermal control system through temperature regulation of the primary structure. In one preferred embodiment of the present invention, the first thermal connection between the auxiliary thermal control system and the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component is structurally compliant so as to compensate for thermal expansion or contraction without effecting an optical alignment of the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component relative to the primary structure. In a preferred embodiment of the invention, targeted cooling power is provided to a selected opto-electronic device with an auxiliary cooling system so as to consume less power by cooling the selected opto-electronic device and allowing other components to function at a higher temperature. A method is disclosed for providing auxiliary cooling and thermal stability to the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, the method comprising providing an auxiliary control system, and cooling the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component with the auxiliary thermal control system. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">REFERENCE TO PENDING PRIOR PATENT APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This patent application claims benefit of pending prior U.S. Provisional Patent Application Serial No. 60/276,402, filed Mar. 16, 2001 by Kevin J. Knopp et al. for VERTICAL-CAVITY SURFACE-EMITTING LASER WITH CAVITY COMPENSATED GAIN (Attorney&apos;s Docket No. CORE-79 PROV), which patent application is hereby incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to semiconductor opto-electronic devices in general and, more particularly, to cooling of opto-electronic devices. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Most commercially available opto-electronic components are positioned on optical platforms designed to operate at 25&deg; C. Significantly better performance of some opto-electronic components is achieved at lower temperatures, such as 15&deg; C. or less. However, traditional thermal management systems for opto-electronic modules are limited in achieving low optical platform temperatures while supporting the high end of typical opto-electronic package operating temperature ranges. These operation temperature ranges include environments in excess of 70&deg;-80&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In addition, the optical alignment of the opto-electronic modules must not be compromised by the thermal management system and the overall module must be commercially viable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> One object of the present invention is, therefore, to provide a novel apparatus for cooling an opto-electronic device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a novel apparatus for cooling an opto-electronic device using an auxiliary cooling system thermally connected to the opto-electronic device and also thermally connected to a primary cooling device, and with the opto-electronic device being isolated from direct thermal effects of the primary cooling device. In a preferred embodiment of the invention, an independent temperature sensor, which is mounted close to the temperature sensitive components, is used to control the auxiliary cooling system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Yet another object of the present invention is to provide a novel method for cooling an opto-electronic device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Still another object of the present invention is to provide a novel method for cooling an opto-electronic device using an auxiliary cooling system thermally connected to the opto-electronic device and also thermally connected to a primary cooling device, and with the opto-electronic device being thermally isolated from direct effects of the primary cooling device. In a preferred embodiment of the invention, an independent temperature sensor, which is mounted close to the temperature sensitive components, is used to control the auxiliary cooling system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> And another embodiment of the present invention is to provide a novel apparatus for targeting cooling power to a selected opto-electronic device with an auxiliary cooling system so as to consume less power by cooling the selected opto-electronic device and allowing other components to function at a higher temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Yet still another object of the present invention is to provide a novel method for selectively targeting a disproportionately large amount of cooling power to selected components which benefit from that additional cooling without targeting excess cooling power to other components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> These and other objects of the present invention are addressed by the provision and use of a novel method and apparatus for cooling an opto-electronic device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a feature of the present invention, there is provided a novel apparatus for providing auxiliary cooling and thermal stability to a temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, the apparatus comprising: a primary thermal control system having a first thermal connection with a primary structure supporting at least one component of an optical system and a second thermal connection being thermally connected with an external environment; and an auxiliary thermal control system having a first thermal connection being thermally connected with the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, and the auxiliary thermal control system having a second thermal connection being thermally connected with the primary thermal control system whereby the auxiliary thermal control system provides cooling to the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component and the primary thermal control system provides additional cooling to the auxiliary thermal control system through temperature regulation of the primary structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a further feature of the present invention, there is provided a novel method for providing auxiliary cooling and thermal stability to a temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, the method comprising: providing an apparatus comprising: an apparatus for providing auxiliary cooling and thermal stability to a temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, the apparatus comprising: a primary thermal control system having a first thermal connection with a primary structure supporting at least one component of an optical system and a second thermal connection being thermally connected with an external environment; and an auxiliary thermal control system having a first thermal connection being thermally connected with the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, and the auxiliary thermal control system having a second thermal connection being thermally connected with the primary thermal control system whereby the auxiliary thermal control system provides cooling to the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component and the primary thermal control system provides additional cooling to the auxiliary thermal control system through temperature regulation of said primary structure; and cooling the temperature sensitive opto-electronic component with the auxiliary thermal control system.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects and features of the present invention will be more fully discussed in the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments of the invention, which is to be considered together with the accompanying drawings wherein like numbers refer to like parts, and further wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagrammatical view of an optical platform having an auxiliary thermal management system including a thermally conductive flexure to thermally connect a temperature sensitive component attached to an insulated mount to an auxiliary cooling device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagrammatical view of an optical platform having an auxiliary thermal management system including intermeshed fins to thermally connect a sensitive component attached to an insulated mount to an auxiliary cooling device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagrammatical view of an optical platform having an auxiliary thermal management system including a structurally compliant, thermally conductive plate to thermally connect a temperature sensitive component attached to an insulated mount to an auxiliary cooling device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagrammatical view of an optical platform having an auxiliary thermal management system including thermally conductive strands to thermally connect a temperature sensitive component attached to an insulated mount to an auxiliary cooling device; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of an optical platform having an auxiliary thermal management system including a thermal connection between a temperature sensitive component attached to an insulated mount and an auxiliary cooling device.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A system <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> for providing auxiliary cooling and temperature stability to a temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, such as a sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, system <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> generally includes an optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> having a primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a thermally insulated mount <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> in attachment to optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, an auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in attachment to optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and a thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, e.g., a flexure <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>A, a set of intermeshed fins <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>B, a structurally compliant plate <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>C, and conductive strands <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>D. In a preferred embodiment of the invention, thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> includes a structurally compliant heat path for heat exchange with temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Such a compliant connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> compensates for thermal expansion or contraction without effecting the optical alignment or performance of temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Still referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> generally comprises a heating/cooling source, such as a thermo-electric cooler or, TEC, herein shown as reference number <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and an auxiliary cooling system temperature sensor (not shown) separate from the temperature sensor used in the primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment of the invention, the cooling effect of auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is supplemented by primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Now looking at FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, four design variations are shown with each having a different thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to create flexible, thermally conductive paths. In each of these variations, temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is securely attached to optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> by thermally insulated mount <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment of the invention, the auxiliary cooling system temperature sensor (not shown) is mounted directly to temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to maximize temperature control and stability of auxiliary thermal management system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Looking at <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, in a preferred embodiment of the invention, thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprises thermally conductive flexure <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>A between temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment of the invention, temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is thermally isolated from optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and is supported in optical alignment, by thermally isolating mount <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Flexure <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>A is compliant to provide a conductive heat path between sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The compliant heat path allows auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> cool and to closely regulate the temperature of the thermally isolated sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> while flexure <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>A compensates for any thermal expansion or contraction in thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. This compensation of flexure <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>A during heat transfer prevents the optical alignment of sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from being disturbed. Simultaneously, primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> regulates the temperature of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and any other components (not shown) in attachment thereto. As such, primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is configured in a preferred embodiment of the invention to provide temperature regulation of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and additional cooling to auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Due to this additional cooling, auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is able to provide additional cooling to temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Looking at <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, in a preferred embodiment of the invention, thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprises intermeshed fins <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>B between temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment of the invention, temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is thermally isolated from optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and is supported in optical alignment, by thermally isolating mount <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Intermeshed fins <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>B can move independent of each other while still providing a conductive heat path between temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The structurally adjustable heat path allows auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to cool and closely regulate the temperature of thermally isolated sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> while intermeshed fins <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>B compensate for any thermal expansion or contradiction in thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. This compensation of intermeshed fins <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>B during heat transfer prevents the optical alignment of temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from being disturbed. Simultaneously, primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> regulates the temperature of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and any other components (not shown) in attachment thereto. As such, primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is configured to in this preferred embodiment of the invention to provide temperature regulation of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and additional cooling to auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Due to this additional cooling, auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is able to provide additional cooling to temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Looking at <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, in a preferred embodiment of the invention, thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprises structurally compliant plate <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>C between temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment of the invention, temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is thermally isolated from optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and is supported in optical alignment, by thermally isolating mount <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Structurally compliant plate <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>C provides a conductive heat path between temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The compliant heat path allows auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to cool and closely regulate the temperature of thermally isolated temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> while structurally compliant plate <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>C compensates for any thermal expansion or contraction in thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. This compensation of structurally compliant plate <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>C during heat transfer prevents the optical alignment of sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from being disturbed. Simultaneously, primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> regulates the temperature of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and any other components (not shown) in attachment thereto. As such, primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is configured in this preferred embodiment of the invention to provide temperature regulation of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and additional cooling to auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Due to this additional cooling, auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is able to provide additional cooling to temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Looking at <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, in a preferred embodiment of the invention, thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprises one or more thermally conductive strands <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>D between temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment of the invention, temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is thermally isolated from optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and is supported in optical alignment, by thermally isolating mount <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Conductive strands <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>D provide a structurally compliant, thermally conductive heat path. This heat path allows auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to cool and closely regulate the temperature of thermally isolated temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> while conductive strands <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>D compensate for any thermal expansion or contraction over thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. This compensation of conductive strands <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>D during heat transfer prevents the optical alignment of sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from being disturbed. Simultaneously, primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> regulates the temperature of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and any other components (not shown) in attachment thereto. As such, primary thermal control system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is configured in this preferred embodiment of the invention to provide temperature regulation of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and additional cooling to auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Due to this additional cooling, auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is able to provide additional cooling to temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, in another preferred embodiment of the invention, system <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is shown with temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> thermally isolated from optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and supported in optical alignment, by mount <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. In this preferred embodiment of the invention, thermal connection <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is structurally compliant and thermally conductive to provide a heat path between temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Such a compliant heat path allows auxiliary thermal component <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to cool and regulate the temperature of thermally isolated temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> without affecting the optical alignment, shown as reference numeral <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, of temperature sensitive temperature component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and optical component <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The primary thermal control system (not shown) may regulate the temperature of optical platform <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, optical component <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, and other components (not shown) in attachment thereto. In other preferred embodiments of the invention, the primary thermal control system (not shown) may be configured to directly or indirectly provide additional cooling to auxiliary thermal control system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Such additional cooling may in turn provide additional cooling to temperature sensitive component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for providing auxiliary cooling and thermal stability to a temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, said apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a primary thermal control system having a first thermal connection being thermally connected with a primary structure supporting at least one component of an optical system and a second thermal connection being thermally connected with an external environment; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an auxiliary thermal control system having a first thermal connection being thermally connected with said temperature sensitive opto-electronic component, and said auxiliary thermal control system having a second thermal connection being thermally connected with said primary thermal control system whereby said auxiliary thermal control system provides cooling to said temperature sensitive opto-electronic component and said primary thermal control system provides additional cooling to said auxiliary thermal control system through temperature regulation of said primary structure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an auxiliary structure configured to thermally isolate said temperature sensitive opto-electronic component from each of said primary thermal control system and said primary structure in thermal connection with said primary thermal control system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first thermal connection between said auxiliary thermal control system and said temperature sensitive opto-electronic component is structurally compliant wherein said compliant thermal connection compensates for thermal expansion or contraction without effecting an optical alignment of said temperature sensitive opto-electronic component relative to said primary structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said compliant thermal connection comprises a thermally conductive flexure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said compliant thermal connection comprises a set of thermally connected, structurally independent intermeshed fins. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said compliant thermal connection comprises a thermally conductive plate having structural flexibility means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said structural flexibility means comprise a corrugated plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said compliant thermal connection comprises at least one flexible and thermally conductive strand. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said primary structure supporting said at least one temperature sensitive component of an optical system comprises an optical platform. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said auxiliary thermal control system comprises a thermo-electric device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said auxiliary thermal control system further comprises a temperature sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said temperature sensor of said auxiliary thermal control system has a strong thermal connection with said temperature sensitive opto-electronic component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said temperature sensor of said auxiliary thermal control system comprises a direct structural connection to said opto-electronic component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said primary thermal control system comprises a temperature sensitive thermoelectric device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said primary thermal control system further comprises a temperature sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said temperature sensor of said auxiliary thermal control system comprises a thermal connection with said primary structure supporting said at least one component of an optical system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said primary structure supporting said at least one component of an optical system comprises an optical platform. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said temperature sensor of said primary thermal control system comprises a thermal connection with one of said at least one component supported by said primary structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said auxiliary thermal control system further comprises a temperature sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said temperature sensor of said auxiliary thermal control system comprises a thermal connection with a thermo-electric device of said auxiliary thermal control system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said temperature sensitive opto-electronic component is alignment sensitive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said alignment sensitive opto-electronic component is aligned with one of said at least one component of said optical system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said opto-electronic component is aligned with one of said at least one component of said optical system.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002255A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002255A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002255A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002255A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002255A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002255A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
