<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002760A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002760A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002760A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002760A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002760A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002760A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002760A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002760A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002760</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10169082</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020708</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-83629</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000324</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F16C027/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>384</class>
<subclass>536000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Center bearing support</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tsuyoshi</given-name>
<family-name>Tatsumura</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Fujisawa-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JACOBSON HOLMAN PLLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>400 SEVENTH STREET N.W.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 600</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/JP01/02336</doc-number>
<document-date>20010323</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">To improve a shock-absorbing property of a center bearing support (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) by a stopper (<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>) at a time when a vibration displacement of a supported shaft is increased, in the center bearing support (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) with an inner ring (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) being provided in the inner periphery of an outer ring (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) fixed to the side of a vehicle body via an elastic body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) made of an elastomer material, and a center bearing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) being mounted to the inner periphery of the inner ring (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>), a stopper (<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>) extending in a taper shape is formed at an end portion (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) of a flexible main body (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>) in the elastic body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>), and a rib (<highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>) is formed between the stopper (<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>) and the end portion (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) of the flexible main body (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>) at a predetermined phase interval, so that a deforming force applied by the stopper (<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>) being in contact with the side of the outer ring (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) at a time when an excessive displacement is input is absorbed by a displacement of the end portion (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) of the flexible main body (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>) , whereby it is possible to restrict a sudden increase of a spring constant. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a center bearing support which elastically supports a center bearing rotatably supporting a propeller shaft of a motor vehicle to the side of a vehicle body. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The center bearing support is structured such as to elastically support a center bearing (ball bearing) mounted to the outer periphery at a predetermined position in the axial direction of a propeller shaft (not shown) of a motor vehicle to the side of a vehicle body, thereby restricting a vibration of the propeller shaft during traveling, and reducing a vibration transmission between the side of the propeller shaft and the side of the vehicle body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, conventionally, as this kind of center bearing support <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, there is a structure in which an outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> mounted to the side of a vehicle body and an inner ring <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> fitly attached to a center bearing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and arranged in the inner periphery thereof are elastically connected via an elastic body <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> formed of an elastomer material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The elastic body <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is structured such that a pair of flexible main bodies <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in a J-like bent shape and being symmetrical with each other in the axial direction extend from both ends in the axial direction of a thick base portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>vulcanized and bonded to the inner ring <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and outer peripheral end portions thereof are pressure inserted and fitted to the inner periphery of the outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> in a fixing manner. Further, a stopper <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>protruding out to the outer peripheral side between the flexible main bodies <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>so as to form a taper shape is formed in the base portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. This stopper <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is structured such as to be in contact with the outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> at a time when an amplitude of the propeller shaft is increased to be a fixed level or more, thereby to effect buffering. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> However, in accordance with the conventional center bearing support, since the stopper <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is formed in the outer periphery of the base portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the elastic body <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, as shown by a characteristic graph in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, when a displacement of the propeller shaft is further increased after the stopper <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is in contact with the inner peripheral surface of the outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> due to a displacement of the propeller shaft in the diametrical direction, a spring constant becomes suddenly high from a certain displacement amount (in this embodiment, near 8 mm) , so that there is pointed out a problem that it is impossible to obtain a sufficient shock-absorbing property. This is because the stopper <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>generates a bending deformation at an initial time when it is in contact with the outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, thereby being soft, however, is exposed to a compression deformation between the outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and the base portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the elastic body <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> at a time of completely falling down, thereby becoming hard. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention is made by taking the problem mentioned above into consideration, and a main technical object thereof is to improve a shock-absorbing property applied by a stopper at a time when a vibration displacement of a supported shaft is increased. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As a means for effectively solving the technical object mentioned above, there is provided a center bearing support in which an inner ring is provided in the inner periphery of an outer ring fixed to the side of a vehicle body via an elastic body made of an elastomer material, and a center bearing rotatably supporting a supported shaft is mounted to the inner periphery of the inner ring, wherein a stopper is formed in one end portion of a flexible main body in the elastic body, the stopper being capable of bending to deform due to contact with the side of another end portion. That is, the stopper is formed in the end portion of the flexible main body, whereby a part of deformation force generated by the stopper contact is absorbed, and it is possible to restrict sudden increase of a spring constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, more preferably, ribs are formed between the stopper and the one end portion of the flexible main body at a predetermined phase interval. That is, it is possible to secure a desired spring constant at a time of the stopper contact due to the ribs.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a partial front view showing a preferable embodiment of a center bearing support in accordance with the present invention in a partly broken manner; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view along a line II-II in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an enlarged cross sectional view of a main portion of the center bearing support in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a characteristic graph showing a spring property of the center bearing support in accordance with the present invention by comparing with that of a conventional art; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a half sectional view showing a center bearing support in accordance with the conventional art by cutting along a plane passing through an axis; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a characteristic graph showing a spring property in accordance with the conventional art.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a partial front view showing a preferable embodiment of a center bearing support in accordance with the present invention in a partly broken manner, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view along a line II-II in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> That is, this center bearing support <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is constituted of a pair of outer rings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> pressure inserted and fitly attached to the inner peripheral surface of an annular bracket <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> fixed to the side of a vehicle body via a mount (not shown) or the like from both sides in the axial direction thereof, a pair of inner rings <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> arranged in the inner peripheries of the outer rings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, and holding a center bearing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> rotatably supporting a propeller shaft (not shown) and oil seals <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> arranged in both sides in the axial direction thereof, and an elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> elastically connecting between each of the outer rings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and each of the inner rings <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The outer rings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are made of a metal, for example, SPCC or SPHC or the like in accordance with Japanese Industrial Standards, and are formed in a symmetrical shape with each other with respect to a flat surface orthogonal to the axis, and flange portions II<highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>brought into contact with both end edges in the axial direction of the bracket <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are formed in end portions facing to the opposite sides each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The inner rings <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are made of a metal, for example, SPCC or SPCE or the like in accordance with Japanese Industrial Standards, and are formed in a symmetrical shape with each other with respect to a flat surface orthogonal to the axis, and bearing mounting portions <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having an outer race <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the center bearing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> pressure inserted and fitly attached are formed in end portions opposing to each other in the axial direction, and oil seal mounting portions <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>having a diameter smaller than the bearing mounting portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and having the oil seals <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> pressure inserted and fitly attached to the inner peripheries thereof are formed in end portions in the opposite side, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The elastic bodies <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are vulcanized and molded with an elastomer material, flexible main bodies <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> thereof are formed in a fold-back shape, the cross section of which is convex outward in the axial direction in the middle in the diametrical direction, and symmetrically with each other, outer peripheral end portions <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are integrally vulcanized and bonded to the inner peripheral surfaces of the outer rings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> respectively, and inner peripheral base portions <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are vulcanized and bonded to the outer peripheral surfaces of the inner rings <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> extending from an inner peripheral end portion <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> to the outer peripheral side and the inner side in the axial direction so as to form a taper shape is formed in the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> extending from the inner peripheral base portion <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in each of the elastic bodies <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, also as shown by an enlarged view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, and a front end portion thereof opposes to the inner surface of the outer peripheral end portion <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> (the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>) in the diametrical direction with a predetermined distance (for example, about 5.5 mm). Further, a lot of ribs <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> extending in the radial direction are formed between the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and the inner peripheral end portion <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> at a predetermined phase interval (for example, at an interval of 30 degrees). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> As the center bearing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, basically a ball bearing having a known structure constituted of an outer race <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and an inner race <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> concentrically arranged with each other, and a lot of steel balls <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> rotatably held between them with a uniform interval in a circumferential direction are used, and the outer race <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is pressure inserted and fitly attached to the bearing mounting portions <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the inner rings <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and the inner peripheral surface of the inner race <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is fitly attached to the outer peripheral surface of the propeller shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Further, the steel ball <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is lubricated with a grease <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The grease <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is injected to the oil seal mounting portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of each of the inner rings <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and is sealed by the oil seal <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the inner peripheral end of which contacts closely to the outer peripheral surface of the propeller shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the structure mentioned above, for example, in the case that a vibration is generated in the propeller shaft at a normal traveling of the motor vehicle, only the flexible main bodies <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> of the elastic bodies <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are exposed to the bending deformation in correspondence to a repeated relative eccentric motion between the inner ring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the side of the propeller shaft and the outer ring <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the side of the vehicle body due to a vibration input. Accordingly, a spring constant is small, and a vibration transmission to the side of the vehicle body can be effectively isolated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Further, when a displacement due to the input vibration reaches a predetermined displacement amount, the outer peripheral end portion <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> vulcanized and bonded to the inner peripheral surface of each of the outer rings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the front end portion of the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> are in contact with each other. Accordingly, since in addition to the bending deformation of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> of the elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is exposed to the bending deformation in a direction shown by an arrow F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, and the rib <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> in the inner periphery is exposed to the compression deformation, the spring constant increases from a contact starting point of the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> as shown by a solid line in the characteristic graph in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, however, a rate of increase thereof is restricted to be low. This is because the compression spring constant of the elastomer material shows a non-linear increase with respect to a displacement, whereby the spring constant thereof is small at an early period of the compression deformation of the rib <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>, and further, a part of the deforming force F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> applied to the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and the rib <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> is absorbed by the inner peripheral end portion <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> being displaced in a direction shown by an arrow F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Further, in the conventional structure previously described and shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, when the relative displacement amount between the outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and the inner ring <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> further increases after the stopper <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>has been in contact with the outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, the fallen down stopper <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is exposed to the compression between the base portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the outer ring <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, whereby the spring constant suddenly increases as shown by a broken line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. On the other hand, in accordance with the structure of the present invention, since a part of the deforming force F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the diametrical direction applied to the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and the rib <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> is absorbed by the inner peripheral end portion <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> being displaced in the direction of F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as mentioned above, the rate of increase of the spring constant becomes gentle in comparison with the conventional one, and can achieve an excellent shock-absorbing property. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Further, for example, in the case of forming the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> near a curved middle portion of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, there is a risk that a normal bending deformation motion of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> is prevented by the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> being held in, however, in the case of employing the structure in which the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> extends from a portion between the base portion in each of the elastic bodies <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and the middle portion of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, preferably extends from the end portion of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, as in the present invention, the risk mentioned above is removed. Accordingly, it is possible to secure the normal bending deformation motion of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> and it is possible to obtain an excellent shock-absorbing property applied by the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In manufacturing the center bearing support <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having the structure mentioned above, it is possible to obtain a mold product in which the elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is integrally vulcanized and bonded in the outer ring <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the inner ring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by concentrically arranging the outer ring <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the inner ring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with each other within metal molds separated in the axial direction and charging a molding material into a forming space defined between the outer ring <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the inner ring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to vulcanize and mold. Next, it is possible to assemble in a state shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> by respectively pressure inserting and fitly attaching the oil seals <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to the oil seal mounting portions <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the inner ring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, thereafter pressure inserting and fitly attaching the respective outer rings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the molded product to the bracket <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> from both sides in the axial direction, and pressure inserting and fitly attaching the bearing mounting portions <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the respective inner rings <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to the outer races <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the center bearing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In this case, for example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> which is previously described, since in the conventional structure in which the elastic body <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> having a pair of flexible main bodies <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is integrally vulcanized and molded vulcanized and bonded in the outer periphery of the inner ring <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a mold releasing direction after molding the elastic body <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is the diametrical direction, it is impossible to form the elastic body <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> in a shape in which the flexible main body <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the stopper <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>overlap with each other in the diametrical direction. On the contrary, in accordance with the center bearing support <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the aspect shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a mold releasing direction of the metal mold after forming the elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is the axial direction, so that a difficulty in mold release is not generated even in the case that the outer peripheral portion of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and the rib <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> in the elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> overlap in the diametrical direction as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Further, therefore the size in the axial direction of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> does not become so large as in the case of forming the elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in the shape in which the outer peripheral portion of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> and the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> do not overlap in the diametrical direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Further, since the center bearing support <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> supports the propeller shaft near the middle joint portion thereof, in the case that the propeller shaft oscillates around the end portion of the front side thereof, the vibration in a pinching direction is input to the center bearing support <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and amounts of displacement applied to the elastic bodies <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are different from each other. In accordance with the structure of the present invention, since the elastic bodies <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are independent from each other, it is possible to execute modification such as giving different spring constants to both of the elastic bodies <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, making the contact starting points of both of the stoppers <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> different from each other, or the like by changing the bending shape or the thickness of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> or the elastomer material for example, so as to correspond to the pinch vibration mentioned above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In this case, the present invention is not limited to the illustrated aspect, and the present invention can be executed by forming the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and the rib <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> in the same manner as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, for example, with respect to the center bearing support in which the single elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is provided. Further, the same effect can be expected even by forming the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and the rib <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> in the inner periphery of the outer peripheral end portion of the flexible main body <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, whereby the stopper <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is in contact with the inner peripheral end portion of the elastic body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> at a time when an excessive displacement is input. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As described above, in accordance with the center bearing support of the present invention, by elastically supporting the center bearing mounted to the propeller shaft of the motor vehicle in the side of the vehicle body, the vibration of the propeller shaft during the travel is restricted, and the vibration transmission between the side of the propeller shaft and the side of the vehicle body is reduced, and by providing the rib in the stopper, the desired spring constant against the excessive displacement input is secured, and by forming the stopper in the end portion of the flexible main body in the elastic body, whereby a part of the deforming force applied to the stopper and the rib is absorbed by the displacement of the end portion of the flexible main body, the spring constant does not suddenly increase at a time when the stopper operates, and it is possible to achieve an excellent shock-absorbing property. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A center bearing support (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) in which an inner ring (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) is provided in the inner periphery of an outer ring (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) fixed to the side of a vehicle body via an elastic body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) made of an elastomer material, and a center bearing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) rotatably supporting a supported shaft is mounted to the inner periphery of the inner ring (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>), wherein a stopper (<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>) is formed in one end portion (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) of a flexible main body (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>) in the elastic body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>), the stopper being capable of bending to deform due to a contact with the side of another end portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A center bearing support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein ribs (<highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>) are formed between the stopper (<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>) and the one end portion (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) of the flexible main body (<highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>) at a predetermined phase interval.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002760A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002760A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002760A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002760A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
