<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002952A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002952A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002952</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10149997</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020611</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-000673</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000106</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F16B023/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>411</class>
<subclass>403000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>081</class>
<subclass>441000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Combination of screw and screw driver bit and header punch for its manufacture</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Katsuyuki</given-name>
<family-name>Totsu</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Jordan &amp; Hamburg</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>122 East 42nd Street</address-1>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10168</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/JP00/09199</doc-number>
<document-date>20001225</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A combination of a screw and a screw driver bit and a header punch for its manufacture capable of effectively preventing a come-out phenomenon of the screw driver bit by improving the structure of a groove part in a cross groove part in a cross groove of a screw to prevent a conventional damage. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a screw, a screw driver bit to be applied to the screw, and a header punch for manufacturing the screw. More particularly, it relates to a combination of a screw and a screw driver bit that ensures tight fitting of the bit-fitting groove of cross groove formed in the screw head, and the screw driver bit to fit into the bit-fitting groove, and can rapidly and securely achieve the attaching and detaching of the screw always by proper torque transmission, and a header punch for the manufacture of the screw. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A conventional general combination of a screw and a screw driver bit, which is configured as shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, is known. That is, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</cross-reference> show a conventional screw having a cross groove, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> shows a screw driver bit for this cross-grooved screw, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> shows the state of fitting of the above-described screw and the screw driver bit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The conventional screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is provided, on a screw head part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>thereof, with a cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. This cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is configured in such a manner that a specified tilted groove part <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed in the direction from each end edge part so as to extend to the center part of a screw neck part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and, at the same time, in the bottom part thereof is formed a roughly conical bottom face <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> with a gentle inclination. Incidentally, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, reference numeral <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> each denotes a tapered side wall part formed between adjacent cross grooves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. That is, the cutting-edge part of a screw driver bit, which will be described later, abuts and engages with this tapered side wall part <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, in the adjacent corner parts of each of the above-described tilted groove parts <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are formed taper connection faces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which extend from the position of the conical bottom face <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to the opening edge part of the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the screw head part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and also against these taper connection faces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>abuts and engages a portion of the cutting-edge part of a screw driver bit, which will be described later. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, a conventional screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is configured in such a manner that the screw driver bit is provided with cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, each of which fits into the respective cross grooves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the above-described screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and there are formed extended cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, each of which extends so as to match the shape of the tilted groove parts <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed in the direction from the end edge parts of the above-described cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to the center part of the screw neck part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Incidentally, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, reference numeral <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> denotes tapered side wall parts formed on both side faces of each of the above-described cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and extended cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. That is, these tapered side wall parts <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> abut and engage against the tapered side wall parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> formed in the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the above-described screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> According to a combination of the conventional screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> thus configured, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, by causing the screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to fit into each other, as described above, each of the cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and each of the extended cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>fit into the tilted groove parts <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the side wall parts <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the above-described cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and extended cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>abut against the tapered side wall parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Therefore, by rotating the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a prescribed torque can be transmitted to the screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. That is, it is possible to perform the attaching and detaching of the screw in a specified object to be mounted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> However, according to the combination of the conventional screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> configured as mentioned above, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the screw head part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has a specified tilted groove part <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which is formed in the direction from the end edge part of the cross groove to the center part of the screw neck part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and, on the other hand, the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which fits into the screw is configured in such a manner that the ridgeline part of the extended cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>matches the shape of the above-described tilted groove part <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and fits into the above-described cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and, furthermore, this ridgeline part of the extended cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed in such a manner that the width increases gradually in the direction from the leading end thereof to the rear. In addition, also the tapered side wall part <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> formed in each cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the screwdriver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> abuts and engages with the tapered side wall part <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> formed in the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Therefore, when the above-described screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is rotated in a prescribed direction, the resulting contact between the above-described screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is such a state that can be said to be totally tapered contact, with the result that the leading end of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> tends to come out along the inclined plane of the tilted groove part <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the above-described cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (indicated by an arrow in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>), leading to the occurrence of what is called a come-out phenomenon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In particular, the shape of the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the conventional screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is such that, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, in order to facilitate the fitting of the leading end of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the groove width of the cross groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is formed in a larger size than the width of the ridgeline part of the extended cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, whereas the areas of the tapered side wall part <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and taper connection faces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the boundary parts between adjacent cross grooves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and in the corner parts thereof are relatively small. For this reason, when by the rotating operation of the above-described screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> large loads are applied to the above-described tapered side wall parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and taper connection faces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the screw tightening resistance is large, the above-described tapered side wall part <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and taper connection faces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are gradually damaged as indicated by shaded portions <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. Therefore, if these damaged portions (shaded portions <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) are expanded, the occurrence of the come-out phenomenon of the above-described screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> becomes frequent, eventually making a screw tightening operation impossible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, the occurrence of this come-out phenomenon brings about the drawback that the cutting-edge part at the leading end of the screw driver bit is worn, for example, in the case of a tapping screw, because the design surface hardness of this screw is high. Also, in the case of a clutch-type automatic screw driver having a torque control function, there is a drawback that when the come-out phenomenon occurs during screw tightening, the operator cannot judge whether the screw has been securely attached with an appropriate torque. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In order to prevent the come-out phenomenon of the above-described screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> from these standpoints, in the rotation of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> it is necessary to apply a thrust which strongly pushes the screw driver bit against the screw groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. However, although there is no problem when the object to which the screw is to be attached is a rigid body such as metal, in the case of a precision component etc. there is a drawback that these objects are damaged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Also, the occurrence of the come-out phenomenon accelerates the wear of the leading end parts of the bit, i.e., the cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and extended cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and the wear of these parts further promotes the occurrence of the above-described come-out phenomenon, with the result that there is a drawback that the damage to the screw groove also increases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, although it is possible to prevent the above-described come-out phenomenon by applying an excessive thrust to the above-described screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, on the other hand an accurate torque cannot be transmitted to the screw and the magnitude of torque applied to the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> differs from operator to operator, with the result that there is a drawback that variations occur in the screw tightening torque. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when screw tightening is manually performed, it costs the operator great labor and fatigue to perform the operation of rotating the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, with the screw driver bit being sufficiently pushed against the screw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Also, according to the combination of the above-described conventional screw <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and screw driver bit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, when screw attaching is performed by use of a manual tool or motor-driven tool, in the fitting of the leading end parts of the bit into the screw groove it is difficult to perform the rotating operation of the screw while keeping the axis of the screw and the axis of the screw driver bit in a coaxial state. Therefore, when there is an inclination between the axis of the screw and the axis of the screw driver bit, there is a drawback that the above-described come-out phenomenon occurs frequently and that besides the damage to the screw groove also occurs frequently, thereby reducing the working efficiency of screw tightening operation and, at the same time, incurring waste of expenses caused by the consumption of damaged screws. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Moreover, also in the screw detaching work, the same come-out phenomenon and damage to the screw groove are apt to occur and, in this case, the detaching of the screw becomes impossible and hence it becomes unavoidable to break a portion of the object to which the screw is attached. In particular, in the case of occurrence of the clogging of the interior of the screw groove with dust and the like, the occurrence of the above-described situation becomes remarkable and, for example, there is a drawback that separation work for the recycling of waste materials involving the detaching of the screw becomes complicated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present inventors devoted themselves to conducting a series of research and trial manufacture and, as a result, found out that, in a screw which is formed so that a bit-fitting groove formed of a cross groove is provided in a screw head part, a specified tilted groove part is formed in the direction from the end edge part of the bit-fitting groove to the center part of a screw neck part, and a roughly conical bottom face is formed at a cross center part, by forming the end edge part of the above-described bit-fitting groove as a generally vertical end wall part of a specified depth, by forming a groove part with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg; in the direction from the lower edge part of the end wall part to the conical bottom face at the center part of the screw neck part, and further by forming the conical bottom face with a gentle inclination angle &agr; of approximately 28&deg;, it is possible to securely prevent the come-out phenomenon of the screw driver bit during the fitting of the screw driver bit into the screw groove, to substantially reduce damage to the screw by increasing the strength of the screw, and besides to achieve well-balanced torque transmission to the screw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It is therefore the object of the invention to provide a combination of a screw and a screw driver bit in which by improving the structure of a groove part in a cross groove of the screw, damage to the screw as in a conventional screw is prevented by effectively preventing the come-out phenomenon of the screw driver bit and in which even if the cross groove part of the screw is damaged, a proper and rapid screw tightening operation can always be achieved and the working efficiency can be remarkably increased, and a header punch for manufacturing the screw. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve the above-described object, the screw related to the invention is a screw which is formed so that a bit-fitting groove formed of a cross groove is provided in a screw head part, a specified tilted groove part is formed in the direction from the end edge part of the bit-fitting groove to the center part of a screw neck part, and a roughly conical bottom face is formed at a cross center part, which is characterized in that the end edge part of the above-described bit-fitting groove is formed as a generally vertical end wall part of a specified depth, that a groove part with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg; is formed in the direction from the lower edge part of the end wall part to the conical bottom face at the center part of the screw neck part, and further that the conical bottom face is formed with a gentle inclination angle &agr; of approximately 28&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In this case, the tilted groove part with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg;, which is formed in the direction from the lower edge part of end edge part of the above-described bit-fitting groove to the conical bottom face at the center part of the screw neck part, can be configured in such a manner that the tilted groove part is bulged inward to the bit-fitting groove in curved form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Also, grooves with a width generally widening toward the end can be formed from the center part of the above-described screw head part outward in the radial direction so that the opening angle of opposed side wall parts of each of said adjacent grooves is a little sharper than a right angle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, a screw driver bit to be applied to the above-described screw related to the invention is provided, at the leading end thereof, with a flat cutting-edge part in which is formed a generally vertical end edge part that fits along a generally vertical end wall part of a bit-fitting groove of a screw head part, and the leading end face of this cutting-edge part is formed as a conical projection having an inclination angle of about 1&deg; to 45&deg; with respect to a horizontal plane so as to fit into the above-described screw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In this case, wall parts on both sides at the leading end of the above-described flat cutting-edge part can be configured in a shape with a width widening toward the end so as to fit into the bit-fitting groove of the screw formed with a width generally widening toward the end, the bit-fitting groove of the screw being formed from the center part of the screw neck part outward in the radial direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the header punch for manufacturing the above-described screw related to the invention is provided with projecting pieces for forming the generally vertical end wall part and the tilted groove part with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg; in the end edge part of bit-fitting groove of the screw head part and has a conical projection for forming the conical bottom face with a gentle inclination angle &agr; of about 28&deg; in the direction from these projecting pieces to the center part of the screw neck part. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an essential sectional side view which shows an embodiment of a screw related to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a plan view of the head part of the screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an essential sectional side view which shows another embodiment of a screw related to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a plan view of the head part of the screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) is a plan view of the head part of a screw which shows a further embodiment related to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) is a plan view of the head part of a screw which shows an example of modification of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an essential side view of a header punch for manufacturing screws for forming the head part of the screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an essential enlarged side view which shows an embodiment of a screw driver bit related to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an essential enlarged perspective view of the screw driver bit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an essential enlarged sectional side view which shows how a screw driver bit of the invention fits into the screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an essential enlarged sectional plan view of a screw head part which shows how a screw driver bit of the invention fits into the screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an essential sectional side view which shows another embodiment of a screw related to the invention and an outline of the fitting state of a screw driver bit which fits into this screw; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is an essential sectional side view of a conventional cross-grooved screw; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a plan view of the head part of the cross-grooved screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is an essential side view of a screw driver bit for conventional cross-grooved screws; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is an essential sectional side view which shows the connected state between the screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> and the screw driver bit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number>  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(Description of Symbols)</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="42PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="161PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>30</entry>
<entry>Screw</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>30&prime;</entry>
<entry>Plus-and-minus screw</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>30a</entry>
<entry>Screw head part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>30b</entry>
<entry>Screw neck part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>32</entry>
<entry>Bit-fitting groove</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>32A, 32B</entry>
<entry>Groove of plus-and-minus screw</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>32a</entry>
<entry>End edge part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>32a&prime;</entry>
<entry>Lower edge part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>32b</entry>
<entry>Tilted groove part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>32b&prime;</entry>
<entry>Bulge in curved form</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>33</entry>
<entry>Side wall part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>33a, 33b</entry>
<entry>Groove with a width widening toward the end</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>34</entry>
<entry>Conical bottom face</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>37a, 37b</entry>
<entry>Taper connection face</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>40</entry>
<entry>Header punch</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>42</entry>
<entry>Projecting piece</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>42a, 42b</entry>
<entry>Tilted edge part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>44</entry>
<entry>Conical projection</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>50</entry>
<entry>Screw driver bit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>52</entry>
<entry>Flat cutting-edge part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>53</entry>
<entry>Side wall part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>53a, 53b</entry>
<entry>Side wall part with a width widening toward the end</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>54</entry>
<entry>Conical projection</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>54a</entry>
<entry>Concavity in curved form</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Next, embodiments of a combination of a screw and a screw driver bit related to the invention and a header punch for its manufacture will be described below by referring to attached drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> (Example of Structure of Screw <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> show an example of a screw related to the invention. That is, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, reference numeral <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> denotes the screw related to the invention, and a bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is provided in a head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of this screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Incidentally, this bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is configured as a cross groove which intersects in plus (&plus;) form at the center part of the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> This bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is constituted by the dimension m of the opening (portion A-A) and the dimension g of the groove bottom part (portion B-B) in accordance with JIS (Japanese Industrial Standard) which have hitherto been publicly known. That is, from the opening end edge part (portion A-A) of the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to a specified depth are formed end wall parts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>each having a draft taper (draft angle &ggr; of header punch) of about 1.5&deg; to 5&deg; and a tilted groove part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg; is formed in the direction from the lower edge part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; of this end wall part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(portion C-C) to the center part of the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and a conical bottom face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with a gentle inclination angle &agr; of about 28&deg; is then formed in the direction from the point of intersection (portion B-B) between this tilted groove part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the dimension of the bottom part in accordance with JIS to the above-described center part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of this example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, at the adjacent corner parts of the above-described bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are respectively formed taper connection faces <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which extend from the position of the conical bottom face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to the opening edge part of the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the same manner as with the conventional cross-grooved screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> (Example of Structure of Screw <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> show another example of a screw related to the invention. That is, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of this example is such that a screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed in pan shape and the structure of a bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> provided in the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is the same as the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> whose screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed in dish shape in the example shown in the above-described <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Therefore, the same reference numerals are given to the same component parts and their detailed description is omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> However, in the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of this example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, in opposed sidewall parts <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are formed grooves with a width generally widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from the center part of the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>outward in the radial direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Thus, in the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of this example, by forming the above-described grooves with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, whereby the opening angle &dgr; of opposed side wall parts of each of adjacent grooves is set at a little sharper angle than a right angle (90&deg;), with the result that in a combination with a screw driver bit, which will be described later, the come-out phenomenon of the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> from the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be effectively prevented. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> (Example of Structure of Screw <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The screw related to the invention is also effective as a plus-and-minus screw (i.e., a screw with a cross grooved and slotted head) that permits the application of a conventional plus screw driver bit and a conventional slotted head screw driver bit. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), for a bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> into which the leading end of the cutting-edge part of a plus screw driver bit fits, grooves with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>can be formed in the same manner as with the example shown in the above-described <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In this case, the section structure of a plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; is basically the same as described in each example shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</cross-reference> and hence its illustration is omitted. Incidentally, in plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, one groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B in a pair of grooves <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B that intersect in cross form in the center part of the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed as a horizontal groove with a sufficient width and depth so that the groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B can abut and engage with the cutting-edge part of the slotted head screw driver bit. Incidentally, the structure of other portions is the same as the structure of the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> shown in the above-described <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> and, therefore, the same reference numerals are given to the same component parts and their detailed description is omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Also, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) shows an example of modification of plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; shown in the above-described <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>). That is, in plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; of the above-described example, the grooves with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which are formed for the groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B that can fit and abut against the cutting-edge part of the slotted head screw driver bit, in a pair of grooves <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B intersecting in cross form, are configured so as not to exceed the width of the horizontal groove that fits and abuts against the cutting-edge part of the slotted head screw driver bit. Therefore, in this case, the maximum groove width of the grooves with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the above-described groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B is configured so as to exceed the width of the above-described horizontal groove, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>). By configuring the grooves with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in this manner, in the engagement thereof against the screw driver bit, which will be described later, the abutting area (driving area) can be increased. Incidentally, in the example of modification of the above-described plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime;, as indicated by broken lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), also for the other groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>A, it is possible to provide a horizontal groove capable of fitting and abutting against the cutting-edge part of the slotted head screw driver bit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments of the screw related to the invention were described above. The bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the screw related to the invention is based on the hitherto publicly known dimension m of the opening (portion A-A) and dimension g of the groove bottom part (portion B-B) in accordance with JIS (Japanese Industrial Standard). By positioning the lower edge part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; of the end wall part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(portion C-C) at a point of intersection between the draft taper angle &ggr; from the opening end edge part (portion A-A) to a specified depth and the inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg; from a point (portion B-B) which provides the base part of the conical bottom face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with a specified gentle inclination angle &agr;, and by providing the tilted groove part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>set by this positioning, through the application of not only a conventional plus screw driver bit, but also a screw driver bit of a structure which will be described later, it is possible to expand the area in which the screw driver bit can give a rotating driving force to the screw (hereinafter referred to as the driving area) and, at the same time, it is possible, to securely prevent the come-out phenomenon of the screw driver bit and to achieve well-balanced torque transmission to the screw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> In addition, the setting of the inclination angle &bgr; of the above-described tilted groove part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, particularly in a screw with the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed in dish shape (refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), enables the wall thickness of a boundary portion between the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the screw neck part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to be maintained at an appropriate value during the formation of the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and, therefore, it is possible to sufficiently increase the strength of the screw during a screw tightening operation, thus providing an advantage. Furthermore, when the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of this shape is formed by means of a header punch, it is possible to keep the life of the above-described header punch long by reducing the wear of the leading end part thereof, thus providing another advantage. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> (Example of Structure of Header Punch for Manufacturing Screws) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows an example of a header punch <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> for manufacturing the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> related to the invention in Example 1 shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. That is, the header punch <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of this example is intended for use in punching and shaping the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. And the header punch <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of this example is provided with projecting pieces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> having tilted edge parts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for forming the end wall part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with a specified draft angle &ggr; and the tilted groove part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg; in the end edge part of bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and has a conical projection <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> for forming the conical bottom face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with a gentle inclination angle &agr; of about 28&deg; in the direction from these projecting pieces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to the center part of the screw neck part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Incidentally, as header punches for manufacturing the screws shown in the above-described Examples 2 and 3, it is possible to configure specified header punches by making the design change of the shape of the above-described projecting pieces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> according to the shape of the screws in each example. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> (Example of Structure of Screw Driver Bit) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference> show an example of a screw driver bit related to the invention. That is, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, reference numeral <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> denotes a main portion of a screw driver bit of this example, and the leading end of the cutting-edge part of this screw driver bit is configured so as to fit into the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> formed as a cross groove in the center part of screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the above-described screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> related to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of this example fits into the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the above-described screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, is provided with flat cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> which respectively engage with the end wall part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and tilted groove part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the end edge part of this bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and has a conical projection <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which sets the leading end face of the above-described flat cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> at an inclination angle &thgr; of about 1&deg; to 45&deg; and preferably 25&deg; to 35&deg; with respect to a horizontal plane according to the tilted groove part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and conical bottom part <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, which are formed in the direction from the end wall part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the above-described bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to the center part of the screw neck part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, reference numeral <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> denotes a generally vertical side wall part, which is formed on both sides of each of the above-described flat cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and for which a certain amount of taper is allowed. Therefore, this side wall part <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> abuts and engages against the side wall part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> formed in the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the above-described screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the engagement of these driving faces can ensure a sufficiently large engagement area and hence the come-out phenomenon that occurred in a combination of a conventional screw and a conventional screw driver bit can be effectively prevented. Incidentally, in the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> related to the invention, the side wall part <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> at the leading end of each of the above-described flat cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> can be configured in a shape which matches the grooves with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the side wall part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> formed in the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the above-described screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, i.e., as side wall parts with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>(refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Next, connecting operations between the above-described screws <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; related to the invention and the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> capable of fitting into these screws in a preferred manner will be described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows the connected state between the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. That is, in this case, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, when the flat cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> formed at the leading end of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> abuts against the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> formed in the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, because of the formation of the leading end face of the flat cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> as the conical projection <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the contact with the opening edge part of the above-described bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> provides very small contact constituted by a point or a line and, at the same time, the mutual positioning of the center parts is easily and rapidly achieved, whereby the wear of the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and damage thereto are reduced and it becomes possible to rapidly perform an appropriate connection of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Also, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> shows the connected state between the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> and the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. That is, in this case, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, because the side wall parts <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> at the leading end of the flat cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are configured as side wall parts with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>so as to fit into the grooves with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which are formed in the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, during the abutment of the cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> against each of the side wall parts (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) of bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, an appropriate engagement between the screw and the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be achieved by minimizing the clearances between the above-described grooves <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the above-described side wall parts <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Also, in this case, by setting the opening angle &dgr; (refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of opposed side wall parts of each of the adjacent grooves <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at a little sharper angle than a right angle, in a screw tightening operation a torque &tgr;<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> acting on each of the above-described side walls (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) can be directed toward the side of the screw neck part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from the tangential direction &pgr; of the screw head part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in which the cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the above-described screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is fitted and, therefore, the come-out phenomenon of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be securely prevented and well-balanced torque transmission to the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, also during the connection between the plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) and the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, which is not shown, the same fitting state as described above can be achieved. That is, in this case, as is apparent also from FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), during the abutment of the cutting-edge part (indicated by broken lines) of the screw driver bit against each of the side wall parts of the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime;, a uniform clearance &egr; is set at each side wall as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and the cutting-edge part can be caused to abut against the side wall parts (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of one groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>A and simultaneously against the side wall parts (T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) of the other groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B and well-balanced torque transmission can be achieved. In particular, for the plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), it is possible to increase the abutting area (driving area) of the cutting-edge part of the screw driver bit against the side wall parts (T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) of the above-described groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B and this provides the advantage that better-balanced torque transmission can be achieved and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Also, in the case where the side wall parts <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> at the leading end of the flat cutting-edge parts <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are configured as side wall parts with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>so as to fit into the grooves with a width widening toward the end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which are formed in the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the above-described plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; (refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>), during the abutment of the cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of this screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> against each of the side wall parts of bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime;, an appropriate engagement between the plus-and-minus screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; and the screw driver bit can be achieved by eliminating the clearance &egr; as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 6 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> (Example of Modifications of Screw and Screw Driver Bit) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows an example of modifications of the screw related to the invention shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and of the screwdriver bit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. That is, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, for the structure of the tilted groove part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg;, which is formed in the direction from the lower edge part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; of the end edge part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to the conical bottom face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> at the center part of the screw neck part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the above-described tilted groove part is bulged <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; in curved form inward to the bit-fitting groove <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In contrast, for the structure of the conical projection <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> formed at the leading end of the cutting-edge part <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> at the leading end of the screw driver bit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, in a portion of the above-described projection <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is formed a concavity <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in curved form so as to fit on the bulge <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; in curved form in the tilted groove part of the above-described screw <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Also in a combination of the screw and screw driver bit of this example thus configured, it is possible not only to effectively prevent the come-out phenomenon of the screw driver bit, but also to increase the strength of the screw. At the same time, this provides advantages including the advantage that the life of the header punch for manufacturing the screw can be extended. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiments of the invention were described above. It is needless to say, however, that the invention is not limited to the above-described examples and that it is possible to make many design changes so long as they do not depart from the spirit of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">ADVANTAGES OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> As is apparent from the above-described examples, the screw related to the invention is formed so that a bit-fitting groove formed of a cross groove is provided in a screw head part, a specified tilted groove part is formed in the direction from the end edge part of the bit-fitting groove to the center part of a screw neck part, and a roughly conical bottom face is formed at a cross center part, which is characterized in that the end edge part of the above-described bit-fitting groove is formed as a generally vertical end wall part of a specified depth, that a groove part with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg; is formed in the direction from the lower edge part of the end wall part to the conical bottom face at the center part of the screw neck part, and further that the conical bottom face is formed with a gentle inclination angle &agr; of approximately 28&deg;. This structure provides many excellent advantages: for example, the strength of the screw can be sufficiently increased during a screw tightening operation and, at the same time, the wear of the leading end part of the header punch is reduced during the manufacturing of the screw, a conventional plus screw driver bit can used, the come-out phenomenon of the screw driver bit during a screw tightening operation is securely prevented, and a well-balanced torque transmission to the screw can be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> And according to the combination of the screw and screw driver bit related to the invention, the screw driver bit is provided, at the leading end thereof, with a flat cutting-edge part in which is formed a generally vertical end edge part that fits along a generally vertical end wall part of a bit-fitting groove of a screw head part, and the leading end face of this cutting-edge part is formed as a conical projection having an inclination angle of about 1&deg; to 45&deg; with respect to a horizontal plane so as to fit into the above-described screws related to the invention. The structure of this screw driver bit provides many excellent advantages: for example, the driving area of the screw driver bit relative to the screw can be expanded, whereby the come-out phenomenon of the screw driver bit can be securely prevented and, at the same time, a well-balanced torque transmission to the screw is achieved, with the result that a rapid screw tightening operation and an improvement in the operation efficiency can be easily achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, the screw related to the invention is configured so that basically, the taper contact area relative to the whole of the bit-fitting groove is partial and small in the engagement with the screw driver bit, and besides the area of the side wall part of the bit-fitting groove against which the side wall part of the leading end of the screw driver bit abuts is expanded. As a result, an appropriate screw tightening operation and an appropriate screw removal operation can be achieved without causing damage (reference numeral <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) to a portion of the bit-fitting groove, for example as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, and without causing the come-out phenomenon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Also, according to the combination of the screw and screw driver bit related to the invention, the screw driver bit can be rotated by ensuring fitting with the axis of the screw and the axis of the screw driver bit always kept in a coaxial state. Therefore, a screw tightening operation by an appropriate torque can always be achieved rapidly by smoothly transmitting a rotating force of the screw driver bit to the screw without causing the come-out phenomenon and damage to the screw etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> In other words, by using the combination of the screw and screw driver bit related to the invention, it is possible not only to always perform a secure screw tightening operation by giving an appropriate torque to an object constituted by various types of hard and soft materials, to which the screw is to be attached, but also to substantially reduce damage to the screw, whereby an improvement in the safety of a screw tightening operation and the working efficiency can be easily and economically achieved. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A screw which is formed so that a bit-fitting groove formed of a cross groove is provided in a screw head part, a specified tilted groove part is formed in the direction from the end edge part of the bit-fitting groove to the center part of a screw neck part, and a roughly conical bottom face is formed at a cross center part, characterized in that the end edge part of said bit-fitting groove is formed as a generally vertical end wall part of a specified depth, in that a tilted groove part with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg;0 is formed in the direction from the lower edge part of the end wall part to the conical bottom face at the center part of the screw neck part, and in that said conical bottom face is formed with a gentle inclination angle &agr; of approximately 28&deg;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The screw according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the tilted groove part with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg;, which is formed in the direction from the lower edge part of end edge part of said bit-fitting groove to the conical bottom face at the center part of the screw neck part, is bulged inward to the bit-fitting groove in curved form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The screw according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, characterized in that grooves with a width generally widening toward the end are formed from the center part of said screw head part outward in the radial direction and that the opening angle of opposed side wall parts of each of said adjacent grooves is a little sharper than a right angle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A screw driver bit, characterized in that the screw driver bit is provided, at the leading end part thereof, with a flat cutting-edge part in which is formed a generally vertical end edge part that fits along a generally vertical end wall part of a bit-fitting groove of a screw head part, and in that the leading end face of this cutting-edge part is formed as a conical projection having an inclination angle of about 1&deg; to 45&deg; with respect to a horizontal plane so as to fit into the screw as set forth in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">3</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The screw driver bit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that wall parts on both sides at the leading end of said flat cutting-edge part are configured in a shape with a width widening toward the end so as to fit into the bit-fitting groove of the screw formed with a width generally widening toward the end, said bit-fitting groove of the screw being formed from the center part of the screw neck part outward in the radial direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A header punch for manufacturing the screw as set forth in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">3</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the header punch is provided with projecting pieces for forming the generally vertical end wall part and the tilted groove part with an inclination angle &bgr; of about 45&deg; in the end edge part of bit-fitting groove of the screw head part and has a conical projection for forming the conical bottom face with a gentle inclination angle &agr; of about 28&deg; in the direction from these projecting pieces to the center part of the screw neck part.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002952A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
