<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001678A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001678A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001678A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001678A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001678A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001678A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001678</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10175497</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020620</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-196965</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H03F003/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>330</class>
<subclass>308000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Semiconductor amplifier circuit</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shigemi</given-name>
<family-name>Miyazawa</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Yamanashi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Fujitsu Quantum Devices Limited.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Nakakoma-gun</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ARMSTRONG,WESTERMAN &amp; HATTORI, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1725 K STREET, NW.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1000</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20006</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A semiconductor amplifier circuit comprises a transimpedance amplifier for amplifying an input signal; a by-pass transistor connected between an input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier and the ground potential; a first resistor, one end of the first resistor being connected to an output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier; a capacitor connected between the other end of the first resistor and the ground potential; a second resistor connected between the other end of the first resistor and the gate of the by-pass transistor via an inverter; and a differential amplifier having a signal input terminal connected to the output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier and a reference-voltage input terminal connected to the other end of the first resistor. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a semiconductor amplifier circuit. In particular, the present invention relates to a semiconductor amplifier circuit used as a component of a receiver for optical communication and having a high gain and a wide dynamic range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A receiver for optical communication has a function for converting an optical signal transmitted through a relay transmission path, such as an optical fiber, to an electrical signal by a light-receiving element and for amplifying the electrical signal by an amplifier circuit. The amplifier should have a high gain in order to amplify a weak signal which has been attenuated due to a long-distance transmission. Further, since the optical signal intensity widely varies depending on the optical transmission distance, a wide dynamic range suitable for this variation in the optical signal intensity is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, in which a feedback resistor <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is connected in parallel to an operational amplifier <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, is widely used as an amplifier circuit for optical communication. The transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> converts a current signal input from a light-receiving element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to a voltage signal so as to amplify the signal. The gain of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> depends on the resistance of the feedback resistor <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Therefore, a high gain can be obtained by increasing the resistance of the feedback resistor <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. However, by increasing the resistance, the output voltage is likely to saturate and thus the dynamic range becomes narrow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As described above, the gain and the dynamic range of the transimpedance amplifier depend on the value of the feedback resistor and are in a trade-off relationship. Thus, a high gain and a wide dynamic range cannot be realized at the same time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows an example of a known amplifier circuit for optical communication including an improved transimpedance amplifier. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> including a resistor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and a capacitor <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> connected in series is connected to the output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Also, a by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to the input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The DC voltage generated in the DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is applied to the gate of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> via an inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Herein, the DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> generates a DC voltage whose value is substantially the same as the time-average value of the voltage signal output from the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to the above-described configuration, the impedance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> varies according to the intensity of the current signal input from the light-receiving element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and thus the gain of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is adjusted. Therefore, the amplifier circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> has excellent characteristics in a gain and a dynamic range, compared to the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Further, the amplifier circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> amplifies the voltage signal output from the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by a differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and externally outputs the signal. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the DC voltage generated in the DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is applied to a reference-voltage input terminal <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the voltage signal applied to a signal input terminal <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> swings, with the center being a DC voltage level which is substantially equal to the time-average value, in accordance with the change of the optical signal intensity. As a result, the voltage amplitude output to the output terminal <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and that output to the output terminal <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are inverted with respect to each other. Therefore, the amplifier circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is capable of externally outputting the voltage signal, which has an amplitude twice as much as a single-phase amplitude and which does not have distortion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In general, an amplifier circuit for optical communication is integrated by using a compound semiconductor having an excellent high-frequency characteristic, such as gallium arsenide (GaAs). As a transistor for constituting the circuit, Schottky gate FET is used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The Schottky gate FET is used as an input device for the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the amplifier circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The DC voltage generated by the DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is applied to the gate of each of the FETs. Accordingly, a large gate leakage current is generated when the DC voltage exceeds the threshold voltage of the Schottky gate FETs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In particular, when the gate leakage current of the FET used as the input device for the inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> becomes large, the current applied to the resistor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> becomes large accordingly. As a result, a large potential difference occurs bitween both terminals of the resistor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and thus the DC voltage input to the reference-voltage input terminal <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is reduced. Accordingly, the DC voltage applied to the reference-voltage input terminal <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is lower than the time-average voltage signal applied to the signal input terminal <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. This causes a problem that the voltage signal input to the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is not normally amplified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The above-described problem occurs because both of the DC voltage to be applied to the inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the DC voltage to be applied to the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are generated by the DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, when the DC voltage to be applied to the reference-voltage input terminal <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is generated by another DC voltage generating circuit, the influence of the gate leakage current of the inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> can be suppressed. In order to achieve this, however, a resistor and a capacitor for forming another DC voltage generating circuit must be fabricated on an amplifier circuit chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Generally, in this type of DC voltage generating circuit, an external microchip capacitor is used because a large capacitance is required to smooth an input voltage. Thus, as described above, the amplifier circuit chip becomes large when another DC voltage generating circuit is provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, a DC voltage can be supplied from a DC voltage generating circuit provided outside the amplifier circuit chip to the reference-voltage input terminal of the differential amplifier in the amplifier circuit chip. In this method, however, a terminal for external connection must be provided in the amplifier circuit chip, which results in an increase in the size of the chip and high cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Further, in the amplifier circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected in parallel to the input terminal of the transimpedance-amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the input capacitance of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> increases by the gate capacitance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. This causes further deterioration in the frequency characteristic of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in a high-frequency region. The input capacitance of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be effectively reduced when the gate width of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is made to be narrow. However, this causes the increase of the impedance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. As a result, the gain characteristic and the dynamic range characteristic of the amplifier circuit deteriorate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to improve the amplification characteristic of an amplifier circuit without causing an increase in the size of the amplifier circuit and an increase in the number of external terminals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In order to overcome the above-described problems, a semiconductor amplifier circuit according to the present invention comprises a transimpedance amplifier for amplifying an input signal; a by-pass transistor connected between an input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier and the ground potential; a first resistor, one end of the first resistor being connected to an output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier; a capacitor connected between the other end of the first resistor and the ground potential; a second resistor connected between the other end of the first resistor and the gate of the by-pass transistor via an inverter; and a differential amplifier having a signal input terminal connected to the output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier and a reference voltage input terminal connected to the other end of the first resistor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The semiconductor amplifier circuit may further comprise level shift means provided at least one of between the by-pass transistor and the input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier and between the by-pass transistor and the ground potential. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the level shift means is a diode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> A light-receiving element may be connected to the input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, a DC voltage is generated by the first resistor and the capacitor connected to the output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier. The generated DC voltage is supplied to the inverter via the second resistor and is also supplied to the reference-voltage input terminal of the differential amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Consequently, even when a current flows from the first resistor and the capacitor through the input unit of the inverter, the current is limited by the second resistor, and thus reduction in the DC voltage generated by the first resistor and capacitor can be suppressed. As a result, reduction in the DC voltage supplied to the reference-voltage input terminal of the differential amplifier can be suppressed, and the differential amplifier can normally amplify the voltage signal input from the signal input terminal so as to externally output the signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Also, according to the present invention, the level shift means connected to the by-pass transistor adjusts the source-drain potential, thereby controlling the impedance of the by-pass transistor. As a result, the gain characteristic and dynamic range characteristic of the amplifier circuit do not deteriorate even when the gate width of the by-pass transistor is narrowed in order to suppress deterioration in the frequency characteristic of the amplifier circuit.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows an amplifier circuit according to an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a transimpedance amplifier according to a known art; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram of an amplifier circuit according to another known art.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a semiconductor amplifier circuit according to an embodiment of the present invention. In this figure, parts having the same functions as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> are referred to with the same reference numerals. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> includes a constant current source <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> as an input stage, an FET <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, level shift diodes <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, an FET <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> as an output stage, a level shift diode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, a current source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and a feedback resistor <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> for connecting the input stage and the output stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> current signal input from a light-receiving element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the gate of the FET <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is transmitted through the feedback resistor <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to the current source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so that a potential difference is generated at both ends of the feedback resistor <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The gate-source potential of the FET <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is kept to be constant by the constant current source <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and thus the gate potential of the FET <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is also kept to be constant. As a result, a voltage signal in inverse phase to that of the current signal is output from an output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to a differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> includes resistors <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, FETs <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, and a constant current source <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The voltage signal output from the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is input to the gate of the FET <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> through a signal input terminal <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> includes a resistor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and a capacitor <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and generates a DC voltage which is equal to the time-average voltage signal output from the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The DC voltage is input to a reference-voltage input terminal <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which is the other input terminal for the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and is supplied to an inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> through a resistor <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes an FET <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, a resistor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, and level shift diodes <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The resistor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is used for adjusting the gain of the inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The level shift diode <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is used for adjusting the output voltage of the inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the level shift diode <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is used for adjusting the gate bias point of the FET <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> A by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to an input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> such that the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected in series to level shift diodes <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The output voltage of the inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is input to the gate of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> via a level shift circuit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In the above-described configuration, the gate potential of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> varies in the same phase as the current signal input to the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Thus, the gate potential of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> decreases when the amplitude of the current signal input from the light-receiving element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is small. In this case, by setting the level shift circuit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> so that the gate potential of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is lower than the threshold voltage, the impedance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes high. Accordingly, a large amount of current signal is transmitted to the feedback resistor <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, without being transmitted to the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. As a result, the gain of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> becomes high. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the amplitude of the current signal input from the light-receiving element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is large, the gate potential of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> increases so as to exceed the threshold voltage. Accordingly, the impedance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes low. As a result, since part of the current signal transmits through the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the gain of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> becomes low. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As described above, the gain of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is adjusted in accordance with the intensity of the current signal input from the light-receiving element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and thus a high gain and a wide dynamic range can be obtained when the current signal is weak. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In the above-described configuration, the gate potential of the FET <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> used as the input unit of the inverter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has a inverse phase to that of the current signal input to the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the gate potential of the FET <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> becomes high when the amplitude of the current signal is small. In this case, gate leakage current is generated when the gate potential of the FET <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> exceeds the threshold voltage, but this gate leakage current can be suppressed by the resistor <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the current applied to the resistor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the DC voltage generating circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> causes only a slight voltage reduction, and as a result, reduction in the DC voltage applied to the reference-voltage input terminal <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is suppressed. Accordingly, normal voltage signals without distortion are externally output from the output terminals <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Also, as described above, the gate capacitance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> must be reduced in order to suppress deterioration in the frequency characteristic of the amplifier circuit caused by the gate capacitance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. However, the impedance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in a low-frequency region increases by narrowing the gate width. As a result, the gain of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> cannot be sufficiently reduced when the amplitude of the current signal becomes large, and thus the dynamic range is limited. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the drain-source potential of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is limited to a value that is lower than the drain current saturation region by the level shift diodes <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> connected in series to the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Thus, the impedance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is kept to be low even when the gate width becomes narrow. Consequently, the impedance of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is kept to be sufficiently low and the gain of the transimpedance amplifier <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> decreases and the dynamic range becomes wide, even when the amplitude of the current signal is large and the gate potential of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> increases so as to exceed the threshold voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> According to the above-described configuration, the gate capacitance can be reduced by narrowing the gate width of the by-pass transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and thus deterioration in a frequency characteristic of the amplifier circuit in a high-frequency region can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As described above, according to the present invention, the amplifier having a high-gain and a wide dynamic range and having an excellent frequency characteristic can be achieved, and the performance of a receiver for optical communication can be improved. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor amplifier circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a transimpedance amplifier for amplifying an input signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a by-pass transistor connected between an input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier and the ground potential; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first resistor, one end of the first resistor being connected to an output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor connected between the other end of the first resistor and the ground potential; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second resistor connected between the other end of the first resistor and the gate of the by-pass transistor via an inverter; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a differential amplifier having a signal input terminal connected to the output terminal of the transimpedance amplifier and a reference-voltage input terminal connected to the other end of the first resistor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor amplifier circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising level shift means provided at least one of between the by-pass transistor and the input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier and between the by-pass transistor and the ground potential. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor amplifier circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the level shift means is a diode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor amplifier circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a light-receiving element is connected to the input terminal of the transimpedance amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001678A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001678A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001678A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
