<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002391A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002391A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002391</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893583</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G04C019/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>368</class>
<subclass>082000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>System and method for customized time display</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kevin</given-name>
<family-name>Biggs</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Toronto</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ORANGE &amp; CHARI</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>66 Wellington St. W., Suite 4900</address-1>
<address-2>P.O. Box 190</address-2>
<city>Toronto</city>
<state>ON</state>
<postalcode>M5K 1H6</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system and method for producing and displaying chronological data according to user specified parameters. The system incorporates language, multi media, and animation into a time display device. The system can include typical features of a conventional time display device, such as an alarm function and a display face. The system also includes a translation engine for combining the parameters and a plurality of supplemental display data, including language, multi media, and animation data, to provide a translation template. The template helps to control the presentation of chronological data in a synchronized fashion by reformatting the chronological data into a translated display format, thereby providing to the user a personalized time display. The display includes selected images and/or language to represent the passage of numerical chronological data. The parameters and the supplemental display data are alterable by the user to customize the presentation of the translated format on the display, so as to present a unique and personalized time display sequence on the display device. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a system and method for producing and displaying customized presentations of chronological data. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Time display devices are used by many people to keep track of the passage of time during daily activities. Conventional electronic time pieces typically provide time keeping functions and can display additional information for indicating years, months, days, and dates. Alternatively, the time keeping functions can also include an alarm function and counter functions in addition to the basic display of actual time and hours, minutes, and seconds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Watches and clocks are usually designed with graduations that are marked around the face of the time piece, internal mechanisms that rotate an hour hand, minute hand, and a second hand. The design of the watch face has on its perimeter the numbers 1 through 12, usually increasing in a clockwise direction with rotating hour hands and minute hands that point to the numbers on the watch face parameter that indicate the exact time of day. This time keeping system can be implemented in either an analog or digital manner. Furthermore, the use of digital numbering systems to indicate time are also known. However, the user of a time display device may wish to have animated or otherwise customizable display functions to provide for the passage of time, in a personalized fashion, by the time piece. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,995,456 (&apos;456) by Brewer et al. teaches a watch having a multi color liquid crystal display, which dynamically changes by way of electronic control. Dynamic color changes within the LCD are presented in which perceived color changes occur in a pattern or sequence independent of the time of day. The apparatus may be adapted to provide various colored images such as geometric, images, designer labels, and logos on colored backgrounds. Color changes may occur in such a way that provides a dynamically changing image or a dynamically changing kaleidoscope effect. The apparatus provides color variation and allows the individual to alter the color appearance using a voltage regulating dial. However, the display itself is not designed to convey time of day information and teaches instead the use of background images. Accordingly, the rate, sequence, and pattern of color changes are independent to the passage of chronological time. Furthermore, the number and type of images presentable on the display are set by the manufacturer, and do not allow for interaction with a user of the display for customization purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Further advances known in the art of time display can include the display of static picture elements for ornamentation purposes on the time display, as well as the display of messages containing alpha numeric words from a list of characters, as shown in U.S. Pat. No. 4,303,996 (&apos;996) by Schmitz. However, the system taught does not allow the user to correlate the alpha numeric words with a passage of chronological time, and the location and presentation format of the alpha numeric characters is set by the manufacturer and not alterable by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the present invention to provide a customized time display to obviate or mitigate some of the above presented disadvantages. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to a time display method and system for incorporating language, multi media, and animation into a time display device. The system can include typical features of a conventional time display device, such as an alarm function and a display face. The system can further include an embedded device for wireless communication, an operating system having windows capabilities, and application software for the device to enable a user to create thematic time displays. The software controls and compiles animation, multi media, language, type setting, schemas, identification, and sequencing of the display material, which can be obtained from a host website. The system is capable of downloading display material from the host website, and a user interface of the system can be used to provide a menu system, from which the user can select and coordinate the display of the downloaded material in a user customized fashion. The time display method and system helps the user or provider of the time displays to create and display a customized presentation of relative chronological data through a translation engine, such that the time presentation on the time display device provides the user with a personalized display, including selected images and/or language to represent the passage of numerical chronological data. By using such a time presentation system, the display software and corresponding device can help the user to customize the presentation of relative chronological data for providing a dynamic translated display of traditional time data in a predetermined sequence on the device, as specified by the user. The software and compatible display device can be used to select and display the passage of chronological data through the use of a time translation engine, so as to present a unique and personalized time display sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to one embodiment of the present invention there is provided a system for producing and displaying chronological data according to user specified parameters. The system comprises a user interface for monitoring the input of the parameters to a translation engine. The translation engine combines the parameters and a plurality of supplemental display data to provide a translation template. The translation template of the system is used to reformat the chronological data in a synchronized fashion to provide translated display data representing the chronological data. The system also includes a digital display device for monitoring a presentation of the translated display data on a display. The parameters and supplemental display data are alterable to customize the presentation of the translated display data on the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to a further embodiment of the present invention there is provided a computer program product for producing and displaying chronological data according to user specified parameters. The product comprises a computer readable medium and a user interface module stored on the computer readable medium. The interface module monitors the input of the parameters to a translation module, which combines the parameters and a plurality of supplemental display data to produce a template module. The template module reformats the chronological data in a synchronized fashion to provide translated display data representing the chronological data. The produce also contains a display module for monitoring a presentation of the translated display data on a display.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> These and other features of the preferred embodiments of the invention will become more apparent in the following detailed description in which reference is made to the appended drawings by way of example only, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a time display system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows example displays on a display device of the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> presents operation of a time translation engine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> show a host site of the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an operational flowchart of the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a further operational flowchart of the device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a further embodiment of the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows example parameters of the engine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a further example of the parameters of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a lookup table for a sample schema of the engine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a further lookup table for a sample schema of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a further lookup table for a sample schema of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> time display system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> consists of a display device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> coupled by a transmission channel <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to a network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> communicates with a host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, such as a time display web site, to access supplemental time display data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to be processed and then displayed on display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the display device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can contain alpha, numeric, and graphical image components related to chronological time. Some examples of networks <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can include the Internet, microwave and antenna relay stations, satellite networks, other wireless communication systems, and composite networks comprising a mixture of these technologies. The device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> uses the network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to access the time related data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which can be applied by the user to create personalized thematic time displays. The device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and related software is used to control and compile animation, multi media, language, type setting, schemas, and sequencing of the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as directed by the user, for the in creation of the customized image display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can include various electronic or digital devices, such as but not limited to an alarm clock, cellular phones, mobile computers, home computers, pagers, wristwatches, and other PDAs with an appropriate resolution display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for obtaining and coordinating the display of the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> could coordinate the presentation of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as a computer desktop icon or ornament. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The time display device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is used by a user to create customized thematic time displays, on display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which translate chronological time data <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and other data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into language and animation, wherein the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is preferably a high resolution LCD display. The computer system of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprises a processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> coupled to the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through the network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> monitors the download or transfer of the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> from the host site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to a local database <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> or memory of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is also coupled to the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by a graphic controller and to user input devices <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, such as a keyboard, a mouse, or a voice activated device. If the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is touch sensitive, then the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> itself can be the user input device <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A computer readable storage medium <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is also coupled to the processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> for providing an operating system or software (OS) to the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, wherein the OS can also be downloaded from the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> directly from the network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The OS could be specific to run or modify the operation of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in respect to the thematic time display functionality. It should be noted that the OS could be downloaded from the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> by another network device and then transferred to the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The computer readable medium <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can include hardware and/or software, such as by way of example only, magnetic discs, magnetic tape, optically readable media such as CD ROMs, and semi conductor memory such as PCMCIA cards. In each case, the medium <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may take to form of a portable item such as a small disc, floppy diskette, cassette, or may take the form of a relatively large or immobile item such as a hard disc drive, solid state memory card, or RAM provided in the computer system of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. It should be noted that the above listed example mediums <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be used either alone or in combination. It should also be noted that the content of the medium <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> could be used to supply time display data sets <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to the processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, or that the content of the medium <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> could be obtained in the form of data files over the network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> also includes a time translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, preferably in the form of software, which interacts with the processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and time related data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> stored in the local data base <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to translate the chronological data <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into a customized language and animation displays for presentation on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. It should be noted, that audio displays of the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> could also be presented to the user through the use of a speaker <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. It should be noted that the user can also augment the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with additional user created or independently obtained data suitable for presentation on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the user can also create time data or multimedia files and provide this to the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for access by other users, as directed by the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, examples of visual time display are shown. Shown are two example presentation modes for the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, namely AlphaTime <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> comprising language and GuiTime <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> comprising a combination of language and/or animation. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, an example five minute time translation cycle is shown, wherein representational images <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, b, c, d, e</italic></highlight>, and <highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>are sequentially displayed on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in a synchronized fashion to indicate the passage of chronological time, for either the AlphaTime <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or GuiTime <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> modes, as selected by the user. The display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can contain a language component <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and a graphic minute indicator component <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The indicator <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> can be used to indicate the passage of minutes or other time units (as specified by the user) with corresponding language or language and animation data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which can be predetermined images and/or animations as obtained from the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Other examples of the indicators <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can include a frame <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> defined as an area which surrounds a main presentation area <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The frame <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be represented by an image file or an animation file, as selected by the user from the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> supplied by the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The background image of the display area <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> can be an image file or an animation file, which can be related through a thematic time display as specified by the user. The language component <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the time display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is comprised of a text translation of corresponding chronological data <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> (day/month/year) in a specified type face, which is supplied by the translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. For example, the indicated type face could be English Time foreign character sets. The user could also specify customized scripts and/or languages, as desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, other sample displays are shown which can combine language with graphic images, such as the &ldquo;Noon&rdquo; image <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> on an alarm clock device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, or an advertisement or message <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, which can be correlated to the particular time display sequence shown or cycled randomly throughout the sequence of time display images. The messages <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> can be images, animation, and video with audio capabilities. Furthermore, predetermined portions of the data, such as graphical images, can be associated with numeric serialization, which provides a unique identifier to each of the downloads containing corresponding graphical images. This serialization can be used by the user to monitor the number and/or type of images contained in the user&apos;s image collection. Accordingly, the use of serialization could coordinate the exchange of images and/or time displays represented by the downloads; or other multi media files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) between users. It should be noted that the users could create and serialize their own time display files or programs <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> combines multi media files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> obtained from the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, user specified parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> obtained through the input device <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and relative chronological data <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> as monitored by the processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to produce a translated time display file or display executable program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> could combine the parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> to produce a translation template <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, which could be used to reformat the data <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> for presentation on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The GuiTime time translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> receives system time <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> from the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in a HR:MM:D/M/Y format. The translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> references a lookup table/flatfile/schema/database, as provided below, to determine how the time <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is to be presented based on the user defined preferences <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> first determines whether the user has selected the GuiTime or Alpha Time format. The GuiTime format preferably presents using language and animation and the Alphatime format preferably uses language. The translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> then determines which language or schema translation has been selected by the user. As each minute lapses the translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> references and combines these two data sources <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and presents them as relative time on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> uses the OS obtained from the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to execute the program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and otherwise monitor the sequencing of images contained in the program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, in synchronization with the relative chronological data <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. For example, the user specified parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are for an alarm (i.e. Event) to be displayed by the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> once the chronological time reaches 10:33 AM on a user specified day of the year. For example, the thematic images and other time data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> obtained by the user from the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can include baseball images <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and animation images <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, along with baseball audio files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and language <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. The translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> combines these selected thematic parameters <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> along with the chronological data <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> obtained from the processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to present the coordinated thematic time display program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and speaker <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In particular, in this example, the time translation program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> contains a &ldquo;crack&rdquo; of a bat and &ldquo;roar&rdquo; of the crowd as an auditory indicator for the alarm, as well as animation sequences <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> located on the frame <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and main display <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> respectively. The animation sequences <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> provide to the user a sequential cartoon animation of a bat hitting a ball and flashing minute indicators <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> respectively. In addition, the advertisement section <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> can also contain ticket information for upcoming baseball games for example, in the user&apos;s geographical area and/or team(s) of interest. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> It should be noted that the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> provides a dynamic time presentation to the user according to user the specified parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, downloaded multi media files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and chronological data <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> provides the user with user specified format of the chronological data <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> for presentation on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or speaker <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which can include images <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, animation <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, video <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, audio <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, and language <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. The program or template <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is designed according to the user parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> to compile the various components <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> into thematic and user specified time display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the file <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> provides a sequential display of the alpha, numeric, and graphic components, with reference to user specified time units (such as minutes), for denoting the passage of time and event indication or reminders. Other functions configurable by the user can include alarm settings, day and date display, international languages, timers or countdowns, all of which can be displayed in a user customizable fashion through the translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or speaker <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10, 11</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, sample lookup tables <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> used by the translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> show available relationships for the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The translation engine can coordinate the reformatting of the time data <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> with the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> using any combination of work and/or numbers contained in the tables <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, as specified by the parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> used to create the file <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can provide a website accessible by the user through a URL <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The website <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can include software downloads of the translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, design software <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, operating system software <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> for specified devices <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and product and order information <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> for compatible devices for using the available operating systems <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The design software <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> can be downloadable to the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> through the network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and can be used to compile the multi media files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, as well as coordinate the animation, language, type setting, schemas, and serialization by the user to produce the time translation program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The host site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> also contains a display download section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> with an accompanying search engine <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The access of the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> through the download interface <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can be coordinated into various categories, such as but not limited to sports, science fiction, and nature. The download data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> from the section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is in the form of multi media file <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) as input for the translation engine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The image files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>comprise images which can be used to populate the frame <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and background <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> sections of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, as well as provide language <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, ad/messages <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, minute indicators <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, AM/PM indicators, and alarm indicators. The animation files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>can be used to populate the frame <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and background <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> sections of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, as well as supply presentation material for the ad/messages section <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, content of the minute indicator <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, AM/PM indicators, and alarm indicators. The video files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>obtainable from the download section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can be used to populate the background <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and ad/messages section <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The audio files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>can be used to supply display data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for the ad/messages section <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and alarm settings, which are indicated to the user through the speaker <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, separate language files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>can be obtained from the download section <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to provide the user with varying language formats for both the AlphaTime <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and GuiTime <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> display modes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In operation of the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, once the user has downloaded and installed the design software <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, operating systems software <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, and translation engine software <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> onto their device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can be ready to download the display time data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> through the interface <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Once the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has been downloaded by the user to the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the installed design software <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> can be used to place or otherwise order the selected or download files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and time display components therein in user specified sequences, as well as how to coordinate the timing of and in what manner and in what sequence in relation to the chronological time the individual files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> will be played or displayed on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, by entering the specified parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The user can access a graphical user interface <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>) generated by the design software <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, which provides a series of menus <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> to customize the presentation of the files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The input menu <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> allows the user to define the parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> to select which of the files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> are to be included on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The Frame item can be selected from the set art menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, by which the user defines the parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> to indicate the downloaded file(s) <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which will be associated with the frame space <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Selection of the Background item from the menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> allows the user to indicate the files which will be associated with the background space <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Selection of the Language item from the menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> allows the user to select the particular language files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>which will appear on top of the background <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> as time indicators <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The language file <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>selected through the Language item references the file comprised of a text translation of the corresponding time of day in the indicated type face, such as English Times Roman, French Helvetica Script, and German Helvetica handwriting. Selection of the Ad/Messages item from the menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> allows the user to specify the files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which will be associated with the advertisements or messages that are cycled through the time display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. These messages <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> can be images, animation, and/or video with audio capabilities. Selection of the Minute Indicator item from the menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> allows the user to indicate which files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> will be associated with the type of minute indicators <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and their manner of placement on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Selection of the Audio item from the menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> allows the user to indicate the files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which will be associated with the selected videos, animations, and ads or alarm events displayed in the frame section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and main section <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Selection of the AM/PM item from the menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> allows the user to identify the files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which will be associated with the AM/PM indicator, which can be represented by an animation or stationary image. Selection of the Alarm item from the menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> allows the user to specify the alarm sequence and representative indicator from the files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which will be associated with the alarm indicator displayed on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the data sequence which plays when the alarm is activated. The alarm indicator files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> can be a combination of animation, or image and the alarm sequence can consist of animation, images, video, and/or audio. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the user can also reference a Set Timers menu <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> from the interface <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The Timer menu <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> allows the user to set the parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> for how long a particular time segment is displayed on the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and how long an ad message <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> appears in the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. This timer function also allows the user to indicate intervals in which selected background files and minute indicators <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> will be displayed. Selection of the Time Display item from the menu <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> allows the user to set the duration of the time, for example in seconds, that the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will present selected files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> indicating chronological time to the user on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> before being replaced or cycled with alternate selected files. Selection of the Ad/Message item from the menu <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> allows user to set the duration of the time, for example in seconds, that the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will present ad information in the region <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Selection of the Background item from the menu <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> allows the user to set the duration of the time that the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will display the selected background files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. In particular, for each background file <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> indicated in the Set Art menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, the user can indicate the start and stop time in a DD/MM/YY:HR:MM format so that particular thematic time displays can be appropriately cycled by the user for presentation on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Selection of the Minute Indicator item by the user from the menu <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> allows the user to set the duration of the time that the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will display the selected minute indicators <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. For each minute indicator file <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> specified from the menu <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, the user can indicate the start and end time of the minute indicators <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> in a DD/MM/YY:HR:MM format, such that the indicators are present during the time presentation on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, once the user has finished placement of various downloaded files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> using the menu <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, the design software <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> then compiles the files and user input into the executable file <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Once the user has completed a particular file <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, the user can save the file <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the database <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> as currently configured for future reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>, example variable definitions are shown at <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The user selects from the definitions shown in table <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. The user can select any combination of the variables contained in each column of the table <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. For example, the user can select: a presentation format P<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>&equals;P<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>; a schema or lookup table (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10, 11</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>)$&equals;$4 Cool; a schema for the type of icon desired to represent the minute indicator <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> such as isx &plus; is 2 Globe; an icon group selection such as ix&equals;i2 &equals;(ic1&plus;ic2), which cycles the minute indicator represented by ic1 and ic2 on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>; the particular icon selected such as icx&equals;id from the group isx; a specified border such as F&equals;F1 Wood Nub; and a specified background such as B&equals;B1 Brick Wall. Any combination of variables can be selected from the table <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to produce the presentation template parameter set <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, which is included in the file <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, thereby providing the thematic time display customization. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows the relation of specific icons <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> to the icon parameters icx in sample fields <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> corresponding to table <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. It should be noted that graphical or image parameters may not be used for Alphatime formats of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, once the executable file <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> has been downloaded <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> to the processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a device menu interface <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is provided to the user which allows the device to download new displays, synchronize time, de-active/active alarms, and select the display mode of the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, thereby altering the file <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> contents and parameters <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Selection of the Update Display item from the menu <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> allows the user to download a new display or altered display program or template <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, as previously created by the user. Furthermore, user specified alarm settings can be reviewed and modified, as well as allowing the user to synchronize the device time <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> as monitored by the processor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> with an external time standard. Selection of the set Display item from the menu <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> allows user to toggle the display mode from either the GuiTime <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> or AlphaTime <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> formats. Selection of the System Info item from the menu <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> allows the user to check remaining battery life of the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the serial number or title of the currently loaded display. Once the items from the menu <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> have been customized to the user&apos;s satisfaction, the user customized presentation of the files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> in combination with the chronological data <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> on the display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will continue until either the current program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is terminated or until such time that the user creates and downloads a new program <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the display device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> further embodiment of the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is described, wherein like numerals with a prefix &ldquo;1&rdquo; denote similar components to those contained in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. A system <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> comprises a computer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to interact with a host system <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> through a network <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The computer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> co-ordinates the download of time related data <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and formats the data <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> according to user specified input <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, to produce an executable time translation template <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to a self-contained time presentation device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> consists of an embedded system with communication capabilities to the device <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, a high resolution color LCD display <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, a speaker <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, a user interface <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, and a power source <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. The device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, for example a watch, contains an operating system for monitoring all VO functions as well as a display driver and device interfaces controlled by a processor <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. For example, the embedded display <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> would have a diameter of approximately 0.8 inches in size with a high resolution display. The embedded processor would control and drive the output and resolution of the display <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The user interface <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> would be used by the user to engage the menu system for downloading a new display, synchronizing time, deactivation/activation of alarms, and the selection of either the GuiTime mode <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> or AlphaTime display mode <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The speaker <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is used to indicate system messages and alarms as well as to play audio files associated with the executable template <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Preferably, a communication interface <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> between the self-contained watch <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and computer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is a wireless solution, as is known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In operation of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the computer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is used to download multi media files <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> from the host <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and to format the presentation of the alpha, numeric, and graphic components of the data <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> contained therein according to user specified parameters <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. The computer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can access the host <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, and the browse and download a selection of display data sets <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The computer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> then produces customized time translation data in the form of the file <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> as a template, which is then downloaded to the watch <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, through a simplified set of interface parameters through the interface <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, the user can co-ordinate the chronological data <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> of the device processor <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> along with the template <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> for presentation of thematic time displays on the display <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. It should be noted that the computational capabilities of the device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> can be reduced to interacting with the template <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> in combination with synchronized chronological data <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. In contrast, the computer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> resources can be used for connecting with the host <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> over the network <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and coordinating the download of data <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, as well as formatting of the data <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> according to user specified parameters <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> to produce the resultant executable template <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, which is executed by the device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, as shown above by example, the display format <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be customized to display various pre-determined time sequences and formats as directed by the user through downloadable files <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> from the host site <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, representing time display data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. This manipulation and translated display format of relative chronological time data helps the user to provide a dynamic and customizable time display <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, by using various customization features, as indicated by example in the customization menus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4, 5</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. It is recognized that the operation of the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be provided by time display software containing the above system features as software modules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Although the invention has been described with reference to certain specific embodiments, various modifications thereof will be apparent to those skilled in the art without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as outlined in the claims appended hereto. It is recognized that the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> features can be represented as software and/or hardware modules as represented by the computer readable media <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. It is further recognized that the related software to control and compile the presentation of the data <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can reside on; the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, so that the user could configure the executable file <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> from user selection off of the host website; the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> which provides a series of pre-configured downloadable files <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> related to the variety of display formats selectable by the user; and software downloadable by the user from the host <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, such that the user can configure and compile their own personalized time displays for presentation on the device <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">The embodiments of the invention in which an exclusive property or privilege is claimed are defined as follows: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A system for producing and displaying chronological data according to user specified parameters, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>a) a user interface for monitoring the input of the parameters to a translation engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) the translation engine for combining the parameters and a plurality of supplemental display data to provide a translation template; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) the template for reformatting the chronological data in a synchronized fashion to provide translated display data representing the chronological data; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) a digital display device for monitoring a presentation of the translated display data on a display; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the parameters and supplemental display data are alterable to customize the presentation of the translated display data on the display. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a menu provided by the user interface for relating the parameters to the supplemental display data. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method for producing and displaying chronological data according to user specified parameters, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>a) selecting the parameters and a plurality of supplemental display data by the user; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) combining the parameters and the plurality of supplemental display data to provide a translation template; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) reformatting the chronological data with the template in a synchronized fashion to provide translated display data representing the chronological data; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) presenting the translated display data on a display; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the parameters and the supplemental display data are alterable to customize the presentation of the translated display data on the display. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A computer program product for producing and displaying chronological data according to user specified parameters, the product comprising: 
<claim-text>a) a computer readable medium; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a user interface module stored on the computer readable medium for monitoring the input of the parameters to a translation module; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) the translation module for combining the parameters and a plurality of supplemental display data to provide a template module; </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) the template module for reformatting the chronological data in a synchronized fashion to provide translated display data representing the chronological data; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>e) a display module for monitoring a presentation of the translated display data on a display; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the parameters and supplemental display data are alterable to customize the presentation of the translated display data on the display.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002391A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
