<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001517A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001517A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001517</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09899769</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05B037/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>315</class>
<subclass>224000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>315</class>
<subclass>291000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Converter for converting an AC power main voltage to a voltage suitable for driving a lamp</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Andrew</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Piaskowski</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>St-Lazare</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>OLSON &amp; HIERL, LTD.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>36th Floor</address-1>
<address-2>20 North Wacker Drive</address-2>
<city>Chicago</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60606</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An electronic converter converts high-voltage AC power main voltage, such as 120V, 240V or 277V, to a low-voltage suitable for driving a halogen lamp. The converter includes a rectifier circuit, starter circuit, a driver circuit, a current sensing circuit and a transformer circuit. The current sensing circuit senses an output current of the converter. The sensed current is used to govern pulse-width modulation of the lamp drive voltage, to provide over-voltage protection. Temperature protection can also be provided to reduce drive current when the converter overheats. This enables reliable operation of the converter over an extended temperature range, and reduces the occurrence of converter component failures due to ground faults or overheating. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This is the first application filed for the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">MICROFICHE APPENDIX </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Not Applicable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to converters for converting alternating current (AC) power main voltage to a voltage suitable for driving a lamp. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Most electronic converters for converting AC power main voltage to a voltage for driving a lamp, such as a halogen lamp, are based on self-oscillating technology using bipolar transistors. Since bipolar transistors are current operating devices, obtaining feedback for oscillation is relatively simple. However, bipolar transistor converters suffer from several disadvantages. For example they are subject to secondary breakdown phenomena, increased current leakage and increased power losses at elevated temperatures. The practical limit for junction temperature is 100&deg; C. (case temperature typically 85&deg; C.). Bipolar transistor converters are also expensive for high voltage applications (for example 277V, 240V and 220V). They also are less efficient in operation than field-effect transistors, because a typical limitation on frequency of operation is 35 kHz. Protection against fault conditions is difficult in a simple circuit using bipolar transistors. In addition, size reduction is limited due to operating frequency limitations, and it is difficult to achieve UL Class B temperature classification (135&deg; C. maximum insulation limitation) without a sacrifice in reliability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 6,157,551 to Barak, et al., assigned to Lightech Electronic Industries Ltd., which issued Dec. 5, 2000, teaches a power converter using bipolar transistors. However, this converter suffers from the foregoing disadvantages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 6,208,806 to Nerone, assigned to General Electric, which issued Mar. 21, 2001, teaches a power converter using N-channel and P-channel field effect transistors (FETs). Nerone achieves size reduction and improves efficiency by operating at higher frequencies (30 kHz-90 kHz). However, Nerone fails to address the issue of high temperature operation and fault protection. Besides, P-channel FETs are expensive compared to N-channel FETs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> There therefore exists a need for a converter that is simple and inexpensive to construct, while providing fault protection and achieving reliable, sustained operation at elevated operating temperatures. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a converter for converting alternating current (AC) power main voltage to a voltage suitable for driving a lamp. The converter comprises a rectifier circuit connectable to the AC power main, adapted to rectify the AC power main voltage and adapted to provide a direct current (DC) voltage; a driver circuit adapted to receive the DC voltage from the rectifier circuit, and provide a driver output voltage and a driver output current, and further adapted to receive an output current limiting signal; a starter circuit for providing a starter signal that initiates oscillation at an operating frequency in the driver circuit; a sensing circuit for sensing the driver output current and providing the output current limiting signal in response to the sensed driver output current; and a transformer for transforming the driver output voltage to a voltage suitable for driving a lamp such as a halogen lamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The sensing circuit may be further adapted to provide overheating protection for the converter. Overheating protection can be provisioned in a plurality of ways. In one embodiment, the sensing circuit includes a Negative Temperature Coefficient (NTC) thermistor that is in good thermal contact with the converter. A resistance of the NTC thermistor is reduced as a temperature of the converter rises. This causes the output current limiting signal to reduce output current from the driver circuit when the converter overheats. The reduction in driver output current permits the converter to cool and inhibits component failure. In another embodiment, a silicon diode is used rather than a NTC thermistor. A switching threshold of the silicon diode is reduced as a temperature of the converter rises. This causes the output current limiting signal to output current from the driver circuit to halt the rise in temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the invention, a method is provided for controlling an output voltage of a driver circuit in response to an output current of a converter for converting an AC (alternating current) power main voltage to a voltage suitable for driving a lamp. The method comprises the steps of sensing the converter output current; testing whether the sensed converter output current exceeds a threshold; sensing the extent to which the converter output current exceeds the threshold; triggering a latch when the sensed converter output current exceeds the threshold and stopping an oscillation of the driver circuit; re-setting the latch after a period of time related to an extent to which the converter output current exceeds the threshold, and re-starting the oscillation of the driver circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Advantages of the invention include power savings, extended service life for converter components, reduced power loss, and reduced heat generation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A further advantage of the invention is an avoidance of high cost electrolytic or tantalum capacitors, and improved reliability at high temperature operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of the invention is a protection against fault conditions, such as output short circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A further advantage of the invention is an extended operational temperature range for the converter, which enables the converter to achieve an Underwriters Laboratories (UL) Class B temperature classification up to 135&deg; C., which is a maximum insulation limitation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Yet another advantage of the invention is providing a converter with an operating frequency that is greater than 43 kHz, which enables smaller converter packages and more power efficient converters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Still another advantage of the invention relates to decreased current leakage and switching losses at elevated temperature resulting from the use of field-effect transistors for switching drive current. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides a converter, that is reliable, versatile, compact and efficient, with a reduced parts count.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Further features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description, taken in combination with the appended drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of converter in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an exemplary rectifier circuit for use in the converter shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an exemplary starter circuit for use in the converter shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an exemplary driver circuit for use in the converter shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an exemplary sensing circuit for use in the converter shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an exemplary sensing circuit for use in the converter shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an exemplary sensing circuit for use in the converter shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an exemplary transformer circuit for use in the converter shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a plot of an output voltage of the rectifier circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, versus time; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a plot of an output voltage of the driver circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, versus time; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a plot of an output current of the transformer circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, versus time; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a plot of an output voltage of the transformer circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, versus time; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a flowchart of a method of controlling pulse-width modulation in a converter in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> It will be noted that throughout the appended drawings, like features are identified by like reference numerals. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in accordance with the invention. The converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, a starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, a driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, a sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A, and a transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> has a first and second input <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> connectable to an AC (alternating current) power main <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> (shown in dotted outline), a first terminal <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> connected to a power supply node <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> connected to a ground reference node <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> has a first terminal <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> connected to power supply node <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, a second terminal <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> connected to ground reference node <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, a clamp <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and an output <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> has a first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> connected to the clamp <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, a first input <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> connected to output <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, a second input <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, a first terminal <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> connected to the power supply node <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, a second output <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. The sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A has an output <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> connected to the second input <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, a first terminal <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> connected to the second terminal <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> connected to ground reference node <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> has an input <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> connected to the second output <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, a first terminal <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> connected to the power supply node <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, a second terminal <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> connected to ground reference node <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and a first and second output <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> connectable to a lamp <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> (shown in dotted outline). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a conventional embodiment of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> includes a fuse <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, an inductor <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, a resistor <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, a capacitor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, a metal oxide varistor (MOV) <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, a first diode <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, a second diode <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, a third diode <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> and a fourth diode <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. The fuse <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is connected between the first input <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and a first node <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Inductor <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is connected between the first node <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and a second node <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. The resistor <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> is connected between the second node <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and a third node <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>. The capacitor is <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> is connected between the third node <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> and the second input <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The MOV <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is connected between the second node <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the second input <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The first diode <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> has an anode <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> connected to the second input <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> connected to the first terminal <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The second diode <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> has an anode <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> connected to the second terminal <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> connected to the second input <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The third diode <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> has an anode <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> connected to the second node <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> connected to the first terminal <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The fourth diode <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> has an anode <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> connected to the second terminal <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> connected to the second node <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a conventional embodiment of the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> that includes a resistor <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, a capacitor <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, a diode <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and a diac <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. The resistor <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is connected between the first terminal <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and a node <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. The capacitor <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> is connected from the node <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to the second terminal <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> of the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The diode <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> has an anode <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> connected to the node <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> connected to the clamp <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The diac <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> is connected between the node <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and the output <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a preferred embodiment of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, which includes a high-side switch, preferably a first N-channel FET (field effect transistor) <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>, a low-side switch, preferably a second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, a first bi-directional voltage clamping circuit <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight>, a second bi-directional voltage clamping circuit <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and a feedback transformer <highlight><bold>446</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> has a gate <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> connected to a first node <highlight><bold>472</bold></highlight>, a source <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> connected to the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and a drain <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> connected to the first terminal <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> has a gate <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> connected to the second input <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, a source <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> connected to the second terminal <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and a drain <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> connected to the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The first bi-directional voltage clamping circuit <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight> includes a first zener diode <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> having an anode <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> connected to a second node <highlight><bold>474</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> connected to the first node <highlight><bold>472</bold></highlight>; and a second zener diode <highlight><bold>426</bold></highlight> having an anode <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight> connected to the second node <highlight><bold>474</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> connected to the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The second bi-directional voltage clamping circuit <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> includes a third zener diode <highlight><bold>434</bold></highlight> having an anode <highlight><bold>436</bold></highlight> connected to a third node <highlight><bold>476</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>438</bold></highlight> connected to the second input <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>; and a fourth zener diode <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> having an anode <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight> connected to the third node <highlight><bold>476</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>444</bold></highlight> connected to the second terminal <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The feedback transformer <highlight><bold>446</bold></highlight> includes a first winding <highlight><bold>448</bold></highlight> having a first terminal <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight>, a second winding <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> having a first terminal <highlight><bold>456</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>458</bold></highlight>, a third winding <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> having a first terminal <highlight><bold>462</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>464</bold></highlight>, and a fourth winding <highlight><bold>466</bold></highlight> having a first terminal <highlight><bold>468</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight>. The first terminal <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> of the first winding <highlight><bold>448</bold></highlight> is connected to the second terminal <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The second terminal <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight> of the first winding <highlight><bold>448</bold></highlight> is connected to the second input <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The first terminal <highlight><bold>456</bold></highlight> of the second winding <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> is connected to the ground reference node <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The second terminal <highlight><bold>458</bold></highlight> of the second winding <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> is connected to the first input <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The first terminal <highlight><bold>462</bold></highlight> of the third winding <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> is connected to the first node <highlight><bold>472</bold></highlight>. The second terminal <highlight><bold>464</bold></highlight> of the third winding <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> is connected to the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The first terminal <highlight><bold>468</bold></highlight> of the fourth winding <highlight><bold>466</bold></highlight> is connected to the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The second terminal <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> of the fourth winding <highlight><bold>466</bold></highlight> is connected to the second output <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The first winding <highlight><bold>448</bold></highlight>, the second winding <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight>, the third winding <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> and the fourth winding <highlight><bold>466</bold></highlight> of the feedback transformer <highlight><bold>446</bold></highlight> are arranged so that current flowing into the first terminal <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> of the first winding <highlight><bold>448</bold></highlight> causes current to flow out of the first terminal <highlight><bold>456</bold></highlight> of the second winding <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight>, the first terminal <highlight><bold>462</bold></highlight> of the third winding <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> and the first terminal <highlight><bold>468</bold></highlight> of the fourth winding <highlight><bold>466</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> illustrates a preferred embodiment of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A, which includes a first resistor <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, a second resistor <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>, a first diode <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> which is preferably a schottky diode, a first capacitor <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>, a third resistor <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>, a second capacitor <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>, a fourth resistor <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>, an NPN transistor <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>, a PNP transistor <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight>, a fifth resistor <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight>, a third capacitor <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>, a fourth capacitor <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight> and a second diode <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The first resistor <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is connected between the first terminal <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A and the second terminal <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. The second resistor <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> is connected between the first terminal <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A and a first node <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight>. The first diode <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> has an anode <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> connected to the first node <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> and a cathode <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> that is connected to a second node <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>. The first capacitor <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> is connected between the second node <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> and the second terminal <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. The third resistor <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> is connected between the second node <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> and a third node <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight>. The second capacitor <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> is connected between the third node <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> and the second terminal <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. The fourth resistor <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> is connected between the third node <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> and the second terminal <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. The NPN transistor <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> has a base <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> connected to the third node <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight>, an emitter <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> connected to the second terminal <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A and a collector <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> connected to a fourth node <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight>. The PNP transistor <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> has a base <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> connected to the fourth node <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight>, an emitter <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> connected to a fifth node <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> and a collector <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight> connected to the third node <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight>. The fifth resistor <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> is connected between the fourth node <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight> and the fifth node <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight>. The third capacitor <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight> is connected between the fourth node <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight> and the fifth node <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight>. The fourth capacitor <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight> is connected between the fifth node <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> and the second terminal <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. The second diode <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight> has an anode <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight> connected to the output <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A and a cathode <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> connected to the fifth node <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight>. For convenience, a portion of sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A that includes the fourth resistor <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>, the NPN transistor <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>, the PNP transistor <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight>, the fifth resistor <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight>, the third capacitor <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>, the fourth capacitor <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight> and the second diode <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight> is hereinafter referred to as a latch <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> illustrates an alternate embodiment of a sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B. The sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B is identical to the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A except that a negative temperature coefficient (NTC) thermistor <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> has been added in parallel with third resistor <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>. The NTC thermistor <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> provides thermal protection for the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, as will be explained below in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference> shows another alternate embodiment of a sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>C. The sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>C is identical to the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A except that the first diode <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> has been replaced with a silicon diode <highlight><bold>509</bold></highlight> having a cathode <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight> connected to first node <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> and an anode <highlight><bold>513</bold></highlight> connected to second node <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>. The silicon diode <highlight><bold>509</bold></highlight> also provides thermal protection for the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, as will likewise be explained below in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a conventional embodiment of the transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> that includes a first capacitor <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>, a second capacitor <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>, and a transformer <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>. The first capacitor <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> is connected between the first terminal <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> of the transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and a node <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight>. The second capacitor <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> is connected between the node <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> and the second terminal <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> of the transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The transformer <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> has a first winding <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> having a first terminal <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight>; and a second winding <highlight><bold>614</bold></highlight> having a first terminal <highlight><bold>616</bold></highlight> and a second terminal <highlight><bold>618</bold></highlight>. The first terminal <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> of the first winding <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> is connected to the input <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> of the transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The second terminal <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> of the first winding <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> is connected to the node <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight>. The first terminal <highlight><bold>616</bold></highlight> of the second winding <highlight><bold>614</bold></highlight> is connected to the first output <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> of the transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The second terminal <highlight><bold>618</bold></highlight> of the second winding <highlight><bold>614</bold></highlight> is connected to the second output <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> of the transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In operation, the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) receives a 60 Hz, 120V power main voltage applied to first and second inputs <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and outputs a semi-sinusoidal voltage <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> at 120 Hz, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the x-axis <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> represents time (seconds) and the y-axis <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight> represents voltage (Volts). The operation of the rectifier circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is understood by those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Oscillation of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> starts each cycle when the voltage applied to the node <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> rises sufficiently to turn on the diac <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. When the diac <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> turns on, a pulse of current is provided to the second winding <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> of the feedback transformer <highlight><bold>446</bold></highlight>. The pulse of current is coupled through the third winding <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> to the gate <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> of the first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and through the second winding <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> to the gate <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> of the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. The direction of the third winding <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> and the second winding <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> are selected so that the pulse of current from the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> will turn off the first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and turn on the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. This causes the voltage on the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to fall. If a load, such as a lamp <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, is connected to the first and second outputs <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> of the transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, then a driver output current will flow through the fourth winding <highlight><bold>466</bold></highlight>. The direction of the fourth winding <highlight><bold>466</bold></highlight> is selected so that a positive feedback is supplied to the gate <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> of the first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and the gate <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> of the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. The voltage of the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> falls to the voltage of the ground reference node <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. After a period of time determined by the size and the maximum flux density of the core used in the feedback transformer <highlight><bold>446</bold></highlight>, the feedback to the gate <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> of the first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and the gate <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> of the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is removed. The voltage of the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> starts to rise, creating a positive feedback that turns on the first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and turns off the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. The voltage of the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> rises to the voltage of the power supply node <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>. Again, after a period of time determined by the size and the maximum flux density of the core used in feedback transformer <highlight><bold>446</bold></highlight>, the feedback to the gate <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> of the first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and the gate <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> of the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is removed. The voltage of the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> then starts to fall, creating positive feedback that turns off the first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> and turns on the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Thus, oscillation is established at an operating frequency in the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. If no load is present, there is no positive feedback and no oscillation occurs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Once oscillation has been established, the diode <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> of the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) maintains a voltage of the node <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> of the starter circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> at a value that is less than a conduction threshold voltage of the diac <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Voltage waveform <highlight><bold>802</bold></highlight> of the first output <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, in which the x-axis <highlight><bold>804</bold></highlight> represents time (seconds) and the y-axis <highlight><bold>806</bold></highlight> represents voltage (Volts). The resulting current waveform <highlight><bold>902</bold></highlight> in the lamp <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, wherein the x-axis <highlight><bold>904</bold></highlight> represents time (seconds) and the y-axis <highlight><bold>906</bold></highlight> represents current (Amperes). It should be noted that the operating frequency illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8, 9</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is much lower than the normal operating frequency for purposes of clarity, and that normal operating frequency is preferably greater than 43 kHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> provides current overload protection. When a current overload condition occurs, such as a short circuit between the first and second outputs <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> of transformer circuit <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> causing the output current of driver circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to rise above a predetermined threshold, a voltage across the first resistor <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>) is large enough to turn on the first diode <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. The first capacitor <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> and the second capacitor <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> are charged so that latch <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> is triggered. The triggering of latch <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> causes current to be drawn into the output <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A and to reduce voltage on the gate <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> of the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and the gate <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> of the first N-channel FET <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> by mutual coupling (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). This turns off the second N-channel FET <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> causing the voltage on the first terminal <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A to decrease, oscillation of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to stop and turn off the first diode <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. After a period of time determined by values of the first capacitor <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>, the third resistor <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>, the second capacitor <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>, the fourth resistor <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>, the fifth resistor <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight>, the third capacitor <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>, the fourth capacitor <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight>, and the extent to which the output current of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> exceeded the predetermined threshold, the latch <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> re-sets to permit oscillation of driver circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to re-start. The resulting waveform <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight> of the voltage across the lamp <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, wherein the x-axis <highlight><bold>1004</bold></highlight> represents time (seconds) and the y-axis <highlight><bold>1006</bold></highlight> represents voltage (Volts). The voltage across the lamp <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is thus pulse-width modulated by the current limiting signal on the output <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The alternate embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> introduces the NTC thermistor <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> to provide temperature protection for the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The NTC thermistor <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> is placed in good thermal contact with converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. As the temperature of the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> rises, the impedance of the NTC thermistor <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> is reduced. This has the effect of reducing the predetermined threshold for the current overload condition described above. Consequently, as the temperature of the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> increases beyond a threshold determined by resistance characteristics of the NTC thermistor <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>, the driver output current provided to the lamp <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is reduced, permitting the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to cool. As cooling occurs, the driver output current is increased. The cycle automatically repeats, as required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In the alternate embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>C, the silicon diode <highlight><bold>509</bold></highlight> serves the same function as the NTC thermistor <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>. The silicon diode <highlight><bold>509</bold></highlight> is placed in good thermal contact with the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. As the temperature of the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> rises, the switching threshold of the silicon diode <highlight><bold>509</bold></highlight> is reduced. This also has the effect of reducing the predetermined threshold of the current limiting circuit described above, to provide thermal protection as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The present invention also provides a method for controlling an output voltage of the driver circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to provide current limiting protection for the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a flowchart <highlight><bold>1100</bold></highlight> illustrating the method. The method starts (step <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight>) when power is supplied to the AC inputs <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the rectifier <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The driver output current is sensed (step <highlight><bold>1104</bold></highlight>) by the sensing current <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B or <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>C to determine whether the sensed driver output current exceeds a threshold (step <highlight><bold>1106</bold></highlight>) determined by the component values of the components of the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A, as described above. If the driver current is not greater than the threshold, the sensing of the driver output current continues (step <highlight><bold>1104</bold></highlight>). If, however, the sensed driver output current exceeds the threshold, then the extent to which the driver output current exceeds the threshold is sensed (step <highlight><bold>1108</bold></highlight>). The latch <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> is triggered when the sensed driver output current exceeds the threshold. This stops an oscillation of the driver circuit (step <highlight><bold>1110</bold></highlight>). The latch <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> is re-set after a period of time related to an extent to which the driver output current exceeded the threshold (step <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight>) Meanwhile, the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A continues to sense the driver output current (step <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As explained above, if the NTC thermistor <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference>) or the silicon diode <highlight><bold>509</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference>) are added to the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is further provided with temperature protection, which permits the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to continue to operate at elevated temperatures without component damage. Experimentation has shown that the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in accordance with the invention can be operated for extended periods of time at case temperatures of at least 110&deg; C., provided that the sensing circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is constructed as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> or <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The invention therefore provides a simple, high-frequency, light-weight, compact converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> that is inexpensive to construct and more robust than converters known from the prior art. The high operating frequency permits all capacitors: <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight> shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A-C, and <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, to be solid-state non-polarized capacitors, thereby reducing the weight and package size of the converter <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The embodiment(s) of the invention described above is (are) intended to be exemplary only. The scope of the invention is therefore intended to be limited solely by the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A converter for converting an AC (alternating current) power main voltage to a voltage suitable for driving a lamp, the converter comprising: 
<claim-text>a rectifier circuit connectable to the AC power main, adapted to rectify the AC power main voltage and adapted to provide a DC (direct current) voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a driver circuit adapted to receive the DC voltage from the rectifier circuit, and provide a driver output voltage and a driver output current and further adapted to receive an output current limiting signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a starter circuit for providing a starter signal that initiates oscillation at an operating frequency in the driver circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing circuit for sensing an output current of the driver circuit and providing the output current limiting signal in response to the sensed output current of the driver circuit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transformer circuit for transforming the driver output voltage to a voltage suitable for driving the lamp. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the driver circuit is adapted to modulate the driver output voltage using the output current limiting signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the driver circuit is further adapted to pulse-width modulate the driver output voltage using the output current limiting signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lamp is a halogen lamp. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rectifier circuit is a full-wave bridge rectifier circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the operating frequency is greater than about 43 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the driver circuit comprises a high-side switch, a low-side switch and a feedback transformer having a first winding for providing feedback the to low-side switch, a second winding for receiving the starter signal from the starter circuit, a third winding for providing feedback to the high-side switch and a fourth winding for receiving the driver output voltage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the high-side switch has a control terminal, a first terminal and a second terminal; the low-side switch has a control terminal, a first terminal and a second terminal; the first, second, third and fourth windings of the feedback transformer respectively have a first terminal and a second terminal; and, the first terminal of the first winding is connected a second terminal of the driver circuit, the second terminal of the first winding is connected to a second input of the driver circuit, the first terminal of the second winding is connected to a ground reference node, the second terminal of the second winding is connected to a first input of the driver circuit, the first terminal of the third winding is connected to the control terminal of the high-side switch, the second terminal of the third winding is connected to a first output of the driver circuit, the first terminal of the fourth winding is connected to the first output of the driver circuit, the second terminal of the fourth winding is connected to a second output of the driver circuit, the first terminal of the high-side switch is connected to first terminal of the driver circuit, the second terminal of the high-side switch is connected to the first output of the driver circuit, the first terminal of the low-side switch is connected to the first output of the driver circuit and the second terminal of the low-side switch is connected to the second terminal of the driver circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first, second, third and fourth windings of the feedback transformer are arranged such that current flowing into the first terminal of the first winding causes current to flow out of the first terminal of the second, third and fourth windings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the high-side and low-side switches are N-channel field-effect transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a first bi-directional voltage clamping circuit connected between the control terminal and second terminal of the high-side switch and a second bi-directional voltage clamping circuit connected between the control terminal and second terminal of the low-side switch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the starter circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a resistor connected between a positive supply node and a charging node; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor connected between the charging node and a ground reference node; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a diode having an anode connected to the charging node and a cathode connected to an input of the starter circuit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a diac connected between the charging node and an output of the starter circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the capacitor is a solid-state non-polarized capacitor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sensing circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>an impedance for sensing the driver output current; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a latch adapted to be triggered when the sensed driver output current exceeds a predetermined threshold and to re-set after a predetermined time interval; and further adapted to provide the output current limiting signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sensing circuit further comprises a temperature dependent impedance for sensing a temperature of the converter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the predetermined threshold is modified in response to a change in the sensed temperature of the converter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the output current limiting signal governs pulse-width modulation of the driver output voltage by the driver circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the temperature dependent impedance is a negative temperature coefficient thermistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the temperature dependent impedance is a silicon diode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sensing circuit comprises a first resistor connected between an input of the sensing circuit and a ground reference node; a second resistor connected between the input of the sensing circuit and a first node; a first diode having an anode connected to the first node and a cathode connected to a second node; a first capacitor connected between the second node and the ground reference node; a third resistor connected between the second node and a third node; a second capacitor connected between the third node and the ground reference node; a fourth resistor connected between the third node and the ground reference node; an NPN transistor having a base connected to the third node, an emitter connected to the ground reference node and a collector connected to a fourth node; a PNP transistor having a collector connected to the third node, a base connected to the fourth node and an emitter connected to a fifth node; a fifth resistor connected between the fourth node and the fifth node; a third capacitor connected between the fourth node and fifth node; a fourth capacitor connected between the fifth node and the ground reference node; and a second diode having an anode connected to an output of the sensing circuit and a cathode connected to the fifth node. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first, second, third and fourth capacitors are solid-state non-polarized capacitors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first diode is a schottky diode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first diode is a silicon diode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a thermistor connected between the second node and the third node. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sensing circuit is further adapted to sense the driver output current and to provide the output current limiting signal according to the driver output current and the temperature of the converter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The converter as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the output current limiting signal governs pulse-width modulation of the driver output voltage by the driver circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A method for controlling an output voltage of a driver circuit in response to an output current of a converter for converting an AC (alternating current) power main voltage to a voltage suitable for driving a lamp, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>sensing the converter output current to determine whether the sensed converter output current exceeds a threshold; </claim-text>
<claim-text>if the threshold is exceeded, sensing an extent to which the converter output current exceeds the threshold; </claim-text>
<claim-text>triggering a latch when the sensed converter output current exceeds the threshold to stop an oscillation of the driver circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>re-setting the latch after a period of time related to an extent to which the converter output current exceeded the threshold to permit the oscillation of the driver circuit to be re-started. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a step of using an output voltage of the converter to drive a halogen lamp. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of sensing further comprises a step using a temperature dependent impedance to perform the output current sensing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a step of sensing a temperature of the converter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a step of reducing the predetermined threshold in response to the sensed temperature of the converter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of sensing the temperature further comprises a step of using a thermistor to sense the temperature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of sensing the temperature further comprises a step of using a silicon diode to sense the temperature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a step of oscillating the driver circuit at frequency that permits exclusive use of solid-state non-polarized capacitors in the converter.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001517A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
