<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000755A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000755A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000755A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000755A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000755</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893942</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B62M007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>180</class>
<subclass>229000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Air management system for a motorcycle</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tony</given-name>
<family-name>Schroeder</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Huntington Beach</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>RANKIN, HILL, PORTER &amp; CLARK LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>700 HUNTINGTON BUILDING</address-1>
<address-2>925 EUCLID AVENUE</address-2>
<city>CLEVELAND</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>44115-1405</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An air management system for a motorcycle including a first air channel and a second air channel. The first air channel defines a first passageway extending through a body of the motorcycle, the first passageway having an inlet located on a first side of the motorcycle and an outlet located under a seat of the motorcycle. The second air channel defines a second passageway passing through the body of the motorcycle, the second passageway having an inlet located on a second side of the motorcycle and an outlet in communication with an engine air inlet. The first and second passageway inlets are relatively symmetrically disposed relative to a longitudinal axis of the motorcycle. The first air passageway delivers cooling air to a radiator that is disposed beneath the motorcycle seat, while the second air passageway delivers air to the engine air inlet. An air filter is disposed in a terminal portion of the second air channel and is oriented relatively transverse to the motorcycle axis. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed toward a system for managing air in a motorcycle and, more particularly, toward a system for managing cooling air and engine air in a motorcycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Motorcycle radiators have traditionally been located at the front of the engine and relatively behind the front tire. While this places the radiator at a location to receive cooling air during operation of the motorcycle, it also places the radiator at a location to be heated by the engine exhaust manifold. Moreover, despite the forward location of the radiator, the flow of cooling air is blocked by the front tire. Accordingly, the size of the radiator must be increased to obtain satisfactory cooling performance. This, in turn, increases the front profile of the motorcycle, which not only has a negative effect on the appearance of the motorcycle, but also increases the motorcycle drag. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Moreover, air inlets for the engine are traditionally located rearwardly relative to the radiator. However, it is important that these inlets be positioned so that the heated air from the radiator does not enter the engine. Moreover, the air inlets require an air filter to remove dirt and particulates from the air stream prior to delivery to the engine. These competing requirements typically place the air filter in a difficult position for replacement and also conventionally requires a separate housing to secure the air filter in place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Therefore, there exists a need in the art for a cooling system that places the radiator in a more advantageous position, and for an air management system that delivers air to the radiator as well as the engine. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF FHE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed toward a motorcycle air management system that delivers cooling air to a rear mounted radiator and delivers air to the engine. The present invention is further directed toward an air management system that provides an easily accessible and replaceable air filter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention the air management system includes a first air channel and a second air channel, each of the first and second air channels having an inlet disposed toward a front of the motorcycle and an outlet disposed rearward relative to the inlet. The first air channel is disposed on a first side of the motorcycle and extends through a body of the motorcycle to the first air channel outlet, which is located behind and beneath a seat of the motorcycle. The second air channel is disposed on a second side of the motorcycle and extends through the body of the motorcycle to the second air channel outlet, which is in communication with an engine air inlet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In further accordance with the present invention, the first and second air channel inlets are symmetrically disposed relative to a longitudinal axis of the motorcycle. The first air channel communicates cooling air to a radiator that is disposed behind and beneath the motorcycle seat. Preferably, cooling air flows from the first air channel outlet and through the radiator. The healed air from the radiator exits the motorcycle body at a location upwardly adjacent a rear wheel of the motorcycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In further accordance with the present invention, the second air channel extends from the second air channel inlet rearwardly beyond the gas tank, and has an air filter disposed therein. The air filter is preferably cylindrical and oriented transverse the longitudinal axis of the motorcycle.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> These and further features of the invention will be apparent with reference to the following description and drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic perspective view of a motorcycle incorporating an air management system according to the present invention; and, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic top plan view of the motorcycle illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> With reference to the drawing figures, an air management system according to the present invention is shown incorporated into a motorcycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The motorcycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a body having a steering head <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a front wheel <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a rear wheel <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a seat or saddle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, an engine <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and a gas tank assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. With the exception of the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the air management system, the construction of the motorcycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is generally conventional and will only be discussed in detail hereinafter as it relates to the inventive structure. The motorcycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> about which the motorcycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is generally laterally symmetrical. The gas tank assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is aligned with the axis <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and disposed relatively forward of the seat or saddle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The engine <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is disposed relatively beneath the gas tank assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and is mechanically interlinked in a known fashion to the rear wheel <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The steering head <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and front wheel <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are ahead of the gas tank assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, while the rear wheel <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is disposed relatively beneath and behind the seat <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated and preferred embodiment, the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is disposed relatively rearward and beneath the seat <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and relatively above the rear wheel <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is disposed in a space between the rear cowling <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the rear wheel <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Insulation, if necessary, may be provided under the seat <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to prevent heat migration to the rider as may occur when the motorcycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is stopped. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The air management system includes a first air channel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and a second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> that each define a passageway for the communication of air from the forward portion of the motorcycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to a relatively rearward location of the motorcycle, to be discussed more fully hereinafter. Each of the air channels <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has an inlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and an outlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The inlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the first air channel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is disposed on a first side of the motorcycle longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, while the inlet <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is disposed on a second, opposite side of the motorcycle longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The outlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the first air channel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is disposed at a location relatively beneath the rear cowling <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, rearward relative to the motorcycle seat <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and relatively above the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Thus, the first air channel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> travels beneath the gas tank cover and the seat <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> as it extends rearwardly from the inlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>toward the outlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The outlet <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is disposed relatively beneath the gas tank assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and in-line with the engine <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, as will be discussed further hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The air channel inlets <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are preferably disposed relatively forward of the steering head <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and extend under and through a front cowling <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Screens (not shown) are preferably disposed within the air channels <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, relatively rearward of the inlets <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. As will be appreciated by one skilled in the art of motorcycle design, the air channels <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are secured by mechanical fasteners to the motorcycle frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Air flows through the passageway of the first air channel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> from the inlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the outlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and then flows across and downwardly through the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to cool the liquid therein. Heated air from the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> exits downwardly toward the rear wheel <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and relatively away from the rider. Naturally, it is contemplated and expected that the orientation of the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> relative to the first air channel outlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>could be adjusted so that the air flows vertically upward or laterally through the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, in dependence upon the radiator orientation. For example, the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> could be oriented vertically or diagonally instead of the illustrated generally horizontal orientation. Finally, the longitudinal position of the radiator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> relative to the seat <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be altered to accommodate various design considerations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> delivers air to engine air inlets via an air filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. As shown best in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> the air filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is disposed in a terminal portion of the second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The illustrated air filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is cylindrical in shape and has a closed proximal end <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and an open distal end, the distal end being adjacent the engine air inlet. The outer surface of the closed proximal end <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the air filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is exposed to the exterior and preferably integrally provides a fastener that cooperates with a surrounding air filter chamber <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> provided by the terminal portion of the second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to releasably secure the air filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to the second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Such a fastener may be a twist and lock or bayonet type fastener, or may be spring biased to normally maintain the air filter in an installed position. As such, the air filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is disposed in a location that is easily accessible, and is adapted to be simply and quickly removed and replaced. Engine air flows through the second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> from the inlet <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the outlet <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and issues into the air filter chamber <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> that receives the air filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The air flows radially through the cylindrical sidewall of the air filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and relatively clean air flows axially, via the open end of the filter <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, to the engine air inlets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Each of the first and second air channels <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extend through the front cowling <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and into the gas tank assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> so as to be relatively beneath a gas tank cover and alongside the gas tank. The channels <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> then curve downwardly and inwardly toward the longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the motorcycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As will be readily appreciated, the first air channel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is longer than the second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and is bent downwardly at a location relatively behind the gas tank assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> so as to pass beneath the seat <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The shorter, second air channel <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> terminates relatively beneath the gas tank assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> so as to provide air to the engine air inlets disposed therebeneath. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The present invention has been described herein with particularity, but it is noted that the scope of the invention is not limited thereto. Rather, the present invention is considered to be possible of numerous modifications, alterations, and combinations of parts and, therefore, is only defined by the claims appended hereto. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An air management system for a motorcycle, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first air channel defining a first passageway extending through a body of the motorcycle, said first passageway having an inlet located on a first side of the motorcycle and an outlet communicating cooling air to a rearwardly disposed radiator; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second air channel defining a second passageway passing through the body of the motorcycle, said second passageway having an inlet located on a second side of the motorcycle and an outlet in communication with an engine air inlet the second passageway inlet being located on a second side of the motorcycle, wherein the inlets for the first and second passageways are positioned in a substantially symmetrical manner at a front of the motorcycle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The air management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first passageway outlet is disposed relatively rearward of the seat. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The air management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the radiator is disposed generally horizontally and the first passageway outlet is disposed adjacent said radiator such that air flowing from the first passageway outlet flows downwardly through the radiator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The air management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an air filter disposed relatively between the second passageway outlet and the engine air inlet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The air management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air filter is oriented transverse to a longitudinal axis of the motorcycle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The air management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air filter is cylindrical and includes a closed proximal end including a fastener to releasably secure the air filter to a terminal portion of the second air channel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The air management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first passageway outlet is disposed relatively rearward of the seat. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The air management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the radiator is disposed generally horizontally, and the first passageway outlet is disposed adjacent said radiator such that air flowing from the first passageway outlet flows downwardly through the radiator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A motorcycle including a front wheel, a rear wheel, a steering head, an engine, a seat, a radiator, and a gas tank assembly, said motorcycle having a longitudinal axis aligned with said front and rear wheels said gas tank assembly being disposed relatively behind said front wheel and said steering head and relatively above said engine, said seat being disposed relatively behind said gas tank assembly and relatively above said radiator, the improvement comprising: 
<claim-text>an air management system for delivering air to the engine and radiator, said air management system comprising: 
<claim-text>a first air channel defining a first passageway extending through a body of the motorcycle, said first passageway having an inlet located on a first side of the motorcycle and an outlet through which cooling air flows to said radiator; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second air channel defining a second passageway passing through the body of the motorcycle, said second passageway having an inlet located on a second side of the motorcycle and an outlet in communication with an air inlet of the engine, the second passageway inlet being located on a second side of the motorcycle, wherein the inlets for the first and second passageways are positioned in a substantially symmetrical manner at a front of the motorcycle and relatively forward of the steering head. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The motorcycle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first passageway outlet is disposed relatively rearward of the seat. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The motorcycle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the radiator is disposed generally horizontally and the first passageway outlet is disposed vertically adjacent said radiator such that air flowing from the first passageway outlet flows downwardly through the radiator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The motorcycle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an air filter disposed relatively between the second passageway outlet and the engine air inlet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The motorcycle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air filter is oriented relatively transverse to the longitudinal axis of the motorcycle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The motorcycle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air filter is cylindrical and includes a closed proximal end including a fastener to releasably secure the air filter to a terminal portion of the second air channel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The motorcycle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first passageway outlet is disposed relatively rearward of the seat. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The motorcycle according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the radiator is disposed generally horizontally and the first passageway outlet is disposed adjacent said radiator such that air flowing from the first passageway outlet flows downwardly through the radiator.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000755A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000755A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
