<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003337A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003337A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003337A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003337A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003337A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003337A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003337A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003337A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003337A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003337A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003337A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003337A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003337</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09996880</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011130</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01M008/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>429</class>
<subclass>026000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>429</class>
<subclass>038000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Fuel cell power system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09996880</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20011130</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09873139</doc-number>
<document-date>20010601</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>P.</middle-name>
<family-name>Scartozzi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Spokane</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>DeVries</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Tekoa</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>WELLS ST. JOHN ROBERTS GREGORY &amp; MATKIN P.S.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>601 W. FIRST AVENUE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1300</address-2>
<city>SPOKANE</city>
<state>WA</state>
<postalcode>99201-3828</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A fuel cell power system is described and which includes a plurality of modules each enclosing a fuel cell stack and a cooling assembly, and wherein at least one of the modules can be easily removed from the fuel cell power system, by hand, while the remaining modules continue to operate. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED PATENT DATA </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/873,139 filed on Jun. 1, 2001, and which is incorporated by reference herein.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a fuel cell power system, and more specifically to a fuel cell power system which employs fuel cell power modules which enclose fuel cell stacks </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The fuel cell is an electrochemical device which reacts hydrogen; and oxygen, which is usually supplied from the air, to produce electricity and water. Heretofore, fuel cells have utilized a wide range of fuels, including, but not limited to, natural gas and coal derived synthetic fuels, and which are subsequently converted to electric power. The basic process is well understood, highly efficient, and for those fuel cells fueled directly by hydrogen, pollution free. Further, since fuel cells can be assembled into stacks of varying sizes, power systems have been developed to produce a wide range of output levels to satisfy numerous applications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Although the fundamental electrochemical processes involved in all fuel cells are well understood, engineering solutions have proved elusive for making fuel cell stack arrangements commercially feasible, and economical. In the case of fuel cell slacks which use proton exchange membranes, reliability has not been the driving concern to date, but rather the principal concern has been the installed cost per watt of generation capacity. With respect to these types of fuel cells, in order to lower the cost per watt, much attention has been placed on increasing power output. In the elusive search to increase power output, much research and development activity has been spent on additional, and often sophisticated balance-of-plant measures. These previous balance-of-plant measures or systems have been deemed necessary to optimize and maintain the high fuel cell power outputs desired. As a direct result of these additional balance-of-plant measures these fuel cell systems do not readily scale down to low generation capacities. Consequently, the installed cost; efficiency; reliability and maintenance expenses are all adversely affected in low generation applications. Yet further, since proton exchange membrane fuel cells produce a useful voltage of only about 0.5 to about 0.7 volts D.C. under a load, practical fuel cell plants have been built from multiple cells stacked together such that they are electrically connected in series. In order to reduce the number of parts and to minimize costs, rigid supporting/conducting separator plates, often fabricated from graphite or special metals have been utilized. This is often described as bipolar construction. Heretofore, practical stacks have consisted of 20 or more cells in order to produce the direct current voltages necessary for efficient inverting to alternating current. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> While the economic advantages of stack designs using bipolar plate construction are compelling, this construction does have numerous disadvantages which have detracted from its usefulness. For example, if the voltage or performance of a single cell in a stack begins to decline or fails, the entire stack, which is held together in compression with tie bolts, must be taken out of service, disassembled and repaired. In traditional fuel cell stack designs, the fuel and oxygen are directed by means of internal manifolds to the proper electrodes. Cooling for the stack is provided either by the reactants; natural convection; radiation; and possibly supplemental cooling plates. Also included in the prior art stack designs are cell-to-cell seals; insulation; piping and various instrumentation and sensors for use in monitoring the fuel cell performance. As should be apparent, if malfunction or a maintenance problem occurs with a fuel cell stack design, there is no ready solution except to take the fuel cell stack off-line and return it to the factory for repair or replacement as necessary. In view of the difficulties encountered in removing fuel cell stacks of this type for repair or replacement, such designs have not become practical from a commercial sense, at least as applied to low generation applications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A new fuel cell power system utilizing fuel cell stack technology which avoids the perceived shortcomings of the prior art is the subject matter of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> One aspect of the present invention is to provide a fuel cell power system which includes a plurality of fuel cell power modules, each enclosing a fuel cell stack, and a cooling assembly, and wherein at least one of the modules can be removed from the fuel cell power system, by hand, while the remaining modules continue to operate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention is to provide a fuel cell power system which includes an enclosure defining an internal space; a subrack or module receiving assembly moveably mounted on the enclosure and operable to be received in the internal space defined by the enclosure; and a plurality of fuel cell power modules each enclosing a fuel cell stack, and wherein the modules operably mate with the subrack or module receiving assembly, and can be removed from the subrack while the remaining modules continue to operate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Yet another aspect of the present invention relates to a fuel cell power system which includes a module receiving assembly; a module frame having an internal cavity, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly; a fuel cell stack mounted in the internal cavity; a controller which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and a cooling assembly borne by the module frame, and which directs a flow of air from ambient through the fuel cell stack, and which returns the air to ambient to facilitate the dissipation of heat generated while the fuel cell stack is operational. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Moreover, another aspect of the present invention relates to a fuel cell power system which includes a module receiving assembly; a module frame having opposite front and rear walls which define, in part, an internal cavity, and which is further defined by a major axis extending between the opposite front and rear walls, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly; a fuel cell stack mounted in the internal cavity; a controller which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and a cooling assembly borne by the module frame and coupled to the controller, and which dissipates heat energy generated by the fuel cell stack while it is in operation; and wherein the cooling assembly further includes an air plenum which extends substantially between the front and rear walls, and which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient, and which directs a flow of air from ambient, along the air plenum, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient; and a fan mounted in the internal cavity of the module frame, and which is operably coupled to the air plenum to facilitate movement of the air along the air plenum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Still another aspect of the present invention relates to a fuel cell power system which includes a module receiving assembly; a module frame defining an internal cavity, and which has opposite first and second ends; a fuel cell stack mounted in the internal cavity, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly; a controller which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and a cooling assembly which directs a flow of cooling fluid along a substantially non-linear path of travel between the first and second ends of the module frame, and through the fuel cell stack to dissipate heat energy generated by the fuel cell in operation.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings serve to explain the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a front elevation view of a fuel cell power system of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the module receiving assembly employed with the present invention, and showing a portion of a fuel cell power module which is enclosed within same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective, rear elevation view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective, plan view of a fuel cell power module employed in the fuel cell power system of the present invention with the top surface removed to show the structure thereunder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective, rear elevation view of the structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> This disclosure of the invention is submitted in furtherance of the constitutional purposes of the U.S. Patent Laws &ldquo;to promote the progress of science and useful arts&rdquo; (Article 1, Section 8). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The fuel cell power system is generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As shown therein, the fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes an enclosure or housing which is generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The enclosure is defined by a top surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>; bottom surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>; opposite side walls <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>; a rear wall <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>; and a front wall <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, all of which defines a generally rigid enclosure. An internal cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is defined by the surfaces or walls <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, respectively. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> pair of subrack apertures <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are formed in, and are defined by the front wall <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and are operable to allow the passage of the respective subracks therethrough. These subracks will be discussed in greater detail hereinafter. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> first pair of rails <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>; and a second pair of rails <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> (shown in phantom lines); are individually mounted within the cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and are oriented in generally horizontal, spaced, parallel relation one to the other. The respective pairs of rails are operable to slidably mate, couple, or otherwise mechanically cooperate with corresponding mating rail structures which are mounted on the subrack, which will be discussed hereinafter, to permit the subrack to be slidably or moveably received through one of the apertures <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and then located in an operable orientation within the cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The enclosure or housing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is supplied with a fuel supply which is generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. This fuel supply may come from numerous sources. For example, the fuel supply may comprise bottled hydrogen, or a fuel which is supplied by way of a fuel processor. The fuel may also comprise a hydrogen rich gas. For purposes of further discussion in this application however, it will be assumed that the fuel supply <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> comprises hydrogen, or a hydrogen rich gas, which may have been generated by means of a fuel processor. A fuel supply conduit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is coupled in fluid flowing relation relative to the fuel supply <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and terminates inside of the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> by way of a suitable releasably sealable fluid coupling. Similarly, a suitable oxidant supply <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is provided, and is coupled in fluid flowing relation relative to the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> by means of an oxidant supply conduit <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. This oxidant supply conduit similarly terminates with an appropriate releasably sealable fluid coupling. The oxidant supply <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may constitute air; although, depending upon the type of fuel cell employed, it may also include other gasses. If air is the oxidant for the fuel cell, in one form of the invention, the oxidant supply conduit, may not be required. This will be discussed in greater detail hereinafter. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1 a</cross-reference> data conduit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is provided, and which terminates in the cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The data conduit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> allows the transmission of electrical signals (data) to and from the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. These electrical signals permit, in some forms of the invention, the control; and monitoring of the performance of the fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Yet further, a power conduit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is borne by the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, and terminates within the cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The power cable or conduit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is operable to direct electrical power generated by the fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> away from the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and to a remote location. The electrical power generated by the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may include D.C. power; or A.C. power, in the event that the fuel cell power system includes an inverter for converting the D.C. to A.C.. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2 a</cross-reference> fuel cell module receiving assembly or subrack is generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. As seen therein, the module receiving assembly or subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is defined by top and bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>; a rear surface <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>; a front surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>; and opposite sidewalls <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. An engagement flange <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is affixed substantially along the peripheral edge of the front surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and is operable to engage the front wall <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> when the module receiving assembly or subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is fully received or seated in an operable position or orientation relative to the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Module apertures <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> are formed in the front surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and are operable to matingly receive and allow the passage of the respective fuel cell power modules, which will be discussed hereinafter. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> pair of rail guides <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> are attached or mounted on each of the opposite sides <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> (only one pair shown). The respective pairs of rail guides <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> slidably and otherwise cooperatively mate with the first and second pair of rail guides <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> which are mounted in the cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In this arrangement the individual module subracks <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can move reciprocally relative to the cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. This arrangement also allows the respective modular subracks <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to be easily repaired, replaced, or inspected in the event of poor performance or failure, while the remaining modular subracks continue to operate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> pair of fluid couplings, which are generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, are mounted at predetermined locations on the rear surface <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The respective fluid couplings <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> include a fuel coupler <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>; and an oxidant coupler <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, both of which extend through the rear surface <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The fuel and oxidant couplers <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> are coupled in releasable, fluid flowing relation relative to the respective fuel and oxidant supply lines <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which terminate within the cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, and which were discussed above. Yet further, a power coupler <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and a data coupler <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> are also provided. These power and data couplers similarly correspondingly releasably mate or electrically couple with the power conduit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>; and the data conduit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, both of which terminate within the cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, in phantom lines, a D.C. Bus <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is provided and which is mounted internally of the subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Yet further a fuel/oxidant manifold <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is also provided and is mounted in spaced, relation relative to the D.C. Bus <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. A data bus <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> is also mounted internally of the subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> for the purposes which will be discussed below. As will be appreciated from a study of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the individual fuel cell modular subracks <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be easily and rapidly detached and removed from the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> without need of special tools, and most importantly by hand. Yet further, and in another form of the invention, the subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may include an inverter (not shown) for converting D.C. to A.C.. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention includes a plurality of fuel cell power modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, each enclosing a fuel cell stack, which will be discussed hereinafter, and wherein at least one of the fuel cell power modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can be removed from the fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, by hand, while the remaining fuel cell power modules continue to operate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, each of the fuel cell power modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> comprise a module frame which is generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The module frame defines an internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> which encloses the operable components or elements which will be discussed below. The module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> includes a front wall or first end <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>; a rear wall or second end <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, which is spaced from the front wall <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>; and opposite first and second side walls <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. Together, these walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> form a generally narrowly rectangular shape. The module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is further defined by a major axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> which extends between the front and rear walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Of course, other enclosure shapes may be employed with equal success. The module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> further has a top surface <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and a bottom surface <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4 a</cross-reference> control or status panel <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which displays several of the operational conditions of the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is mounted on or affixed to the front wall <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. The control or status panel may have various warning lights; alpha-numeric indicators; visually perceptible digital or analog controls of various types, and assorted switches which control or display various aspects of the operation or condition of the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Still further, and as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> an air passageway or cooling fluid passageway <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> is formed through, or defined by the front wall <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. This air passageway <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> allows ambient air to pass into, and through the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> for the purposes which will be discussed in greater detail below. Also seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, is a handle <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> which is attached to the front wall <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, and a pair of rail guides <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> which are individually mounted on the first and second sidewalls <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. It should be understood that these rail guides <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> matingly couple or mechanically cooperate with other rail guide assemblies (not shown) which are mounted internally of the fuel cell module subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Such can be understood from a study of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. As will be appreciated, the pair of rail guides <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> permit the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to be easily removed, by hand, from the subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> for purposes of maintenance, repair, or replacement depending upon the operational needs or conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, it will be seen that a plurality of fluid couplers <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> are mounted on the rear wall <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. In this regard the respective fluid couplers <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> include a fuel or hydrogen feed or delivery coupler <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, and an air or oxidant feed or delivery coupler <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. Yet further, the rear wall <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> further includes a releasably engageable data coupler <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>, and a releasably engageable electrical coupler <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. It should be understood that the respective fluid couplers <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> appropriately mate or otherwise cooperate with the fuel/oxidant manifold <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> such that they are disposed in fluid flowing relation relative thereto. Similarly, the D.C. electrical bus <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> electrically couples with the electrical coupler <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. Yet further, the data coupler <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> releasably electrically couples in signal transmitting and receiving relation relative to the data bus <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> further includes a fuel cell stack which is generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is received in the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and is operable to produce electricity when supplied with a suitable fuel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and an oxidant <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> as described above. The fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is electrically coupled to the controller or electronic control assembly which will be described in detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is of a traditional design, that is, it has opposite end plates which are generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, and which are pulled or urged, one towards the other, by a plurality of tie bolts which are generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The respective tie bolts place a plurality of proton exchange fuel cell membranes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>, and other assemblies, such as bipolar plates (not shown), into compression, such that a pair of spaced current collectors <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may receive and collect the electrical current that is generated by each of the fuel cell membranes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>. Yet further, the fuel cell stack may have a monopolar structure which employs fuel cell membranes that are fabricated in a strip cell arrangement. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> pair of electrical conduits <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> respectively electrically connect or couple the individual current collectors <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> with the electrical coupler <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As seen further in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, a fuel/air or oxidant delivery and bleed manifold <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is mounted within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The fuel/air or oxidant delivery and bleed manifold <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is coupled in fluid flowing relation with the respective fluid couplers <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. The fuel/air delivery and bleed manifold <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> also includes a pair of adjustable valve or metering assemblies <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> which operate to selectively meter the fuel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the oxidant <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> which is delivered respectively by way of the fuel delivery conduit <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, and the oxidant delivery conduit <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The fuel and oxidant delivery conduits <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are coupled in fluid flowing relation with the respective fuel coupler <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> and oxidant coupler <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> which are mounted on the rear wall <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As should be understood from the drawings, the oxidant delivery conduit <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> couples the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in fluid flowing relation with a suitable oxidant supply <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> such as air or oxygen, and the fuel delivery conduit <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> couples the fuel cell stack in fluid flowing relation relative to a suitable fuel supply which may comprise a source of hydrogen <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> or a hydrogen rich gas, as earlier discussed. This is of course, providing that the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> takes on the form of a proton exchange membrane fuel cell stack. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Again referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> includes a cooling assembly generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> facilitates the dissipation of heat energy generated while the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is operational. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is borne by the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, and directs a flow of air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back to ambient. The components of the cooling system will be described in greater detail hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, an air passageway <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> is formed through the front wall <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The air passageway is made up of a plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. These apertures <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> facilitate the coupling of the air passage <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> to ambient, and facilitates movement of air from ambient into a fan compartment <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> which is positioned within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and near the front wall <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Still referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> compressor or fan is <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is mounted within the fan compartment <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> and is oriented in air moving relation relative to the air passageway <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. The fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is electrically coupled with, and controlled by, an electronic control assembly which will be discussed in greater detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> also includes an air passageway, or air plenum, or cooling fluid path <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> which extends substantially between the front and rear walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> includes three major portions. The first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the air plenum is coupled in fluid receiving relation relative to the air passageway <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> and to the fan compartment <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight>. As shown in the drawings, the first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the air plenum is positioned within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, and is oriented in substantially parallel relation relative to the first side wall <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Once ambient air has entered the fan compartment <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> through the air passageway <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, the fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> operates to move the air along the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The second portion <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> of the air plenum is coupled in downstream relation relative to the first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>. The second portion is positioned within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and extends substantially between the opposite first and second sidewalls <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The second portion directs the flow of ambient air through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and in a direction which is generally normal to the longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The third portion <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight> of the air plenum is to coupled in fluid flowing relation to and downstream of the second portion <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. The third portion is positioned within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and extends in a direction which is substantially parallel to the second side wall <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The third portion is coupled in fluid flowing relation relative to the rear air passageway <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the rear air passageway <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> is formed through the rear wall <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. A plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>167</bold></highlight> are formed in the rear wall <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and make up the rear air passageway. The air plenum a <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> therefore directs the flow of air in a substantially ogee or &ldquo;S&rdquo; shaped path of travel <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. Further, the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> has a variable diameter, and variations in the diameter of the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> cause the velocity and pressure of the air or cooling fluid to vary as it flows through the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Although the course or path of the air plenum described above is utilized in the preferred embodiment, a variety of other courses or paths of travel which direct a flow of air from ambient through the fuel cell stack, and which return the air to ambient are comprehended by this invention. In other embodiments, the course or path of the air plenum may not necessarily extend substantially between the front and rear walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. For example, in one embodiment the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> has opposite first and second sidewalls <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, and the cooling assembly includes an air plenum or cooling fluid path which extends substantially between the first and second sidewalls <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient. In yet another embodiment, the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> has opposite top and bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, and the cooling assembly includes an air plenum or cooling fluid path which extends substantially between the top and bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As described above, and in the preferred embodiment, a compressor or fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is mounted on the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and is in air moving relation to the air passageway <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. However, it should be recognized that the compressor or fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> may be located remotely relative to the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. For example, the compressor or fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> may be located on the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> but outside of the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>; on the fuel cell module subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; or on the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>; or in other remote locations, so long as the fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is in air moving relation relative to the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Additionally, it should be recognized that other means for facilitating the movement of air or cooling fluid may also be utilized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments, the cooling assembly may create a pressure gradient across the fuel cell stack to facilitate the movement of air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. In yet another embodiment, the cooling assembly may create a temperature gradient across the fuel cell stack which facilitates the movement of air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Referring once again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the operation of the fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> will be described in greater detail. As described above, the fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is operably coupled to the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, and facilitates the movement of air from ambient, along the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back to ambient. The fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is operable to move a substantially steady supply of ambient air through the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> for purposes of eliminating heat energy generated by the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is also electrically coupled to the electronic control assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> which is operable to energize and de-energize the fan in order to maintain the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> within a given operational temperature range. The electronic control assembly is discussed in greater detail hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The electronic control assembly is indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The electronic control assembly is electrically coupled with the data coupler <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>, and is mounted in spaced relation relative to the bottom surface <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> as shown. The electronic control assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and is further electrically coupled to the control or status display panel <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which shows the current operational state of the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. It should be recognized that the electronic control assembly <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> may be located remotely relative to the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. For example, it may be located on the fuel cell subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; the enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>; or at a distant location away from the fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> It should also be understood that the fan or compressor <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is selectively energized by the electric control assembly such that heat energy generated by the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, during operation, and which is captured within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, may be exhausted to ambient. Additionally, it should be understood that the individual fuel cell power modules may also enclose an inverter (not shown) for converting D.C. to A.C. or D.C. to D.C.. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Operation </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The operation of the described embodiments of the present invention are believed to be readily apparent and are briefly summarized at this point. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> A fuel cell power system of the present invention is generally indicated by the numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> respectively. The fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of fuel cell power modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, each enclosing a fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and a cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>; and wherein at least one of the fuel cell power modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, can be removed from the fuel cell power system, by hand, while the remaining fuel cell power modules continue to operate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Still further, the fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention includes an enclosure <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> defining a space or cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A fuel cell module receiving assembly or subrack <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is moveably mounted on the enclosure and operable to be received in the internal space or cavity <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the enclosure. A plurality of fuel cell power modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> each including a fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> operably mate with the module receiving assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and can be removed from the module receiving assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> while the remaining fuel cell power modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> continue to operate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In addition to the foregoing a fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is disclosed, which includes a module receiving assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; a module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> having an internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; a fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> mounted in the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>; a controller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and a cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> borne by the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, and which directs a flow of air from ambient through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and which returns the air to ambient to facilitate the dissipation of heat generated while the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is operational. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> has opposite front and rear walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and is defined by a major axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> which extends between the opposite front and rear walls, and the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes an air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient, and which extends substantially between the front and rear walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> directs the air to flow in a substantially ogee shaped path of travel <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. Further, the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> has a variable diameter, and variations in the diameter of the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> cause the velocity and pressure of the air to vary as it flows through the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As described above, in one embodiment, the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> has opposite first and second sidewalls <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, and the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes an air plenum which extends substantially between the first and second sidewalls <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, and wherein the air plenum is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient. In yet another embodiment, the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> has opposite top and bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, and wherein the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes an air plenum which extends substantially between the top and bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, and wherein the air plenum is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As disclosed above, the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes a fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> which facilitates the movement of air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back to ambient. Further, the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes at least one fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> mounted in the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, and which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back to ambient. Yet further the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes at least one fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> operably coupled to the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, and which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, along the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back to ambient. As disclosed above, the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may create a pressure gradient across the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to facilitate the movement of the air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back to ambient. Further, the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may create a temperature gradient across the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to facilitate the movement of the air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back to ambient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In addition to the foregoing a fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is disclosed, which includes a module receiving assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; a module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> having opposite front and rear walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> which define in part an internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and which is further defined by a major axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> extending between the opposite front and rear walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; a fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> mounted in the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>; a controller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and a cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> borne by the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and coupled to the controller <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, and which dissipates heat energy generated by the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> while it is in operation; and wherein the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> further includes an air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> which extends substantially between, the front and rear walls <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient, and which directs a flow of air from ambient, along the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back to ambient, and a fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> mounted in the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, and which is operably coupled to the air plenum to facilitate movement of the air along the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Further, the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> includes a first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> disposed in laterally offset, substantially parallel relation relative to the major axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>, and which directs the flow of air from ambient into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>; a second portion <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> of the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> coupled in fluid flowing relation to, and downstream of, the first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, and which further directs the flow of air generally transversely or perpendicular to the major axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> and through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>; and a third portion <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight> of the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> disposed in laterally offset substantially parallel relation relative to the major axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>, and which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to, and downstream of, the second portion <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, and which further directs the flow of air back to ambient. Still further, the fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is mounted near the first end <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and is operably coupled with the first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, and wherein the fan <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> facilitates the movement of the air from ambient into the first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the air plenum <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In addition to the foregoing a fuel cell power system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is disclosed, which includes a module receiving assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; a module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> defining an internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and which has opposite first and second ends <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>; a fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> mounted in the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>; a controller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and a cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> which directs a flow of cooling fluid along a substantially non-linear path of travel <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> between the first and second ends <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the module frame <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, and through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to dissipate heat energy generated by the fuel cell in operation. Further, the fuel cell power module <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> has a major axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> which extends between the opposite first and second ends <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and wherein the cooling assembly <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> further includes a cooling fluid path which directs the flow of cooling fluid. Yet further, the cooling fluid path includes a first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> disposed in laterally offset substantially parallel relation relative to the major axis, and which directs the flow of cooling fluid into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>; a second portion <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> of the cooling fluid path <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> coupled in fluid flowing relation to the first portion <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, and which further directs the flow of the cooling fluid generally transversely relative to the major axis <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> and through the fuel cell stack <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>; and a third portion <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight> of the cooling fluid path <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> disposed in laterally offset substantially parallel relation relative to the major axis, and which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to the second portion <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, and which further directs the flow of cooling fluid out of the internal cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In compliance with the statute, the invention has been described in language more or less specific as to structural and methodical features. It is to be understood, however, that the invention is not limited to the specific features shown and described, since the means herein disclosed comprise preferred forms of putting the invention into effect. The invention is, therefore, claimed in any of its forms or modifications within the proper scope of the appended claims appropriately interpreted in accordance with the doctrine of equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A fuel cell power system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a module receiving assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a module frame having an internal cavity, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fuel cell stack mounted in the internal cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cooling assembly borne by the module frame, and which directs a flow of air from ambient through the fuel cell stack, and which returns the air to ambient to facilitate the dissipation of heat generated while the fuel cell stack is operational. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly further comprises at least one fan which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly further comprises at least one fan mounted in the internal cavity of the module frame, and which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly creates a pressure gradient across the fuel cell stack which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly creates a temperature gradient across the fuel cell stack which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the module frame has opposite front and rear walls and is defined by a major axis which extends between the opposite front and rear walls, and wherein the cooling assembly further comprises an air plenum which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient, and which extends substantially between the front and rear walls of the module frame. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly further comprises at least one fan operably coupled to the air plenum, and which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, along the air plenum, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly further comprises at least one fan mounted in the internal cavity of the module frame and operably coupled to the air plenum, and which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, along the air plenum, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air plenum directs the air to flow in a substantially ogee shaped path of travel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air plenum has a variable diameter, and wherein variations in the diameter of the air plenum cause the velocity and pressure of the air to vary as it flows through the air plenum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the module frame has opposite first and second sidewalls, and wherein the cooling assembly further comprises an air plenum which extends substantially between the first and second sidewalls of the module frame, and wherein the air plenum is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly further comprises at least one fan operably coupled to the air plenum, and which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, along the air plenum, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly further comprises at least one fan mounted in the internal cavity of the module frame, and which is operably coupled to the air plenum to facilitate the movement of the air from ambient, along the air plenum, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the module frame has opposite top and bottom surfaces, and wherein the cooling assembly further comprises an air plenum which extends substantially between the top and bottom surfaces of the module frame, and wherein the air plenum is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly further comprises at least one fan operably coupled to the air plenum, and which facilitates the movement of the air from ambient, along the air plenum, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling assembly further comprises at least one fan mounted in the internal cavity of the module frame and operably coupled to the air plenum, and which facilitates the movement of air from ambient, along the air plenum, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A fuel cell power system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a module receiving assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a module frame having opposite front and rear walls which define in part an internal cavity, and which is further defined by a major axis extending between the opposite front and rearwalls, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fuel cell stack mounted in the internal cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cooling assembly borne by the module frame and coupled to the controller, and which dissipates heat energy generated by the fuel cell stack while it is in operation; and wherein the cooling assembly further includes an air plenum which extends substantially between, the front and rear walls, and which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to ambient, and which directs a flow of air from ambient, along the air plenum, through the fuel cell stack, and back to ambient, and a fan mounted in the internal cavity of the module frame, and which is operably coupled to the air plenum to facilitate movement of the air along the air plenum. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air plenum further comprises: 
<claim-text>a first portion disposed in laterally offset substantially parallel relation relative to the major axis, and which directs the flow of air from ambient into the internal cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second portion of the air plenum coupled in fluid flowing relation to the first portion, and which further directs the flow of air generally transversely across the major axis and through the fuel cell stack; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third portion of the air plenum disposed in laterally offset, substantially parallel relation, relative to the major axis, and which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to the second portion, and which further directs the flow of air back to ambient. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air plenum directs the air to flow in a substantially ogee shaped path of travel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air plenum has a variable diameter, and wherein variations in the diameter of the air plenum cause the velocity and pressure of the air flowing through the air plenum to vary. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the fan is mounted near the first end of the module frame and is operably coupled with the first portion of the air plenum, and wherein the fan facilitates the movement of the air from ambient into the first portion of the air plenum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A fuel cell power system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a module receiving assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a module frame defining an internal cavity, and which has opposite first and second ends, and which slideably matingly cooperates both electrically and in fluid flowing relation with the module receiving assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fuel cell stack mounted in the internal cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller which is electrically coupled to the fuel cell stack; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cooling assembly which directs a flow of cooling fluid along a substantially non-linear path of travel between the first and second ends of the module frame, and through the fuel cell stack to dissipate heat energy generated by the fuel cell in operation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a major axis extends between the opposite first and second ends of the module frame, and wherein the cooling assembly includes a cooling fluid path which directs the flow of cooling fluid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling fluid path directs the cooling fluid to flow in a substantially ogee shaped path of travel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The fuel cell power system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cooling fluid path further comprises: 
<claim-text>a first portion disposed in laterally offset substantially parallel relation relative to the major axis, and which directs the flow of cooling fluid into the internal cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second portion of the cooling fluid path coupled in fluid flowing relation to the first portion, and which further directs the flow of the cooling fluid generally transversely relative to the major axis and through the fuel cell stack; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third portion of the cooling fluid path disposed in laterally offset, substantially parallel relation, relative to the major axis, and which is coupled in fluid flowing relation to the second portion, and which further directs the flow of cooling fluid out of the internal cavity.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003337A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003337A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003337A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003337A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003337A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003337A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
