<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001333A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001333A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001333A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001333A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001333A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001333A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001333A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001333A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001333A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001333A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001333A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001333A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001333A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001333A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001333A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001333A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001333</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10214689</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020808</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2159/98</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19981026</filing-date>
<country-code>CH</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B65G047/86</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>271</class>
<subclass>204000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>271</class>
<subclass>082000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>271</class>
<subclass>277000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>198</class>
<subclass>470100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>198</class>
<subclass>803900</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>198</class>
<subclass>803300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus for conveying printed products</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10214689</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020808</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09832568</doc-number>
<document-date>20010411</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6457708</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09832568</doc-number>
<document-date>20010411</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/CH99/00389</doc-number>
<document-date>19990824</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>UNKNOWN</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Werner</given-name>
<family-name>Honegger</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Bach</city>
<country-code>CH</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Ferag AG</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ALSTON &amp; BIRD LLP</name-1>
<name-2>BANK OF AMERICA PLAZA</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>101 SOUTH TRYON STREET, SUITE 4000</address-1>
<city>CHARLOTTE</city>
<state>NC</state>
<postalcode>28280-4000</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method and apparatus for conveying printed products in an imbricated formation with different spacings between the products, from a feed conveyor to the grippers on a removal conveyor. The printed products are introduced into the grippers in groups without any change in the spacing between successive printed products, and the conveying speeds of the feed conveyor and the removal conveyor are coordinated such that the portion of each group of products which projects into a gripper is less than the depth of the mouth of the gripper. Also, a deflection device at the transfer location serves to deflect the leading end of each group of products toward the approaching gripper. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This is a divisional of U.S. application Ser. No. 09/832,568, filed Apr. 11, 2001, which is a continuation of international application PCT/CH99/00389, filed Aug. 24, 1999, and designating the U.S.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method of, and to an apparatus for, conveying printed products in imbricated formation with different spacings between successive products, from a feed conveyor to the grippers on a removal conveyor. Such a method and such an apparatus are suitable, in particular, for conveying newspapers and periodicals as well as parts thereof and inserts therefor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> CH-A-630 583 and the corresponding U.S. Pat. No. 4,320,894 disclose a method and an apparatus of the abovementioned type wherein the drives for the feed conveyor and the removal conveyor are independent of one another, that is to say there is no correlation of the conveying speed of the removal conveyor to the timed sequence of the arriving printed products conveyed by the feed conveyor. This means that, on the one hand, the grippers grip a different number of printed products and, on the other hand, the printed products reaching the transfer location may not necessarily come into contact with a gripper. For this reason, the following precautions are taken in order nevertheless to ensure that the printed products are received satisfactorily by in each case one gripper: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Arranged in the transfer region are stop rails against which a printed product which reaches the transfer region earlier than the associated gripper strikes. A printed product butting against the stop rails is prevented from moving any further forward until such time as it is carried along by the associated gripper. Also provided in the transfer region is a deflecting arrangement which has a rotating wheel which is driven by the feed conveyor and on which resilient deflecting fingers are fastened. These deflecting fingers are deflected in each case, by the trailing clamping part of the grippers, into an active position, in which the deflecting fingers serve as a stop for printed products reaching the transfer region late. The printed products positioned against a deflecting finger are deflected downward, out of the normal conveying path, in the region of their leading edge and braked in the process and subsequently then fed to the next gripper. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> These two measures taken in the case of the known apparatus ensure that all the printed products are gripped satisfactorily by in each case one gripper, but, as has been mentioned, cause the printed products reaching the transfer region to be braked. This braking of the printed products results in a reduction in the spacing between the braked printed products and the respectively following products. In other words, there is a change in the imbricated formation as it is transferred from the feed conveyor to the removal conveyor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is known from EP-A-0 330 868 and the corresponding U.S. Pat. No. 4,953,847 for the printed products which are fed in an imbricated formation, with uniform spacings between the respectively successive printed products, to a transfer location to be received by a removal conveyor with grippers in such a way that each gripper grips in each case two printed products, with the spacing of the latter in the imbricated formation being maintained. This is achieved in that the feeding speed of the feed conveyor and the conveying speed of the removal conveyor are selected such that, during the time in which the fed printed products cover double the spacing between two printed products, the grippers of the removal conveyor cover a distance which corresponds to the fixed spacing between two grippers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The object of the present invention, then, is to provide a method and an apparatus of the type mentioned in the introduction which make it possible, in a straightforward manner, for the printed products which are fed with irregular mutual spacings to the transfer location to be received satisfactorily and carefully by the grippers of the removal conveyor without it being necessary, for this purpose, for individual products to be braked and displaced. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects and advantages of the invention are achieved by the provision of a method and apparatus wherein the printed products are introduced into the grippers of the removal conveyor without any change in the spacing between successive printed products, so that each gripper grips the number of printed products fed to it with the same mutual spacing as in the imbricated formation. Also, once a number of printed products have been received by a gripper, the following printed products are directed into an open mouth of the next gripper, with the spacing being maintained between the last printed product gripped by the preceding gripper and the following printed product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention is based on the finding that the printed products can be transferred from the feed conveyor to the removal conveyor, while maintaining their mutual spacing, if it is ensured that, on the one hand, the printed products running into a gripper in each case are not inhibited in their forward movement prior to the closure of the gripper and, on the other hand, the following printed products which cannot be gripped correctly by the preceding gripper are directed to the open mouth of the next gripper while maintaining their mutual spacing.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Preferred exemplary embodiments of the subject matter of the invention are explained in more detail hereinbelow with reference to the drawings, in which, purely schematically: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a side view of a first embodiment of a conveying apparatus according to the invention, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a view in the direction of the arrow II in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and partially in group, of the end region of the feed conveyor of the conveying apparatus according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>show how the operation of the grippers of the removal conveyor receiving printed products proceeds over time, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>show the deflecting arrangement in different phases following one after the other in time, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a side view of a second embodiment of a conveying apparatus according to the invention, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>show a simplified side view of a third embodiment of a conveying apparatus according to the invention in two product-receiving phases following one after the other in time, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>show the product-transfer sequence in a conveying apparatus according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> at different points in time. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The first embodiment of a conveying apparatus according to the invention illustrated schematically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> has a feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The conveying direction of the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is designated A and the conveying direction of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is designated B. In the exemplary embodiment illustrated, the two conveyors <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are arranged such that the conveying direction A and the conveying direction B form an angle &agr; which is greater than 90&deg;, as is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. This means that the conveying direction B of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a component which is parallel to the conveying direction A of the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and runs in the same direction as A. The feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> conveys printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in an imbricated formation S, at the conveying speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, to a transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be newspapers, periodicals and the like or parts thereof, and inserts therefor. In the exemplary embodiment shown, in the imbricated formation S, in each case one printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> rests on the following printed product. This means that, in the imbricated formation S, the leading edges <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are located at the bottom, i.e. rest on the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In the imbricated formation S, the imbrication spacings a, i.e. the spacings between the leading edges <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of successive printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, are irregular, as is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> with reference to the spacings a<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. These spacings a<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to a<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> differ from one another but, in certain cases, it is quite possible for them also to be the same. In other words, the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are located in an irregular manner in the imbricated formation S. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is formed by two conveying belts <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> which are arranged parallel to one another and are spaced apart from one another (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). The two conveying belts <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are each guided over deflecting rollers, of which only the end-side deflecting rollers <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are shown. The two conveying belts <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are driven at the speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Arranged above the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is a pressure-exerting belt <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> which is driven in circulation in the direction of the arrow C. This pressure-exerting belt <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is likewise guided over deflecting rollers, of which only one deflecting roller <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which also serves as a pressure-exerting roller, is shown. The imbricated formation S is guided between the pressure-exerting belt and the deflecting roller <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and is pressed onto the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the process. The deflecting roller <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is set back by a certain distance in relation to the deflecting rollers <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a drawing element (not illustrated) which is guided in a guide channel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and is driven in circulation in conveying direction B at the conveying speed v<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are fastened at fixed and identical spacings D one behind the other on said drawing element. The grippers shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> correspond, in terms of design and function, to the grippers described in EP-A-0 600 183 and the corresponding U.S. Pat. No. 5,395,151. For this reason, you are referred to these documents as regards construction and functioning of the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. It goes without saying that it is also possible to use grippers of some other suitable design. Each gripper has two clamping parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> which can be moved toward one another into a clamping position and away from one another into an open position. In order to control the movement of the clamping parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and to pivot the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, control arrangements (not illustrated specifically), e.g. guide elements, are provided. The gripper mouth defined by the two clamping parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is designated <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Arranged in the end region of the feed conveyor, between the two deflecting rollers <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, is a deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which has a wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> which is mounted rotatably on a pin <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Fastened on the circumference of the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are two diametrically opposite deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> which are of L-shaped design in side view. One leg <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is spaced apart from the circumference of the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and serves as a directing part, as will be explained in more detail with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. The wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is driven, via a toothed belt <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, by a gearwheel <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> which, for its part, is driven via a jointed shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). The varying drive speed of the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, i.e. the movement speed of the deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, is coordinated with the conveying speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the position of the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The conveying speeds v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and v<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> relate to one another in a given, fixed ratio, although this may be adjusted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> It can be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> that the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, which are fed at a constant conveying speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, are conveyed to the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and gripped by said grippers in groups, without any change in the original mutual spacing a of the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the imbricated formation S. In this case, depending on the size of the mutual spacing a between respectively successive printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, each gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> grips different numbers of printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. It is ensured here, by coordination of the conveying speeds v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and v<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and with account being taken of the gripper spacing D, that the length F of that portion of a received group which projects into a gripper mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is smaller than the depth E of the clamp mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, so that no printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> strikes against a gripper part, and is braked in the process, as it runs into a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. F thus designates the distance in which are located those edges of the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> which are gripped by a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, it being necessary to ensure that the rearmost printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> still gripped by a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> projects into the gripper mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to a sufficiently large extent for this printed product also still to be reliably secured. The printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of a group which are gripped by a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and conveyed away thus have the same mutual spacing a&prime; or a&Prime; as in the fed imbricated formation S. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> By way of the deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> dipping periodically into the imbrication formation S, the deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> ensures, in a manner which is still to be described, that the individual groups are separated from one another and the first printed products of the respectively following group are directed to the next gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The deflecting element <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, however, only acts if the spacing between the rearmost printed product of one group and the foremost printed product of the following group is such that it is not ensured that said foremost printed product will be directed satisfactorily into the next gripper. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The functioning of the conveying apparatus according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> will now be explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, which is simplified in relation to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrate four phases, following one after the other in time, during the transfer of the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> from the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Just as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, F</cross-reference> designates the lengths of that portion of a group which projects into a gripper mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, said length, as has been mentioned, being smaller than the gripper-mouth depth E. The front boundaries of each of these groups are designated <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> At the point in time according to the illustration of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; have already received the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the groups s<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and s<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> respectively assigned to them, while the next gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is reaching the transfer location and is ready for receiving the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the next group s<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. At this point in time, the first printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; of the next group s<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> comes into the region of action of a deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of a deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and, as will be explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, is deflected out of the normal conveying path <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which is defined by the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> At a somewhat later point in time according to the illustration of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the imbricated formation S have already moved on, while the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, with the deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, has rotated somewhat further. From <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, it is possible to see the commencing deflection of the incoming printed products out of the normal conveying path <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> under the action of a deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> At a somewhat later point in time, at least the foremost printed products of the next group s<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, which is to be received by the following gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, have already been clearly deflected out of the normal conveying path <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> into an alternative conveying path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, which is oriented in the direction counter to the conveying direction B of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, as can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. It can also be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>that, by virtue of this deflection of the printed products onto the alternative conveying path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, it is ensured that the printed products are reliably directed into the open mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of the gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> At the point in time according to the illustration of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, the printed products of the group s<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, which is to be received by the gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, have been directed into the gripper mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and are ready to be firmly clamped. The clamping parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are then closed. The deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of the deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has released the printed products which it previously deflected onto the alternative conveying path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. According to the illustration of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, the other deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> then moves into the incoming imbricated formation S from beneath, but does not act on the first printed product of the next group s<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> since said product has a sufficiently large spacing in order to run satisfactorily into the next gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by the direct route. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The functioning of the deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> will now be explained in more detail with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>show the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, which rotates in the direction of the arrow G, with the two deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> in different positions following one after the other in time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and the deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> assume approximately the same position as the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. In this case, the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> engages in the imbricated formation S and raises the leading printed products, i.e. the final printed products of the preceding group, to some extent. At this point in time, the movement speed v<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is somewhat greater than the advancement speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the imbricated formation S, in order to catch up with, and overtake, the conveyed printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In that position of the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the movement speed v<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is lower than the conveying speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the movement speed v<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> decreasing. This, then, allows the printed products of the next group (illustrated by a single printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>) to catch up with the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>). The foremost printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of this group then comes into the region of action of a deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and moves, by way of its leading edge <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, into the interspace between the circumferential surface of the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and the directing part <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> By virtue of the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which now has essentially the same speed as the printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the printed product is then deflected out of the normal conveying path <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> onto the alternative conveying path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, as has already been described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is then accelerated, which results in the movement speed v<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> being greater than the advancement speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. It is thus possible for the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to be released from the printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, with the result that, during the further advancement, said printed product can run into the open mouth of the associated gripper, as has already been described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> It can be gathered from above that the wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is driven at changing circumferential speed in order first of all to make it possible for the printed products to catch up with the deflecting elements <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, subsequently to allow a printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to move into the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and then to ensure that the deflected printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is released by the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. It is important that the movement speed of the deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is such that the leading edge <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of a printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> never strikes against a deflecting element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. This means that the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are deflected onto the alternative conveying path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> without being braked or accelerated. This ensures that the spacing a between successive printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is maintained even during the deflecting operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As has been mentioned, the deflecting roller <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and thus the end of the pressure exerting belt <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, is set back in relation to the end of the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The distance by which it is set back, then, is selected such that the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of each group remain in the region of influence of the deflecting roller <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> until they are secured at their leading end <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by the clamping parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The action of the printed products of each group being pressed onto the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in this way during the transfer operation helps to maintain, as desired, the mutual position of the printed products during the transfer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In the second embodiment of a conveying apparatus according to the invention, this embodiment being shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are likewise provided. The feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> supplies the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in an imbricated formation S in the direction of the arrow A, at a conveying speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, to a transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. In contrast to the embodiment according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, in this imbricated formation S, each printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> rests on the preceding printed product. This means that, in this fed imbricated formation S, the leading edges <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are located at the top. It is also the case in this embodiment that the spacings a, a<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> between respectively successive printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are irregular. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> receives the fed printed products in groups at the transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and conveys them away in the direction of the arrow B at the conveying speed v<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The conveying direction B of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the conveying direction A of the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> form an obtuse angle. This means that, just as in the embodiment according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the conveying direction B has a component which runs parallel to the conveying direction A and in the same direction as A. The conveying speeds v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and v<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> relate to one another in a given, fixed ratio, which can be changed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> likewise has a drawing element (not shown) which is guided in a guide channel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are arranged at uniform, fixed spacings B on said drawing element, although they differ in design from the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Note CH-A-592 562 and the corresponding U.S. Pat. No. 3,955,667 with regard to the construction and functioning of the grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Each gripper <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> has a gripper housing <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> which is fastened on the abovementioned drawing element in a non-pivotable manner. A fixed clamping part <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is formed on each gripper housing <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. In the gripper housing <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, a shank <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is mounted such that it can be displaced in the direction of its longitudinal axis and pivoted about the latter. The shank <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is prestressed in the direction of the open position, as is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> for the rearmost gripper <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>&prime;, as seen in the conveying direction B, by a spring (not shown). Fastened on the shank <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is a movable clamping part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> which, in the open position of the gripper <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>&prime;, is pivoted through approximately 90&deg; in relation to the conveying direction B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> By virtue of correspondingly designed control arrangements, which comprise for example stationary guide elements, the shank <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, together with the movable clamping part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, are pivoted through approximately 90&deg; and moved into a position in which the movable clamping part <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> runs approximately parallel to the fixed clamping part <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and thus forms the gripper mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, as is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> for the gripper <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>&Prime;. In order to close the grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the shank <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is displaced in the direction of its longitudinal axis, likewise by means of suitable control arrangements, and the two clamping parts <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are thus brought together. The shank <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is arrested in its closed position by means of a releasable locking element <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Following the transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, beneath the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, there is arranged a directing plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which runs approximately parallel to the conveying direction B and by means of which the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> guided away by the grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are supported in the region of their trailing edges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Provided in the region of the discharge end of the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and at the transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, is a deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> which has a roller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> which is driven in rotation in the direction of the arrow H. This roller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is provided with two diametrically opposite suction regions <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime;. These suction regions <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; (not illustrated in any more detail) have holes which can be connected periodically to a negative pressure source. The rotational speed of the roller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is coordinated with the conveying speed v<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> such that one of the suction regions <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; comes into contact with a printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the fed imbricated formation S in each case when the trailing, fixed clamping part <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of a gripper <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is about to leave the transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. This is because the roller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has the same task as the deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the exemplary embodiment according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> and serves, if necessary, for deflecting in each case the first printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of a group out of the normal conveying path onto an alternative conveying path, which is directed counter to the conveying direction B of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Each time one of the suction regions <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; comes into contact with a printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the imbricated formation S, the holes of the suction region <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; are connected to the negative-pressure source. The roller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> thus carries along the gripped region of the corresponding printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and deflects it towards the next gripper (in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the gripper <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>&prime;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Just as in the embodiment according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are fed to the grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> at the conveying speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and gripped, and carried along, by the grippers in groups. This likewise ensures that the length F of that portion of the formation which projects into the mouth of the grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is smaller than the depth E of the grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, with the result that there is no mutual displacement of the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as the latter are received by the grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The printed products secured by the clamping parts <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of a gripper <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> thus have the same mutual spacing a&prime;, a&Prime; as in the imbricated formation S fed by the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Since the roller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> has a circumferential speed which corresponds to the feeding speed v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> gripped by the roller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> also maintain their speed. This avoids the situation where the printed products gripped by the roller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are displaced in relation to the following printed products. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> A third embodiment of a conveying apparatus according to the invention is shown with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, which corresponds in illustrative terms to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and in which both the feed conveyor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are shown merely in a quite schematic and simplified manner, and to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The same designations are used in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> for corresponding parts. This third embodiment is very similar to the embodiment according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. In particular, the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are of the same design in both embodiments. Unlike the embodiment according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the embodiment which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference> does not have a deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The operation of deflecting the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, i.e. of directing them into the open grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, is achieved, in a manner which is still to be described, by control of the clamping parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate the product receiving situations at two successive points in time. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>show even more clearly, in an illustration which is on a larger scale than <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, with reference to the regions designated T and T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, how the product&mdash;receiving operation proceeds over time. In this case, the situation illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>corresponds to that according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, it is important that the clamping parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; running into the region of the transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are controlled such that in each case the trailing clamping part <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; and the leading clamping part <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the next gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> butt against one another, as is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>. This measure means that there is no interspace, between the clamping parts <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of successive grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, into which a printed product <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> could pass accidentally. The control of the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; and of the clamping parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> thereof may take place, for example, in a manner similar to that described in EP-A-0 557 680 and the corresponding U.S. Pat. No. 5,388,820. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>shows a first point in time, at which the gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; has already gripped a group comprising three printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The spacings a&prime; and a&Prime; between the leading edges of successive products are the same here as the corresponding spacings between these printed products in the fed imbricated formation S. The following gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; is about to grip the group of printed products which is assigned to it, and is designated s<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The length of this group is given by the group boundaries <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The situation occurring at a later point in time is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; is closed and firmly clamps the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the gripped group s<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. This group s<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comprises four printed products, of which the rearmost printed product is designated <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime;. The next gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is reaching the transfer location <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and is ready to receive the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the next group s<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>show, even more clearly, the procedure at the changeover between the products being received by a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; and the following gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. These figures illustrate the end region of the group s<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is gripped by the gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, and the starting region of the following group s<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which runs into the next gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The last product of the group s<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is designated <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime;, and the first product of the group s<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is designated <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&Prime;. It is clear from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> that the abutment of the leading clamping part <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> against the trailing clamping part <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the preceding gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; forms an essentially continuous directing-in surface which ensures that the printed products which are intended to run into the gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> pass satisfactorily into the mouth of said gripper. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> It can readily be seen with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference> that in the third embodiment, which is shown in these figures, the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are fed to the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> while maintaining their spacing. Just as in the other embodiments, it is also the case here that, by coordinating the conveying speeds v<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and v<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in relation to the gripper spacing D, it is ensured that the length F of that portion of the received group which projects into the gripper mouth is smaller than the depth E of the grippers (see also <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In the illustration of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, the two conveying directions A and B form an angle of approximately 90&deg;. Of course, it is also possible, or even desirable, in this embodiment for this angle, just as in the other embodiments, to be greater than 90&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In all the exemplary embodiments shown, during the time in which the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> cover a distance corresponding to the gripper spacing D, the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are advanced by a distance which corresponds to the length F, which, as is known, is equal to the length of that portion of each group s which projects into the gripper mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. This means that each group s gripped by a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> always projects into the gripper mouth <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> by the same length F. However, the number of printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> per group s differs and depends on the mutual spacing a of the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the fed imbricated formation S, i.e. a gripper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> grips one, two or more printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, e.g. up to six products, or even no product at all. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The position of the deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in relation to the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is adapted to the design of the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, i.e. the spacing between the deflecting arrangement <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is selected such that the sought after operation of directing the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> into the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> also actually takes place (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 5</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> secured and transported away by the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the removal conveyor <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may be discharged again at a discharge location in such a way as to re-form an imbricated formation in which the spacings a of successive printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are the same again as in the original imbricated formation S. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> In addition, however, it is also possible to discharge the printed products <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in groups, i.e. to release and open all of the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or some of the grippers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> irrespective of the other grippers. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for conveying printed products comprising 
<claim-text>a feed conveyor for continuously feeding printed products in an imbricated formation, with spacings between successive printed products, to a transfer location, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a removal conveyor which receives the fed printed products at the transfer location and comprises individually controllable grippers which are arranged at fixed spacings one behind the other in a conveying direction and are configured for gripping printed products, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the grippers of the removal conveyor have a depth which is larger than at least the spacing between two printed products following one after the other in the fed imbricated formation, with the result that at least some of the grippers of the removal conveyor can grip at least two printed products with the same mutual spacing which the gripped printed products have in the fed imbricated formation, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein for directing in each case a number of fed printed products into the grippers of the removal conveyor without a change in the spacing between respectively successive printed products, a deflecting arrangement is provided which is coordinated with the movement of the grippers past the transfer location and acts periodically and briefly on the printed products running along a normal conveying path toward the transfer location as defined by the feed conveyor and while the printed products maintain their feeding speed, so as to deflect said printed products from the normal conveying path onto another conveying path which is oriented counter to the conveying direction of the removal conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conveying speeds of the feed conveyor and removal conveyor relate to one another in a given, fixed ratio. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conveying directions of the feed conveyor and removal conveyor form an angle (&agr;) which is approximately 90&deg; or greater than 90&deg;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the depth of the grippers is larger than the sum of the spacings between in each case two adjacent printed products of a group of three or more successive printed products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deflecting arrangement comprises a wheel which can be driven in rotation, with said wheel being provided on its outer periphery with at least one deflecting element which, as it comes into contact with the printed products in the imbricated formation, acts on at least one printed product and deflects the latter onto said another conveying path as the wheel rotates further. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the wheel is arranged beneath the conveying path which is defined by the feed conveyor, and so that the conveying path is generally tangent to an upper portion of the outer periphery of the wheel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said wheel is driven to rotate in a direction such that the upper portion of the outer periphery of the wheel moves in the direction in which the products are fed by the feed conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the at least one deflecting element is of L-shaped configuration in side view and includes a radial first leg and a second leg which is generally parallel to and radially spaced from the outer periphery of the wheel, and with the second leg extending in a direction from the radial first leg opposite the rotational direction of the wheel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wheel is driven at a variable speed during each rotation thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the deflecting arrangement comprises a suction element which is arranged on the normal conveying path which is defined by the feed conveyor, is driven at the conveying speed of the feed conveyor, and is connected periodically to a negative pressure source which, as it comes into contact with the printed products in the imbricated formation, acts on at least one printed product and deflects the latter onto said another conveying path as it rotates further. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a pressure exerting arrangement which is arranged above the feed conveyor and by means of which the printed products running up to the transfer location are pressed against the feed conveyor in the region of their trailing end, until the printed products are firmly clamped at their leading end by a gripper. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the feed conveyor is configured for feeding printed products in an imbricated formation with irregular spacings between successive printed products.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001333A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001333A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001333A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001333A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001333A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001333A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001333A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001333A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
