<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004576A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004576A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004576</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894315</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61F002/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>623</class>
<subclass>017160</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Modular anatomic fusion device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>S.</middle-name>
<family-name>Thalgott</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Las Vegas</city>
<state>NV</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>NUTTER MCCLENNEN &amp; FISH LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>WORLD TRADE CENTER WEST</address-1>
<address-2>155 SEAPORT BOULEVARD</address-2>
<city>BOSTON</city>
<state>MA</state>
<postalcode>02210-2604</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A modular fusion cage and tool for the insertion of the fusion cage is provided. The fusion cage includes a ramp member having superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces, and anterior and posterior sides. The ramp member is adapted to be positioned between adjacent vertebral bodies. The implant also includes a ring member slidably matable with the ramp member. The ring member includes superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces, and anterior and posterior sides. The implant according to the present invention is particularly useful for facilitating the safe and accurate insertion of the implant between adjacent vertebral bodies. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to spinal implants, tools for the insertion of spinal implants, and methods of use thereof, and more particularly, to an implantable modular fusion cage for promoting fusion of adjacent vertebral bodies. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Degenerative changes in the spine can cause the loss of normal structure and/or function. The intervertebral disk is one structure prone to the degenerative changes associated with wear and tear, aging, and even misuse. Over time the collagen (protein) structure of the intervertebral disk weakens and may become structurally unsound. Additionally, the water and proteoglycan (the molecules that attract water) content decreases, thereby narrowing the space between the adjacent vertebrae, which can result in nerve root compression and pain. These changes can lead to the disk&apos;s inability to handle mechanical stress. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> One form of treatment available for degenerative disk disease is spinal fusion surgery, which involves the surgical removal of a portion or all of an intervertebral disk followed by fusion of the adjacent vertebrae. A prosthetic device, e.g. a fusion cage, is usually placed between the two adjacent vertebrae to fill the space left by the removed disk and to allow bone to grow between the adjacent vertebrae. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Spinal fusion procedures can present the surgeon with several challenges, especially where the disk is severely degenerative. When the natural disk is removed, the adjacent vertebral bodies collapse upon each other thereby requiring the bodies to be separated to enable placement of the prosthesis. However, separation or distraction of the vertebral bodies beyond a certain degree can result in further injury or damage to the vertebrae. Conversely, where the disk is severely degenerative, the narrow disk space and lack of elasticity between the vertebrae can hinder the surgeon&apos;s ability to separate the vertebrae to a height sufficient to enable placement of the prosthesis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To overcome some of these problems, specialized tools have been developed to facilitate the placement of disk prosthesis between adjacent vertebral bodies of a patient&apos;s spine. Among the known tools for performing such procedures are spinal distracters, e.g. spreaders, and insertion devices. In general, the spreader is placed between adjacent vertebrae, and then used to pry the vertebrae apart. Once the space between the vertebral bodies is sufficient to enable placement of a prostheses, the prosthetic device can then be inserted, either manually or with an insertion tool, into the space to hold the adjacent vertebrae apart. Typically, cancellous bone is packed in and/or around the cage to promote fusion of the adjacent vertebrae. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> While most spreader devices are effective to assist surgeons with the placement of disk prosthesis, the use of such tools can prove cumbersome. For example, insertion of a spreader device into the limited disk space can cause fracture of a vertebra. Moreover, once inserted, the spreaders can cause over-distraction of the vertebral bodies, or can hinder placement of the prosthesis. In the presence of degenerative disease or chronic changes where the disk space has become narrow, it can be difficult to maintain an adequate interbody height and, at the same time, insert and position the implant. Over-insertion, or under-insertion of the prosthesis can lead to pain, postural problems and/or limited mobility or freedom of movement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Despite existing tools and technologies, there remains a need for a device to facilitate the safe and accurate insertion of a disk prosthesis between adjacent vertebral bodies while minimizing the risk of further injury to the patient. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a modular fusion cage for promoting fusion of adjacent vertebral bodies, and a tool for the insertion of the fusion cage. The implant is effective for maintaining an adequate interbody height between adjacent vertebrae during insertion, and therefore is particularly useful for patients with degenerative disk disease. In addition, the modularity of the implant facilitates the safe and accurate insertion of the implant between adjacent vertebrae. The modular fusion cage of the invention is particularly useful as an anterior fusion cage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In general, the modular fusion cage includes a ramp member and a ring member, each of which has superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces, and anterior and posterior sides. The ramp member is adapted to be positioned between adjacent vertebral bodies, and the ring member is slidably matable with the ramp member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the ring member is generally C-shaped with an opening that is preferably disposed on the posterior side of the ring member. The opening represents an interruption in the continuity of the annular walls of the ring member and is effective for receiving the ramp member. The ring member can also include a substantially wedge-like posterior tip formed between the superior and inferior surfaces of the ring. The ramp member can include transverse sides connecting the superior and inferior surfaces, each of which can be adapted to conform to the opening in the ring member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the ring member further includes first and second rib structures that extend substantially parallel to each other between the posterior and anterior sides of the ring member. The first and second rib structures are each separated from the side walls of the ring member, and each other, by openings in which bone growth promoting materials, e.g. cancellous bone, can be placed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The superior and inferior surfaces of the ring and/or ramp members of the modular fusion cage of the present invention can have any shape, and can include bone engaging surface features (e.g. teeth or ridges) formed on at least a portion thereof. Preferably, these surfaces are generally shaped and contoured to conform to and to be complimentary to the surfaces of the vertebral bodies that they are intended to contact. By way of non-limiting example, the superior and inferior surfaces of the ring and/or ramp members can have a convex shape, or can have a height extending between the superior and inferior surfaces that is greater at the anterior side than at the posterior side of the ring/ramp member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> As a modular fusion cage, the components that form the cage are assembled within the patient&apos;s body during a surgical procedure. The ramp member is positioned first and the ring member is subsequently installed and mated to the ramp member. To ensure proper mating, the ring and/or ramp members include alignment features that assist in aligning the ring member with the ramp member during insertion. The alignment guide can be, for example, a tongue and groove formed on the transverse side walls of the ramp member and the opening in the ring member. The ring and ramp members can optionally include other features, such as a locking mechanism effective to lock the ring and ramp members together, or a handle removably attached to the ramp member for inserting the ramp member into the disk space, and optionally for inserting the ring member around the ramp member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In yet another embodiment, a spinal implant system is provided having a modular fusion cage and an insertion tool for implanting the modular cage within the vertebral disk space. The modular fusion cage includes a ramp member and a ring member, each having posterior and anterior faces, and superior and inferior bone contacting faces. The posterior face of the ring member defines an opening for receiving the ramp member, and the anterior side of the superior and inferior faces each have at least one groove formed therein for receiving the insertion tool. The insertion tool includes first and second opposed grasping elements movable between an open position and a closed position, and matable with the at least one groove formed in each of the superior and inferior surfaces of the ring member. First and second opposed actuating members are mated to the first and second grasping elements and are effective to move the first and second grasping elements between the open and closed positions.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The invention will be more fully understood from the following detailed description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a posterior perspective view an implantable modular fusion cage having a ring member and a ramp member according to one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is another posterior perspective view of the modular fusion cage shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, in a partially assembled condition; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a posterior perspective view of a ramp member according to one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a posterior perspective view of another embodiment of a ramp member mated to a ring member according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a posterior perspective view of a ring member according to one embodiment of the present invention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is an anterior perspective view of the ring member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> FIG, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A is a posterior perspective view of another embodiment of a ring member according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is an anterior perspective view of the ring member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a posterior perspective view of a modular fusion cage having a ring member with sloped superior and inferior surfaces according to another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> is a posterior perspective view of a modular fusion cage having dome shaped superior and inferior surfaces; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> is an anterior view of the modular fusion cage of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7C</cross-reference> is a side illustration of the modular fusion cage of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</cross-reference> is a top posterior perspective view of a partially assembled modular fusion cage having a handle mated to a ramp member according to another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</cross-reference> is a top anterior perspective view of the modular fusion cage and handle of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> is a top perspective view of a portion of an insertion tool and a ring member according to yet another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> is a top perspective view of another embodiment of an insertion tool according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of the insertion tool and ring member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides an implantable modular fusion cage that is effective to fuse together adjacent vertebral bodies. The modular fusion cage of the present invention is particularly useful for patients with degenerative disk disease, where the deteriorated elasticity between adjacent vertebral bodies causes the bodies to collapse. The modular fusion cage is effective to maintain an adequate interbody height between adjacent vertebrae during insertion of the remainder of the implant, and thereby eliminates the necessity for additional tools to overcome the deteriorated elasticity between the vertebrae. The fusion cage is also effective to provide greater flexibility in implantation and assists with alignment of the cage between adjacent vertebrae. A tool for inserting the modular fusion cage according to the present invention is also provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the modular fusion cage <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the present invention generally includes two modular components: a ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a size and a geometry that enables it to be efficiently installed and to remain securely positioned between adjacent vertebral bodies until healing and fusion take place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has superior and inferior bone-contacting surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, posterior and anterior sides <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and first and second transverse sides <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, respectively. Similarly, the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which is formed by an annular wall <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, has superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, posterior and anterior sides <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and opposed transverse sides <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The annular wall <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is interrupted by a wall opening <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> that gives the ring member a substantially C-like shape. Preferably, the wall opening <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is formed in a posterior side of the annular wall. The annular wall <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> also defines a central opening <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> that is oriented in the superior-inferior plane, and communicates with the wall opening <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The wall opening <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is dimensioned to accept the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which fits within the central opening <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> in the course of mating with the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Use of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is effective to hold adjacent vertebrae apart while the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is slidably inserted around the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and thereby obviates the need for a spreader tool during a fusion procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> illustrates one embodiment of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> having a generally rectangular shape and including superior and inferior bone-contacting surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, posterior and anterior sides <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and first and second transverse sides <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can have any shape and size, but should have a height and width sufficient to fit within the vertebral space. The size of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can vary depending upon a variety of factors, including the size of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the objectives relating to use of the modular fusion cage <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the height of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is equal to or greater than the height of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to provide a vertebral opening in which the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be placed. The superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be parallel to one another, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, or, as described below, the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can have a somewhat wedge-like shape, or it can be shaped to match the end plates of the adjacent vertebrae. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> illustrates another embodiment of a ramp member <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> having a height equal to the height of the ring member along the entire superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. As shown, the ramp member <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> includes converging surfaces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> formed along the posterior side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to facilitate the insertion of the ramp member <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> between adjacent vertebrae. Preferably, the converging surfaces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are formed by a general incline or curvature of the opposed superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> towards each other. The converging surfaces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> can extend over a region that represents a distance of about 10 to 50 percent of the anterior-posterior depth of the ramp member <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and can have an angle of convergence between about 10 and 25 degrees, and most preferably about 17.5 degrees. As illustrated, the posterior side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the ramp member can have a generally rounded shape </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can optionally include a number of bone engaging surface features <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> formed on the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to facilitate the secure mounting of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> between the vertebral bodies. The bone engaging surface features can be present on the entire surface area of the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, or optionally, selected regions of the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can be free of surfaces features <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, the posterior region of the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is free of bone engaging surface features to facilitate the insertion of the implant from an anterior or anterior-lateral surgical approach. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The bone engaging surface features <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can have a variety of shapes, but are preferably in the form of wedge-shaped ridges formed on the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and extending between the transverse sides <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Each bone engaging surface feature <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes a posterior side wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and an anterior side wall <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, which meet at a peak p. Preferably, the posterior side wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of each bone engaging surface feature <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> slopes downwardly toward the posterior side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to facilitate insertion of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into the disk space. The posterior side wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may be sloped at an angle (&agr;) with respect to the base <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> of superior or inferior surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The value of the angle (&agr;) is preferably in the range of about 5&deg; to 60&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The bone engaging surface features <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> should have a size sufficient to cause each surface to engage and penetrate the adjacent vertebrae. Preferably, each surface feature has a height h, which can be in the range of about 0.5 to 2.5 mm, and more preferably is about 0.75 mm, as measured from the superior or inferior surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. It will be understood that while ridges have been shown in a preferred embodiment, it is contemplated that there are a variety of structures which could provide a surface for effective engagement with the vertebral bodies to limit expulsion from the disc space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which is slidably matable with the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference>. In general, the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be a C-shaped annular body that includes superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, posterior and anterior sides <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and first and second transverse sides <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> extending between the posterior and anterior sides <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The annular body of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> defines a central opening <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> that is oriented in the center of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and extends between the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The posterior side <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes a wall opening <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> formed by an interruption in the continuity of the annular walls of the ring member. The opening <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is in communication with the central opening <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, and is adapted to receive the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The opening <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be formed between the first and second transverse walls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, or can be positioned at some other location on the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> depending on the surgical approach to be used. For example, where an anterio-lateral surgical approach is used, the opening can be angularly positioned along one of the transverse walls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> adjacent the posterior side <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the ring member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The size of the opening <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> can be selected to conform to the width of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as defined by the transverse sides <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the width of the opening can be slightly larger than the width of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, the anterior side <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can have a generally square or rectangular shape with rounded edges <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, and can include a flattened surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The flattened surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is effective to facilitate the insertion of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> around the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> such that an impacting device, such as a mallet or hammer, can be used to apply force to the flattened surface of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and thereby push the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> around the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The transverse walls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extend from the anterior side <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and can be slightly rounded to form the C-shaped ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The transverse walls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> can have any thickness, however, the walls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> should further define the opening <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> in the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The walls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> can include one or more openings or bores <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> for receiving bone growth promoting materials, such as cancellous bone. The openings <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> can have any size and any shape, and can be positioned anywhere along the transverse walls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be parallel to each other, and can include a converging tip <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> formed along the posterior side <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> to facilitate the insertion of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> between adjacent vertebrae. Preferably, the tip <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> possesses a substantially wedge-like or bullet-like shape, and is formed by a general convergence or curvature of the opposed superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> towards each other. The tip <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> can extend over a region that represents a distance of about 10 to 50 percent of the anterior-posterior depth of the body <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and can have an angle of convergence between about 10 and 25 degrees, and most preferably about 17.5 degrees with respect to the anterior-posterior axis x. As illustrated, the posterior-most portion of the tip <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> can have a generally rounded shape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The ring member according to the present invention can also include a pair of rib members <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> which extend between the superior and anterior sides <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</cross-reference>. The first and second rib members <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> are parallel to each other and separate the central opening <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and first and second bone-ingrowth openings <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The bone-ingrowth openings <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> can have any shape and size, and are effective to receive bone growth promoting materials, such as cancellous bone. The rib members <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> are also effective to provide additional structural integrity to the ring member <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The superior and inferior surfaces of the ring member according to the present invention can also optionally include a number of bone engaging surface features <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; similar in construction and purpose to the bone engaging surface features <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> described with respect to the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A, surface feature-free regions can be located along the anterior side <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> of the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to facilitate grasping of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and on the converging tip <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> on the posterior side of the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to facilitate insertion of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> into the vertebral space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> By way of non-limiting example, FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>C illustrate alternative embodiments of a ring member according to the present invention. A person having ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that the features illustrated herein can be formed on one or both of the ring and ramp members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a modular fusion cage <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> having assembled together a ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a ring member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, similar to ring member <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> described with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</cross-reference>. The ring member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> includes sloped superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. As shown in comparison to the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the incline on the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> extends from the posterior side <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> to the anterior side <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, thus making the thickness of the ring member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> greater on the anterior side than on the posterior side. The degree of the incline can be determined based on the angle of the adjacent endplates of the particular vertebral bodies where the cage is to be implanted, and is preferably in the range of about 0&deg; to 15&deg;, and more preferably about 10&deg;. In use, the sloped surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> facilitate insertion of the ring member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> into the vertebral space, particularly where the cage is implanted between vertebral bodies located on the lower portion of the spine. In addition to the ring member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> having sloped superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can also or alternatively include sloped superior and inferior surfaces (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>C illustrate another embodiment of a modular fusion cage <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> having a ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, each having a dome-like or convex profile on the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. In addition to having a dome-like profile, the ring member and ramp member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are shown having sloped superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The dome-like profile of the ring and ramp members <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is formed by a curvature located in both the sagittal and coronal planes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> illustrates the radius of curvature R<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>in the coronal plane <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7C</cross-reference> illustrates the radius of curvature R<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in the sagittal plane of the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. The radius of curvature R<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, R<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in each plane is preferably in the range of about 50 mm to 350 mm, and is more preferably in the range of about 100 mm to 200 mm. Most preferably, the radius of curvature R<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, R<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is about 150 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In use, the modular fusion cage of the present invention can be implanted between adjacent vertebrae preferably using an anterior or anterio-lateral approach. Generally, the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is positioned between adjacent vertebrae in an orientation in which the transverse sides <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are in contact with the end plates of the adjacent vertebral bodies. Thereafter, the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is rotated 90&deg; to enable the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to contact and distract the end plates of the vertebral bodies. The modular construction of the fusion cage of the invention and its manner of installation promotes a safe and effective surgical procedure. Placement of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in an initial orientation in which the transverse sides <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> contact the vertebral end plates can be accomplished without undue distraction of the vertebrae. Once the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is rotated, the vertebrae are distracted only by the amount necessary to accept the fusion cage. When the ramp is properly positioned, the ring member is mated to the ramp, as explained below, without any additional distraction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can also be inserted between adjacent vertebrae using a distractor or spreader device. Distractor and spreader devices are known in the art, and are effective for separating adjacent vertebrae, and optionally assisting with insertion of the implant. Typical distractors include two opposed blade members which are inserted between the adjacent vertebrae, and then opened to separate the vertebrae. The ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can then be inserted into the disk space either manually, or with using an impacting device, such as a mallet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> By way of non-limiting example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A and 8B</cross-reference> illustrate a modular fusion cage <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, as described with respect to FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>C, having a handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> for inserting the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> between adjacent vertebrae, and for positioning the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> around the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. The handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can have any size and shape, and is preferably a substantially elongate rigid member having a distal end <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> removably attached to the anterior side <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. The handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can be mated to the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> using any type of fastening element, such as, for example, threads which engage similar threads in a bore disposed in the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, or a taper post matable with a taper bore disposed in the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can be formed integrally with the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and, once the modular fusion cage is implanted, the handle can be broken or snapped off of the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. A person having ordinary skill in the art will readily appreciate that handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can be disposed on or attached to the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, or the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> using a variety of different techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Once the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is positioned, the handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can be removed, or alternatively, it can be used to assist with the insertion of the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> around the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>B, the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> can include an opening or bore <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> disposed in the anterior side <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> for receiving the handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The opening should be sized and shaped to slidably receive the handle, and should be positioned to align the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> with the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> upon insertion of the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. The handle can be used to hold the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> in position while an impacting device is used to force fit the ring member around the ramp member, if necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The modular fusion cage according to the present invention can optionally include an alignment guide in addition to, or as an alternative to, the handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. By way of non-limiting example, the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> include an alignment guide formed from at least one tongue <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> disposed on at least one transverse side <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and at least one groove <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> formed along the inner side (not shown) of at least one of the transverse walls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In use, the tongue <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and groove <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are aligned with one another and the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is mated with the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by sliding the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> over the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Although the fusion cage is described as having a tongue on the ramp and a groove on the ring, this arrangement can be reversed. In addition, other alignment mechanisms can be used, such as, for example, a morse-taper, dovetail, or mortise and tenon mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The tongue and groove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be tapered (not shown) toward the anterior side <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to form a dovetail lock, or similar type of locking mechanism. The taper is preferably at an angle between about 0&deg; and 5&deg;. In use, the locking mechanism prevents the ring member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> from sliding with respect to the ramp member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A person having ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that a variety of different types of locking mechanisms can be used to prevent the ring member from moving with respect to the ramp member. For example, a fastening element (not shown), such as a screw, can be inserted through opening <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</cross-reference>) to replace the handle <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and secure the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A and 10</cross-reference>, the present invention also provides an insertion tool <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> which can be used to insert the ring member around the ramp member. In general, the insertion tool <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> includes two opposed grasping elements <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and two opposed handles <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> mated at pivot point <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> in a scissor-like fashion. The first grasping element <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is mated to handle <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> to form a first lever <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, and the second grasping element <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is mated to handle <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to form a second lever <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. A fastening element, such as a pin, screw, or similar structure can be used to mate the first and second levers <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. The insertion tool <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can optionally include a locking element <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> to prevent the first and second levers <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> from moving with respect to each other. In one embodiment, the locking element <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> can be in the form of a ratchet mechanism in which a pawl <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> is disposed at a proximal end of the handle <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and teeth <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight> are formed on a lever <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> that is pivotally attached to handle <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. In another embodiment, the locking mechanism <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> can be in the form of a vise-grip <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>, as shown on insertion tool <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference>. Vise-grips are known in the art and typically employ a toggle mechanism (not shown) which allows for the first and second levers <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> to be maintained in locking engagement with the implant <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> once a force is applied to the handle members <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. The vise-grips <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> can include an adjustment screw (not shown) which must be initially adjusted to set the opening of the levers <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> in relation to the implant to be grasped. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the distal end <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> of each grasping element <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> includes at least one engaging element <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> for mating with and grasping a ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Each engaging element <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> can be formed from an extending portion protruding from the distal end <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> of each grasping element <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, and can have a shape and size adapted to fit within a groove <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> formed in the anterior side <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> of the superior and inferior surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. A person having ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) is shown for illustration purposes only, and that any ring member according to the present invention can be used with insertion tool <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> In use, the engaging elements <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> are placed in the grooves <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> in the ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, and the handles <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> are squeezed together to hold the ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> securely at the distal end <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> of the insertion tool <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The locking element <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> can be engaged to lock the handles <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> together and thereby hold the ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The insertion tool <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is then manipulated to position the ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> around a ramp member. The locking element <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> can then be released when it is appropriate to free the ring member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. A person having ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that prior to insertion of the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> around the ramp member <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, the ring member <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> can be packed with a bone ingrowth promoting composition that may include, for example, cancellous bone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The modular fusion cage of the present invention may be constructed from a variety of materials that are bio-compatible and suitable for medical applications. One preferred material from which the implant can be made is a carbon fiber reinforced polymer. Other materials from which the implants can be made include metals, metal alloys, biologically compatible polymers, allograft bone, and combinations of these materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> One of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate further features and advantages of the invention based on the above-described embodiments. Accordingly, the invention is not to be limited by what has been particularly shown and described, except as indicated by the appended claims. All publications and references cited herein are expressly incorporated herein by reference in their entirety.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A modular fusion cage, comprising: 
<claim-text>a ramp member adapted to be positioned between adjacent vertebral bodies, the ramp member having superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces, and anterior and posterior sides; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cage forming member slidably matable with the ramp member, the cage forming member having a central opening extending in a superior-inferior plane that is defined by an annular wall that is interrupted by a wall opening that communicates with the central opening, the ring-like wall further having superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces, and anterior and posterior sides. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wall opening is disposed in the posterior side of the ring member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cage forming member includes first and second transverse walls extending between the posterior and anterior sides. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wall opening in the posterior side of the cage forming member extends between the first and second transverse walls of the cage forming member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ramp member includes first and second transverse sides adapted to conform to the wall opening in the posterior side of the ring member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the superior and inferior surfaces of the posterior side of the cage forming member define a wedge-like tip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a portion of the superior and inferior surfaces of at least one of the cage forming member and the ramp member include a plurality of bone-engaging surface features. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wedge-like tip is substantially free of bone engaging surface features. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the cage forming member and the ramp member includes an alignment guide that is effective to align the cage forming member and the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the alignment guide is disposed on the transverse sides of the ramp member, and on the opposed faces of the annular wall that are adjacent to the wall opening of the cage forming member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the alignment guide comprises dovetail lock. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the alignment guide comprises a tongue and groove joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the ramp member and the cage forming member includes a locking mechanism for locking the ring member to the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the locking mechanism comprises a dovetail lock. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ramp member has a height extending between the superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces and the height of the ramp member decreases from the anterior side to the posterior side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cage forming member has a height extending between the superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces and the height of the cage forming member decreases from the anterior side to the posterior side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the height of the ramp member is greater than the height of the cage forming member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces of the cage forming member have a convex shape in both the saggital and coronal places. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ramp member includes a handle removably mated to the anterior side of the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anterior side of the cage forming member includes a bore formed in the anterior side for slidably receiving the handle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bore is adapted to receive a fastening element effective to secure the ring member to the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cage forming and ramp members are made from a material selected from the group consisting of allograft bone, metals, metal alloys, carbon fiber reinforced polymers, biocompatible polymers and combinations thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A modular fusion cage, comprising: 
<claim-text>a substantially rectangular ramp member adapted to be positioned between adjacent vertebral bodies, the ramp member having opposed transverse sides, superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces, and anterior and posterior ends; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a substantially annular ring-like member slidably matable with the ramp member, the ring-like member being formed of a structural wall that is interrupted by a wall opening, the ring-like member having 
<claim-text>superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces, anterior and posterior ends, and first and second rib members extending between the posterior and anterior ends and disposed inwardly of the structural wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a central opening, oriented in a superior-inferior plane, and disposed between the rib members; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second transverse openings, oriented in a superior inferior plane, and disposed between one of the rib members and the structural wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the superior and inferior surfaces of the posterior side of the ring member define a wedge-like tip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a portion of the superior and inferior surfaces of at least one of the ring member and the ramp member include a plurality of bone engaging surface features, each bone engaging surface feature having a base integral with one of the superior and inferior surfaces. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wedge-like tip is substantially free of bone engaging surface features. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the ring-like member and the ramp member includes an alignment guide that is effective to align the ring-like member with the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the alignment guide is disposed on the transverse sides of the ramp member, and on the opposed faces of the annular wall that are adjacent to the wall opening of the ring-like member </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the ramp member and the ring-like member includes a locking mechanism for locking the ring member to the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ramp member has a height extending between the superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces and the height of the ramp member decreases from the anterior side to the posterior side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ring-like member has a height extending between the superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces and the height of the ring-like member decreases from the anterior side to the posterior side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the height of the ramp member is greater than the height of the ring member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces of the ring-like member have a convex shape in both the saggital and coronal planes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ramp member includes a handle removably mated to the anterior side of the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ring-like member includes a bore formed in the anterior side of the ring-like member for slidably receiving the handle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The modular fusion cage of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ring-like and ramp members are made from a material selected from the group consisting of allograft bone, metals, metal alloys, carbon fiber reinforced polymers, biocompatible polymers and combinations thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A modular fusion cage, comprising: 
<claim-text>a ramp member having posterior and anterior faces, superior and inferior bone contacting faces, and first and second transverse faces; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ring member defined by an annular wall having posterior and anterior faces, superior and inferior bone contacting faces, and first and second transverse faces, the posterior face including an opening formed in the annular wall for receiving the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A spinal implant system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a modular fusion cage having 
<claim-text>a ramp member having posterior and anterior faces, superior and inferior bone contacting faces, and first and second transverse faces, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ring member defined by an annular wall having posterior and anterior faces, superior and inferior bone contacting faces, and first and second transverse faces, the posterior face including an opening formed in the annular wall for receiving the ramp member, the anterior side of the superior and inferior faces further having at least one groove formed therein for receiving an insertion tool; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insertion tool effective to grasp and manipulate the ring member relative to the ramp member, the insertion tool having 
<claim-text>first and second opposed grasping elements movable between an open position and a closed position and matable with the at least one groove formed in each of the superior and inferior faces of the ring member, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second opposed actuating members mated to the first and second grasping elements and effective to move the first and second grasping elements between the open and closed positions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A method of implanting a spinal disk prosthesis, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a modular fusion cage having 
<claim-text>a ramp member adapted to be positioned between adjacent vertebral bodies, the ramp member having superior and inferior bone contacting surfaces and first and second transverse sides, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cage forming member slidably matable with the ramp member, the cage forming member having a central opening adapted to receive the ramp member; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>separating adjacent vertebrae, each vertebra having an endplate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the ramp member between the endplates of the adjacent vertebrae in an orientation in which the first and second transverse sides are in contact with the endplates; </claim-text>
<claim-text>rotating the ramp member to enable the superior and inferior surfaces to contact the endplates of the adjacent vertebrae; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sliding the cage forming member around the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of locking the cage forming member to the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A method of implanting a spinal disk prosthesis, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a modular fusion cage having a ramp member adapted to be positioned between adjacent vertebral bodies, and a ring member having a central opening adapted to slidably receive the ramp member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>separating adjacent vertebrae; </claim-text>
<claim-text>partially inserting the ramp member between the adjacent vertebrae; </claim-text>
<claim-text>impacting the ramp member with an impacting device to fully insert the ramp member between the adjacent vertebrae; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sliding the ring member around the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of claim <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, further comprising the step of locking the ring member to the ramp member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A method of implanting a spinal disk prosthesis, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a modular fusion cage having a ring member and a ramp member, the ring member including an opening for receiving the ramp member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting the ramp member between adjacent vertebrae; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing an insertion tool effective to grasp and manipulate the ring member, the insertion tool having first and second opposed grasping elements movable between an open position and a closed position and matable with the ring member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>grasping the ring member with the first and second grasping elements of the insertion tool; </claim-text>
<claim-text>manipulating the insertion tool to position the ring member around the ramp member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030004576A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
