<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005362A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005362A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005362A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005362A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005362A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005362A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005362</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896495</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04L001/22</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>714</class>
<subclass>027000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>714</class>
<subclass>042000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>System and method of automatic information collection and problem solution generation for computer storage devices</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jennifer</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Miller</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Greeley</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alex</given-name>
<family-name>Lenart</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HEWLETT-PACKARD COMPANY</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Administration</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P. O. Box 272400</address-1>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80527-2400</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention includes a system for and a method of a support system which includes an information manager to gather performance information and error condition-related information from a computer product which is sent by the information manager electronically to a support server. The support server, working with an associated database, attempts to solve the underlying error present in the computer product by analyzing the information received, comparing the information to a database containing previously reported error related information and identification of a proposed solution or corrective action from the database. This proposed solution, or corrective action is then sent to the information manager. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Typically, manufacturers of computer systems, computer devices, computer components or software (computer products) offer customers technical support once the computer products have been purchased or leased by the consumer. This support may consist of technical information on the use of the computer products or may be directed to the identification and solution of problems encountered when using the computer products. Typically, when a customer encounters a problem with a computer product, he or she calls the manufacturer&apos;s support center, who in turn generates an incident number, and then requests that the consumer manually gather data from the malfunctioning computer product. This data is then formatted into an electronic mail, or e-mail, message or described verbally and sent or communicated to the service center of the manufacturer. After allowing time for the service center to receive this information, the customer calls the service center where technical personnel access the data contained in the e-mail or verbal message and, working with the customer, attempt to identify the malfunction (or the misuse) of the computer product. Once the problem is identified, the service center personnel instructs the customer on the steps required to correct the problem. If, however, the service center personnel cannot identify and/or solve the malfunction, a service technician is dispatched to the site or the consumer is asked to bring the computer product in for repair. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The process in identifying and solving malfunctions in computer products is manually intensive, time consuming, and inefficient. Additionally, each service center personnel must be trained in the identification and solutions for malfunctions which may appear in the supported computer products. This process is again inefficient as support personnel turnover requires retraining and additional education. Additional inefficiencies occur when trained service personnel spend time and expend resources in solving known problems or when particularly complicated or difficult problems are resolved by different personnel at a later time for a different customer. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to a method of and apparatus for a support system which comprises a storage device including an information manager configured to collect performance information and to generate an error message including the performance data. Also included is a support server which receives the error message and, working with the information in an associated database, identifies malfunctions and proposes solutions. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a system which automatically gathers error information and suggests solutions for the error condition according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow chart which depicts an overall process of an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a system that may be used pursuant to the present invention to automatically gather parameter information from a malfunctioning storage device indicative of symptoms of a fault. The information is then transmitted to a dedicated support server that may include a central processing unit and a connection to a database which, working together, are programmed to identify malfunctions and propose solutions to correct the malfunctions of the storage device. Specifically, for example, consumer <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> purchases computer storage device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, such as a tape library, from a manufacturer and installs storage device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> into the consumer&apos;s system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Included within storage device <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is an information manager such as a Remote Management Card (RMC) <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> that collects and packages information used to troubleshoot the malfunction within computer product <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> for analysis and tracking by dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. This information may be performance data or error information or combined performance and error information. RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> gathers the relevant information, the information is embedded in a performance or error message and the message, including that information is sent to dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> through consumer firewall <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> (if present) via Internet <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The performance or error information collected may be error-condition related information. &ldquo;Pushing&rdquo; this information through firewall <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> allows the information to be received by dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> which could not otherwise initiate access of the information. This communication may be transmitted using HTTP or other protocol and/or format. Consumer firewall <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, if present, allows RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to push data out from the consumer&apos;s Local Area Network (LAN) (not shown) or other local communications environment to Internet <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Once RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> data is received by dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, embedded Central Processing Unit (CPU) <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> executes resident software to analyze the data contained in RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> message. In analyzing this data, CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> may access database <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> to compare RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> data to pre-existing records or trends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> If dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> cannot identify or solve the malfunction, RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> data may be sent to support personnel <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> for follow-on analysis. Alternatively, if dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> can identify the problem and identify a proposed solution, an appropriate message may be sent from dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> to RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> or to consumer <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> with the suggested corrective action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Additionally, database <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> collects, stores and processes data gathered by RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and performs comparisons between this data and other data generated by, and collected from similar storage devices. This information is used to create a database of information about storage devices, their characteristics, maintenance issues, error conditions, malfunctions, solutions, and early indications that would be helpful in future trouble-shooting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the report page generated by RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> would be written in Extensible Markup Language (XML) which would allow CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to easily parse the data for processing and storage in database <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, other mark-up languages and formats may be used or formats that can be converted into a user-friendly form can also be used without deviating from the spirit of this invention. The XML-based report page may be communicated using Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) as the transport mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> If repair information containing corrective or proposed solutions is sent from CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> this information may be sent via an e-mail to gain access through consumer firewall <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, or may be in response to RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> generated poll to CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a flow chart which outlines an overall process of an embodiment of the invention. In step <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, the user of the storage device determines that the storage device is malfunctioning. The user requests that RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> gather relevant information (from sensors or internal logs) and send that information to dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). In step <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> establishes communication with CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, through dedicated support server <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, and downloads the information to CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> in step <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. In step <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> analyzes the information and preferably accesses the database (step <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>) to identify the malfunction and, if possible, a solution. At step <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, if information relevant to the identified malfunction is contained in the database, CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> uses the information to determine a course of action (step <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>), and sends this information to the user or RMC <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) for implementation (step <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>). The information collected may be performance data, error messages or information, or any other data pertinent to the operation of the storage device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, if at step <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> information relevant to identified malfunction is not contained in the database, in step <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> a new database entry is created in which to store this error information. Because CPU <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> cannot suggest a solution, the problem is referred to support personnel in step <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> for resolution. In step <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> the support personnel identify a solution and import information relevant to the solution into the database. The support personnel would preferably also follow up with the customer to ensure the problem with the storage device was correctly resolved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> If a problem is experienced by the tape library, for instance an updated release of the software or firmware stored within the tape library is interrupted during loading causing the tape library to remain in boot-up, the RMC may preferably be used to collect corresponding information when enabled by the user. In this example, the corresponding information may include software or firmware version number, the date the software or firmware was loaded, the size of the corresponding file, etc. The collected information would be sent to the support server, which upon analysis of the problem would identify the failed software or firmware update and accordingly would instruct the operator to reload the information. In this example, the problem may be identified from a variation in size between the expected software or firmware loaded and the actual size of the file. Similarly, partial availabilities of tape libraries, or other problems, may be identified by the support server by analysis of information collected by the RMC. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the present invention includes an automatic recognition capability that determines the presence of an error condition and begins collecting error-related information as a result of this detection. Such automatic detection mechanisms are known in the art and this embodiment of the present invention includes these as the impetus to start information collection. For example, Hewlett-Packard manufactures a C7200 tape library that is currently shipped with a Remote Management Card (RMC) installed. The RMC card allows access of the purchasing company&apos;s local network&apos;s tape library to gather information from sensors located within the tape library. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A support system comprising: 
<claim-text>an information manager within a storage device configured to collect performance information and embed said performance information of said storage device into an error message; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a support server configured to receive said error message from said information manager and analyze said performance information; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a database configured to maintain a history of previous performance information and at least one corresponding corrective solution wherein said support server uses said history to identify a proposed one of said at least one solution and communicates said proposed solution to said information manager. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The support system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information manager is a remote management card within said storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The support system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said error message is written in Extensible Markup Language. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The support system of claim l wherein said support server receives said error message via the Internet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The support system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said support server is configured to search said database to identify matching performance information and send said solution associated to said performance information to said information manager as said proposed solution. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The support system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said support server is configured to send a message to support personnel if said performance information received from said information manager does not correspond to performance information contained in said database. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The support system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>a database update logic configured to update said performance information and said at least one solution in said database to include performance information received from said information manager and corresponding said at least one solution. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method of identifying proposed solutions to correct an error condition within a storage device, said method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>gathering error condition-related information of said storage device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>embedding said error condition-related information into an electronic message; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting said electronic message to a remote support server; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying at said remote support server a proposed solution to an error that corresponds to said error condition-related information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of gathering error condition-related information further comprises at least one of the group of-. 
<claim-text>sensing parameters of said storage device and reading information from an internal log. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of embedding said error condition-related information further comprises formatting said information in an Extensible Markup Language. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of communication further comprises transmitting said electronic message on the Internet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said method further comprises the step of: 
<claim-text>communicating identified proposed solutions from said remote server via said Internet to said storage device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of identifying a proposed solution to said error further comprises a step of comparing said error condition-related information to error information contained in a database. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a step of: 
<claim-text>communicating said proposed solution to a remote management card in said storage device that exhibits an error corresponding to said error condition-related information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of communicating further comprises transmission of an electronic message to said remote management card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of communicating further comprises providing an electronic message to a user of said computer product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method of automatically identifying a solution to an error condition comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>automatically recognizing, without manual intervention, an error condition within a computer storage device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>gathering error condition-related information; </claim-text>
<claim-text>embedding said error condition-related information into an electronic message; </claim-text>
<claim-text>communicating said electronic message to a support server remote from said computer storage device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying at a remote location a proposed solution to an error which corresponds to said error condition-related information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of automatically recognizing an error condition further comprises sensing parameters with said computer storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of gathering error condition-related information further comprises performing at least one of the group of: 
<claim-text>sensing parameters of said storage device and reading information from an internal log. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of embedding said error condition-related information uses Extensible Markup Language. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>communicating identified ones of said proposed solutions from said remote location to said computer storage device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005362A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005362A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005362A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
