<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001287A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001287A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001287</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893036</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L023/48</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L023/52</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/40</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>780000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Flexible tape electronics packaging</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ajit</given-name>
<middle-name>V.</middle-name>
<family-name>Sathe</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chandler</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Intel Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type></assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Schwegman, Lundberg,</name-1>
<name-2> Woessner &amp; Kluth, P.A.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 2938</address-1>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">To decrease the weight and the thickness, and to increase the flexibility, of an electronics package, the package includes an integrated circuit (IC) mounted on a flexible tape substrate. In one embodiment, an IC is mounted on a flexible tape substrate using a ball grid array arrangement; however, other arrangements, including lead bonding, can be used. The flexible tape substrate can comprise conductive traces, vias, and patterns of lands on one or more layers. Methods of fabrication, as well as application of the flexible tape package to an electronic assembly, an electronic system, and a data processing system, are also described. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to electronics packaging. More particularly, the present invention relates to an electronic package that includes an integrated circuit packaged on a flexible tape substrate, and to manufacturing methods related thereto. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Integrated circuits (ICs) have typically been assembled into electronic packages by physically and electrically coupling them to a substrate made of organic or ceramic material. One or more such IC packages can be physically and electrically coupled to a secondary substrate such as a printed circuit board (PCB) or motherboard to form an &ldquo;electronic assembly&rdquo;. The &ldquo;electronic assembly&rdquo; can be part of an &ldquo;electronic system&rdquo;. An &ldquo;electronic system&rdquo; is broadly defined herein as any product comprising an &ldquo;electronic assembly&rdquo;. Examples of electronic systems include computers (e.g., desktop, laptop, hand-held, server, etc.), wireless communications devices (e.g., cellular phones, cordless phones, pagers, etc.), computer-related peripherals (e.g., printers, scanners, monitors, etc.), entertainment devices (e.g., televisions, radios, stereos, tape and compact disc players, video cassette recorders, MP3 (Motion Picture Experts Group, Audio Layer 3) players, etc.), and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In the field of electronic systems there is an incessant competitive pressure among manufacturers to drive the performance of their equipment up while driving down production costs. This is particularly true regarding the packaging of ICs, where each new generation of packaging must provide increased performance while generally being smaller or more compact in size. As market forces drive equipment manufacturers to produce electronic systems with increased performance and decreased size, IC packaging accordingly also needs to support these requirements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In addition, manufacturers of high-end IC packages, such as processors, are experiencing increasing demand for IC packages mounted in thin, light-weight, and/or resilient packaging, because such packaging is useful for many applications. For example, hand-held electronic systems, such as cellular telephones, palm-top computers, personal digital assistants, calculators, MP3 players, watches, hearing aids, and similar equipment typically requires ICs in thin, light-weight, and/or flexible packages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> An IC substrate may comprise a number of metal layers selectively patterned to provide metal interconnect lines (referred to herein as &ldquo;traces&rdquo;), and one or more electronic components mounted on one or more surfaces of the substrate. The electronic component or components are functionally connected to other elements of an electronic system through a hierarchy of electrically conductive paths that include the substrate traces. The substrate traces typically carry signals that are transmitted between the electronic components, such as ICs, of the system. Some ICs have a relatively large number of input/output (I/O) terminals (also called &ldquo;lands&rdquo;), as well as a large number of power and ground terminals or lands. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Surface mount technology (SMT) is a widely known technique for coupling ICs to a substrate. One of the conventional methods for surface-mounting an IC on a substrate is called &ldquo;controlled collapse chip connect&rdquo; (C4). In fabricating a C4 package, the electrically conductive terminals or lands of an IC component are soldered directly to corresponding lands on the surface of the substrate using reflowable solder bumps or balls. The C4 process is widely used because of its robustness and simplicity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In addition to using SMT to couple an individual IC die to a substrate, it is also well known to use SMT to couple an IC package to a substrate such as a printed circuit board (PCB) or motherboard. Solder bumps, for example, can be employed between lands on the IC package and corresponding lands on the PCB. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> As the internal circuitry of ICs, such as processors, operates at higher and higher clock frequencies, and as ICs operate at higher and higher power levels, the amount of loop inductance produced within IC packages and electronic assemblies can increase to unacceptable levels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> For the reasons stated above, and for other reasons stated below which will become apparent to those skilled in the art upon reading and understanding the present specification, there is a significant need in the art for apparatus and methods for packaging an IC that minimize the thickness and weight of the packaging, and that minimize loop inductance within the packaging.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of an electronic system incorporating at least one electronic assembly with a flexible tape package in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional representation of a prior art electronic assembly comprising an IC package mounted on a printed circuit board (PCB); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a partially exploded cross-sectional representation of a flexible tape package assembly, taken along dashed line <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, including a die aligned for mounting to a flexible tape substrate overlying a secondary substrate, such as a PCB, in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a top-view of the flexible tape package assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, with cut-away portions corresponding to dashed line <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> together illustrate different stages in a process of fabricating a flexible tape package assembly, in accordance with one embodiment of the invention, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a flexible tape substrate having a pattern of lands thereon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a flexible tape substrate having solder paste applied to lands on a surface thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a flexible tape substrate with dice mounted on a surface thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a bottom view of a segment of flexible tape IC package having solder balls on a surface thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a portion of a secondary substrate, such as a PCB, having a flexible tape IC package mounted thereon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a portion of the secondary substrate and flexible tape IC package of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, with leads mounted; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a flow diagram illustrating a method of fabricating a flexible IC package substrate, in accordance with one or more embodiments of the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference> together form a flow diagram illustrating a method of fabricating an electronic assembly, in accordance with one or more embodiments of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In the following detailed description of embodiments of the invention, reference is made to the accompanying drawings which form a part hereof, and in which is shown by way of illustration specific preferred embodiments in which the inventions may be practiced. These embodiments are described in sufficient detail to enable those skilled in the art to practice the invention, and it is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized and that mechanical, chemical, structural, electrical, and procedural changes may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention. The following detailed description is, therefore, not to be taken in a limiting sense, and the scope of the present invention is defined only by the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a solution to thickness, weight, and/or rigidity limitations in an IC package, and to loop induction problems that are associated with prior art IC packages, by substituting a flexible tape for a rigid organic package substrate. In one embodiment, an IC is mounted on a flexible tape substrate using a ball grid array (BGA) arrangement. Other mounting arrangements, including lead bonding, can be used in conjunction with or in place of BGA mounting. The flexible tape can comprise one or more layers, conductive traces, and patterns of lands. Various embodiments are illustrated and described herein, including methods of fabrication, as well as application of the flexible tape package to an electronic assembly, an electronic system, and a data processing system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of an electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> incorporating at least one electronic assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> with a flexible tape package in accordance with one embodiment of the invention. Electronic assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> has a reduced weight and a reduced thickness or stack height. Electronic assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can also possess a degree of flexibility, such that it can be bent or molded for particular applications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is merely one example of an electronic system in which the present invention can be used. In this example, electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comprises a data processing system that includes a system bus <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to couple the various components of the system. System bus <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> provides communications links among the various components of the electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and can be implemented as a single bus, as a combination of busses, or in any other suitable manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Electronic assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is coupled to system bus <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Electronic assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can include any circuit or combination of circuits. In one embodiment, electronic assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> includes a processor <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> which can be of any type. As used herein, &ldquo;processor&rdquo; means any type of computational circuit such as, but not limited to, a microprocessor, a microcontroller, a complex instruction set computing (CISC) microprocessor, a reduced instruction set computing (RISC) microprocessor, a very long instruction word (VLIW) microprocessor, a graphics processor, a digital signal processor (DSP), or any other type of processor or processing circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Other types of circuits that can be included in electronic assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are a custom circuit, an application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC), or the like, such as, for example, one or more circuits (such as a communications circuit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) for use in wireless devices like cellular telephones, pagers, portable computers, two-way radios, and similar electronic systems. Electronic assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can perform any other type of function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can also include an external memory <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which in turn can include one or more memory elements suitable to the particular application, such as a main memory <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the form of random access memory (RAM), one or more hard drives <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and/or one or more drives that handle removable media <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> such as floppy diskettes, compact disks (CDs), digital video disk (DVD), and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can also include a display device <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, a speaker <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, and a keyboard and/or controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which can include a mouse, trackball, game controller, microphone, voice-recognition device, or any other device that permits a system user to input information into and receive information from the electronic system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Among various embodiments, system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> could be a hearing aid, a pacemaker, a wristwatch, a pager, a cellular phone, an Internet appliance, a personal digital assistant (PDA), or a palmtop computer. However, many other different embodiments can also take advantage of the relatively low stack height, relatively low weight, and relatively high degree of flexibility of electronic packaging provided by the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional representation of a prior art electronic assembly comprising an IC package mounted on a printed circuit board (PCB). The prior art electronic package includes die <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> having a plurality of signal and power supply lands (not shown) on its lower surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The package also includes substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, e.g. an IC package substrate, having a plurality of signal and power supply lands (not shown) on its upper surface that are coupled to corresponding lands of die <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> through bumps or balls <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. IC package substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is typically formed of an organic material. FR-4 is one type of organic material that is widely used. IC package substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> comprises a plurality of signal and power supply lands <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> on its lower surface. Lands <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of IC package substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> are coupled to corresponding lands <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of a secondary substrate, such as printed circuit board PCB <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, through solder balls or bumps <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. PCB <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can optionally have lands <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> on its lower surface for attachment to an additional substrate or other packaging structure in the packaging hierarchy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Regarding the prior art electronic assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the &ldquo;stack height&rdquo; <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is the distance between the upper surface of die <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the upper surface of PCB <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. It is desirable to minimize the stack height <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in order to provide an electronic assembly having minimum thickness and minimal loop inductance. It will be understood that the stack height of a prior art electronic assembly that utilizes a socket arrangement would typically be even greater than the BGA assembly illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a partially exploded cross-sectional representation of a flexible tape package assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, taken along dashed line <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, including a die <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> aligned for mounting to a flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> overlying a secondary substrate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, such as a PCB, in accordance with one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Die <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can be any type of IC, such as a processor, memory chip, chipset component, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, die <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> comprises a plurality of electronic circuits and signal conductors (not shown) that terminate in lands (not shown) arranged in several rows near the periphery of the bottom surface of die <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, with die <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in a flip-chip orientation). Die <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> also comprises a plurality of power and ground conductors (not shown) that terminate in lands (not shown) within the central core region of die <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The signal and power lands on the lower surface of die <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can be coupled to corresponding lands, pads, or signal nodes (not shown) on substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> by appropriate connections such as solder bumps or solder balls <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Flexible substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, comprises three layers <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. Substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, including layers <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, can be formed of a thin, flexible, electrically insulating tape or film. Such films are well known in the tape automated bonding (TAB) art. Such films can be formed of various materials. For example, they can be formed of polymeric films, such as polyimide. Other possible materials include polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, and fiberglass. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, each layer of flexible substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> has a thickness of approximately 0.20 mm, and the overall thickness of flexible substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, comprising three layers <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, is approximately 0.60 mm. However, in other embodiments, thicker or thinner film could be used. In general, each layer of film can be in the range of approximately 0.15 mm to 0.30 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Upper layer <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> has formed on its upper surface a plurality of terminals or lands <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> to couple with corresponding pads of IC <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> through bumps <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Other lands <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> can also be formed on the upper surface of upper layer <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. Lands <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> can be used to couple to corresponding terminals <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> on the upper surface of PCB <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> through wire leads such as lead <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Between upper layer <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and middle layer <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are formed a plurality of conductive traces, such as trace <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. Likewise, between middle layer <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and bottom layer <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> are formed a plurality of conductive traces, such as trace <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. Traces can be formed using any suitable conductive material, such as copper, aluminum, silver, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Bottom layer <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> has formed on its lower surface a plurality of lands such as lands <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Conductive vias, such as vias <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, can be formed in any layer <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, through a subset of layers <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, or through all three layers <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, to couple traces within different layers <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, or to couple lands such as <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> to internal traces such as traces <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> While three layers <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> are illustrated in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, fewer or more layers could be used. For example, just one layer could be used. Further, not all layers need to be electrically insulating, because one or more ground planes could be inserted that are formed of any suitable electrically conductive material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can be mounted on a secondary substrate such as PCB <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> by coupling lands <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to corresponding terminals <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> on the upper surface of PCB <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, lands <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> are coupled to terminals <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> via a ball grid array (BGA) of solder balls (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, lands on the upper surface of substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, such as land <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>, can be coupled to corresponding lands <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> on the upper surface of PCB <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> through conductive leads or wires, such as lead <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. In yet another embodiment, a combination of BGA and wire lead attachments can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Substrate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> can be of any type, such as a printed circuit board (PCB) or card, a motherboard, or any other type of packaging element. Substrate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> can be a multi-layered substrate or a single-layered substrate. The present invention is not to be construed as limited to any particular type of substrate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> or to any particular method of coupling substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to substrate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Substrate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> can optionally have lands (not shown) on its lower surface for attachment to an additional substrate or other packaging structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The resulting stack height of flexible tape package assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is significantly less than that of the prior art electronic assembly illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. For example, if a flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> having a thickness of 0.6 mm is used in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the resulting overall stack height is approximately 20% less than the stack height of the prior art electronic assembly illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, assuming the thicknesses of the die and die bumps, and the interconnect between the package and the PCB are held constant. Even thinner assemblies can be achieved by using fewer layers within flexible tape package assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a top-view of the flexible tape package assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, with cut-away portions corresponding to dashed line <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. A first cut-away portion A is to the left of line <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. A second cut-away portion B is between lines <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. And a third cut-away portion C is to the right of line <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The top-view of flexible tape package assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in portion A includes the top of IC <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> as mounted upon flexible tape package substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> by way of, for example, a surface mount technique, such as a BGA pattern that can include lands <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> (shown in dashed lines in portion A, since they are underneath IC <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, in turn, can be mounted to a secondary substrate, such as PCB <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, in at least two different ways, both of which are illustrated in portion A, or in a combination of these two ways. A first way is using a BGA pattern that can include lands on the bottom surface of substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, such as lands <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> (shown in dashed lines in portions A-C, since they are underneath substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>), that are coupled to corresponding terminals on the upper surface of PCB <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> (such as terminals <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). Another way is using conductive leads or wires, such as lead <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, which couples a land <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> on the upper surface of flexible tape package substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to a corresponding terminal <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> on the upper surface of PCB <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The top-view of flexible tape package assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in portion B includes the top of flexible tape package substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, showing a BGA pattern on its upper surface, which includes lands <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The top-view of flexible tape package assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in portion C is of the top of layer <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, showing a plurality of conductive traces <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> on the upper surface of layer <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>. Also shown (in dashed outline) are lands <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> on the bottom surface of substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Lands <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> can be coupled to traces <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> using vias such as vias <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Flexible tape package substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> has a &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo; that is adapted to have mounted thereon an IC, such as IC <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. As used herein, a &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo; means a region that can contain vias, traces, and/or lands anywhere within the boundary of the region, as defined for example by dashed outline <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> (to be described below). A &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo; is typically substantially square or rectangular, though it need not be limited to such shapes. A &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo; is distinguishable from a tape automated bonding (TAB) lead-frame conductive pattern, which has conductive leads and pads that are located at the periphery of the pattern, surrounding an IC, but which does not have traces, vias, or lands beneath the IC. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Flexible tape package substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can include sprockets <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> that are outside the conductor region. Sprockets <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> can be used in conjunction with a suitable transport mechanism (not shown) to facilitate production movement within a high volume manufacturing environment, at least until the flexible tape is separated or &ldquo;singulated&rdquo; into individual IC-mounted tape segments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> together illustrate different stages in a process of fabricating a flexible tape package assembly, in accordance with one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> having a pattern of lands <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>527</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> thereon. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> has been formed, and it comprises several layers. Dashed outlines <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> show locations where ICs will subsequently be mounted. Within each dashed outline <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> appears an illustrative pattern of lands, such as land <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>, which will be coupled to corresponding pads on the bottom of an IC. In one embodiment, the pattern is a BGA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Also seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> are lands <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> (shown in dashed outline) on the bottom surface of flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, which will be used to mount flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> to a secondary substrate, such as a PCB. In addition, lands <highlight><bold>527</bold></highlight> are seen on the upper surface of flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, and they can be coupled to corresponding lands on the PCB using wire leads if desired. Sprockets <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> can be provided to enable transport of the flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> through a high volume manufacturing area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> having solder paste applied to lands <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> on a surface thereof. Prior to mounting ICs on flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, solder paste can be applied to all exposed lands on flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, or alternatively just to lands <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> (as indicated by cross-hatching) to which the ICs will be mounted. The ICs can have a bump or ball pattern already applied. Alternatively, a ball pattern could be applied to lands <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> of flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> with dice <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> mounted on a surface thereof. Dice <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> can be mounted using a BGA arrangement in which solder bumps or balls on the lower surfaces of dice <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> are coupled using, for example, a solder reflow process, to corresponding lands <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> (shown in dashed outline) on the upper surface of flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a bottom view of a segment of flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> having solder balls on a surface thereof. Seen in dashed outline <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> is an IC mounted on the upper surface of flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>. Prior to this stage in the process, flexible tape substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> has been segmented or &ldquo;singulated&rdquo; into individual tape segments. After singulation, the individual flexible tape substrate segments, referred to hereinafter as flexible tape IC packages <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>, are typically placed into transport carriers or trays for subsequent testing and possibly other manufacturing and shipping operations. Next, solder balls are formed on corresponding lands <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a portion of a secondary substrate <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>, such as a PCB, having a flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> mounted thereon. Flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> includes IC <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. Also shown is a pattern of lands <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> (in dashed outline) on the bottom of flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>, which pattern can be a BGA. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> has been aligned with PCB <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>, and lands <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> have been coupled to corresponding terminals (not shown) on PCB <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>, e.g. using a solder reflow process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a portion of the secondary substrate <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> and flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, with leads <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> mounted. As mentioned earlier, flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> can be mounted using solely a BGA pattern, using solely lead bonding, or using a combination of BGA and lead bonding. If lead bonding is used, leads <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> are coupled between lands <highlight><bold>527</bold></highlight> on the upper surface of flexible tape IC package <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> and corresponding terminals <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> on the upper surface of PCB <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a flow diagram illustrating a method <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> of fabricating a flexible IC package substrate, in accordance with one or more embodiments of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> In <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>, a thin, flexible substrate is provided. The substrate is formed of material such as a polymeric film, polyimide, polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, fiberglass, or a combination of these materials. The substrate has a &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo; (as defined earlier) adapted to mount an IC. The substrate can include from 1 to N layers. The substrate can also include, if desired, sprocket holes located outside the &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>, a plurality of traces are formed in the conductor region. The traces can be formed on different layers, or they can be formed on one layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>, a plurality of lands are formed that are coupled to certain traces of the plurality of traces. The lands can be formed on opposite sides of the substrate, or on just one side of the substrate. In one embodiment, the lands are arranged in one or more ball grid arrays (BGAs). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> In <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>, solder bumps or balls are formed on the plurality of lands. The solder balls can be formed on different groups of the lands. For example, a first set of lands can be covered with solder balls in order to couple the substrate to an IC, and a second set of lands can be covered with solder balls in order to couple the substrate (including IC) to a PCB. The process ends at <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference> together form a flow diagram illustrating a method <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> of fabricating an electronic assembly, in accordance with one or more embodiments of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight>, a thin, flexible substrate is provided. The substrate is formed of material such as a polymeric film, polyimide, polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, fiberglass, or a combination of these materials. The substrate has a &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo; (as defined earlier) that includes a plurality of traces and a plurality of lands coupled to certain traces. The substrate can include from 1 to N layers, each comprising a plurality of traces in the &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo;. The lands can be formed on different layers. The substrate can also include, if desired, sprocket holes located outside the &ldquo;conductor region&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight>, solder balls are formed on a first set of lands, which can be a ball grid array (BGA). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> In <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>, pads of an IC are coupled to corresponding ones of the first set of lands using, for example, a solder reflow operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> In <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight>, the substrate is mounted on an additional substrate, such as a PCB. Either or both of the following techniques can be used: (1) use a BGA pattern between the substrate and the PCB, by forming solder balls on a second set of the lands, and coupling ones of the second set of lands to corresponding terminals on the PCB; (2) use leads between the substrate and the PCB, by coupling leads, such as wires, between corresponding ones of a third set of lands and additional terminals of the PCB. The process ends in <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The operations described above with respect to the methods illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11, 12A</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B can be performed in a different order from those described herein. Also, it will be understood that while an &ldquo;end&rdquo; block is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference>B, these methods can be performed continuously. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Conclusion </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides for a lightweight electronic package, in several different embodiments, and for methods of manufacture thereof, that minimize the thickness of the package, and that offer some degree of flexibility and/or of moldability. Loop inductance within the package is also reduced, because conductive paths through the flexible tape substrate are shorter than they are through an organic substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> An electronic system and/or data processing system that incorporates one or more electronic assemblies that utilize the present invention can be produced in configurations having reduced thickness and weight, and with enhanced flexibility and electronic performance, and such systems are therefore more commercially attractive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> As shown herein, the present invention can be implemented in a number of different embodiments, including an electronic package substrate, an electronic package, an electronic system, a data processing system, one or more methods of fabricating a flexible tape package, and one or more methods of fabricating a flexible tape package assembly. Other embodiments will be readily apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art. The elements, materials, geometries, dimensions, and sequence of operations can all be varied to suit particular packaging requirements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> For example, while an embodiment of an IC is shown in which signal traces are provided around the periphery and in which power supply traces are provided at the die core, the invention is equally applicable to embodiments where signal traces and power supply traces are provided anywhere on the die. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Further, the present invention is not to be construed as limited to use in ball grid array (BGA) packages, and it can be used with any other type of IC packaging technology where the herein-described features of the present invention provide an advantage, e.g. land grid array (LGA), chip scale package (CSP), or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Various embodiments of flexible tape substrates can be implemented. The structure, including types of materials used, dimensions, layout, electrical properties, and so forth, of flexible tape substrates can be built in a wide variety of embodiments, depending upon the requirements of the IC package and/or electronic assembly of which the flexible tape substrate forms a part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> While an embodiment has been described in which the electronic component that is mounted on flexible tape substrate is an IC, the electronic component could also be a passive component such as a resistor, capacitor, or inductor, or any other type of electronic component, whether or not implemented as an IC, such as an oscillator, filter, sensor, variable resistor, fuse, coil, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The above-described choice of materials, geometry, and assembly operations can all be varied by one of ordinary skill in the art to optimize the performance of the electronic package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 10</cross-reference> are merely representational and are not drawn to scale. Certain proportions thereof may be exaggerated, while others may be minimized. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B are intended to illustrate various implementations of the invention that can be understood and appropriately carried out by those of ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Although specific embodiments have been illustrated and described herein, it will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that any arrangement that is calculated to achieve the same purpose may be substituted for the specific embodiment shown. This application is intended to cover any adaptations or variations of the present invention. Therefore, it is manifestly intended that this invention be limited only by the claims and the equivalents thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a thin, flexible substrate having a conductor region adapted to mount an integrated circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a plurality of traces in the conductor region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a plurality of lands coupled to the traces. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate is formed of material from the group comprising a polymeric film, polyimide, polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, and fiberglass. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the substrate comprises forming a plurality of layers, each comprising a plurality of traces in the conductor region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the substrate comprises forming a plurality of sprocket holes outside the conductor region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lands are arranged in a ball grid array, the method further comprising: 
<claim-text>forming solder balls on the plurality of lands. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a thin, flexible substrate having a conductor region comprising a plurality of traces and a plurality of lands coupled to the plurality of traces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling pads on an integrated circuit (IC) to corresponding lands on the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate is formed of material from the group comprising a polymeric film, polyimide, polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, and fiberglass. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the substrate comprises forming a plurality of layers, each comprising a plurality of traces in the conductor region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the substrate comprises forming a plurality of sprocket holes outside the conductor region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising before coupling: 
<claim-text>forming solder balls on the lands. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising: 
<claim-text>mounting the substrate on an additional substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the additional substrate comprises a printed circuit board. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein lands are coupled to corresponding terminals on the additional substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising before mounting: 
<claim-text>forming solder balls on the lands. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lands are coupled to the terminals using a ball grid array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein leads are coupled between corresponding lands and terminals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An electronic package substrate comprising: 
<claim-text>a thin, flexible, electrically insulating film having a conductor region adapted to mount an integrated circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of traces in the conductor region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of lands coupled to the traces. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The electronic package substrate recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film is formed of material from the group comprising a polymeric film, polyimide, polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, and fiberglass. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The electronic package substrate recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film comprises a plurality of layers, each comprising a plurality of traces in the conductor region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The electronic package substrate recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lands are arranged in a ball grid array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An electronic package comprising: 
<claim-text>an electrically insulating film having a thickness in the range of approximately 0.15 to 0.90 millimeters, the film having a conductor region, a plurality of traces in the conductor region, and a plurality of lands coupled to the traces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an electronic component having a plurality of pads coupled to the plurality of lands. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The electronic package recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film is formed of material from the group comprising a polymeric film, polyimide, polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, and fiberglass. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The electronic package recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film comprises a plurality of layers, each comprising a plurality of traces in the conductor region, and wherein each layer has a thickness within the range of approximately 0.15 to 0.30 millimeters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The electronic package recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lands are arranged in a ball grid array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The electronic package recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electronic component comprises an integrated circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An electronic system comprising at least one electronic assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a thin, flexible, electrically insulating film having a conductor region, a plurality of traces in the conductor region, and a plurality of lands coupled to the traces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an electronic component having a plurality of pads coupled to the plurality of lands. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The electronic system recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film is formed of material from the group comprising a polymeric film, polyimide, polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, and fiberglass. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The electronic system recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film comprises a plurality of layers, each comprising a plurality of traces in the conductor region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The electronic system recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lands are arranged in a ball grid array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The electronic system recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electronic component comprises an integrated circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A data processing system comprising: 
<claim-text>a bus coupling components in the data processing system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a display coupled to the bus; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory coupled to the bus; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor coupled to the bus and comprising an electronic assembly including, 
<claim-text>a thin, flexible electrically insulating film having a conductor region, a plurality of traces in the conductor region, and a plurality of lands coupled to the traces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an integrated circuit having a plurality of pads coupled to the plurality of lands. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The data processing system recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film is formed of material from the group comprising a polymeric film, polyimide, polyester, polyparabanic acid, epoxy, and fiberglass. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The data processing system recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the film comprises a plurality of layers, each comprising a plurality of traces in the conductor region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The data processing system recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lands are arranged in a ball grid array.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030001287A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
