<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000563A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000563A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000563A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000563A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000563A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000563A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000563A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000563A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000563A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000563A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000563A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000563A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000563A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000563A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000563A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000563A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000563</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09927456</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010813</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>144041</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>IL</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E04H015/60</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>121000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>120400</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>117000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>114000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>157000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Construction frame</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Arieh</given-name>
<family-name>Kuperman</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Nesher</city>
<country-code>IL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BROWDY AND NEIMARK, P.L.L.C.</name-1>
<name-2>624 NINTH STREET, NW</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>SUITE 300</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20001-5303</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A structure comprising at least three essentially rigid legs, each having a top end, and a bottom end, with at least two connecting elements fitted on each leg and at least three elongate braces each having a first end and a second end and being fitted with at least four anchoring sites. Each brace is connected with two adjacent legs, and at least one of the anchoring sites is directly coupled with a respective connecting element of one adjacent leg, and at least one other of the anchoring sites is coupled via a tensioning member to another respective connecting element of the other adjacent leg. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to structures, and in particular, to easily erectable and collapsible structures such as, for example, pavilions, tent frames, as well as frame structure such as for marine or airborne vehicles, etc. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Many common known structures, such as tent frames, pavilions and other shelters or structures, are constructed using support poles/rods, bars and multiple other parts that must be assembled together. Such a process is time-consuming and often requires considerable effort and skill, in particular where assembling and disassembling should be performed at specific sequence of operations. Also, the plurality of components that must be assembled and disassembled increases the likelihood of loss of parts, improper assembly, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> An example where a structure according to the invention may be utilized is a sukkah (a booth with a roof of branches and leaves used during the Jewish feast of Sukkoth&mdash;tabernacles), it is used for a week each year and is then stored for a prolonged period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Several conventional tents, such as those disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,884,646 and U.S. Pat. No. 6,021,795, are constructed of jointed rods, which allow the tent frame to lock and become rigid when the tent is assembled and also enable the tent to be easily collapsed during disassembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Another type of collapsible tent frame is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,152,157. The frame is constructed of several side poles connected by a network of hinged ribs that extend outward when the tent is in use and fold inward for storage. This structure also has a center pole whose height can be adjusted by a spring to stretch and sustain a roof for the tent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention calls for a new structure frame which essentially overcomes or reduces the above referred to drawbacks. In particular the invention is concerned with a frame structure which is easily erected and disassembled, using simple components and connecting elements and giving rise to a structure which at its assembled, erect position is essentially rigid. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention there is provided a structure frame comprising a plurality of elongate connecting members with suitable connectors and tensioning elements, which at an erect state of the structure render it rigidity and stability. A frame according to the invention may be useful for a variety of structures e.g. vehicles (hulls of ships, air balloons, plains etc.), sheds etc. The frame may be a collapsible or a fixed structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides for a structure comprising at least three essentially rigid legs, each having a tip end, and bottom end, with at least two connecting elements fitted on each leg; at least three elongate braces each having a first end and a second end and being fitted with at least four anchoring sites; each brace being connected with to two adjacent legs, where at least one of said anchoring sites is directly coupled with a respective connecting element of one adjacent leg, and at least one other of said anchoring sites is coupled via a tensioning member to another respective connecting element of the other adjacent leg. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to a first embodiment of the present invention, the tensioning members provide an inward force on the top ends of the legs, causing them to approach a center of the structure while causing bottom ends of the legs to depart from the center of the structure. However, according to a second embodiment of the invention, the tensioning members provide an outward force on the top ends of the legs, also causing the bottom ends of the legs to depart from the center of the structure. The above first and second embodiments may be utilized simultaneously or separately in the same embodiment, together imparting the structure its stability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to the first and second above embodiments, the bottom ends of the legs are secured by a restraining member to prevent their departure in a direction away from the center of the structure. According to one specific arrangement, the bottom ends of the legs are secured to a supporting surface (typically ground) by suitable attachment members for securing to the supporting surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to a different embodiment, the bottom ends of the structures&apos; legs are connected by an additional tensioning member providing the bottom ends of the legs with a force countering the inward force generated at the top ends of the legs, affording the structure with a high degree of stability. The tension in the additional tensioning member may be adjustable and may have means for its adjustment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> By one application, the direct coupling of the anchoring sites with the connecting elements is pivotal, allowing the structure to collapse and erect with relative ease. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The anchoring sites on adjacent braces may be attached to prevent the augmentation of the angle between the braces. This may be achieved in a variety of ways including attaching the anchoring sites on adjacent braces via a tensioning member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> According an arrangement of the present invention, at least one end of one or more braces is directly coupled to a respective leg, with a tension member extending between a portion of the brace and a portion of the respective leg above the point of direct coupling with said brace; or at least one brace is directly coupled to a respective leg at a portion of the brace other then its end and where said braces is coupled to the respective leg by a tension member extending between a portion of the brace and a portion of the respective leg below the point of direct coupling with said brace. These options may be combined in a single structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The anchoring or tensioning of the bottom ends of the legs mentioned hereinabove may be obviated according to still another embodiment of the invention, wherein at least some, though preferably all, braces are coupled to the respective legs with a first tensioning member extending between a portion of the brace and a portion of the respective leg below the point of direct coupling with said brace and a second tensioning member extending between a portion of the brace and a portion of the respective leg above the point of direct coupling with said brace. According to one particular embodiment, tensioning members extending from two intersecting braces towards a portion of a leg are coupled to the leg at the same site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Typically but not necessary according to the invention, all components remain connected to respective other components also at the collapsed state of the structure.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In order to understand the invention and to see how it may be carried out in practice, some embodiments will now be described, by way on non-limiting examples only, with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an isometric view of an erect construction in accordance with the present invention, illustrating two embodiments of connection of components of the construction; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a portion of the construction seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in an erect through un-tensioned state; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a portion of the construction seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in an erect and tensioned state; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an exploded view illustrating a corner of the structure in accordance with an embodiment the invention seen as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an exploded view of a direct connection in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a section through an anchoring member useful for fixing a leg of the construction to a support surface; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an isometric view of a construction in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A, 7B</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>C illustrate a leg/brace connecting zone (corner), of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, in three respective positions, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> illustrates the construction at a collapsed state; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> illustrates the device during assembly; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7C</cross-reference> illustrates an erect position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an isometric view of an adjustable tensioned member used in erecting a construction according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A and 9B</cross-reference> illustrate another embodiment of an erect structure frame according to the invention, in a pre-tensioned and tensioned state, respectively.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Attention is first directed to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> of the drawings illustrating a construction in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention generally designated <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The construction <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises four essentially rigid legs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> made for example of reinforced fiber material, aluminum, plastic, etc. Each leg has a respective top end <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a bottom end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, where the bottom ends are engageable with a support surface, e.g. ground, floor, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The structure <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further comprises four elongate braces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> each having a first end designated <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and a second end designated <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Each brace <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is fitted with at least four anchoring sites which depending on their function and position are designated <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, as will become apparent hereinafter and wherein each leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is fitted with at least two connecting elements of different types <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> as will become apparent hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As noted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, each brace <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected with an adjacent leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> at corners of the construction generally designated <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> where it is noticeable that the front top corner of the construction is different from the other corners and is thus designated <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In corners <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, connection is achieved by directly coupling one anchoring site <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of a brace <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at a top portion of a corresponding leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by directly coupling it to a connecting element <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> fixed on leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Connecting sites <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the respective corners <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are connected to respective connecting element <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of leg <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via tensioned elements <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> which also interconnect to adjacent anchoring sites <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Tensioning members <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> are made of an unextendible cord, e.g. fabric, metal chain, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Turning now also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference> illustrating the corner <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and the respective bottom end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> illustrating the corner at a pre-tensioned position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference>) and at a tensioned position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference>). The tensioned position of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> renders the entire structure <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> stability and rigidity. This is obtained by imparting an essentially inwardly directed force F (illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> of the drawings by a dashed line). As noted in the figures, the force F is a resultant force as a result of tensioning a tension line <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> fixed at the bottom end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of legs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and tensioning said tension line in the direction of arrows f. Alternatively, and as one will appreciate, the bottom ends <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be directly inwardly in the direction of force F. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> According to a different embodiment, or in combination, there may be provided a surface engaging member designated <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> which can also be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The surface engaging member comprises a receptacle <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> for receiving the bottom <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of legs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a through going bore <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> for inserting a tent peg <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> or, for example, a concrete rivet or bolt for connecting same to the floor. The engagement member <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> further comprises an eye hook <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> through which the tensioning cord <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> extends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In utilizing a tension cord <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, it is advantageous to employ a tensioning member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> which is seen in more detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The tensioning member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> comprises a hollow body member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> through which tension cords <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>&prime; extends with a stopper member <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> biased by means of spring <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> against a slack end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of the cord <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>&prime;. Member <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is typically formed with a ridged peripheral portion <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> for improved gripping with a corresponding portion of the cord. A cord <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> which may be the opposite end of cord <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>&prime;, or another cord, is tied at a suitable ear <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> or an alternative ear <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> as may be required, depending on the direction of tension. Pulling the slack end of the cord <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> gives rise to tensioning cords <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The housing <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of the tensioning member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is cylindric and is dimensioned so as to receive an end portion of a leg member <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> or a brace member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention, where the tensioning device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> may serve for adjusting the tension through tensioning members <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> as discussed hereinabove. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the components of a corner <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in a somewhat enlarged scale wherein the different anchoring sites can be better appreciated. Anchoring sites <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are eye hinges mounted over braces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and slidable fixed by suitable means, e.g. by riveting or by suitable bolts, as known, per se. Anchoring sites <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are hooks fitted with a spring closure of a known type, connectable to a corresponding eye hinge of connecting element <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> which in turn is slidably fixed on leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. It is further noted that tensioning element <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is a flexible cord fitted with three hooks <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> for engagement with corresponding anchoring sites <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on braces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and connecting element <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment the length of the tensioning member <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is fixed and it is appreciated that the tension through this cord may be adjusted by suitable tensioning member, e.g. tensioning member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> disclosed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Reverting now to the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, attention is directed to the front-most top corner designated <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> which serves the same function as the other corners <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> though it is constructed in a different manner. In accordance with this embodiment braces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are coupled at their respective anchoring sites <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to a corresponding connecting element <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (see also <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) whereby anchoring sites <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are coupled via tensioning cords <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> to a respective connecting element <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> fitted on leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. It is appreciated that the anchoring sites <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> as well as connecting elements <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> respectively, are fixed to the braces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, respectively to prevent their axial displacement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> It is appreciated that also in connection with the embodiment represented by corner <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> tensioning cord <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> entails the bottom end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the respective leg <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to deform inwardly towards the center of the construction thereby tensioning cords <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, impairing the entire structure, stability, and rigidity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Turning now to the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, there is illustrated a construction generally designated <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> comprising three legs <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, each having an upper portion <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> which curves inwardly towards the center of the triangular construction and each terminating with a hooked portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. The arced portion <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> may be suitable for stretching a fabric over the construction whereas the hooked portions <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> may serve for hanging different loads as utility hangers or for increasing stability of the structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Each pair of adjoining legs <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is interconnected by a corresponding brace <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and it is noted that each of the braces is fitted with four anchoring sites <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> corresponding with anchoring sites <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and attention is directed to the relevant description hereinabove. Each of the legs <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> comprises two connecting elements <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> corresponding with connecting element <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and one connecting element <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> corresponding with the connecting element <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The principle difference between the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> and the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is the obviation of tensioning cord <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> applying an inwardly directed force at the bottom of the structure&apos;s legs, owing to tensioning cords <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> which in their mutual tensioned position render the structure, stability and rigidity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A, 7B</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>C, a typical corner of the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is illustrated in three consecutive positions, namely, a collapsed state of the structure (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference>) and erecting state (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference>) and a erected, stable state (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7C</cross-reference>), respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> the braces <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> are collapsed over leg <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, enabled by disconnecting tension cords <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> from connecting element <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> fixed on leg <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. For that purpose, it is advantageous that the tensioning cord <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> be fitted at its end with suitable clip hinges <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Connecting clips <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> to connecting element <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of leg <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is possible upon positioning the braces at their erected position and slightly deforming each of the leg <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and braces <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> towards one another as illustrated by arrows F thereby decreasing the distance between anchoring sites <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the connecting element <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, whereby the hooks <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> can be hooked onto the respective connecting element <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Upon ceasing of force F, the structure will obtain stability and rigidity owing to tension residing within the tension cords <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</cross-reference>. Obviously, suitable tensioning members may be provided, e.g. tensioning member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A and 9B</cross-reference> there is illustrated another embodiment of construction frame in accordance with the present invention. The frame comprises components which are principally similar to those disclosed in connection with previous embodiments and accordingly some specific details have been omitted and thus the reader is directed to these previous embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The construction generally designated <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> comprises four legs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> formed in a rectangular shape and supported by four braces <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> fitted at the lower ends of the legs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Braces <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are articulated to the legs in a similar manner as illustrated in connection with the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> with tension cords <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> extending between ends of braces <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and respective bottom portions of legs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Top ends <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of legs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are fitted with an eye-hook <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> through which a peripheral tension cord <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> extends with a tensioning member <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, for example, such as the one disclosed in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, is provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Upon tensioning the cord <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, e.g., in the direction of arrow F, the top ends <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of legs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> approach one another as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> giving rise to a dome-shape which by means of member <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> retains its position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> It is noted that the structure <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be secured to the ground by means of suitable pegs <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> However, it will also be appreciated that the structure may be used for different purposes such as, for example, a hot air balloon in which case no support pegs will be required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> It will be understood that the above described embodiments constitute only examples of such structures in accordance with the present invention and that the scope of the present invention fully encompasses other embodiments which may become obvious to those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The structure, according to the present invention may be used in a variety of ways. It may serve as a tent frame or as an internal framework for other such shelters such as vending booths. As it may be constructed in a range of sizes, the structure may also serve as the framework for advertising displays, and the like. In addition, the structure may serve as the frame of a ship&apos;s hull, an airborne vehicle (such as, for example, a hot air balloon, a zeppelin, etc.). </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A structure comprising at least three essentially rigid legs located about a center of the structure, each leg having a top end and a bottom end, with at least two connecting elements fitted on each leg; at least three elongate braces each having a first end and a second end and being fitted with at least four anchoring sites; each brace being connected with to two adjacent legs, where at least one of said sites is directly coupled with a respective connecting element of one adjacent leg, and at least on other of said sites being coupled via a tensioning member to another respective connecting element of the other adjacent leg. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the direct coupling of the anchoring sites with the connecting elements is pivotal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tensioning members provide an inward force on the top ends causing them to approach the center of the structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ends of the legs are connected by an additional tensioning member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein tension in the additional tensioning member provides the ends of the legs with a force countering the inward force. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tension in the additional tensioning member is adjustable. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein anchoring sites on adjacent braces are attached to prevent the augmentation of the angle between the braces. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein anchoring sites on adjacent braces are attached via a tensioning member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bottom ends of the legs are capable of being attached to the supporting surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the top ends of the legs extend towards a center of the structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extended upper ends are capable of supporting a stabilizing weight to further stabilize the structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extended upper ends are capable of supporting a canopy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the structure is a tent frame or a sukkah. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein all components remain connected to respective other components also at the collapsed state of the structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tensioning members provide an inward force on the top ends of the legs, causing them to approach the center of the structure while causing bottom ends of the legs to depart from the center of the structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one brace is directly coupled to a respective leg at a portion of the brace other then its end and where said braces is coupled to the respective leg by a tension member extending between a portion of the brace and a portion of the respective leg below the point of direct coupling with said brace. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein two or more braces are coupled to the respective legs with a first tensioning member extending between a portion of the brace and a portion of the respective leg below the point of direct coupling with said brace and a second tensioning member extending between a portion of the brace and a portion of the respective leg above the point of direct coupling with said brace. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A structure according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein tensioning members extending from two intersecting braces towards a portion of a leg are coupled to the leg at the same site.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000563A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000563A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000563A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000563A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000563A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000563A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000563A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000563A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
