<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001030A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001030A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001030</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09733714</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20001211</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B05B005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>698000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>697000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>690000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>587100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>588000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>426000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>434000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Flexible charged powder particle application device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Buscemi</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Rutland</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>John J. Welch, Jr., Esq.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>8 E. Center Street</address-1>
<city>Rutland</city>
<state>VT</state>
<postalcode>05701</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A flexible charged powder particle application device consisting of a resistor unit in contact with a power source on one side thereof and with wiring on a second side thereof, the resistor being found within an electrode block unit with a centerhole and connected to an electrode block extension unit with a centerhole all within housing and with the wiring being insulated within flexible tubing material being attached at one end to splines on an end of the extension unit such that the tubing is amenable to carriage within it of the wiring as well as accommodating within it, a flow of powder particles introduced under pressure into the centerholes such that charge from the power source via the wiring and the powder particles under pressure are amenable to concomitant expulsion from the tubing held at a second end by splines on an electrode hub holding an electrode base and electrode and adapter nozzle via a held base bushing and adapter screw lock into and about the housed electrode out through the hub for ultimate application to a metallic surface. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCES TO PRIOR OR PARENT APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> There are no prior or parent applications to which the instant invention relates. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> There is no federally sponsored research and development to which the instant invention relates. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The instant invention is within that field of devices serving to facilitate the application of charged powder particles to metallic surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> 2. Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Your inventor is aware of no prior art that anticipates the instant invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> 1. A Brief Description of the Invention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The invention consists of an electrode block within which there is affixed a 15 meg resistor. The resistor is in contact with an external electrical power source via a contact ring unit. Wiring is attached to the resistor opposite to where the resistor is in contact with the contact ring. An electrode block extension unit is affixed anteriorly to the electrode block. Flexible tubing is affixed anteriorly to the electrode block extension unit. A hollow central through hole in the electrode block and one in the electrode block extension unit as well allows for the flow of powder particles under pressure into the flexible tubing also holding the wiring leading from the resistor. A hollow threaded sleeve unit envelopes the electrode block and electrode block extension unit. The wiring within the flexible tubing leads to an electrode contact via an electrode base unit to which there is anteriorly attached an electrode unit fitted with the contact all within a threaded electrode hub to which a base bushing unit is threadably fitted. The base bushing unit functions to hold in place, the electrode base unit, the electrode unit and an adapter nozzle unit within the electrode hub. An adapter screw lock unit in turn holds the base bushing unit in place at the front of the electrode hub. The invention accommodates use of a so-called flat jet adapter nozzle or an open-ended adapter nozzle. The open-ended adapter nozzle serves to accommodate insertion of a corona deflector unit onto the anterior end of the electrode unit. Powder particles under pressure entering the central through holes in the electrode block and electrode block extension unit and then coming up through the flexible tubing then pass through a center through hole in the electrode hub unit then around and about the electrode, through the base bushing unit via the adapter nozzle and exit out about the frontal aspect of the jet where they invariably come into contact with the charged outermost end of the stiff linearly shaped anterior tip of the electrode. In this way, then charged powder particles are readily amenable to adherence to the surface of any metallic object to which one would be seeking to apply such a coating of paint. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> 2. An Object of the Invention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Current state of the art charged powder paint application devices are stiff and inflexible. There is no device within the aegis of the prior art that is in any way flexible so as to permit consistent, dependable and even coating of irregularly shaped metallic surfaces or pieces characterized by the presence of obstacles or corners. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The instant invention in view of its new and unique flexible tube component instantly serves to solve the problem of permitting consistent, dependable and even coating of irregularly shaped metallic surfaces or pieces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, the instant invention, respectfully submitted is not only new and unique, but is likewise useful to the extent that it is veritably revolutionary in the art of powder pain application devices. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">A DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> 1. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic depiction of a prior art in use for powder coating purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> 2. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic depiction of the invention in use for powder coating purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> 3. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a depiction of a result obtained from use of prior art for powder coating purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> 4. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a is a depiction of the result obtained from use of the invention for powder coating purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> 5. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a broken lateral plan view of a first embodiment of the invention depicting a portion thereof cross-sectionally. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> 6. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an isolated broken perspective view of flexible tubing in respect of a second </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> 7. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an isolated broken perspective view of a third embodiment of flexible tubing in respect of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> 8. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an isolated view of a segment of that portion of the invention depicted cross-sectionally in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> 9. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional depiction of that portion of the invention wherefrom charged powder particles emanate with use of a corona jet component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> 10. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional depiction of that portion of the invention wherefrom charged particles emanate with use of a flat jet component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> 11. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a schematic depiction of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> 12. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional depiction of powder particles emanating from the frontal aspect of the invention being charged as applied to a metallic surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> 13. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of various anterior components of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> 14. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the components shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> but assembled together. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> 15. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view evidencing assembly of various posterior components of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> 16. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of various posterior components of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">A DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> as contrasted with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates the clear difference as between universally inflexible prior art in respect of charged powder particle application devices, in general, and the instant invention, a flexible charged powder particle application device. Powder C is processed forward from a powder reservoir G under pressure from, for example, forced air and, interactively with current from a power source A influenced by electronic controls D is ultimately deposited onto a metallic surface E. Flexible tubing component <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the invention with body and length is the unique feature that serves to markedly distinguish the invention from prior art devices in respect of the matter of depositing charged power particles in a form of painting application to metallic surfaces E. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> serve to illustrate the marked advantages of the invention vis a vis inflexible prior art devices. A comparison of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> will, at once, facilitate the observation that bare, untreated spots F in metallic work E, remain after completion of a painting application process utilizing an inflexible prior art charged powder application device, are markedly absent in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> where a resort to utilization of the instant invention was undertaken for such purposes. It is the unique feature of flexibility as respects the invention that serves to enable a user to achieve even, dependable and complete charged powder particle paint application to tightly positioned, relatively hard to reach nooks, crannies and corners in and about metallic objects, the surfaces of which are sought to be coated. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates the essence of the invention more or less panoramically, as does <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> however in schematic fashion. Power from a power source A via a contact ring is introduced to a 15 meg resistor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> housed within an electrode block unit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> seen, for example in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. Electrode block unit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> abuts contact ring B that in turn abuts power source A as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> on the side of resistor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and opposite the side thereof in contact with ring B there is to be found wiring <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> soldered to resister <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as seen for example, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 8</cross-reference>. Electrode block unit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is affixed at the anterior side thereof to the posterior end of an electrode block extension unit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Electrode block unit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and electrode block extension unit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are each characterized by the presence of electrode block centerhole <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and electrode block extension centerhole <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> respectively to facilitate the passage of powder particles C flowing through units <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> under pressure from a powder reservoir G. Block housing <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> houses units <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and, this, if you will, posterior aspect of the invention is held intact once assembled, by any one of various means. For example, a first pin <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> insertable into a first pinhole <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> extending through housing <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and units <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is serviceable as a means of maintaining such assembly. Electrode block pinhole <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in unit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and pinhole <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in unit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> receive second pin <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> in order to prevent undesirable rotation of unit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in relation to unit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> during actual operation of the invention in variant forms of the invention wherein unit <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and unit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> would not have been, for example, press fitted together during initial manufacture of the invention. The purpose of an electrode block extension unit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is to provide electrode block extension splines <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> to which one end of flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is affixed. An electrode block extension relief surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> serves to prevent tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> from riding posteriorly about unit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> during operation of the invention. Power source affixation means <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, for example, threading about inner walling of block housing <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> serve to hold intact power source A, contact ring B and units <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> all within block housing <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An anteriorly positioned housing through hole <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in block housing <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> permits emanation therefrom of flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5, 6</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> illustrate the manner in which wiring <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is found within flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, in a first embodiment of the invention wiring <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is shown as it courses alternatively through the lumen within flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> from where it is soldered to resistor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, in a second embodiment, wiring <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is shown built right into the body of flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and so within flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> courses anteriorly from where it is soldered to resistor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, wiring <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in a third embodiment is also shown built into the body of flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, however, it is held within an external extrusion of the outer walling of flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and courses accordingly anteriorly from the point where it is soldered to resistor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Suitable insulating material <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> circumscribes wiring <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the instance where as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, current in wiring <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> coursing anteriorly from resistor <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> must be prevented from contacting powder particles C flowing through the lumen of flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> from the locus of electrode block extension centerhole <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</cross-reference> illustrate, if you will, the anterior aspect of the invention. The anterior aspect of the invention in exploded perspective view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is shown wholly assembled in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. With resort to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, an electrode base unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is anteriorly assembled to an electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Located upon electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is electrode contact component <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Within electrode base unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> there is to be found horizontally inclined wiring through hole <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and electrode base centerhole <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Wiring <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> within flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> ultimately passes through wiring through hole <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to make contact with electrode contact component <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> while powder coursing under pressure from within the lumen of flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> enters electrode base centerhole <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Hollow adapter nozzle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is posteriorly affixable to electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as is also evidenced with resort to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. Adapter nozzle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has either a wholly open anterior end to accommodate affixation of a corona deflector <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to an anterior end of electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> or the anterior end thereof is closed but for a slit therein. An electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> serves to house electrode base unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and adapter nozzle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> as well as to posteriorly consist of hub splines <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which a second end of flexible tubing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is affixed. A base bushing unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is equipped with means, for instance, threading <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> for affixation of base bushing unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> via threading <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> on interior walling of electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to the interior of electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Base bushing unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> posteriorly accepts and concomitantly stabilizes, within electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the complex made up of conjoined electrode base unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and adapter nozzle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. An adapter screw lock unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> equipped with means, for instance, threading <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> for affixation of adapter screw lock unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to i.e., threading <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> on the interior walling of base bushing unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> serves to stabilize the position of base bushing unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> within electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> via a relief surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>A located anteriorly upon the exterior of adapter screw lock unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A hub pin <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> insertable into a hub pinhole <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> within electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and in turn insertable into a base pinhole <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> within electrode base unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> provides an optimal means of further stabilizing the above-referenced complex within electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Hub pinhole <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> could moreover optimally be moved anteriorly on electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to accommodate insertion of hub pin <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> into a nozzle pinhole <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to accomplish the same purpose. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates cross-sectionally the assembly of components depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> cross-sectionally illustrates the flow of powder particles C under pressure coursing as illustrated with arrows through electrode base unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, about electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, through adapter nozzle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and then under pressure out and about corona deflector <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> where they come into contact with a charged tip of electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to then themselves acquire charge to facilitate deposit of such particles upon a metallic surface E. Removal of an open-ended adapter nozzle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and corona deflector <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and insertion instead of a slit-ended adapter nozzle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> in place of the open-ended adapter nozzle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, within the slit of which the charged tip of electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> would be found serves to facilitate tighter application of powder particles C emanating to and through the slit and coming into contact with the charged tip of electrode unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, to a metallic surface E. The novel combination of those components of the invention such as the electrode block extension unit <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the electrode base unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and electrode hub unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is occasioned as a means of accommodating the need for the presence of electrode block splines <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and electrode hub splines <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in order to hold and stabilize in place the novel component, flexible housing <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In conclusion, it is once again respectfully submitted, that the invention is not merely new, useful and unique, but is, moreover, indeed virtually revolutionary in the art of charged powder particle application devices:</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A Flexible Charged Powder Particle Application Device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a) 15 meg resistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) wiring with length affixed to said resistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) an electrode block unit housing said resistor affixed therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) an electrode block extension unit affixed at a posterior end thereof to an anterior side of said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>e) an electrode block centerhole within said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>f) an electrode block extension centerhole within said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>g) an electrode block extension relief surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>h) electrode block extension unit splines located near an anterior end of said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>i) a hollow block housing unit housing said electrode block unit and said electrode block extension unit with a through hole at an anterior end of said block housing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>j) means within said hollow block housing unit for affixation to said hollow block housing unit of an external power source to which a posterior side of said electrode block is connected via a contact ring unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>k) flexible tubing with body and length affixed at a first end to said electrode block extension unit splines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>l) an electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>m) electrode hub unit splines located near a posterior end of said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>n) said flexible tubing being affixed at a second end thereof to said electrode hub unit splines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>o) an electrode base unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>p) said electrode base unit having a horizontally inclined center through hole; </claim-text>
<claim-text>q) said electrode base unit having a horizontally inclined wiring through hole in a body thereof; </claim-text>
<claim-text>r) an electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>s) an electrode contact component affixed to said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>t) a hollow base bushing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>u) said electrode base unit being anteriorly attached to a posterior portion of said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>v) an adapter nozzle posteriorly attached to said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>w) said base bushing unit being affixed at outer walling thereof to inner walling of said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>x) said base bushing unit holding said adapter nozzle and in turn said electrode unit and in turn said electrode base unit within said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>y) an adapter screw lock unit attachable about an anterior end of said electrode hub unit by way of affixation of said adapter screw lock unit at outer walling thereof to inner walling of said base bushing unit, and; </claim-text>
<claim-text>z) said wiring traversing said length of said flexible tubing within said flexible tubing beginning from a locus of said resistor and coursing through said wiring through hole and terminating affixed to said electrode contact component. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The flexible charged powder particle application device of claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>., whereby, said wiring along said length of said wiring is circumscribed by insulating material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A Flexible Charged Powder Particle Application Device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a) a 15 meg resistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) wiring with length affixed to said resistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) an electrode block unit housing said resistor affixed therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) an electrode block extension unit affixed at a posterior end thereof to an anterior side of said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>e) an electrode block centerhole within said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>f) an electrode block extension centerhole within said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>g) an electrode block extension relief surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>h) a horizontally inclined first pinhole in a posterior portion of said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>i) a horizontally inclined second pinhole in an anterior side of said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>j) a pin insertable into said first pinhole and into said second pinhole; </claim-text>
<claim-text>k) electrode block extension unit splines located near an anterior end of said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>l) a hollow block housing unit housing said electrode block unit and said electrode block extension unit with a through hole at an anterior end of said block housing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>m) means within said hollow block housing unit for affixation to said hollow block housing unit of an external power source to which a posterior side of said electrode block is connected via a contact ring unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>n) flexible tubing with body and length affixed at a first end to said electrode block extension unit splines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>o) an electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>p) electrode hub unit splines located near a posterior end of said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>q) said flexible tubing being affixed at a second end thereof to said electrode hub unit </claim-text>
<claim-text>r) an electrode base unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>s) said electrode base unit having a horizontally inclined center through hole; </claim-text>
<claim-text>t) said electrode base unit having a horizontally inclined wiring through hole in a body thereof; </claim-text>
<claim-text>u) an electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>v) an electrode contact component affixed to said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>w) a hollow base bushing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>x) said electrode base unit being anteriorly attached to a posterior portion of said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>y) an adapter nozzle posteriorly attached to said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>z) said base bushing unit being affixed at outer walling thereof to inner walling of said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>aa) said base bushing unit holding said adapter nozzle and in turn said electrode unit and in turn said electrode base unit within said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>bb) an adapter screw lock unit attachable about an anterior end of said electrode hub unit by way of affixation of said adapter screw lock unit at outer walling thereof to inner walling of said base bushing unit, and; </claim-text>
<claim-text>cc) said wiring traversing said length of said flexible tubing within said flexible tubing beginning from a locus of said resistor and coursing through said wiring through hole and terminating affixed to said electrode contact component. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The flexible charged powder particle application device of claim <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>., whereby, said wiring along said length of said wiring is circumscribed by insulating material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A Flexible Charged Powder Particle Application Device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a) electrode block extension unit splines located near an anterior end of said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a hollow block housing unit housing said electrode block unit and said electrode block extension unit with a through hole at an anterior end of said block housing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) means within said hollow block housing unit for affixation to said hollow block housing unit of an external power source to which a posterior side of said electrode block is connected via a contact ring unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) an electrode block extension unit affixed at a posterior end thereof to an anterior side of said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>e) an electrode block centerhole within said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>f) an electrode block extension centerhole within said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>g) an electrode block extension relief surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>h) electrode block extension unit splines located near an anterior end of said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>i) a hollow block housing unit housing said electrode block unit and said electrode block extension unit with a through hole at an anterior end of said block housing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>j) means within said hollow block housing unit for affixation to said hollow block housing unit of an external power source to which a posterior side of said electrode block is connected via a contact ring unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>k) flexible tubing with body and length affixed at a first end to said electrode block </claim-text>
<claim-text>l) an electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>m) electrode hub unit splines located near a posterior end of said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>n) said flexible tubing being affixed at a second end thereof to said electrode hub unit splines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>o) an electrode base unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>p) said electrode base unit having a horizontally inclined center through hole; </claim-text>
<claim-text>q) said electrode base unit having a horizontally inclined wiring through hole in a body thereof; </claim-text>
<claim-text>r) an electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>s) an electrode contact component affixed to said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>t) a hollow base bushing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>u) said electrode base unit being anteriorly attached to a posterior portion of said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>v) an adapter nozzle posteriorly attached to said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>w) said base bushing unit being affixed at outer walling thereof to inner walling of said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>x) said base bushing unit holding said adapter nozzle and in turn said electrode unit and in turn said electrode base unit within said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>y) an adapter screw lock unit attachable about an anterior end of said electrode hub unit by way of affixation of said adapter screw lock unit at outer walling thereof to inner walling of said base bushing unit, and; </claim-text>
<claim-text>z) said wiring traversing said length of said flexible tubing within said body of said flexible tubing beginning from a locus of said resistor and coursing through said wiring through hole and terminating affixed to said electrode contact component. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A Flexible Charged Powder Particle Application Device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a) a 15 meg resistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) wiring with length affixed to said resistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) an electrode block unit housing said resistor affixed therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) an electrode block extension unit affixed at a posterior end thereof to an anterior side of said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>e) an electrode block centerhole within said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>f) an electrode block extension centerhole within said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>g) an electrode block extension relief surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>h) a horizontally inclined first pinhole in a posterior portion of said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>i) a horizontally inclined second pinhole in an anterior side of said electrode block unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>j) a pin insertable into said first pinhole and into said second pinhole; </claim-text>
<claim-text>k) electrode block extension unit splines located near an anterior end of said electrode block extension unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>l) a hollow block housing unit housing said electrode block unit and said electrode block extension unit with a through hole at an anterior end of said block housing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>m) means within said hollow block housing unit for affixation to said hollow block housing unit of an external power source to which a posterior side of said electrode block is connected via a contact ring unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>n) flexible tubing with body and length affixed at a first end to said electrode block extension unit splines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>o) an electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>p) electrode hub unit splines located near a posterior end of said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>q) said flexible tubing being affixed at a second end thereof to said electrode hub unit splines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>r) an electrode base unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>s) said electrode base unit having a horizontally inclined center through hole; </claim-text>
<claim-text>t) said electrode base unit having a horizontally inclined wiring through hole in a body thereof; </claim-text>
<claim-text>u) an electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>v) an electrode contact component affixed to said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>w) a hollow base bushing unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>x) said electrode base unit being anteriorly attached to a posterior portion of said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>y) an adapter nozzle posteriorly attached to said electrode unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>z) said base bushing unit being affixed at outer walling thereof to inner walling of said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>aa) said base bushing unit holding said adapter nozzle and in turn said electrode unit and in turn said electrode base unit within said electrode hub unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>bb) an adapter screw lock unit attachable about an anterior end of said electrode hub unit by way of affixation of said adapter screw lock unit at outer walling thereof to inner walling of said base bushing unit, and; </claim-text>
<claim-text>cc) said wiring traversing said length of said flexible tubing within said body of said flexible tubing beginning from a locus of said resistor and coursing through said wiring through hole and terminating affixed to said electrode contact component.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001030A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
