<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000042A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000042A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000042A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000042A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000042A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000042A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000042A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000042A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000042A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000042A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000042A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000042A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000042</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10119265</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020409</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>01 2 29283.4</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>CN</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A47L009/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A47L005/24</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>344000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>369000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Eraser having selectively openable and closable aperatures</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yu</given-name>
<middle-name>Long</middle-name>
<family-name>Wang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country-code>CN</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Diane E. Burke</name-1>
<name-2>Mueller and Smith, LPA</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>7700 Rivers Edge Drive</address-1>
<city>Columbus</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>43235</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An apparatus and method for collecting dust is disclosed. Preferably, the dust to be collected is chalk dust. The apparatus includes a housing supporting an eraser head and having a cavity in fluid communication with a suction device. Interposed between the cavity and the suction device is a collection chamber assembly. A matrix of apertures in the front wall are selectively openable and closeable by a controller in response to the orientation of the eraser. When the eraser is moved across a chalkboard to create airborne chalk dust, the apertures are selectively opened by the controller, the suction device urging the airborne chalk dust through the apertures, through the cavity, and into the collection chamber assembly where it is filtered and stored. The method includes the steps of providing the apparatus of the invention, energizing the suction device, and moving the eraser across a chalkboard to collect chalk dust. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority based on Chinese Application No. 01 2 29283.4 filed Jun. 29, 2001, the disclosure of which is herein incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Not applicable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Many schools provide chalkboards and chalk for teachers to use as educational tools. The teachers write on the blackboards with the chalk and erase the writings with cotton head erasers, causing particles of chalk dust or powder to drift into the air. The floating chalk dust is harmful to health of the teachers and students. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> As an alternative to conventional erasers, teachers may use a wet cloth to clear the chalkboard in order to reduce the amount of chalk dust polluting the air. A consequent problem with this method is that the teacher must wait until the board is dry before writing on it again with chalk, which is inconvenient for both teachers and students. In recent years, new ideas in improving chalk to produce less chalk dust have come to light. While somewhat reducing chalk dust, such chalk usually provide lighter writing and make scratching noises when in contact with a chalkboard. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Attention also has been given to erasers with vacuum devices, including motor-driven fans, which act to more efficiently collect dust particles. While these devices represent an advance in the art, improvements to such devices continue to be sought. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to an eraser for collecting dust, i.e., chalk dust, released from a surface, i.e., a chalkboard. The eraser includes a housing having a front wall to which is attached an eraser head. Extending through the front wall are a matrix of apertures. A controller, consisting in part of a single panel or a series of panels, is provided to selectively open and close the apertures in response to the orientation of the eraser as it contacts the chalkboard. Within the housing is a cavity and a collection chamber assembly. Attached to the eraser housing is a selectively energizeable suction device. When the suction device is energized, the controller selectively opens and closes the apertures and airborne chalk dust is drawn through the open apertures through the cavity and into the collection chamber assembly. Inside the collection chamber assembly the air is filtered, the chalk dust remaining in the collection chamber of the assembly, while filtered air is exhausted by the suction device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Also disclosed is a method for collecting dust, i.e. chalk dust, released from a surface, i.e., chalkboard. The method includes the steps of providing an eraser such as described above, energizing the suction device, and moving the eraser across a chalkboard to collect chalk dust.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> For a fuller understanding of the nature and advantages of the present invention, reference should be had to the following detailed description taken in connection with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the eraser of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> spaced apart from a chalkboard; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view taken through the plane <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> showing the eraser in a horizontal orientation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view taken through the plane <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> showing the eraser in a horizontal orientation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view taken through the plane <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> showing the eraser in a vertical orientation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view taken through the plane <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> showing the eraser in a vertical orientation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view of an alternative embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> showing the eraser in a horizontal configuration; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> showing the eraser in a vertical orientation; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> showing the eraser at a 45&deg; angle.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Generally, as an eraser is moved across a chalkboard, chalk dust is released into the air, which is deleterious to the health of teachers and students. The present invention addresses the problem of effectively collecting that chalk dust. In operation, the user activates a motor and blower assembly located at the rear of the eraser to create a vacuum within the eraser housing, which causes air to flow from the front of the eraser rearward. Then, the user moves the eraser across a chalk board to release chalk dust into the air. Airborne chalk dust (e.g., particles) is drawn away from the chalk board and directed into the eraser. A controller selectively opens and closes a series or matrix of apertures located around the periphery of the eraser head in response to the orientation of the eraser as it confronts the chalkboard. Advantageously, the controller biases the flow of chalk dust and air mixture toward the apertures located at the bottom of the eraser. Airborne chalk dust passing through the apertures is drawn into a cavity within the eraser where it passes into a collection chamber assembly which filters the air. The chalk dust is retained in the collection chamber assembly for later removal, while the filtered air is directed rearwardly toward the back of the eraser and is expelled through vents in the blower assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an eraser incorporating the features of the invention is represented generally at <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a generally rectangular housing, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, having a front wall, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>), and a rearwall, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Extending between front wall <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and rear wall <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is sidewall <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Within housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, airborne chalk is filtered and stored. Housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> preferably is formed of plastic, which optionally may be reinforced. Alternatively, housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be formed of fiber board, fiber composite, ceramic, metal, etc. Any of the foregoing materials may be fiber reinforced or laminated in construction. As will be described in greater detail below, apertures through which airborne chalk dust enters the eraser are located in the front wall of the housing (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) which contacts the chalkboard. Contained within housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is a collection chamber assembly which filters air and stores collected chalk dust. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Connected to rear wall <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is a selectively energizeable suction device, shown generally at <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Suction device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> creates a vacuum within housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> which draws airborne chalk through the eraser. Preferably, suction device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes a circular blower assembly, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a motor, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and a power supply, i.e., two batteries as shown at <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Blower assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may include, for example, a squirrel cage blower (as shown) or an axial fan. In conventional fashion, blower assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of vents for exhausting air. Two such vents are shown at <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to the rear of blower assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A switch, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, located along the rear wall <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is provided for selectively energizing motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be a fractional horsepower DC (e.g., battery powered as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) or AC motor (e.g., line powered, not shown). When connected as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, blower assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> provide a convenient handle for the user to grasp eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. However, suction device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is not limited to this configuration and other configurations may be employed. Also, as an alternative to blower assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, suction device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may include a cyclone mechanism with an associated power supply. Cyclone mechanisms capable of use as a suction device are well known to those of ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the flow of air entraining chalk dust resulting from a user erasing a chalkboard. The chalkboard is shown at <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> with eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in close adjacency thereto. In actual use, eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> would be held flush against the chalkboard. However, for illustrative purposes eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown spaced apart from the chalkboard so that chalk dust can be seen being directed into the eraser. Moving eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> across chalkboard <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> releases chalk dust into the air, the airborne chalk dust being shown generally at <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Suction device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is energized to create a vacuum in housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and airborne chalk dust <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is drawn into cavity <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> through a matrix of apertures <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Airborne chalk dust <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> then passes into a collection chamber assembly at <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. In collection chamber assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> the air is filtered, the chalk dust remaining in the collection chamber for later removal while clean, filtered air passes through collection chamber <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and into blower assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The clean air then is exhausted from eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through vents <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a bottom view of eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including front wall <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Connected to front wall <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is an eraser head, shown generally at <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, which contacts the surface of the chalk board. Eraser head <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes a generally rectangular-shaped central portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as well as W-shaped portions <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Eraser head <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be formed of any conventional material, such as laminated felt, cellular latex, wool, cotton, etc., or a combination thereof. These types of materials are effective in releasing chalk dust and because each is of a porous nature, air and some airborne chalk dust will pass therethrough. Eraser head <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be removable for cleaning or in order to be replaced when it becomes worn out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> About the periphery of front wall <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are pairs of rectangular apertures, one pair being shown at <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, and another pair being shown at <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Positioned to selectively open and close these apertures, respectively, are pairs of panels shown in phantom at <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. When opened, the apertures permit airborne chalk dust to be drawn into housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> illustrate how the apertures are selectively opened and closed by a controller in response to the orientation of the eraser. FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> show an embodiment of the invention utilizing a weight system to control the apertures&apos; opening and closing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Looking to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> cross sectional view of eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is shown. In this view, it may be seen that motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to blower assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> by means of a shaft, <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. For cost, convenience, and safety reasons, all of the components of eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be contained within housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Because the eraser may be used by students as well as teachers, enclosing all of the components within the housing provides a beneficial safety feature. No rotatable equipment is exposed, which otherwise might be bent or broken, or cause injury to the user. To make eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> easier to use, a strap may be provided extending across the rearwall of housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, through which a user could insert his or her hand. Alternatively, as shown, housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may conform to the shape of suction device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, with the motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and blower assembly <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> being contained therein. This configuration provides a convenient handle for the user to grasp. By selecting a relatively small motor, the eraser handle may be easily grasped by small children. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Shown within housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is cavity <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Interposed between cavity <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and suction device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is a rectangular collection chamber assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. Collection chamber assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> includes a forward foramenous lid <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, which allows air entraining chalk dust to pass from cavity <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> into a collection chamber, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. At the rear of collection chamber <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is a rearward filter <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Filter <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> acts to filter chalk dust from the air. The porosity of filter <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is such that air passes through it while chalk dust remains retained on filter <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and in collection chamber <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. Collection chamber assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> may be removable so that chalk dust can be emptied from it. While collection chamber assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> having a rectangular shape that conforms to the dimensions of housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, collection chamber assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> may vary in both size and shape. For example, as shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, collection chamber <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> may be oval in shape. Collection chamber <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> also may be formed to accommodate other components contained within housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Located on either side of collection chamber <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> are batteries <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. These batteries are electrically connected to motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and constitute the power supply referred to in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Although batteries <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> are shown as conventional alkaline batteries, which may be replaced, <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> also may be Nickel-Cadmium or other rechargeable batteries. Power may be supplied to motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by any conventional means consistent with the invention. For example, instead of batteries, motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be selectively energizeable by line power for an a.c. motor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> weight system controls the opening and closing of the eraser&apos;s apertures. This weight system is indicated generally at <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and includes a lever arm weight, <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, which is pivotally connected at either end to two T-shaped rotatable members <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. Each of rotatable members <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> also is connected to a pivot support, <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, respectively. Pivot supports <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> in turn are connected to front wall <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and extend transversely to lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Finally, rotatable members <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> are connected to panels <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> by wires <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, respectively. Panel <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is seen to be pivotally connected to front wall <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at pivot assembly <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Similarly, panel <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is pivotally connected to front wall <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at pivot assembly <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Lever arm weigh <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> may be formed of material, such as metal, plastic, wood, etc. Lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> may be formed as a solid. Alternatively, lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> may be formed as a hollow tube which may contain movable weights, i.e., ball bearings, to provide level arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> with additional momentum as it moves in response to movement of eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Looking to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, weight system components that control panels <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are shown. Extending transversely to lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> are two oscillating components, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Oscillating components <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are connected to each other and to lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> by a wire, <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Oscillating component <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is connected to panel <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> by pivot assembly <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, while oscillating component <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is connected to panel <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> by pivot assembly <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown in a horizontal orientation. In this orientation, lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is in a central or resting position. When lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is located in this position, the panels open and close the apertures as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. Panels <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> are held in a partly open position as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, panels <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> partly cover apertures <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown in a vertical orientation. When eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is turned to a vertical orientation, lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> falls downward under the force of gravity as indicated by directional arrow <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. This motion of lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> pulls down on rotatable member <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> causing it to rotate in a clockwise direction about its connection to pivot support <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. This clockwise rotation pulls wire <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> inwardly closing panel <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Advantageously, such closure does not require an airtight seal. The downward motion of lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> also causes rotatable member <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> to rotate in a clockwise direction about its connection to pivot support <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, which slackens wire <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and further opens panel <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows the pivoting of panels <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. As lever arm weight <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> falls downward, wire <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is drawn downward placing force on oscillating components <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, which causes panels <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> to pivot about pivot points <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, respectively. Included as part of oscillating components <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are slots <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> for arc accommodation. Because wire <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is drawn downward, the tops of panels <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are pivoted inwardly to close the tops of apertures <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> as shown generally at <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The bottoms of panels <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are pivoted outwardly to open the bottoms of apertures <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, as shown generally at <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. It can be seen that in this orientation, weight system <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> opens and closes apertures <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to provide a configuration wherein the apertures are open toward the bottom of eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to admit airborne chalk dust and closed at the top such that chalk dust is not admitted. This orientation should be contrasted with the horizontal orientation, in which the apertures are selectively opened and closed such that airborne chalk dust is drawn into cavity <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> all about the periphery of front wall <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As can be seen from the above-description, the weight system controls the selective opening and closing of the apertures. This opening and closing includes the situation where the apertures are opened or closed and the situation where the apertures are only partially opened or partially closed. As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, panels <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are shown to pivot in order to open and close the respective apertures. The weight system also could be modified such that one or more of these panels slideably open and close the apertures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the eraser having a different controller is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. This second embodiment includes an elliptical-shaped housing having a greater number of small apertures located about its circumference. The controller of this embodiment consists of a single panel with a plurality or matrix of apertures, the alignment of these apertures acting to open and close the front wall apertures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Looking to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>, the eraser, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, has a generally elliptical shape. Eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes a housing, <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, with a front wall, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. In the center of front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is an eraser head, <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. Extending through front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and located about its circumference is a matrix of apertures indicated generally at <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. Two of these apertures are shown at <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As in the previously described embodiment, eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes a cavity, <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, and a collection chamber assembly, <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Collection chamber assembly <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> includes a foramenous lid, <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, a collection chamber, <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, and a rearward filter, <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. Connected to the rear of housing <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is a suction device, <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. Suction device <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> includes a blower assembly, <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, and a motor, <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Located behind front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is a controller, <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, which controls the opening and closing of the apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. Controller <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> consists of a single, thin, elliptical panel, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, whose major and minor axes are slightly smaller than those of front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. Controller <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is shown in phantom in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Controller <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes a matrix of apertures, <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, (shown in phantom in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) the apertures of which correspond in size and number to those of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. Two of these apertures are shown at <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>167</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. Panel <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is held in abutment against front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> by a retaining band, <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, projecting from the interior surface of housing <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> If the centers of front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and panel <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> were placed in registration, there would be correspondence between the apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and matrix <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> except that the apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> would be disposed inwardly of the apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. However, because the major and minor axes of panel <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> are slightly smaller than those of front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, as panel <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> moves in relation to front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, the apertures will be opened and closed in response to the orientation of eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> illustrate the selective opening and closing of the apertures in response to the orientation of eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> in a horizontal orientation. In this orientation, panel <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> falls under the force of gravity such that its bottom edge rests along the bottom edge of housing <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, as shown generally at <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. In this orientation, one aperture of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> aligns with one aperture of matrix <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, making that aperture, aperture <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, open. Other apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> are partially aligned with apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> causing them to be partially opened, e.g., <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. Finally, certain apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> are unaligned with apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> causing them to be closed, e.g., <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. As can be seen from this figure, the apertures of panel <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> become increasingly more in coincidence with the apertures of front wall <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> toward the bottom of eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to provide the advantageous biasing of airflow toward the bottom of eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> shows eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> in a vertical orientation. In this orientation, panel <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> falls to the bottom of housing <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> under the force of gravity to align the apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> with the apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> as shown. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows the alignment of the apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> with the apertures of matrix <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> when eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is tilted to a 45&deg; angle, i.e., an orientation between horizontal and vertical. As can be seen from FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, regardless of the orientation of eraser <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, apertures at the bottom of the eraser are opened to a greater degree than those at a higher position vertically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The embodiments shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 8</cross-reference> are of rectangular and elliptical configurations, respectively. However, it may easily be seen that other geometries may be utilized. Further, the number and size of apertures and panels also may vary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> While eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has been described above as being directed primarily to erasing chalk dust from a chalkboard, the present invention is not limited to this use. The eraser may be used on any surface having adherent material that, when removed or dislodged from the surface, forms airborne dust. For example, eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be used to collect dust from furniture or dust from a construction site. The design of eraser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is sufficiently flexible and adjustable that the eraser may be used effectively on horizontal and vertical surfaces. When used in a vertical orientation, however, the eraser is designed to accommodate the force of gravity acting on the airborne dust. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described with reference to a preferred embodiment, those skilled in the art will understand that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the scope of the invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from the essential scope thereof. Therefore, it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular embodiment disclosed as the best mode contemplated for carrying out this invention, but that the invention will include all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims. In this application all units are in the metric system and all amounts and percentages are by weight, unless otherwise expressly indicated. Also, all citations referred herein are expressly incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An eraser for collecting dust released from a surface by said eraser, comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) a housing having a front wall with an interior surface and an exterior surface and a back wall, said front and back walls being connected by a sidewall to define a cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) an eraser head located along a portion of said exterior surface of said front wall for releasing chalk dust from said surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a selectively energizable suction device in fluid communication with said cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a collection chamber assembly interposed between said cavity and said suction device for admitting airborne dust, filtering said dust from air, storing said dust, and expelling filtered air; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) a matrix of selectively openable and closable apertures extending through said front wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) a controller for controlling the opening and closing of said matrix of apertures in response to the orientation of said housing as it confronts said surface, </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby when said eraser is moved across said surface to create airborne dust, said aperture openings are selectively opened by said controller and said suction device urges said airborne dust through said matrix of apertures, through said cavity, and into said collection chamber assembly. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said surface is a horizontal surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said surface is a vertical surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said vertical surface is a chalkboard and said dust is chalk dust. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including one or more panels controlled by said controller, which one or more of slidably open and close or pivotally open and close said apertures of said matrix. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said matrix of apertures includes a first set of apertures and a second set of apertures, said first set of apertures being located at a lower position than said second set of apertures and being preferentially closed to a greater extent than said second set of apertures when said eraser is in a vertical orientation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said housing is formed of plastic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said eraser head has a given size selected to maximize the amount of chalk erased from a chalkboard. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said suction device comprises: 
<claim-text>a selectively energizable motor connected to said cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a power supply connected to said motor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a blower connected to said motor to create a vacuum when said motor is energized. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said suction device comprises: 
<claim-text>a selectively energizable cyclone mechanism connected to said cavity; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a power supply connected to said cyclone mechanism. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method for collecting dust released from a surface, which comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>(a) providing an eraser including, 
<claim-text>(1) a housing having a front wall with an interior surface and an exterior surface and a back wall, said front and back walls being connected by a sidewall to define a cavity, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(2) an eraser head located along a portion of said exterior surface of said front wall for releasing dust from a surface, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(4) a selectively energizable suction device in fluid communication with said cavity, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(3) a collection chamber assembly interposed between said cavity and said suction device for admitting airborne dust, filtering said dust from air, storing said dust, and expelling filtered air, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(4) a matrix of selectively openable and closable apertures extending through said front wall, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(5) a controller for controlling the opening and closing of said matrix of apertures in response to the orientation of said housing as it confronts said surface; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) energizing said suction device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) moving said eraser across said surface to release said dust therefrom, so that said suction device urges said dust through said matrix of apertures, through said cavity, and into said collection chamber assembly. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said surface said eraser is moved across is a chalkboard and said dust released is chalk dust. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said eraser is provided further including one or more panels controlled by said controller, which one or more of slidably open and close or pivotally open and close said apertures of said matrix. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said eraser is provided with said matrix of apertures including a first set of apertures and a second set of apertures, said first set of apertures being located at a lower position than said second set of apertures and being preferentially closed to a greater extent than said second set of apertures when said eraser is in a vertical orientation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said eraser is provided with said suction device comprising: 
<claim-text>a selectively energizable motor connected to said cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a power supply connected to said motor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a blower connected to said motor to create a vacuum when said motor is energized. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An eraser for collecting chalk dust, comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) a housing having a front wall with an exterior surface and a back wall, said front and back walls being connected by a sidewall to define an cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) an eraser head located along a portion of said exterior surface of said front wall for erasing chalk from a chalkboard; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a selectively energizable suction device in fluid communication with said cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a collection chamber assembly interposed between said cavity and said suction device for admitting airborne chalk dust, filtering said chalk dust from air, storing said chalk dust, and expelling filtered air; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) a first set of apertures and a second set of apertures, each aperture of said first and second sets extending through said front wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) a first set of panels and a second set of panels, each mechanically connected to a weight system for selectively opening and closing said first and second sets of apertures, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said suction device comprises: 
<claim-text>a selectively energizable motor connected to said cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a power supply located within said cavity and electrically connected to said motor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a blower located within said cavity and connected to said motor to create a vacuum when said motor is energized. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said back wall of said housing conforms to the shape of said motor and said blower to provide a hand graspable portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>said first set of panels includes a first panel and a second panel; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said weight system comprises, 
<claim-text>a lever arm weight extending between a first end and a second end, said lever arm weight being freely movable such that it falls downward under the force of gravity when said housing is in a vertical orientation, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a weight support located between said first and second ends for supporting said lever arm weight, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pivot support and a second pivot support, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first rotatable member connected to said first end of said lever arm weight, said first pivot support, and said first panel, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second rotatable member connected to said second end of said lever arm weight, said second pivot support, and said second panel </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby when said lever arm weight falls under the force of gravity, said first rotatable member rotates about said first pivot support to close said first panel and said second rotatable member rotates about said second pivot support to open said second panel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The eraser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>said second set of panels includes a third panel and a fourth panel; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said weight support extends transversely with respect to said lever arm weight and has a first segment and a second segment, said first and second segments being pivotally connected to said third and fourth panels at first and second pivot points, respectively, such that when said lever arm weight falls downward under the force of gravity, said third and fourth panels pivot about </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first and second pivot points to partially open said second set of apertures.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000042A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000042A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000042A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000042A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000042A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000042A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
