<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002889A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002889A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002889A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002889A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002889A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002889A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002889A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002889A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002889A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002889A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002889A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002889A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002889</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10183404</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-198053</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03G015/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>399</class>
<subclass>211000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Image-reading device having a contact prevention member preventing a lamp harness from contacting other elements</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Masashi</given-name>
<family-name>Kohchi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>OBLON SPIVAK MCCLELLAND MAIER &amp; NEUSTADT PC</name-1>
<name-2>FOURTH FLOOR</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1755 JEFFERSON DAVIS HIGHWAY</address-1>
<city>ARLINGTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22202</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An image-reading device exposes and scans an image of a subject copy by reciprocating a first traveler including an exposure lamp and a mirror, and a second traveler including two mirrors, along a sub scanning direction at a velocity ratio of 2:1. The image-reading device comprises a harness, a flexible cable, and a contact prevention member. The harness supplies power to the exposure lamp. The flexible cable has one end connected to the harness and the other end connected to a power source. The contact prevention member is provided on the first traveler so as to prevent the harness from contacting the second traveler and the mirrors included in the second traveler. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to an image-reading device, an image-forming device, and a copying machine, and more particularly, to an image-reading device which exposes and scans an image of a subject copy by moving two travelers including an exposure lamp and mirrors at different velocities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, there has been an image-reading device that exposes and scans an image of a subject copy placed on a contact glass by causing a stepping motor to drive a first traveler including an exposure lamp and a mirror, and a second traveler including two mirrors, along a sub (slow) scanning direction at a velocity ratio of 2:1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Generally, in the image-reading device that causes the stepping motor to drive the first traveler and the second traveler, a driving velocity of the stepping motor is controlled to change gradually, because of structural requirements. Additionally, another type of image-reading device causing the stepping motor to drive the first traveler and the second traveler reads an image of a subject copy within a range where the driving velocity of the stepping motor is constant, because of an easier control required therefor and a quality of the read image achieved therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Such an image-reading device as mentioned above requires a dimension in the sub scanning direction to be equal to or larger than a total dimension of a dimension in the sub scanning direction of an image of a subject copy and a dimension in the sub scanning direction required for a run-up and a slowdown of the first traveler and the second traveler. In other words, the dimension of the image-reading device in the sub scanning direction can be theoretically decreased to equal the above-mentioned total dimension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Additionally, for the purpose of miniaturization, there is still another image-reading device in which the first traveler and the second traveler are arranged close to each other in the course of traveling, or are arranged close to each other by being overlapped at a home position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> By the way, the above-mentioned exposure lamp is provided with a lamp harness used for supplying power to the exposure lamp. This lamp harness is connected to one end of a flexible cable the other end of which is connected to a power source. In some image-reading devices, this flexible cable is drawn around a travel-back side of the second traveler (i.e., a side toward which the second traveler travels back), because it becomes easy to assemble the image-reading device, or it becomes easy to draw around the flexible cable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> For the purpose of miniaturizing the image-reading device, it is preferred that the flexible cable be drawn around the travel-back side of the second traveler as closely as possible. However, when the flexible cable is positioned close directly to the second traveler, the flexible cable contacts the mirrors and other elements mounted on the second traveler. Moving the first traveler and the second traveler back and forth repeatedly with the flexible cable contacting the mirrors and other elements mounted on the second traveler may possibly cause the flexible cable and the mirrors to rub on each other so that a friction thereof damages the flexible cable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> To prevent this damage, a conventional image-reading device comprises a cable guide mounted on the second traveler such that a guide surface guiding the flexible cable is positioned between the mirrors and the flexible cable. This arrangement prevents the flexible cable and the mirrors from rubbing on each other, and thus prevents the flexible cable from being damaged therefrom. The cable guide is provided with guide ribs raised from both sides of the guide surface past the flexible cable. These guide ribs position the flexible cable on the guide surface, and prevent the flexible cable from shifting with respect to the guide surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> By the way, in some cases, the lamp harness is connected to the flexible cable in a state where the lamp harness is deformed toward the second traveler due to a varying precision in assembling the image-reading device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In the above-described image-reading device including the first traveler and the second traveler arranged close to each other for the purpose of miniaturization, when the first traveler and the second traveler are moved back and forth in the above-mentioned state where the lamp harness is deformed toward the second traveler, the lamp harness is more likely to contact the second traveler or the mirrors mounted on the second traveler. Since the first traveler and the second traveler are reciprocated at different velocities, moving the first traveler and the second traveler back and forth repeatedly may cause the lamp harness to be rubbed by the second traveler or the mirrors mounted on the second traveler, which may result in a fatigue breakage of the lamp harness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Also, in the above-described image-reading device comprising the cable guide, the guide ribs are raised from both sides of the guide surface past the flexible cable. Therefore, when the first traveler and the second traveler are arranged close to each other for the purpose of miniaturization, the lamp harness deformed toward the second traveler is more likely to contact the guide ribs. Moving the first traveler and the second traveler back and forth repeatedly with the lamp harness contacting the guide ribs may result in a fatigue breakage of the lamp harness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The fatigue breakage of the lamp harness results in a heteropolar leak involving a voltage difference between the damaged lamp harness and the flexible cable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> As a conceivable countermeasure thereagainst, the assembly of the image-reading device may be performed so that the lamp harness be provided at a prescribed position in consideration of various factors, such as a particular tendency of the lamp harness for bending. However, assembling the image-reading device in consideration of the various bending tendency of the lamp harness takes time so as to reduce a productivity of the assembly, which does not suit a mass production of the image-reading device. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It is a general object of the present invention to provide an improved and useful image-reading device and a copying machine in which the above-mentioned problems are eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A more specific object of the present invention is to provide an image-reading device, and a copying machine using the image-reading device which can be miniaturized by having a first traveler and a second traveler arranged close to each other without damaging a harness, regardless of a varying precision in an assembly thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve the above-mentioned objects, there is provided according to one aspect of the present invention an image-reading device exposing and scanning an image of a subject copy by reciprocating a first traveler including an exposure lamp and a mirror, and a second traveler including two mirrors, along a sub scanning direction at a velocity ratio of 2:1, the image-reading device comprising a harness supplying power to the exposure lamp, a flexible cable having one end connected to the harness and the other end connected to a power source, and a contact prevention member provided on the first traveler so as to prevent the harness from contacting the second traveler and the mirrors included in the second traveler. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the contact prevention member prevents the harness from contacting the second traveler and the mirrors included in the second traveler. Accordingly, for example, when the first traveler and the second traveler are arranged close to each other for the purpose of miniaturizing the image-reading device, the harness can be prevented from rubbing on the second traveler and the mirrors included in the second traveler and thus from being damaged thereby which would otherwise occur due to a difference between the velocities of the first traveler and the second traveler traveling back and forth. In addition, since the contact prevention member is provided on the first traveler, the contact prevention member moves together with the harness in the course of exposing and scanning an image of a subject copy. Thereby, the harness and the contact prevention member can be prevented from rubbing on each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the image-reading device according to the present invention may further comprise a cable guide provided on the second traveler so as to guide the flexible cable to a side toward which the second traveler travels back, wherein the contact prevention member prevents the harness from contacting the cable guide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the contact prevention member prevents the harness from contacting the cable guide. Accordingly, when the cable guide is provided on the second traveler so as to draw the flexible cable closely around the second traveler, the harness can be prevented from rubbing on the cable guide and thus from being damaged thereby which would otherwise occur due to the difference between the velocities of the first traveler and the second traveler traveling back and forth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the image-reading device according to the present invention may further comprise a plate-form reinforcing member bonded to the flexible cable so that the harness and the flexible cable are connected to each other with the reinforcing member therebetween, wherein the contact prevention member is a plate-form member formed unitarily with the reinforcing member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> At this point, upon soldering wires, a reinforcing plate, for example, may sometimes be used to flatten a part at which the wires are connected, and to flatten a periphery thereof. Thus, when the harness and the flexible cable are connected by soldering, the plate-form reinforcing member according to the present invention becomes necessary for flattening a part at which the harness and the flexible cable are connected, and for flattening a periphery thereof. Additionally, the contact prevention member is provided as a plate-form member formed unitarily with the plate-form reinforcing member so as to reduce the number of elements composing the image-reading device and to decrease the number of steps required for assembling the image-reading device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the image-reading device according to the present invention may further comprise a first connector provided at an end of the harness, and a second connector provided at the one end of the flexible cable so that the first connector is detachably inserted into the second connector, wherein the first connector can be inserted into and detached from the second connector at a side of the second connector opposite the one end of the flexible cable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the harness and the flexible cable are led out in an identical direction from a position at which the first connector is inserted into the second connector. Therefore, when the above-mentioned one end of the flexible cable is positioned nearer to the exposure lamp, connecting the harness to the flexible cable by inserting the first connector into the second connector enables the flexible cable to be drawn from the position nearer to the exposure lamp around the second traveler. Accordingly, the first traveler and the second traveler can be arranged closer to each other so as to further miniaturize the image-reading device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Additionally, in the image-reading device according to the present invention, at least a part of the harness may be fixed to the contact prevention member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the harness can be positioned at a periphery of the contact prevention member. Thereby, the harness can be prevented from departing from the contact prevention member into a friction against neighboring elements; thus, the harness can be prevented from being damaged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the image-reading device according to the present invention may further comprise a restricting member provided on a surface of the contact prevention member opposite the flexible cable so as to restrict the harness on the surface of the contact prevention member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the harness is restricted to the contact prevention member by the restricting member such that the harness is positioned opposite the flexible cable with the contact prevention member therebetween. Thereby, the harness and the flexible cable can be surely prevented from contacting each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve the above-mentioned objects, there is also provided according to another aspect of the present invention a copying machine comprising the above-mentioned image-reading device, and an image-forming device forming the image of the subject copy read by the image-reading device on a sheet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the copying machine can provide the same advantages as the above-mentioned image-reading device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Other objects, features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view of a main structure of an image scanner according to a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a magnified perspective view in the vicinity of a first traveler shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view in the vicinity of the first traveler shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view in the vicinity of the first traveler shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a top view of a cable unit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the cable unit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view in the vicinity of the first traveler according to a variation of the present embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a magnified perspective view in the vicinity of the first traveler according to a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view in the vicinity of the first traveler shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view of a copying machine according to a third embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A description will now be given, with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>B, of a first embodiment according to the present invention. The present embodiment is an example of applying the present invention to an image scanner of a flatbed type as an image-reading device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view of a main structure of an image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> according to the present first embodiment. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> contact glass <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is provided on an upper surface of a scanner housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A subject copy is to be placed on the contact glass <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Also as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an exposure optical system <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is provided in the scanner housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The exposure optical system <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> comprises a first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, a second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, a lens <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and a photoreceptive sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are mounted on the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Two mirrors <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are mounted on the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Each of the exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the mirrors <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is arranged longitudinally in a main (fast) scanning direction. The photoreceptive sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is mounted on a sensor board <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> An end of a flexible printed circuit board (hereinafter referred to as FPC) <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is connected to the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> functions as a flexible cable having a long form consisting of two conductive cables and an insulating film coating an outer periphery of the two conductive cables. A lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is connected via a connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to the above-mentioned end of the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> connected to the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> functions as a harness used for supplying power to the exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is held by a connector holder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> provided on the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Flexibly transformable hooks <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) are formed unitarily on the connector holder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The connector holder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is supported by a supporter <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> mounted on the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> by the hooks <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being locked into respective holes <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) formed in the supporter <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is drawn around a travel-back side of the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> (at the left side of the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), and the other end of the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> opposite the connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is connected to an inverter <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> provided as a power source on a bottom surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the scanner housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> An FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is provided as a cable guide at a part of the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> around which the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is drawn. The FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is provided so as to guide the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to a predetermined path. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> comprises a guide surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and guide ribs <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The guide surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is so curved as to cover the mirrors <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The guide ribs <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are provided at both ends of the guide surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the main scanning direction such that the guide ribs <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are raised from the guide surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>past the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Thereby, the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be prevented from shifting in the main scanning direction with respect to the guide surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> A more detailed description will be given, with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, mainly of the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a magnified perspective view in the vicinity of the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view thereof. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view in the vicinity of the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is held at both ends by a pair of lamp holders <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> provided on the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A notched portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is formed in one of the lamp holders <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> so that the notched portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> guides the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of the exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A convex-form connector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is provided as a first connector at an end of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> guided out from the notched portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> A concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is provided as a second connector on the connector holder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> mounted on the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> with the supporter <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> therebetween. The convex-form connector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is inserted into the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is connected to the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> at a travel-forth side opposite the above-mentioned travel-back side (i.e., at the right side of the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) by soldering. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The convex-form connector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can be inserted into and detached from the travel-back side of the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> (at the left side of the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). Accordingly, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is led out from the convex-form connector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the same direction as the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is led out from the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> at the above-mentioned travel-back side of the connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (at the left side of the connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). The lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are led out in the same direction with respect to the connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> so that an end surface of the connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at the travel-forth side (i.e., at the right side of the connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) can be positioned nearer to the exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B, a</cross-reference> flat reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is bonded to the end of the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> with an adhesive <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is bonded to the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> with the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> therebetween. The reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is provided so that the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is bonded to the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> on a flat surface. Thereby, the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be connected to the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> favorably by soldering. The adhesive <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is applied to a minimum range necessary for the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to be bonded to the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be bent without being unnecessarily restricted by the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Thus, the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be bent at a position nearer to the exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In addition, a coating of resin P is applied, for example by a hot-melt process, to a connection part at which the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is connected to the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> by soldering. The coating of resin P is applied so as to prevent electricity from leaking from the connection part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> A harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> having a flat-plate form is provided as a contact prevention member so that the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> extends horizontally from the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> toward the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> along a sub (slow) scanning direction. In the present embodiment, the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are formed unitarily of a single plate material. Although the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are formed unitarily, the adhesive <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is applied only to a part corresponding to the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Accordingly, even when the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are formed unitarily, the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is bonded with the part corresponding to the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In addition, mounting grip pieces <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are provided at both ends of the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> in the main scanning direction. In the present embodiment, the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the mounting grip pieces <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are formed unitarily of a single plate material. The concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the mounting grip pieces <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> compose a cable unit <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Slits <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are formed in the connector holder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Each of the slits <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a width equivalent to a thickness of the mounting grip piece <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The slit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is elastically transformable due to an elasticity of a material forming the connector holder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> so that the slit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> opens wide. A projection <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is provided at an entrance to each of the slits <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The projection <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is so projected as to block the entrance to each of the slits <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Upon mounting the above-mentioned cable unit <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, each of the slits <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is elastically transformed so that the slit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> opens wide. Then, each of the mounting grip pieces <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is inserted into the opened slit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. After the insertion of the mounting grip piece <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, the slit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> returns to a closing state by the elasticity thereof. Thus, the cable unit <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> can be mounted with ease. Additionally, each of the mounting grip pieces <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is prevented from jouncing in the slit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by the projection <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> provided at the entrance to the slit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the cable unit <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> can be surely fixed at a mounting position. The convex-form connector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is inserted into the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in the state where the cable unit <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is fixed to the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. This enables the exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to be supplied with power. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As described above, the end of the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is bonded to the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> with the adhesive <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Therefore, in the state where the cable unit <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is fixed to the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> bends downward from a boundary part between a part at which the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is bonded to the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and a part at which the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is not bonded to the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is guided toward a backside of a reflective surface of each of the two mirrors <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> mounted on the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Additionally, in the FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> according to the present embodiment, a part of one of the guide ribs <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>located outside in the main scanning direction which overlaps the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in terms of a vertical position is exsected so that the guide rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a part in the same plane as an upper part of the guide surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Upon reading an image of a subject copy, the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> structured as above exposes and scans the image of the subject copy by moving the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> along the sub scanning direction at a velocity ratio of 2:1, and lighting the exposure lamp <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> while the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> travel at respective constant velocities. A light reflected from the image of the subject copy is converged as an incident light into the photoreceptive sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via the mirrors <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the lens <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The photoreceptive sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> converts the incident light photoelectrically so as to output an image signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Supposedly in a conventional image scanner, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> would be connected to the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in a state where the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is deformed toward the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> due to a varying precision in assembling the image scanner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> In the image scanner including the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> arranged close to each other for the purpose of miniaturization, when the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are moved back and forth in the above-mentioned state where the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is deformed toward the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> would contact the guide ribs <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and other elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> At this point, since the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are reciprocated at different velocities, moving the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> back and forth repeatedly would cause the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to undergo a fatigue breakage due to a friction between the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and the guide ribs <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The fatigue breakage of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> would result in a heteropolar leak involving a voltage difference between the damaged lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> As a countermeasure thereagainst, the assembly of the image scanner might be performed so that the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> would be provided at a prescribed position in consideration of various factors, such as a particular tendency of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for bending. Actually, however, assembling the image scanner in consideration of the various bending tendency of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> would take time so as to reduce a productivity of the assembly, which would not suit a mass production of the image scanner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> prevents the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> from contacting the FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Thereby, even when the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged close to each other for the purpose of miniaturizing the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be prevented from being damaged due to frictions against the FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> caused by a difference between the velocities of the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> traveling back and forth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> At this point, since the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is provided on the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> moves together with the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> when the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> travel back and forth. Accordingly, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be prevented from rubbing on the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and thus can be prevented from being damaged therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> According to the present embodiment, not only the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be further miniaturized by drawing the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> closely around the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, but also the heteropolar leak involving a voltage difference between the damaged lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be prevented from occurring due to a damage of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, regardless of a varying precision in assembling the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Thus, upon assembling the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, an assembler can assemble the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> without paying particular attention to various factors, such as a bending tendency, of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be assembled more effectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Additionally, in the present embodiment, since a part of one of the guide ribs <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is exsected so that the guide rib <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a part in the same plane as the upper part of the guide surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be more effectively prevented from being damaged due to a friction against the FPC guide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Besides, although the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is connected to the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by the insertion of the convex-form connector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> into the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> at the connector unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in the present embodiment, the present invention is not limited thereto. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be connected to the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> directly by soldering, with only the reinforcing plate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> including the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> therebetween. This miniaturizes the connection part at which the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is connected to the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Further, in the present embodiment, the convex-form connector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is provided at the end of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and the concave-form connector <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is provided at the end of the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>; however, the present invention is not limited thereto. A concave-form connector may be provided at the end of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and a convex-form connector may be provided at the end of the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Next, a description will be given, with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, of a second embodiment according to the present invention. Elements in the present second embodiment that are identical or equivalent to the elements described in the foregoing first embodiment are referenced by the same reference marks, and will not be described in detail. The same applies to the herein-later described embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a magnified perspective view in the vicinity of the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> according to the present second embodiment. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view thereof. In the present embodiment, a harness restriction unit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is provided on an upper surface of the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A pair of restricting hooks <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> bending inward respectively are formed as restricting members on the harness restriction unit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is fixed at a position on the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> by an extra-length portion thereof being restricted by the harness restriction unit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Thereby, at least a part of the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is fixed to the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so that the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is positioned at a periphery of the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be prevented from departing from the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> into a friction against neighboring elements; thus, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be prevented from being damaged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Especially, in the present embodiment, the restricting members <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the harness restriction unit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> are provided on the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> opposite the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is restricted to the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> by the restricting members <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Thus, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is positioned opposite the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> with the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the above-described simple structure can surely prevent the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and the FPC <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> from contacting each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Additionally, in the course of the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> traveling back and forth, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be surely prevented from jouncing on the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Thus, even when the first traveler <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the second traveler <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> travel back and forth, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be positioned constantly on the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Besides, although the harness restriction unit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> having the restricting hooks <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is provided on the upper surface of the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in the present embodiment, the present invention is not limited thereto. For example, the restricting hooks <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may be provided directly on the upper surface of the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Further, the lamp harness <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be fixed directly on the upper surface of the harness guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> by using an adhesive and so forth. Accordingly, the number of elements composing the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is reduced so that the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be assembled more easily. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Next, a description will be given, with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, of a third embodiment according to the present invention. The present embodiment is an example of applying the present invention to a copying machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a vertical-sectional side view of a copying machine <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> according to the present third embodiment. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the copying machine <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> comprises the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> described in the foregoing embodiments, and a printer device <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> as an image-forming device provided under the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In the printer device <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is formed a sheet conveyance path <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The sheet conveyance path <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> starts from a feeding tray <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> on which sheets are stacked, via a printer unit <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> adopting an electrophotographic method, via a fixing unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and to a delivery stacker <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. A photosensitive member <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> is provided at a substantially central part of the printer unit <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. Around the photosensitive member <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> are arranged an electrifying unit <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, an exposing unit <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight>, a developing unit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, a transferring unit <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, and other components. The electrifying unit <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> electrifies a surface of the photosensitive member <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> uniformly. The exposing unit <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> exposes an image of a subject copy read by the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> so as to form a latent image on the surface of the photosensitive member <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. The developing unit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> develops the latent image by applying toners thereto. The transferring unit <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> transfers the developed image to a sheet conveyed along the sheet conveyance path <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In the copying machine <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> structured as above, the image of the subject copy read by the image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is formed by the printer unit <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> on the sheet conveyed along the sheet conveyance path <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> according to a synchronized timing, and then is fixed by the fixing unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, the copying machine <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> uses the miniaturized image scanner <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> so as to function highly conveniently for a user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Besides, although the printer unit <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> adopts an electrophotographic method in the present embodiment, the present invention is not limited thereto. For example, the present invention may be applied to an inkjet printer using jets of ink. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> The present invention is not limited to the specifically disclosed embodiments, and variations and modifications may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The present application is based on Japanese priority application No. 2001-198053 filed on Jun. 29, 2001, the entire contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An image-reading device exposing and scanning an image of a subject copy by reciprocating a first traveler including an exposure lamp and a mirror, and a second traveler including two mirrors, along a sub scanning direction at a velocity ratio of 2:1, the image-reading device comprising: 
<claim-text>a harness supplying power to said exposure lamp; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible cable having one end connected to said harness and the other end connected to a power source; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a contact prevention member provided on said first traveler so as to prevent said harness from contacting said second traveler and said mirrors included in said second traveler. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a cable guide provided on said second traveler so as to guide said flexible cable to a side toward which said second traveler travels back, 
<claim-text>wherein said contact prevention member prevents said harness from contacting said cable guide. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a plate-form reinforcing member bonded to said flexible cable so that said harness and said flexible cable are connected to each other with said reinforcing member therebetween, 
<claim-text>wherein said contact prevention member is a plate-form member formed unitarily with said reinforcing member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a plate-form reinforcing member bonded to said flexible cable so that said harness and said flexible cable are connected to each other with said reinforcing member therebetween, 
<claim-text>wherein said contact prevention member is a plate-form member formed unitarily with said reinforcing member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a first connector provided at an end of said harness; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connector provided at said one end of said flexible cable so that said first connector is detachably inserted into said second connector, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first connector can be inserted into and detached from said second connector at a side of said second connector opposite said one end of said flexible cable. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a first connector provided at an end of said harness; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connector provided at said one end of said flexible cable so that said first connector is detachably inserted into said second connector, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first connector can be inserted into and detached from said second connector at a side of said second connector opposite said one end of said flexible cable. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a part of said harness is fixed to said contact prevention member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a part of said harness is fixed to said contact prevention member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a restricting member provided on a surface of said contact prevention member opposite said flexible cable so as to restrict said harness on said surface of said contact prevention member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The image-reading device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a restricting member provided on a surface of said contact prevention member opposite said flexible cable so as to restrict said harness on said surface of said contact prevention member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A copying machine comprising: 
<claim-text>an image-reading device exposing and scanning an image of a subject copy by reciprocating a first traveler including an exposure lamp and a mirror and a second traveler including two mirrors along a sub scanning direction at a velocity ratio of 2:1 so as to read said image of said subject copy, the image-reading device including a harness supplying power to said exposure lamp, a flexible cable having one end connected to said harness and the other end connected to a power source, and a contact prevention member provided on said first traveler so as to prevent said harness from contacting said second traveler and said mirrors included in said second traveler; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an image-forming device forming said image of said subject copy read by said image-reading device on a sheet. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The copying machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said image-reading device further includes a cable guide provided on said second traveler so as to guide said flexible cable to a side toward which said second traveler travels back, 
<claim-text>wherein said contact prevention member prevents said harness from contacting said cable guide.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002889A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002889A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002889A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002889A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002889A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002889A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
