<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001015A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001015A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001015A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001015A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001015A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001015A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001015</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895190</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06K007/10</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>235</class>
<subclass>458000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>235</class>
<subclass>489000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Voting device with immediate feedback</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>William</given-name>
<middle-name>Spence</middle-name>
<family-name>Rouverol</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Berkeley</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>William S. Rouverol</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1331 Arch St.</address-1>
<city>Berkeley</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94708</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">All data registering devices, including voting machines, are subject to error, either from human lapses or mechanical malfunction. The object of the present invention is to disclose a device that incorporates features that immediately alert the user to the fact that an error has occurred, before it is too late or too inconvenient for the user to correct it. In voting devices that produce a machine-processable record card, such as the Votomatic and the Poll Star, votes are counted photo-electrically by shining a light through holes punched in the ballot card. According to the present invention, the greatest certainty regarding what punch-outs represent a valid vote can be obtained only if the same principle is employed to inform the voter as to whether his punch-out is or is not in the intended position and is a complete punch-out. To provide the voter with this verification, backlighting is introduced that directs a beam of light upward through each punch-out toward the voter&apos;s eye. To achieve the optimum results, which demand that the frequency of faulty ballots be less than about one percent the special backlighting features employed are combined with mechanical improvements that minimize defective punch-outs. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to devices for the manual registering of data on machine-processable record cards. More particularly it relates to punch-card voting devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The principal prior art resides in the basic patents concerning the &ldquo;Votomatic&rdquo; voting device, relative to which the invention discloses improvements intended to increase the accuracy of that voting system. The basic patents on the Votomatic are U.S. Pat. Nos. 3,201,038 and 3,240,409. A U.S. patent referred to in the latter is No. 3,007,620. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> All data registering devices, including voting machines, are subject to error, either from human lapses or mechanical malfunction. The object of the present invention is to disclose a device that incorporates features that immediately alert the user to the fact that an error has occurred, before it is too late or too inconvenient for the user to correct it. In voting devices that operate on a machine-processable record card, such as the Votomatic and the Poll Star, votes are counted photo-electrically by shining a light through holes punched in the ballot card. According to the present invention, the greatest certainty regarding what punch-outs represent a valid vote can be obtained only if the same principle is employed to inform the voter as to whether his punch-out is or is not in the intended position and is a complete punch-out. To provide the voter with this verification, backlighting is introduced that directs a beam of light upward through each punch-out toward the voter&apos;s eye. To achieve the optimum results, which demand that the frequency of faulty ballots be less than about one percent, the special backlighting features employed are combined with mechanical improvements that minimize defective punch-outs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Backlighting had previously been considered and rejected because it was in conflict with the disposal of the chads. As more and more chads were accumulated underneath the punching surface, they would blanket the light source, reducing or eventually eliminating the illumination and possibly even creating a fire hazard if the light was hot enough. The solution to this problem, which is a main feature of the invention, was to divide the illumination into two parts, one well to the right of the region where the punched out chads fall vertically by gravity, and one well to the left of the region. The two light sources are directed to throw their light at opposite angles toward the underside of the punch card, and this combined effect is a bright vertical beam that tells the voter he/she has (or has not) made a clear punch-out directly adjacent to the right (or wrong) candidate&apos;s name. Obtaining this feedback information enables the voter to make immediate correction on his/her original ballot or, for more serious errors, to obtain a fresh ballot card from the precinct attendant. Every form of errant card punch can be quickly identified with this punch-out backlighting. The only person who can make this correction without a breach of ballot secrecy is the voter, and he/she has full opportunity to make the necessary repair, regardless of whether it is a &ldquo;dimpled&rdquo; chad, a hanging chad, undervoting, overvoting, or a misplaced vote. Even the notorious &ldquo;butterfly ballot&rdquo; which has been shown to confuse and disqualify thousands of voters would not be a problem. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> When the above-described voter-activated backlighting system for the exposure and correction of ballot errors is combined with some very advantageous improvements in mechanical features, punch-card voting should become more reliable and accurate than any electronic voting system currently available, including optical scanning and touch-screen, as well as costing only a fraction as much to install and operate. Hopefully the improvements disclosed will reduce the observed undervoting or defective voting on punch-card voting devices from its present 1 to 4% to perhaps as low as &frac13; to {fraction (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>)}%. This level of accuracy is better than that of any competing device and should make a manual recount seldom if ever needed. It is not conceivable that the improvement described herein can achieve what should be the goal of all voting machines: zero disenfranchisement.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a voting device embodying the invention. It is analogous to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> of U.S. Pat. No. 3,240,409, which shows in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> the position and direction of sight of the sectional cut. The view indicates how a Votomatic could be modified to provide backlighting that illuminates the underside of the punch card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a broken-out plan view indicating one method of introducing a limit switch that energizes the lighting circuit when the punch card is properly inserted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a wiring diagram for the embodiment that uses a single electric light bulb. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a wiring diagram for the embodiment that specifies two electrical light bulbs in parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an enlarged diagram showing how the stylus may bind up in the inner template hole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an enlarged diagram showing a modification to the stylus probe that prevents it from binding in the inner template apertures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a voter instruction sheet adapted to reduce the frequency of voter errors that lead to overvotes, undervotes, or incomplete chad removal.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Because the invention consists of a set of improvements to the punch-card devices covered by the above-listed prior art patents, the descriptions below will concentrate insofar as possible on the new features introduced, showing only as much of the prior art structures as is needed to support the applicant&apos;s claims. A full explanation of how the Votomatic voting device operates is provided in U.S. Pat. No. 3,240,409, so it will not be reiterated in this specification. The fact that assigned part numbers are the same as those assigned in that patent should not be construed to imply that the disclosed improvements are applicable only to the Votomatic. They are equally applicable to most other punch-card voting devices as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In detail and referring to the drawings, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is analogous to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> in U.S. Pat. No. 3,240,409. Comparing the two figures, it will be seen that the housing <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has been made much deeper. This is to provide space for at least one electric lamp but preferably two light sources, consisting of an elongated light bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> to the left of the punching die strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and a mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to the right of those strips. Mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the socket <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> for bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> are supported on brackets <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> fixed to the bottom part of housing <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> shows here as a circle, since it is a sectional view. A plan view of it would show that its diameter is at most a third of its length, and preferably a fifth or less. The lengthwise dimension of bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, which ideally is similar to the length of the columns of preperforated areas of the punch card, is oriented parallel to the long direction of the base <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and the same is true of mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. A cylindrical or parabolic reflector <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> may be used to direct the light from bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> toward the mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the underside of die strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Both bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> are mounted below the plane occupied by punch card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> when that card has been inserted into the device. Mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is tilted at an angle and has a width such that beams of light from bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> are reflected directly from the lower edge of mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to the left-most die strip <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and from the upper edge of mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to the right-most die strip <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. This arrangement ensures that the left side of all the T-strips is illuminated by bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and the right side by mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, so that when any aperture is made in punch card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the combined illumination will send a strong beam of light upward to the eye of the voter. (For &ldquo;right&rdquo; read &ldquo;left&rdquo; and vice versa if bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is to the right and mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to the left of die strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Several other characteristics of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> should be noted. The T-strips have the same shape as the corresponding T-strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in U.S. Pat. No. 3,240,409, but they are made of a different material. Instead of the opaque black rubber T-strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> used in the Votomatic and other prior art punch card devices, the T-strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> are made of a resilient elastomer that is pervious to light (transparent or translucent), such as latex or clear urethane rubber. In addition, the supporting ribs <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the lower part of frame <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which in the Votomatic are molded of opaque plastic, are in the present invention molded of a transparent plastic such as clear acrylic (&ldquo;Lucite&rdquo;) or clear polystyrene. The combination of the pervious-to-light T-strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and the transparent supporting ribs <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which are an integral part of base <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, ensures that the maximum amount of light will reach the underside of the punch card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. This gives to the voter &ldquo;instant verification&rdquo; that he/she has produced a clear punch-out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> It will be evident, from comparing the structure disclosed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> of the Votomatic patent, that the depth of the sides of base <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has been increased by introducing a transparent protective sleeve <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. This is to ensure that the light sources (bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>) are protected from the chads <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> that have been punched out of card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Sleeve <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> is rectangular in a plan view and has a projected area that is the same as card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Its bottom end opens into a removable plastic collection box <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> that catches the falling chad <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In general, all of the desirable features of the Votomatic may be retained in voting devices having the improvements disclosed in this specification. This includes (a) making the housing in two parts, a top part and a bottom part, as show in FIG. 1 and FIG. 2 of U.S. Pat. No. 3,240,409 and (b) utilizing two templates, an outer template <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> having apertures <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> only at positions adjacent to ballot choices printed on the spaced-apart leaves <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, and an inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> having apertures <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> only at positions that are in register with preperforated areas <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> on ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> when it is inserted into the device far enough to bear against a flange <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> cemented to the lower end of said inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (see FIG. 9 of U.S. Pat. No. 3,240,409). As explained in the specification of said patent, when said ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is fully inserted, said inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is shifted to a position of register of the apertures <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of said inner and outer templates <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> respectively, against the urging of a light spring <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> bearing against said flange <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (per said FIG. 9). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Although the Votomatic is the best of all prior art punch-card voting devices, it shares with these prior art devices one important shortcoming that is responsible for about half the 1% or so of defective ballots commonly cast on that machine. A failure of the voter to insert the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> far enough into the device to bring the template apertures <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> into register causes the punching stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to strike the inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> between adjacent apertures <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> so that it is prevented from reaching the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. To remedy this particular shortcoming, the present invention proposes to put the switch that turns on the backlighting at a position such that the energizing of light sources <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> occurs only if the inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is at the point where apertures <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> are both in register with preperforated areas <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, that is to say, when the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is fully inserted. Since the voter is instructed not to vote until the backlighting is on, this serves as a dramatic reminder that the ballot card must be fully inserted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> One way to switch on the backlighting is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. This is a partial plan view of the bottom end of the inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, made visible by a break-out of part of frame <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Flange <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> projects downward from the lower end of the inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and carries a light metal leaf spring <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> in place of the coil spring <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> shown in FIG. 9 of U.S. Pat. No. 3,240,409. At or adjacent to the central portion of leaf spring <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> or any convenient point on flange <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> or the bottom edge of the inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, there is a limit switch <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> that is positioned to close at the exact point when the preperforated areas <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and apertures <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> are all in register. Limit switch <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> is mounted on an L-shaped bracket <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> that is in turn mounted on the lower portion of housing <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. One lead of limit switch <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> is connected to bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and the other to the main power supply, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> It will be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> that the power circuit for bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is a very simple one, consisting only of the bulb itself and limit switch <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> in series. The bottom part of housing <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> may be either metal or plastic, but if it is metal it should be connected to the ground wire of the power supply cord. Although it is possible to use a second bulb in parallel with bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>), this is less desirable than using one bulb and a mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, on the basis of first cost, heat generation, and amperage load imposed on limit switch <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. Mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may of course be omitted, but this would cause the right hand columns of punch-outs to have less illumination than the left-hand columns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic drawing that illustrates the second main shortcoming of the Votomatic, which is just as serious as failing to insert the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> fully. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, it will be seen that the stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is not held vertical to the face of the inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, so that the stylus probe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is subject to what may be called &ldquo;the dresser drawer effect.&rdquo; Because the apertures <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> in the inner template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are partly cylindrical, the sharp edge of the probe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> can dig into the side wall of the aperture <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, and bind the stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> against further inward movement. If there is substantial tipping of the stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, the digging in will occur high up in aperture <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> so no mark will be made on the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and no vote will have been cast. If the stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> tipping is less extreme, the digging in will occur much close to the bottom of the aperture <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, so that only the needle-like tip <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> of the stylus <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> will reach the card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, to make a &ldquo;dimple&rdquo; on the preperforated area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> but no dislodgement of this area will occur, and the mechanical card-reader will not record a vote. This opens the door to controversies as to what should count as a vote and what should not. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> To reduce the frequency of such problems, a small change may be made to the stylus probe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The sharp corner of the stylus probe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is rounded sufficiently to prevent the &ldquo;dresser drawer&rdquo; effect. The particular amount of rounding depends on the clearance provided between the diameter of the cylindrical portion of the aperture <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> in template <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the diameter of the stylus probe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. It is also important that the rounded portions have as smooth a finish as the balance of probe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, so that both can be completely free of machining ridges or grooves. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> the Votomatic stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> has a needle-like tip <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> protruding from the end of the probe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The function of this small protrusion is to spear the preperforated area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> so that it cannot slide laterally during the punching action and hang up on one end or one side, producing what is called a &ldquo;hanging chad&rdquo; instead of a clean punch-out. There is not much question that a hanging chad counts as a vote in a manual recount, but if such a chad happens to get folded back to reoccupy its original aperture in the main body of card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, no light may be transmitted through the punch-out so no vote will be recorded. For this reason it is desirable to strip away any hanging chads present on the completed ballot. This can and should be done by the voter, with or without the aid of the backlighting. It is important to note that a stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> on which the needle-like tip <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> has been broken or worn off will produce many more hanging chads than one on which the spear-like tip <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is intact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows an instruction sheet <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> that should be continuously visible to the voter. Ideally it should be mounted just above the voting device. This is decidedly preferable to having it printed on one side of the first or second ballot leaf <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In summary, it should be noted that the foregoing disclosures all have the same objective, namely the reduction of ballot errors currently being produced by the best presently available voting device, the Votomatic, from its average error rate of about 1% to 0.5% or less, A realistic goal may be as small as 0.2 or 0.3%. The shortcomings of the Votomatic (sensitivity to insufficient insertion of the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and tilting of the stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) have both been addressed herein by three innovations, and it is the hope of the applicant that this &ldquo;fail-safe&rdquo; approach will achieve the desired results, of largely eliminating voting errors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Both the above-noted shortcomings are addressed by (1) more visible instructions (FIG. 7), and (2), the disclosed system of backlighting, which affords the voter a unique &ldquo;instant verification&rdquo; of a clean punch-out. The third innovation is different for each of the two above-noted shortcomings. Insufficient card insertion is addressed by having the backlighting turned on by full insertion of the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and excessive tilting of the stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is offset by rounding the sharp corner of the stylus probe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The following observations are believed to be relevant to the claims: (a) All punch-card voting devices are designed for a particular ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, because the horizontal spacing of the parallel columns of perforated areas <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> must be the same for apertures <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, adjacent leaf <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> axes, and adjacent die T-strip <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> slits <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and ribs <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>; similarly, the vertical spacing of the parallel rows of the preperforated areas <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> must match the vertical spacing of apertures <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and choices exhibited on the ballot leaves <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Most punch card voting devices are designed for the same generally available ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, which has <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> columns and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> rows of preperforated areas <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is not part of the claimed structure. (b) Preferred lamps include a long and narrow incandescent bulb (type T10) or an even longer and narrower fluorescent bulb (e.g., F9BX). The latter runs cooler and imposes only a fourth as much amperage on the limit switch <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. LEDs can also be used. (c) The description &ldquo;pervious to light&rdquo; includes both transparent and translucent. (d) If it is desired to reduce the number of hanging chads, the preperforated areas <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be made circular, in which case the slits in the punching die should be two directional, as for example a &plus; shape. (e) In keeping with industry usage, a preperforated area <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is called a &ldquo;chad&rdquo; once it is fully or partially detached from the body of the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. (f) For the purposes of the claims, a stylus is a light form of punch, appropriate for a punch-out that has been preperforated. (g) Any light source used should be offset from the region beneath the die, so that no chads will blanket it. (h) The term &ldquo;lamp&rdquo; or &ldquo;electric light bulb&rdquo; includes all types of bulb, whether incandescent, fluorescent, LED, or any other form of electrically-driven illumination. (i) Instead of the enclosed limit switch <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, two contacts on leaf spring <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> may be used. (j) The preferred feature for holding the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in place is the same one used by the Votomatic, which is a pair of red colored pins. (k) It will be obvious that if a spacer is inserted into the housing <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of a Votomatic, it can be made deep enough to accommodate one or more light sources. (l) Although the device disclosed herein is called a &ldquo;voting device&rdquo;, it may also be sued for exams, surveys, etc. (m) If desired, a blinker may be introduced into the lighting circuit. (n) The removable catch basket <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> provided to catch the falling chads should be either transparent or low enough not to interfere with light beams emitted by bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and directed toward the T-strips or mirror <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. (o) Mechanical devices could be introduced to overcome the shortcomings of the Votomatic, but they would increase the cost of the disclosed device and increase its complexity. The latter is always a problem because complexity tends to produce errors. Examples of such mechanical means include a door that is closed to force a complete insertion of the ballot card <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> as shown in FIG. 11 of U.S. Pat. No. 3,240,409. Another such device that could be introduced to keep the stylus <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> perpendicular to the ballot card would be a square-section telescoping arm pivotally mounted at one corner of the housing <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and holding at its free end a vertically slidable stylus. It appears likely that the complexity of such arrangements would produce more errors than will occur with the above-described tip-rounded stylus fastened to a bead chain. (p) Another mechanical device that could be introduced is a sharpened sheet steel scraper mounted on the bottom of the ballot slot <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The purpose of this would be to scrape off the back side of the ballot any hanging chad as the ballot is withdrawn from its slot. While it is desirable to get rid of all hanging chads, this is not the way to do it, as it deviates from the basic concept of the present invention, which is to alert the voter to any improper punch-out so he/she can take steps to make the necessary repair. Since the scraper would operate on the ballot after the voter has finished, the &ldquo;instant verification&rdquo; would be circumvented and any unexpected error produced by the scraper would go uncorrected. It is much better to have &ldquo;hanging chads,&rdquo; on the rare occasions when they do occur, discovered and corrected by the voter, as proposed in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> instruction section &ldquo;When you finish voting.&rdquo; (q) The term &ldquo;light source&rdquo; means an electric lamp or at least one mirror or other reflective surface. (r) If a sole lamp or light bulb is positioned above the plane of the card (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>), there must be at least one mirror or other image-reflecting surface below that plane. (s) If bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is an incandescent light, apertures should be provided in the top and bottom of housing <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to increase the convection of air for cooling. (t) On the same side of housing <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> that houses lamp <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, a &ldquo;ready-to-vote&rdquo; signal light (preferably green) is mounted, to tell the voter that the backlighting is operative. This signal light is illuminated by diverting a small portion of the light produced by bulb <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> by a small mirror. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device including a punch, a die adapted to support a machine-processable record card while it is being punched, and a light source mounted below the plane of said card in a position to direct light through the aperture made in said card by said punch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said light source includes an electric light bulb and a mirror. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said light source includes two electric light bulbs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said light source includes an electric light bulb, partially surrounded by a reflector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said light source includes an electric light bulb having an overall length greater than three times its maximum diameter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said light source is illuminated by the operation of a limit switch closed by the full insertion of said card into said device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the upper surface of said die is made of a material that is pervious to light. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the upper surface of said die is supported on ribs made of transparent material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least one transparent pane is interposed between said light source and chads punched out of said card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein light from said light source is made visible to the user of said device, to indicate to said user that the light source is energized. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein an open space is provided below said die, said space having at least as great a width and length as said die, and a depth at least as great as the vertical height of said light source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said punch is in the form of a stylus with (a) a handle and (b) a slender probe, preferably of metal and having a diameter smaller than the minimum width of preperforated areas to be punched out of said card, the free end of said probe being slightly rounded to prevent binding during the punch operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said light source includes one electric light bulb and one mirror spaced apart by more than the width of said die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein instructions to the user regarding the proper method for inserting said card and manipulating the punch are visible to said user during the punching operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said card has a plurality of preperforated areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said card has a plurality of preperforated areas arranged in a plurality of rows and a plurality of columns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said card has a plurality of preperforated areas arranged in a plurality of rows and a plurality of columns, and said device has a plurality of leaves turnably mounted on co-planar parallel axes spaced apart by multiples of the distance between adjacent columns of said preperforated areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said card has a plurality of preperforated areas arranged in a plurality of rows and a plurality of columns, and said device has a plurality of leaves turnably mounted on co-planar parallel axes spaced apart by multiples of the distance between adjacent columns of said preperforated areas, said leaves each having an edge adjacent to a different column of said preperforated areas and exhibiting a plurality of legible choices each aligned with a different one of said rows. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said card has a plurality of preperforated areas arranged in a plurality of rows and a plurality of columns, and said device has a plurality of leaves turnably mounted on co-planar parallel axes spaced apart by multiples of the distance between adjacent columns of said preperforated areas, said leaves each having an edge adjacent to a different column of said preperforated areas and exhibiting a plurality of legible choices each aligned with a different one of said rows, said device also having (a) an opaque outer template mounted immediately underneath the plane of said axes and having an aperture adjacent to each of said choices, and (b) a transparent inner template immediately underneath said outer template and having an aperture in register with each preperforated area of said card when said card has been inserted into said device sufficiently to bear against a flange fixed to the lower end of said inner template. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said card has a plurality of preperforated areas arranged in a plurality of rows and a plurality of columns, and said device has a plurality of leaves turnably mounted on co-planar parallel axes spaced apart by multiples of the distance between adjacent columns of said preperforated areas, said leaves each having an edge adjacent to a different column of said preperforated areas and exhibiting a plurality of legible choices each aligned with a different one of said rows, said device also having (a) an opaque outer template mounted immediately underneath the plane of said axes and having an aperture adjacent to each of said choices, and (b) a transparent inner template immediately underneath said outer template and having an aperture in register with each preperforated area of said card when said card has been inserted into said device sufficiently to bear against a flange fixed to the lower end of said inner template, said card shifting said inner template to a position of register of the apertures in said inner and said outer templates against the urging of a light spring bearing against said flange. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the upper surface of said die is made of a resilient material and has slits adapted to permit said punch to detach preperforated areas from said card and force t hem into the open space beneath said die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said punch is in the form of a stylus with (a) a handle and (b) a slender probe, preferably of metal and have a diameter smaller than the minimum width of preperforated areas to be punched out of said card, the free end of said probe being slightly rounded to prevent binding during the punching operation and having a needle-like projection adapted to spear said preperforated areas of said card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a rectangular open-top box is snapped onto the underside of said device beneath said die, adapted to catch all chads punched out of said card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A punch-card device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a small portion of the illumination from said light source is made visible to the user of said device, to signal that said device is ready for voting.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001015A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001015A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001015A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
