<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000323A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000323A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000323A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000323A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000323A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000323A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000323A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000323A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000323A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000323A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000323A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000323A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000323A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000323A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000323A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000323A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000323</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10180124</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-198680</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-200803</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-200804</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F16H059/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>074</class>
<subclass>335000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>074</class>
<subclass>473120</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Gear change device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michinobu</given-name>
<family-name>Suzuki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Masahiko</given-name>
<family-name>Hayashi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ANTONELLI TERRY STOUT AND KRAUS</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>SUITE 1800</address-1>
<address-2>1300 NORTH SEVENTEENTH STREET</address-2>
<city>ARLINGTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22209</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A gear change device comprising a shift lever support mechanism arranged in a casing to support a shift lever in a manner so as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate, a select actuator for operating said shift lever in the axial direction which is the direction of selection, and a shift actuator for rotating said shift lever support mechanism in the direction of shift, wherein said shift actuator has an operation lever of which the base portion is mounted on said shift lever support mechanism; a pair of electromagnetic solenoids arranged facing each other with the acting portion of said operation lever interposed therebetween and inclined with respect to the horizontal direction; and a resilient urging means that produces the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation of the one electromagnetic solenoid which operates upward along the inclination, out of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a gear change device for shifting a transmission mounted on a vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A gear change device for shifting a transmission comprises a select actuator for actuating a shift lever of a speed-changing mechanism in a direction of selection and a shift actuator for actuating the shift lever in a direction of shift. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> As the select actuator and the shift actuator, there are usually used fluid pressure cylinders using a fluid pressure such as pneumatic pressure or hydraulic pressure as a source of operation. The select actuator and the shift actuator employing the hydraulic cylinders require pipes for connecting the source of fluid pressure to each of the actuators, require electromagnetic change-over valves for changing over the flow passage of the operation fluid, and require space for arranging the above components, resulting in an increase in weight of the device as a whole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In recent years, there have been proposed a select actuator and a shift actuator constituted by electric motors as a gear change device for a transmission mounted on a vehicle which is provided with neither a source of compressed air nor a source of hydraulic pressure,. The select actuator and the shift actuator constituted by electric motors can be constituted in a compact size as a whole and in a reduced weight since they need neither the pipes for connection to the source of hydraulic pressure nor the electromagnetic change-over valve unlike the actuators that use fluid pressure cylinders. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The actuators using electric motors require a speed reduction mechanism for obtaining a predetermined operation force. As the speed reduction mechanisms, there have been proposed the one using a ball-screw mechanism and the one using a gear mechanism. However, the actuators using the ball-screw mechanism and the gear mechanism are not necessarily satisfactory in regard to durability of the ball-screw mechanism and of the gear mechanism and in regard to durability and the operation speed of the electric motors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> As a source of driving the select actuator and the shift actuator capable of operating the shift lever in the direction of shift and in the direction of selection without using the speed reduction mechanism, the present applicant has proposed a gear change device using an electromagnetic solenoid in Japanese Patent Application No. 183470/2001. However, this electromagnetic solenoid has moving members such as a moving iron core having a large mass that operates in the axial direction and hence, the moving member is affected by its own gravity. Therefore, the operation force changes depending upon the arrangement of the electromagnetic solenoid. Particularly, in the shift actuator having a pair of electromagnetic solenoids facing each other with the operation lever interposed therebetween, there occurs a difference between the shifting force in one direction and the shifting force in the other direction when operation forces of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids undergo a change. When the pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting the shift actuator are so arranged that the moving iron cores operate on a horizontal plane, there occurs no change in the of shifting forces of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids. owing to the requirement of layout, however, it often becomes necessary to arrange the electromagnetic solenoids in an inclined manner with respect to the horizontal direction. That is, in the shift actuator in which the pair of electromagnetic solenoids are arranged in an inclined manner with respect to the horizontal direction, the one electromagnetic solenoid which operates downward along the inclination produces an increased operation force due to the gravity of the moving member, while the other electromagnetic solenoid which operates upward along the inclination produces a decreased operation force due to the gravity of the moving member. Therefore, the shifting force may often become insufficient in the shifting operation by the other electromagnetic solenoid which produces the decreased operation force. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> It is, therefore, an object of the present invention to provide a gear change device equipped with a shift actuator, which is so constituted as to compensate the influence of gravity on the moving members of a pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting the shift actuator, and is capable of producing nearly the same shifting forces at all time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In order to accomplish the above-mentioned object according to the present invention, there is provided a gear change device comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> a shift lever support mechanism arranged in a casing to support a shift lever in a manner to slide in the axial direction and to rotate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> a select actuator for operating said shift lever in the axial direction which is the direction of selection; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> a shift actuator for rotating said shift lever support mechanism in the direction of shift; wherein said shift actuator has: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> an operation lever of which the base portion is mounted on said shift lever support mechanism; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> a pair of electromagnetic solenoids arranged facing each other with the acting portion of said operation lever interposed therebetween and inclined with respect to the horizontal direction; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> a resilient urging means that produces the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation of the one electromagnetic solenoid which operates upward along the inclination, out of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The resilient urging force of the resilient urging means is set to a value that compensates the influence of gravity on the moving members of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids, caused by the inclination. The resilient urging means comprises an extension spring which urges the operation lever toward the direction of operation by the one electromagnetic solenoid. Further, the resilient urging means comprises a compression spring which urges the moving iron core of the one electromagnetic solenoid in the direction of operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In order to solve the above-mentioned technical problem, further, the present invention provides a gear change device comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> a shift lever support mechanism arranged in a casing to support a shift lever in such a manner as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> an operation lever of which the base portion is mounted on said shift lever support mechanism; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> a select actuator for operating said shift lever in the axial direction which is the direction of selection; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> a shift actuator having a pair of electromagnetic solenoids arranged facing each other with the acting portion of said operation lever interposed therebetween; wherein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> the pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting said shift actuator are arranged on the same axis inclined with respect to the horizontal direction; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> the angle of intersection of said operation lever and the axis on which said pair of electromagnetic solenoids are arranged is so set as to compensate the influence of gravity on the moving members of said pair of electromagnetic solenoids produced by said inclination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In order to solve the above-mentioned technical problem, further, the present invention provides a gear change device comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> a shift lever support mechanism arranged in a casing to support a shift lever in such a manner as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> an operation lever of which the base portion is mounted on said shift lever support mechanism; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> a select actuator for operating said shift lever in the axial direction which is the direction of selection; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> a shift actuator having a pair of electromagnetic solenoids arranged facing each other with the acting portion of said operation lever interposed therebetween; wherein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> the pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting said shift actuator are arranged being inclined with respect to the horizontal direction; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> the operation rods of said pair of electromagnetic solenoids are brought into contact with the acting portion of said operation lever in a predetermined offset amount in the lengthwise direction, the operation rod of the one electromagnetic solenoid that operates downward along the inclination being so constituted as to come into contact with said acting portion of said operation lever on the side closer to the base portion thereof than on the side of the operation rod of the other electromagnetic solenoid that operates upward along the inclination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The offset amount is set to a value that compensates the influence of gravity on the moving members of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids produced by the inclination.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view illustrating an embodiment of a gear change device constituted according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a sectional view along the line A-A in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a view illustrating the operation of a select actuator that constitutes the gear change device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view along the line B-B in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a sectional view illustrating another embodiment of a shift actuator that constitutes the gear change device of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a sectional view illustrating a further embodiment of the shift actuator that constitutes the gear change device of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a sectional view illustrating a still further embodiment of the shift actuator that constitutes the gear change device of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The gear change device constituted according to the present invention will now be described in further detail with reference to the accompanying drawings illustrating preferred embodiments of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view illustrating an embodiment of the gear change device constituted according to the present invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a sectional view along the line A-A in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view along the line B-B in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The gear change device <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> according to the illustrated embodiment is constituted by a select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the illustrated embodiment has three casings <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>formed in a cylindrical shape and coupled to each other. The casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on the left side is opened at both ends thereof and has an opening <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed in the central lower portion thereof. The central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is opened at its both ends thereof and has an opening <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the lower portion at the right end thereof in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. The central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed protruding downward. In the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, an opening <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>communicating with the opening <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is formed at right angles with the axial direction of the casing. The casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>on the right side is opened at its left end in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, and has an end wall <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>at the right end in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is arranged in the three casings <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>constituted as described above. The control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is provided with a fitting portion <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> having an internal spline on the right side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. An external spline <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> formed at the left end of a rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is spline-fitted to the fitting portion <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> in such a manner as to slide in the axial direction. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is rotatably supported at its right side portion by a bearing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> mounted on the right end of the casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the right side. The rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> thus supported is rotated in the direction of shift by a shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> that will be described later. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> thus spline-fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is arranged in the casings <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>so as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate. A shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is mounted onto the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprises a cylindrical mounting portion <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight> and a lever portion <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight> protruding from the mounting portion <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight> in the radial direction, the mounting portion <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight> being spline fitted to the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The mounting portion <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight> of the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> thus spline-fitted to the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is limited from moving in the axial direction by a snap ring <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> operates, as one unit, together with the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> mounting the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> constitute a shift lever support mechanism which supports the shift lever so as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the lever portion <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight> of the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is arranged penetrating through the opening <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed in the lower portion of the left casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. An end of a lever portion <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight> that constitutes the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comes into suitable engagement with the shift blocks <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> that are arranged at a first select position SP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, at a second select position SP<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, at a third select position SP<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and at a fourth select position SP<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and that constitute a shift mechanism of a transmission (not shown). In the illustrated embodiment, the first select position SP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is set at a reverse gear-first gear select position, the second select position SP<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is set at a second gear-third gear select position, the third select position SP<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is set at a fourth gear-fifth gear select position, and the fourth select position SP<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is set at a sixth gear select position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, an electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> arranged coaxially with the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is mounted on the left end of the casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> comprises a cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, an electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> arranged in the casing <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, a fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> arranged in the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, a moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> arranged coaxially with the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> being opposite to one end surface (left end surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, an operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, and a cover <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> mounted on one end (left end in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>) of the cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> has, at one end thereof (left end in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>), an end wall <highlight><bold>411</bold></highlight> having a hole <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> at the central portion thereof and is open at the other end thereof (right end in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>). The electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is wound on an annular bobbin <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> made of a nonmagnetic material such as a synthetic resin or the like, and is arranged along the inner periphery of the casing <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is formed of a magnetic material, has a flange portion <highlight><bold>431</bold></highlight> at the other end thereof (right end in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>), and is mounted on one end of the casing <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> (on the right end in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>) via the flange portion <highlight><bold>431</bold></highlight>. The moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is formed of a magnetic material, and is constituted to come into contact with, and separate away from, the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> in the axial direction. The operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is formed of a nonmagnetic material such as a stainless steel or the like and has, at one end thereof (left end in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>), a small-diameter portion <highlight><bold>451</bold></highlight>. The small-diameter portion <highlight><bold>451</bold></highlight> of the thus constituted operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is inserted in the hole <highlight><bold>441</bold></highlight> formed at the central portion of the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and is caulked at its one end to mount the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The other end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> thus mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is arranged penetrating through the hole <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> formed in the central portion of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, so as to slide in the axial direction, and its other end surface (right end surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>) is constituted to come into contact with the left end surface of the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The cover <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is mounted on one end of the casing <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> by using screws <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to cover one end of the casing <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and one end of the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> according to the illustrated embodiment is constituted as described above. When an electric current is fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is magnetized, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is attracted by the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, whereby the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, i.e., the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> produces a thrust toward the right in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. The magnitude of the thrust produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, i.e., produced by the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is determined by the amount of electric power fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the illustrated embodiment has a select position-limiting mechanism <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> for limiting the position of the shift lever to the first select position SP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, to the second select position SP<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, to the third select position SP<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or to the fourth select position SP<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in cooperation with the magnitude of thrust produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, i.e., by the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> that varies in response to the amount of electric power fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The select position-limiting mechanism <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has the left casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, a first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, a second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and a third moving ring <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> arranged in such a manner as to slide along the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is limited from moving toward the left in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by a snap ring <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> mounted on the inner peripheral surface of the left casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The first compression coil spring <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is arranged between the first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and the second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, and a second compression coil spring <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is arranged between the second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and a stopper <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> which is slidably fitted onto the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and is positioned at a stepped portion <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed on the inner periphery of the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Further, a third compression coil spring <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is arranged between the second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and the third moving ring <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, and a fourth compression coil spring <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> is arranged between the third moving ring <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and the stopper <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The spring force of the second compression coil spring <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is set to be greater than the spring force of the first compression coil spring <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and the spring force of the fourth compression coil spring <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> is set to be greater than the spring force of the third compression coil spring <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. Due to the spring forces of the first compression coil spring <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the second coil spring <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, therefore, the first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is thrusted leftward in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> to come into contact with the snap ring <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is brought, at its left end, into engagement with an engaging portion <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> provided on the outer periphery of the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the illustrated embodiment is constituted as described above. The function will be described hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> When no electric power is fed (no electric current is fed) to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> constituting the select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and third moving ring <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> constituting the select position-limiting mechanism <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are positioned in states shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, where the spring forces are balanced among the first compression coil spring <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, second compression coil spring <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, third compression coil spring <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and fourth compression coil spring <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. At this moment, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> constituting the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are brought to positions shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, so that the right end surface of the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> comes into contact with the left end surface of the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. And, the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is brought to a first select position (SP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) at which an engaging portion <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> provided on the outer periphery of the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> comes into contact with the first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the first select position (SP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) is set to the reverse gear-first gear select position as described above. In case the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> becomes defective, therefore, the select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> brings the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to the reverse-first gear select position. Namely, in case the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> becomes out of order, the transmission can be shifted to the first speed gear with which the vehicle starts moving or to the reverse gear, and the vehicle can be driven to a predetermined place such as a repair shop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> When a voltage of, for example, 2 V is applied to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> constituting the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in a state shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is attracted by the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, whereby the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> produce a thrust toward the right in the drawings. As a result, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> move toward the right in the drawing, overcoming the spring force of the first compression coil spring <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Here, the second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is not displaced since the spring force of the second compression coil spring <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is greater than the spring force of the first compression coil spring <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> come to a halt at a position at which the first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> comes into contact with the second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is brought to a second select position (SP<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Next, when a voltage of, for example, 4 V is applied to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> constituting the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> produce an increased thrust toward the right. As a result, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> move toward the right in the drawing in a state where the first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is in contact with the second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, overcoming the spring force of the second compression coil spring <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. And, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> come to a halt at a position at which the second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is in contact with the third moving ring <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is brought to a third select position (SP<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Next, when a voltage of, for example, 8 V is applied to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> constituting the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> produce a further increased thrust toward the right. As a result, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>), the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> move toward the right in the drawing in a state where the second moving ring <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is in contact with the third moving ring <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, overcoming the spring forces of the second compression coil spring <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> and the fourth compression coil spring <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. And, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and first moving ring <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> come to a halt at a position at which the third moving ring <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is in contact with the stopper <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is brought to a fourth select position (SP<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As described above, the select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> constituting the gear change device <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> actuates the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which mounts the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> integrally thereon, by using the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and features improved durability since it has no rotary mechanism. Unlike the actuator that uses an electric motor, further, the select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> does not require a speed reduction mechanism constituted by a ball-screw mechanism or a gear mechanism, and can be constituted in a compact size and operated at an increased speed. Besides, the illustrated select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> has a select position-limiting mechanism and is constituted to bring the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to any one of a plurality of select positions depending upon the thrust produced by the operation rod <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> that varies in response to the amount of electric power fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Thus, any of the plurality of select positions can be selected by using a single electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, enabling the gear change device to be constructed in a compact size and at a low cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Next, the shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> will be described with reference chiefly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The illustrated shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has an operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> mounted on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> that constitutes a shift lever support mechanism for supporting the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> so as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate, a pair of electromagnetic solenoids, i.e., a first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and a second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> for operating the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and an operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> for transmitting the operation forces of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged on the same axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which is inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. A hole <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight> to be fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is formed in a base portion <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is constituted to be rotated integrally with the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> by fitting a key <highlight><bold>613</bold></highlight> into a keyway <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> formed in the inner peripheral surface of the hole <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight> and into a keyway <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> formed in the outer peripheral surface of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is arranged inserting through the opening <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the lower portion of the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and an acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> which is an end portion (lower end portion) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> reaches the central portion of the opening <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in its neutral state is arranged to be nearly at right angles with the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on which the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged. The operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> has an engaging groove <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> formed in the intermediate portion thereof, to which the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is fitted. Further, fitting holes <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> to be respectively fitted by the operation rods described later of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are formed at both ends of the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Next, the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> has the same constitution as that of the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> described above, and comprises a cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, an electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> wound on an annular bobbin <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and is made of a nonmagnetic material such as a synthetic resin or the like, a fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and is formed of a magnetic material, a moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> which is formed of a magnetic material and is arranged coaxially with the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> being opposite to one end surface of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, an operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> which is formed of a nonmagnetic material such as a stainless steel or the like and is arranged to slide in the axial direction with its one end being mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and its other end passing through a hole <highlight><bold>731</bold></highlight> formed in the central portion of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, and a cover <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> mounted on one end of the cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> by using screws <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. In the thus constituted first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is mounted by bolts <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> on one side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provided in the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and the end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> is coupled to the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. That is, the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is fitted, at its end portion, into a fitting hole <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> formed in one end of the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, and is coupled to the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> by forcibly inserting a split cotter pin <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into pin holes <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>751</bold></highlight> formed in the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and in the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. When an electric current is fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which is mounted on one side of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and is coupled to the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is attracted by the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. As a result, the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> moves toward the right lower side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> along the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, whereby one wall <highlight><bold>911</bold></highlight> forming the engaging groove <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> of the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> coupled to the end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> acts on the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, causing the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to be turned on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the counterclockwise direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Thereby, the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> spline-fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> turns, and the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is shifted in the first direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Next, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is arranged being opposed to the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and is mounted on the other side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Like the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, too, comprises a cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, an electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> wound on an annular bobbin <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and is made of a nonmagnetic material such as a synthetic resin or the like, a fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and is formed of a magnetic material, a moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> which is formed of a magnetic material and is arranged coaxially with the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> being opposite to one end surface of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, an operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> which is formed of a nonmagnetic material such as a stainless steel or the like and is arranged to slide in the axial direction with its one end being mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and its other end passing through a hole <highlight><bold>831</bold></highlight> formed in the central portion of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, and a cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> mounted on one end of the cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> by using screws <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. In the thus constituted second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> is mounted by bolts <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight> on the other side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and the end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> is coupled to the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. That is, the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is fitted, at its end portion, into a fitting hole <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> formed in the other end of the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, and is coupled to the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> by forcibly inserting a split cotter pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> into pin holes <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>752</bold></highlight> formed in the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and in the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. When an electric current is fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which is mounted on the other side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as described above, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is attracted by the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. As a result, the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> moves toward the left upper side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> along the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, whereby the other wall <highlight><bold>912</bold></highlight> forming the engaging groove <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> of the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> coupled to the end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> acts on the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, causing the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to be turned on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the clockwise direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Thereby, the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> spline-fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> turns, and the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is shifted in the second direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> has an extension coil spring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> which works as a resilient urging means that produces the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which operates upward along the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or along the inclination, out of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids. The extension coil spring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is hooked at its one end to an engaging member <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> which is mounted on the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, hooked at its other end to an engaging member <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> mounted on the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and urges the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to turn clockwise on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Accordingly, the extension coil spring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> works as the resilient urging means that produces the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> that operates upward along the inclination, out of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids. The spring force, i.e., resilient urging force of the extension coil spring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is set to a value that compensates the influence of gravity on the moving members of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids, i.e., of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, caused by the inclination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Described below is the rotational torque of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> operated by the shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> A rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> constituting the shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is a value obtained by multiplying a thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> owing to the magnetic field generated by feeding a predetermined electric power to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, by a length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> up to a contacting portion onto one wall <highlight><bold>911</bold></highlight> forming the engaging groove <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> of the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Here, the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged being inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. Therefore, a force (f) based on gravity of the moving members including moving iron cores <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and operation rods <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> acts toward the downward direction along the inclination when the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> operates toward downward direction along the inclination. Therefore, the actual rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes a value obtained by adding up the thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members and then, by multiply the sum by the above-defined length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T1&equals;(F&plus;f)&times;L1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, a rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is a value obtained by multiplying a thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> owing to the magnetic field generated by feeding a predetermined electric power to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, by a length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> up to a contacting portion onto the other wall <highlight><bold>912</bold></highlight> forming the engaging groove <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> of the operation block <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Here, the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged being inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. Therefore, a force (f) based on gravity of the moving members such as moving iron cores <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and operation rods <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> acts toward downward direction along the inclination when the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> operates toward upward direction along the inclination. Therefore, the actual rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> becomes a value obtained by subtracting the force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members from the thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and then, by multiplying by the above-defined length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T2&equals;(F&minus;f)&times;L1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> If the rotational torque (T1&equals;(F&plus;f)&times;L1) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is adjusted to be equal to the rotational torque (T2&equals;(F&minus;f)&times;L1) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T1&equals;T2), then, the shifting force by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes equal to the shifting force by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, in order that the rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes equal to the rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the spring force or the resilient urging force of the extension coil spring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> working as the resilient urging means that produces the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> may be set to a value that cancels the force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Next, another embodiment of the shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the same members as those of the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> are denoted by the same reference numerals but their description is not repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In the shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> resilient urging means is installed in the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> that operates toward the left upper side along the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, i.e., along the inclination in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, to compensate the influence of gravity on the moving members of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. That is, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> has a compression coil spring <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> arranged between the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and the cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The compression coil spring <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> produces the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The spring force or the resilient urging force of the compression coil spring <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be set to a value that cancels the force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The above-mentioned embodiments have dealt with the examples of using the extension coil spring <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the compression coil spring <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as a resilient urging means for producing the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation by one of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids, which operates upward along the inclination. It, however, needs not be pointed out that a spiral spring or a pneumatic spring may be used in their place, as a matter of course. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Next, the shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> according to a further embodiment will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the same members as those of the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> are denoted by the same reference numerals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Like the shift actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, the illustrated shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has a pair of electromagnetic solenoids, i.e., a first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and a second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, for operating the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> mounted on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of the select actuator. The first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged on the same axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which is inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. A hole <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight> to be fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is formed in a base portion <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is constituted to be rotated integrally with the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> by fitting a key <highlight><bold>613</bold></highlight> into a keyway <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> formed in the inner peripheral surface of the hole <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight> and into a keyway <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> formed in the outer peripheral surface of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is arranged inserting through the opening <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the lower portion of the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and an acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> which is an end portion (lower end portion) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> reaches the central portion of the opening <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> has side surfaces formed in a spherical shape or in an arcuate shape so as to be faced to the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and to the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in its neutral state is arranged to be nearly perpendicular to the horizontal surface H. Therefore, the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> are arranged at an angle (&agr;) of intersection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Next, the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> has the same constitution as that of the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, and comprises a cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, an electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> wound on an annular bobbin <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and is made of a nonmagnetic material such as a synthetic resin or the like, a fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and is formed of a magnetic material, a moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> which is formed of a magnetic material and is arranged coaxially with the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> being opposite to one end surface of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, an operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> which is formed of a nonmagnetic material such as a stainless steel or the like and is arranged to slide in the axial direction with its one end being mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and its other end passing through a hole <highlight><bold>731</bold></highlight> formed in the central portion of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, and a cover <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> mounted on one end of the cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> by using screws <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. A compression coil spring <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is arranged between the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the cover <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The compression coil spring <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is for eliminating a gap between the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, and is not necessary needed. In the thus constituted first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is mounted by bolts <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> on one side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provided in the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and the end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> in its neutral state is brought into contact with a first contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on the side surface of the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. When an electric current is fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which is thus mounted on one side of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is attracted by the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. As a result, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> move toward the right lower side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> along the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, whereby the end thereof acts on the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, causing the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to be turned on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the counterclockwise direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Thereby, the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> spline-fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> turns, and the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is shifted in the first direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Next, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is arranged being opposed to the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and is mounted on the other side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Like the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, too, comprises a cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, an electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> wound on an annular bobbin <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and is made of a nonmagnetic material such as a synthetic resin or the like, a fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and is formed of a magnetic material, a moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> which is formed of a magnetic material and is arranged coaxially with the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> being opposite to one end surface of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, an operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> which is formed of a nonmagnetic material such as a stainless steel or the like and is arranged to slide in the axial direction with its one end being mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and its other end passing through a hole <highlight><bold>831</bold></highlight> formed in the central portion of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, and a cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> mounted on one end of the cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> by using screws <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. A compression coil spring <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is arranged between the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and the cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The compression coil spring <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is for eliminating a gap between the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, and is not necessary needed. In the thus constituted second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> is mounted by bolts <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight> on the other side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and the end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> in its neutral state is brought into contact with a second contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on the side surface of the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The length (L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the second contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is larger than the length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of therefrom to the first contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(i.e., L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&lt;L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). When an electric current is fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which is mounted on the other side of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is attracted by the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. As a result, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> move toward the left upper side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> along the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, whereby the end thereof acts on the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, causing the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to be turned on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the clockwise direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Thereby, the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> spline-fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> turns, and the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is shifted in the second direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Described below is the rotational torque of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> mounting the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and is operated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> that constitute the shift actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> A rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is a value obtained by multiplying a thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> owing to the magnetic field generated by feeding a predetermined electric power to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, by a length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> up to the first contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Here, the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is arranged being inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. Therefore, a force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members including moving iron cores <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and operation rods <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, acts in the downward direction along the inclination when the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> operates downward along the inclination. Therefore, the actual rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> mounting the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, which is actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes a value obtained by adding up the thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members and then, by multiply the sum by the above-defined length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T1&equals;(F&plus;f)&times;L1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, a rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is a value obtained by multiplying a thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> owing to the magnetic field generated by feeding a predetermined electric power to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, by a length (L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> up to the second contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Here, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is arranged being inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. Therefore, a force (f) based on gravity of the moving members such as moving iron cores <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and operation rods <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, acts in the downward direction along the inclination when the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> operates upward along the inclination. Therefore, the actual rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> becomes a value obtained by subtracting the force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members from the thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and then, by multiplying by the above-defined length (L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T2&equals;(F&minus;f)&times;L2). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> If the rotational torque (T1&equals;(F&plus;f)&times;L1) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is adjusted to be equal to the rotational torque (T2&equals;(F&minus;f) &times;L2) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T1&equals;T2), then, the shifting force by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes equal to the shifting force by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, in order that the rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes equal to the rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the lengths (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) and (L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> may be so set as to cancel the force (f) which is based on the gravity of the moving members. Namely, the angle (&agr;) of intersection of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on which the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged may be so set as to compensate the influence of gravity on the moving members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Next, still further embodiment of the shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the same members as those of the embodiment shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are denoted by the same reference numerals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The shift actuator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is equipped with a pair of electromagnetic solenoids, i.e., a first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and a second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, for operating the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> mounted on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of the select actuator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> like in the shift actuator shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged on the axes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which are inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. A hole <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight> to be fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is formed in a base portion <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is constituted to be rotated integrally with the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> by fitting a key <highlight><bold>613</bold></highlight> into a keyway <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> formed in the inner peripheral surface of the hole <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight> and into a keyway <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> formed in the outer peripheral surface of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is arranged inserting through the opening <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the lower portion of the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and an acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> which is an end portion (lower end portion) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> reaches the central portion of the opening <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed in the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in its neutral state is arranged to be nearly at right angles with the axes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on which the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are arranged respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Next, the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> has the same constitution as that of the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and comprises a cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, an electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> wound on an annular bobbin <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and is made of a nonmagnetic material such as a synthetic resin or the like, a fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and is formed of a magnetic material, a moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> which is formed of a magnetic material and is arranged coaxially with the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> being opposite to one end surface of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, an operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> which is formed of a nonmagnetic material such as a stainless steel or the like and is arranged to slide in the axial direction with its one end being mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and its other end passing through a hole <highlight><bold>731</bold></highlight> formed in the central portion of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, and a cover <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> mounted on one end of the cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> by using screws <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. A compression coil spring <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is arranged between the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the cover <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The compression coil spring <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is for eliminating a gap between the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, and is not necessary needed. In the thus constituted first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the casing <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is mounted by bolts <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> on one side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provided in the central casing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and the end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> in its neutral state is brought into contact with a first contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on the side surface of the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. When an electric current is fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which is thus mounted on one side of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is attracted by the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. As a result, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> move toward the right lower side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> along the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, whereby the end thereof acts on the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, causing the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to be turned on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the counterclockwise direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Thereby, the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> spline-fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> turns, and the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is shifted in the first direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Next, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> The second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is arranged being opposed to the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and is mounted on the other side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Like the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, too, comprises a cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, an electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> wound on an annular bobbin <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and is made of a nonmagnetic material such as a synthetic resin or the like, a fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> which is arranged in the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and is formed of a magnetic material, a moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> which is formed of a magnetic material and is arranged coaxially with the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> being opposite to one end surface of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, an operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> which is formed of a nonmagnetic material such as a stainless steel or the like and is arranged to slide in the axial direction with its one end being mounted on the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and its other end passing through a hole <highlight><bold>831</bold></highlight> formed in the central portion of the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, and a cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> mounted on one end of the cylindrical casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> by using screws <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. A compression coil spring <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is arranged between the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and the cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The compression coil spring <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is for eliminating a gap between the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, and is not necessary needed. In the thus constituted second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the casing <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> is mounted by bolts <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight> on the other side surface of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and the end of the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> in its neutral state is brought into contact with a second contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on the side surface of the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. When an electric current is fed to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which is thus mounted on the other side of the shift actuator-mounting portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is attracted by the fixed iron core <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. As a result, the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> move toward the left upper side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> along the axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, whereby the end thereof acts on the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, causing the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to be turned on the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the clockwise direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Thereby, the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> spline-fitted to the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> turns, and the shift lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> mounted on the control shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is shifted in the second direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> As described above, the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are each brought, in their neutral state, into contact with the first contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>a and the second contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Namely, the operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> are brought into contact with the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, being offset in the lengthwise direction. The operation rod <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> that operates toward an aslant and downward direction along the inclined axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>comes into contact with the acting portion <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> on the side closer to the base portion <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> thereof than on the side of the operation rod <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> that operates toward an aslant and upward direction along the inclined axis <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Therefore, the length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the first contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>becomes shorter than the length (L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the second contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, i.e., (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&lt;L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Described below is the rotational torque of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> mounting the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and is operated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> that constitute the shift actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> A rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is a value obtained by multiplying a thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> owing to the magnetic field generated by feeding a predetermined electric power to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, by a length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> up to the first contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Here, the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is arranged being inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. Therefore, a force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members including moving iron cores <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and operation rods <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, acts in the downward direction along the inclination when the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> operates downward along the inclination. Therefore, the actual rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> which is actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes a value obtained by adding up the thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members and then, by multiply the sum by the above-defined length (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T1&equals;(F&plus;f)&times;L1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, a rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is a value obtained by multiplying a thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> owing to the magnetic field generated by feeding a predetermined electric power to the electromagnetic coil <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, by a length (L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) from the mounting center of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> up to the second contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Here, the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is arranged being inclined at a predetermined angle (&thgr;) with respect to the horizontal plane H. Therefore, a force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members such as moving iron cores <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and of the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and operation rods <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, acts in the downward direction along the inclination when the electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> operates upward along the inclination. Therefore, the actual rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> becomes a value obtained by subtracting the force (f) based on the gravity of the moving members from the thrust (F) produced by the moving iron core <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and then, by multiplying by the above-defined length (L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T2&equals;(F&minus;f)&times;L2). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> If the rotational torque (T1&equals;(F&plus;f)&times;L1) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is adjusted to be equal to the rotational torque (T2&equals;(F&minus;f) &times;L2) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, i.e., (T1&equals;T2), then, the shifting force by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes equal to the shifting force by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, in order that the rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the first electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> becomes equal to the rotational torque (T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> actuated by the second electromagnetic solenoid <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the lengths (L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) and (L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the operation lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> may be so set as to cancel the force (f) which is based on the gravity of the moving members. Namely, the offset amount S between the first contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the second contact point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the lengthwise direction may be so set as to compensate the influence of gravity on the moving members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Being constituted as described above, the gear change device according to the present invention exhibits the following action and effect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> That is, according to the present invention, a pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting the shift actuator of the gear change device are arranged being inclined with respect to the horizontal direction, and provision is made of a resilient urging means for producing the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation by one of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids, which operates upward along the inclination. Therefore, nearly the same shifting force can be obtained at all times even when the pair of electromagnetic solenoids are arranged in a state of being inclined with respect to the horizontal direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, further, a pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting the shift actuator of the gear change device are arranged on the same axis which is inclined with respect to the horizontal direction, and the angle of intersection of the operation lever and the axis on which the pair of electromagnetic solenoids are arranged is so set as to compensate the influence of gravity of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids produced by the inclination. Therefore, nearly the same shifting force can be obtained at all times even when the pair of electromagnetic solenoids are arranged in a state of being inclined with respect to the horizontal direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, further, a pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting the shift actuator of the gear change device are arranged being inclined with respect to the horizontal direction, and the operation rods of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids are each brought into contact with the acting portion of the operation lever in a predetermined offset amount, the operation rod of the first electromagnetic solenoid that operates downward along the inclination being so constituted as to come into contact with the acting portion of the operation lever on the side closer to the base portion thereof than on the side of the operation rod of the second electromagnetic solenoid that operates upward along the inclination. Therefore, nearly the same shifting force can be obtained at all times even when the pair of electromagnetic solenoids are arranged in a state of being inclined with respect to the horizontal direction. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What we claim is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A gear change device comprising: 
<claim-text>a shift lever support mechanism arranged in a casing to support a shift lever in such a manner as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a select actuator for operating said shift lever in the axial direction which is the direction of selection; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shift actuator for rotating said shift lever support mechanism in the direction of shift; wherein said shift actuator has: 
<claim-text>an operation lever of which the base portion is mounted on said shift lever support mechanism; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of electromagnetic solenoids arranged facing each other with the acting portion of said operation lever interposed therebetween and inclined with respect to the horizontal direction; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a resilient urging means that produces the urging force in the direction same as the direction of operation of the one electromagnetic solenoid which operates upward along the inclination, out of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A gear change device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the resilient urging force of said resilient urging means is set to a value that compensates the influence of gravity on the moving members of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids, produced by the inclination. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A gear change device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said resilient urging means comprises an extension spring which urges said operation lever toward the direction of operation of the one electromagnetic solenoid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A gear change device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said resilient urging means comprises a compression spring which urges the moving iron core of the one electromagnetic solenoid in the direction of the operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A gear change device comprising: 
<claim-text>a shift lever support mechanism arranged in a casing to support a shift lever in such a manner as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation lever of which the base portion is mounted on said shift lever support mechanism; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a select actuator for operating said shift lever in the axial direction which is the direction of selection; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shift actuator having a pair of electromagnetic solenoids arranged facing each other with the acting portion of said operation lever interposed therebetween; wherein </claim-text>
<claim-text>the pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting said shift actuator are arranged on the same axis inclined with respect to the horizontal direction; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the angle of intersection of said operation lever and the axis on which said pair of electromagnetic solenoids are arranged is so set as to compensate the influence of gravity on the moving members of said pair of electromagnetic solenoids produced by said inclination. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A gear change device comprising: 
<claim-text>a shift lever support mechanism arranged in a casing to support a shift lever in such a manner as to slide in the axial direction and to rotate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation lever of which the base portion is mounted on said shift lever support mechanism; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a select actuator for operating said shift lever in the axial direction which is the direction of selection; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shift actuator having a pair of electromagnetic solenoids arranged facing each other with the acting portion of said operation lever interposed therebetween; wherein </claim-text>
<claim-text>the pair of electromagnetic solenoids constituting said shift actuator are arranged being inclined with respect to the horizontal direction; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the operation rods of said pair of electromagnetic solenoids are each brought into contact with the acting portion of said operation lever in a predetermined offset amount in the lengthwise direction, the operation rod of the one electromagnetic solenoid that operates downward along the inclination being so constituted as to come into contact with said acting portion of said operation lever on the side closer to the base portion thereof than on the side of the operation rod of the other electromagnetic solenoid that operates upward along the inclination. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A gear change device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said offset amount is set to a value that compensates the influence of gravity on the moving members of the pair of electromagnetic solenoids produced by the inclination.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000323A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000323A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000323A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000323A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000323A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000323A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000323A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000323A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
