<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005311A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005311A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005311</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10178538</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020625</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-196566</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04L009/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>713</class>
<subclass>186000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Sending apparatus, receiving apparatus, use limit system and method of sending contents</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Toshiyuki</given-name>
<family-name>Kajimura</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Nara</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tomohiko</given-name>
<family-name>Kitamura</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Toshiro</given-name>
<family-name>Nishio</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>MATSUSHITA ELECTRIC INDUSTRIAL CO., LTD.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>McDERMOTT, WILL &amp; EMERY</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>600 13th Street, N.W.</address-1>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005-3096</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A use limit system in which only contents users who have made a viewing contract can decrypt encrypted contents and use the contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">Use limit is set on contents on the basis of the physical features of the rightful user. The use limit system is made up of a sending apparatus for sending the contents and a receiving apparatus which removes use limit of contents sent from the sending apparatus by acquiring the physical features of the rightful user of contents. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a use limit system limiting the use of contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Prior Art of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> There are a number of methods of setting use limit on contents such as image data, voice data, etc. Representative of them is a method in which, with contents encrypted, a decryption key is distributed to rightful members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> For example, among the contents received by broadcast-receiver called set stop box are contents encrypted by a method laid down by contents provider (hereinafter &ldquo;contents agent&rdquo;). Therefore, when a viewer wants to view such contents, the viewer has to hold a viewing contract with the contents agent to get the decryption key and input the decryption key into the set top box. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Then, the encrypted contents is decrypted by decryption means provided in the set top box and then inputted into the monitor etc. This way, only the user who has made a viewing contract with the contents agent and gets a decryption key can remove use limit on the contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Among the methods of the viewer&apos;s inputting the decryption key in set top box are a method of inputting a decryption key using operating means such as remote control etc. and a method of the viewer&apos;s inserting an integrated circuit (IC) card with a decryption key memorized therein into the set top box </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> However, when trying to remove the use limit by inputting the decryption key using the above-mentioned operating means, the user can not view the contents if the user forgets the decryption key. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Another problem, if the user loses the IC card with a decryption key memorized therein and a third party steals the key, there is a possibility that the third party will use the contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the IC card is stealed the outsider, the secret information to be disclosed to only a specific user is included in the contents can leak out to the outsiders. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present invention having been achieved in view of the above circumstances, it is an object of the invention to provide a use limiting system that allows a rightful user alone to use contents by decrypting the ciphertexts of the contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> To achieve the object, the present invention adopts the following means. Sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> sets a limit on the use of contents so that only specific users can use the contents. That is, sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> sets a use limit permit information of the physical features of the user such as fingerprint, palm print, hand print, voiceprint, pattern of the retina, pattern of the iris, form of the face, and DNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> To use the contents on which a use limit is set by sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the use limit has to be removed. The limit is removed by a removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> provided in the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> When a person identified from the physical features set on the use limit of the contents is found identical with a person with the physical features acquired by an acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> provided in the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> removes the use limit on the contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Using the use limit of the contents and the physical features to remove the use limit of the contents that way solves the problems with the prior art, that is, if the user forgets the decryption key, the user can not use the contents; an IC card with a decryption key memorized therein can be stolen and used by a third party. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The above method of setting use limit can be changed. If the method is changed, the user of contents will have to buy receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> provided with a function of removing a changed use limit. In case different methods of setting use limit are set on different contents providers or contents&apos;, the user will have to buy a plurality of receiving apparatuses <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> But since the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is provided with a function of receiving contents and another function of removing use limit, the apparatus is expensive, and the economic burden will be heavy on the contents user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> To avoid that, a first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is made to have the receiving function of contents possessed by the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and a third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, an apparatus different from receiving means <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight>, is made to have the removal function of the use limit. Thus, the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> without a receiving function is lower than the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> in manufacturing cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Therefore, even if the use limit is set on contents in any method, the contents user can use all contents by buying only the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> of the above method, which can reduce the economic burden of the user of contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> If the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is used and individual contents agents provide their own third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, individual contents agents can provide the use limit using their own individual means and individual algorithm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 13</cross-reference>, the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is provided with reading means <highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> reading information for removal of the use limit in a storage medium and inputting the information into the removal means <highlight><bold>339</bold></highlight> or operating means (not shown) for inputting information for removal of the use limit into removal means <highlight><bold>339</bold></highlight>.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a use limit system to which the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing the operation of the use limit system in Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing the operation of the use limit system in Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a conceptual diagram of data registered with storage means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a conceptual diagram of data registered with storage means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a conceptual diagram of data registered with storage means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a use limit system to which the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a use limit system to which the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a first apparatus to which the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a second apparatus to which the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a third apparatus in Embodiment 5. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a third apparatus in Embodiment 6. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a third apparatus in Embodiment 7. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a schematic function block diagram of a use limit system to which the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing the operation of the use limit system in Embodiment 5. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing the operation of the use limit system in Embodiment 7</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EMBODIMENT 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a case in which sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is used for TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to send pay TV broadcast (hereinafter &ldquo;pay broadcast&rdquo;) as contents and set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is used as receiving apparatus for viewers to receive the pay broadcast. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> scrambles and broadcasts a pay broadcast program so that the pay broadcast may be viewable only when the pay broadcast is received by set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of a viewer who has made a viewing contract. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> To view the pay broadcast of TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, the viewer has to hold a viewing contract with TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. That is, when making a viewing contract with TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, the viewer reports to TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> the product&apos;s number of the viewer&apos;s set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, lot number, serial number etc. the identification number to identify the set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and the physical features of the viewer. The physical features are fingerprint, palm print, hand print, voiceprint, pattern of the retina, pattern of the iris, form of the face, and DNA. In the following description, it is to be understood that the physical features mean the fingerprint of the thumb. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> If TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> makes a viewing contract with a viewer, master key Km corresponding to the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the viewer is registered with master key management means <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> installed within TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, and the fingerprint of the viewer is registered with a storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, with a master key management means <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> provided in individual set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the master key Km corresponding to the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is registered in the manufacturing stage of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> When a viewing contract is made as mentioned above and a new master key Km is registered with master key management means <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>, a encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> provided in the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> encrypts work key Kw with the newly registered master key Km and makes individual information (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> Step S <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>). This work key Kw is a key to encrypt scramble key Ks that TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> uses to scramble a program of the pay broadcast, managed by work key management means <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> provided in the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Individual information thus prepared is transferred to a multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, multiplexed with a program etc. by the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> which will be described later, and broadcast via sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> So that the individual information may be received by the set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of a viewer making viewing contract, the TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> informs the viewer the broadcasting time when the individual information will broadcast beforehand. According to this notice, the viewer sets the channel of the receiving broadcast to the pay broadcast in set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> so that set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> receives the individual information at the broadcast time </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The individual information sent from sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is received by a receiving means <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> of the set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>). The individual information received by the receiving means <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> is inputted into a separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and is separated from other information multiplexed with the individual information by the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The separated individual information is inputted into a decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> If the individual information is inputted, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> decrypts work key Kw included in the individual information with master key Km stored in the master key management means <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>). If work key Kw is decrypted, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> registers the work key Kw with work key management means <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Master key Km used to encrypt work key Kw is master key Km stored in the viewer&apos;s set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of which the identification number is reported when the viewing contract is made. Therefore, even if the set top box of a viewer who has not made a viewing contract receives the above individual information, decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> provided in the set top box can not decrypt work key Kw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Acquiring work key Kw, set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can decrypt a scramble key Ks that is decrypted and broadcast, and to descramble a program of the pay broadcast that is furthermore scrambled using the scramble key Ks and broadcast. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The scramble key Ks, which is managed by scramble key management means <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> in sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, is used in scrambling a program at TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> as shown below, and at the same time encrypted by work key Kw and broadcast. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> When TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> broadcasts a filmed program, the program stored in contents management server <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> provided in TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is sent to a scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> provided in the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. In case a live relay broadcast is broadcast, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> sends to the scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> a program prepared at studio <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> or relay station <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> If a program is inputted from contents the management server <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>, the studio <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> or the relay station <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>, the scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> acquires scramble key Ks from the scramble key management means <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and scrambles the sent out program using the scramble key Ks and transfers the program to the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Meanwhile, in order that set top boxes <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of all the viewers who have made viewing contracts can descramble the scrambled program, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> multiplexes the scramble key Ks into the program and broadcasts. But if scramble key Ks is received by set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of a viewer who has made a viewing contract, a viewer who has not made a viewing contract can receive a pay broadcast through the set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, decrypts scramble key Ks and descramble the program. To prevent viewers without making a viewing contract from descrambling a program, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> makes a broadcast by multiplexing use permit information made up of the physical features of all the viewing contractors registered with storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and the scramble key Ks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> There is a possibility that if broadcast, the scramble key Ks and the use permit information are acquired by a third party. To block that, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> makes a broadcast by encrypting the scramble key Ks and use permit information by the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>). Information in which the scramble key Ks and use permit information are encrypted shall be hereinafter called common information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> To prepare this common information, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> first acquires scramble key Ks from the scramble key management means <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and use permit information from the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. Then, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> encrypts the acquired scramble key Ks and use permit information with work key Kw managed by the work key management means <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. And when common information is prepared, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> transfers the common information to the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> If one scramble key Ks is fixed, there is a possibility that a third party knows the scramble method, and to prevent that, the scramble key management means <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> changes scramble key Ks every several seconds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> If informed by the scramble key management means <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, for example, that scramble key Ks is changed, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> will re-prepare common information. That is, each time scramble key Ks is changed, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> acquires scramble key Ks from the scramble key management means <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and use permit information from the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, and encrypts the acquired scramble key Ks and use permit information with work key Kw. And each time common information is re-prepared, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> transfers the prepared common information to the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As a scrambled program is transferred from the scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> broadcasts the program as pay broadcast in principle through the sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. But the common information and the individual information can be transferred from the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> to the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. When the common information and the individual information are transferred, the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> broadcasts multiplex information with the common information and individual information multiplexed into a program as pay broadcast through the sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As set forth above, since a program is scrambled by scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and scramble key Ks is encrypted by the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, a third party can not view a program even if the third party acquires broadcast wave of the pay broadcast. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> When a viewer who has made a viewing contract views such a pay broadcast, the viewer applies power to set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and inputs an instruction into set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to select the channel for the pay broadcast using a remote control or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> When the instruction is given, pay broadcast from the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is inputted into separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> via the receiving means <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>). In case information other than the program, that is, common information and individual information, are included in the pay broadcast, the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> separates common information and individual information from the program. And the program is transferred to the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, and common information and individual information are transferred to the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. In case no information other than a program is included in the pay broadcast, the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> does not separate and transfers the program to the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> If individual information is inputted from the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> decrypts work key Kw of individual information with master key Km as described above. If common information is inputted, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> judges if the work key Kw is registered with the work key management means <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>). In case it is judged that work key Kw is registered, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> takes out work key Kw from the work key management means <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, and decrypts scramble key Ks and use permit information included in common information and sends them to a judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Meanwhile, after the user applies power to set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and adjusts the reception channel to the pay broadcast as described above, the viewer puts the thumb on feature reader (sensor) <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> making up the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> provided in set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>). If the feature reader <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> is put thumb ,the feature reader <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> is read the thumb fingerprint. The read fingerprint as fingerprint information is acquired by the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and inputted into the judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. It is noted that an arrangement may be so made that feature reader <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> is detachably fixed on the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> If use permit information is inputted from the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and fingerprint information is inputted from the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> judges whether a fingerprint information is included in the use permit information found to be identical with the fingerprint information inputted from acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>). If it is judged that the fingerprint information found, judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> gives scramble key Ks to the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. If it is judged in the judgement step S<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> that a fingerprint information information is included in the use permit information found to be identical with the fingerprint information, the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> gives the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> scramble key Ks transferred from the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> even if no fingerprint information is inputted from the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> for a certain period after judgement. The certain period after judgement is a period from judgement to cutoff of power of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, a period until a program ends, 1 hour, 2 hours . . . after judgement, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Receiving scramble key Ks, the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> descrambles a program transferred from the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> using the scramble key Ks (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>). The removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> sends the descrambled program to viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> such as a monitor, speaker etc. connected to set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Thus, the scrambled program is sent to viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, and viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> can reproduce the program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> If it is judged in the judgement step S <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> that work key Kw is not registered, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> does not decrypt scramble key Ks and use permit information included in common information but transfers the common information to the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> can not judge whether fingerprint information inputted from the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is included in use permit information. In case judgement can not be made, the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> does not give scramble key Ks to the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. Thus, to viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, a scrambled program is sent, and viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> can not reproduce the program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, if the judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> judges in the judgment step S <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> that fingerprint information is included in the use permit information does&apos;nt found to be identical with the fingerprint information the judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> does not give scramble key Ks to the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Thus, if a use limit which is removed when the broadcast physical feature and that acquired by the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> are identical is set on contents, set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can not descramble the program even if a viewer who has not made a viewing contract with TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> has the fingerprint reader <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> read a fingerprint. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In the above description of the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is held up an example. But if the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is provided with a monitor, speaker and others in addition to the functions that set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> has, the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> may send a descrambled program to a monitor or speaker provided in the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, there is a possibility that a program descrambled by the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> may be acquired and viewed by a third party while being sent from the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> to the viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. To prevent that, the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> may send the descrambled program to the viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> after encrypting the program as mentioned above. In case a program is encrypted and sent like that, viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> has to have a decryption key to reproduce an encrypted program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In case a plurality of persons view a pay broadcast using one set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, it is necessary to report the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the physical features of all the persons to TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. An example in which a plurality of persons use one set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is this: all members of a family use one set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> at their home. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> If the physical features of all members of a family, for example, are reported to TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, the physical features of all the family members will be registered with the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> by TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. If the physical features of all the family members are registered with storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, the common information includes the physical features of all the family members and any member of the family can have the fingerprint reader <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> read the fingerprint and view a pay broadcast. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EMBODIMENT 2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The viewing contract in Embodiment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is a contract permitting viewing all the programs broadcast by TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The viewing contract may be a contract permitting specific programs only, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> When a viewing contract for news programs, for example, is made, the viewer reports to TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, physical features and news program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> If a viewing contract for a new program is made, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> will register with the master key management means <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> the master key Km corresponding to the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the viewer who has made a viewing contract, and registers with the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> the physical features by relating them to the program identification number of the new program involved in the viewing contract. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> If the master key Km is registered with the master key management means <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>, the work key Kw will be sent to set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the viewing contract viewer in the same way as in Embodiment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Then, when a news program involved in the viewing contract is broadcast, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> sends to the scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> the news program prepared at the studio <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> or the like as described above. The scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> scrambles the sent out news program with the scramble key Ks and transfers the program to the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> To send the scramble key Ks and use permit information to set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> inputs the program identification number of the news program to the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> when broadcasting the news program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> If a program identification number is inputted, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> acquires from the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> a physical feature (use permit information) registered by relating the physical feature to the program identification number of a news program as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A and gets scramble key Ks from the scramble key management means <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. The encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> prepares common information by encrypting the acquired the scramble key Ks and, the use permit information with work key Kw and sends the prepared the common information to the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Needless to say, in present embodiment, too, the scramble key Ks is changed at certain intervals, and each time the scramble key Ks is changed, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> re-prepares the common information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> multiplexes the transferred the common information into a program transferred from the scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and broadcasts the common information through sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> If the physical feature is registered by relating the physical feature to the program identification number, it is possible to broadcast use permit information corresponding to a program now being broadcast. In Embodiment 2, the news program and the physical features of a person only who has made a viewing contract are broadcasting, and therefore those who have not made a viewing contract for the news program can not view the news program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> In case all the members of a family view a news program using one set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, it is necessary to report to TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, news program for viewing contract, and the physical features of all the family members when a viewing contract is made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> If the physical features of all the family members are reported when a viewing contract is made, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> registers the physical features of all the family members by relating the physical features to the program identification number of the news program as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference>. Then, use permit information of the news program includes the physical features of all the family members involved in the viewing contract. Thus, any member of the family involved in the viewing contract can view the news program by having the fingerprint reader read the fingerprint of the thumb. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EMBODIMENT 3 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> In Embodiment 1, it is explained that if the broadcast physical feature is identical with the fingerprint acquired by the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> descrambles the program. Thus, a viewer who has the physical feature registered with the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> can descramble the program using not only the viewer&apos;s own set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> but also another&apos;s set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> storing the work key Kw in the work key management means <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In case many viewers who have made a viewing contract does not want to have the viewer&apos;s own set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> used by the another set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> owner, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> has each viewer report the physical feature and the identification number of one set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> or the identification numbers of a plurality of set top boxes <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> If a viewing contract is made, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> registers with the master key management means <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> the master key Km corresponding to the identification number of one set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> or the identification numbers of a plurality of set top boxes <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> reported for the viewing contract. In addition, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> registers with the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> in which the physical features of a viewer making a viewing contract are related to master key Km corresponding to the identification number (s) of one or a plurality of set top boxes <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> reported for the viewing contract as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> After the master key Km is registered with the master key management means <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>, the work key Kw is sent to set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the viewer who has made a viewing contract in the same way as in Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Also, as Embodiment 1, each time the scramble key Ks is changed, common information is prepared at the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, and the common information is multiplexed with a program etc. and broadcast. However, details of common information in the present embodiment are different from those in Embodiment 1. That is, the details of common information in the present embodiment, that is, Embodiment 3 are all limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> registered with the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and the scramble key Ks which are encrypted with work key Kw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> As explained, if common information including limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> is received by the receiving means <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> separates the common information from programs and the like, and inputs the common information into the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> If the common information is inputted, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> decrypts the limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> and scramble key Ks included in the common information using the master key Km as described above. The decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> transfers decrypted the limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> and the scramble key Ks to the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> If the limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> and the scramble key Ks are transferred and fingerprint information of the thumb is inputted from the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> extracts from the limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight>A including the same master key Km as the master key Km stored in the master key management means <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Next, judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> judges whether the fingerprint information found to be identical with the fingerprint information inputted from the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is included in limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight>A. If it is judged as included, the judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> transfers the scramble key Ks to the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> As described, if limit removal information <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> including the master key Km and the physical features are included in the common information, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> can limit set top box to one or a plurality of specific set top boxes <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> using descramble the program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In case all the family members view a pay program using set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> at their house only, it is arranged that the physical features of all the family members and the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of their house are reported to TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> If a report is made, TV broadcasting station <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> registers the report with the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> by relating the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to the physical features of all the family members as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> If a report is registered by relating the identification number of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> at the house of this family to the physical features of all the family members like that, it is possible for all the family members to descramble the program using set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> at their home. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EMBODIMENT 4 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> The setting of apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and the receiving apparatuses <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that can be for limit of pay broadcast and removal of the use limit has been described. The setting of apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and the receiving apparatuses <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can be used for other than the setting or removal of the use limit of pay broadcasting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> For example, reference to the patient&apos;s chart is limited to a specific person. The patient&apos;s chart is memorized in the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, and the patient&apos;s chart at information terminal of a personal computer or the like is connected with the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> via LAN, Internet or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> In this case, it is a prerequisite that the fingerprint of a person who has been permitted to refer to the patient&apos;s chart is registered in advance with the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and the work key Kw is registered with the work key management means <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> communicably connected with the information terminal. Fingerprint information and the work key Kw can be registered in the same way as Embodiment 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> For example, a doctor who is permitted to refer to patient charts sends a request for a specific patient&apos;s chart to the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> using personal computer <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> connected with the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and LAN. This sending request includes the identification number of the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> communicably connected with personal computer <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> and identification number of the patient for the patient&apos;s identification. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> The sending request sent from personal computer <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> is received by sending request control means <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> in the sending apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Receiving the sending request, the sending request control means <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> transferrs the patient&apos;s identification number to the scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and the identification number of receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to the sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Receiving the patient&apos;s identification number, the scramble means <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> acquires the patient&apos;s chart corresponding to the patient&apos;s identification number received from clinical chart management means <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> storing patient&apos;s charts, and scrambles the chart with scramble key Ks. The scrambled chart is transferred to the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Receiving a patient&apos;s identification number, the encryption means <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> prepares common information by encrypting scramble key Ks and the physical feature registered with the storage means <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> with physical features and transfers the common information to multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> The multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> multiplexes the transferred scrambled chart and common information and sends to the sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> Receiving information with the chart and common information multiplexed from the multiplexing means <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, the sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> sends the information to receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the identification number sent in from the sending request control means <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> The scrambled patient&apos;s chart and common information sent in from the sending means <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are received by receiving means <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> in receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The patient&apos;s chart and common information received by receiving means <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> are separated by the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, and the scrambled patient chart is transferred to the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> and the common information is transferred to the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> The subsequent processing is the same as that in Embodiment 1 except that the program is the patient&apos;s chart. That is, the doctor who wants to see the patient&apos;s chart has the fingerprint of the thumb read by the fingerprint reader, and only when it is judged for by the judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> that a fingerprint found to be identical with the doctor&apos;s fingerprint in the common information will be descrambled by the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. The descrambled patient&apos;s chart will be displayed on the monitor of personal computer <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> connected with receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, the contents are a patient&apos;s chart and, the person who is permitted to see the patient&apos;s chart may be a doctor. The contents may be files on accidents and events possessed by police, and the person who is permitted to see the files may be a policeman. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EMBODIMENT 5 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> The method of setting such use limit is possible to change by revising encryption standards, merging TV broadcasting stations <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> or the like. Each time the method of setting the use limit is changed, the contents user has to buy the receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that can remove the changed use limit. The receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> provided with functions of receiving contents and removing the use limit is expensive and is a heavy economic burden for contents user. Furthermore, to use a plurality of contents on which the use limit is set in different methods, the contents user will have to buy receiving apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> having functions of removing the use limit on each contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the present embodiment will describe the reading of physical features using third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> that has a function of reading removal information to remove the use limit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the prerequisite is a use limit system, that is, when the use limit of contents received by first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is removed on the basis of removal information on the use limit, the contents can be viewed on second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> The term first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> used herein is an apparatus such as set top box, CD player or the like to get contents as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. The second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is an apparatus such as monitor, personal computer or the like to utilize contents as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. That is, the second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> corresponds to viewing equipment <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> in Embodiment 1. And the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is an apparatus offered in the form adapter to connect the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and the second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> Now, there will be described a use limit system as example in which a set top box is adopted as the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> and a monitor is used as the second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. It is to be understood that in the following description contents and related information will be collectively called &ldquo;data.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, it is assumed that data received by first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is trebly encrypted on broadcasting station side. This treble encryption consists of the following three: first encryption for protection in transmission between the broadcasting station and the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>; second encryption for transmission protection between the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and the second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>; and third encryption to prevent data from being used by a person who has not made a viewing contract with the contents agent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> First, data received by receiving means <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> in the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is usually encrypted (scrambled) by the first encryption method (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> Therefore, first decryption means <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> which receives the encrypted data from the receiving means <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> decrypts (descrambles) this data using first decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and then refers this decrypted data to sending means <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Steps S <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> The reason why data received by the receiving means <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> in the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is encrypted is to protect protection between the broadcasting station and the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (to provide the sending system with a special use limit). That is, the reason why data received by receiving means <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> in first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is encrypted is the same reason that the scramble key Ks and removal conditions in Embodiment 1 are encrypted with the work key Kw. Therefore, in case data received by the receiving means <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> in first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is not encrypted, it is not necessary to provide the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> with the first decryption means <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> and the first decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> Next, since data passed on to the sending means <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> in the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is encrypted by second encryption method, the data is inputted into second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> through a receiving means <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>). Hereby, second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> decrypts the data using second decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>), and then refers this decrypted data to third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> Thus, the reason why data received by receiving means <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is further encrypted is to provide protection between the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> and between the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> and the second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> (to provide the reproduction system with a special use limit). Therefore, in case those sections are not protected, that is, data received by the receiving means <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is not encrypted, it is not necessary to provide the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> with the second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> and the second decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and, furthermore, second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> which will be described later and second encryption key Ke<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Meanwhile, the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is provided with a function capable of reading storage medium M such as IC card in which &ldquo;third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> encrypted by fourth encryption method&rdquo; is stored by the broadcasting station. This storage medium M is given to a viewer by the broadcasting station when a viewing contract is made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> If the storage medium M is inserted on third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, reading means <highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight>, which detects that, reads &ldquo;third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> encrypted by fourth encryption method&rdquo; stored in storage medium M and passes the third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> on to a fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> Hereby, the fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> decrypts &ldquo;third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> encrypted by fourth encryption method&rdquo; using fourth decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and then passes this third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> on to the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> The reason why third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> stored in storage medium M is encrypted like that is to prevent this third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> from being read in other than the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. Therefore, in case this prevention mechanism is not provided, that is, in case third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> stored in storage medium M is not encrypted, it is not necessary to provide the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> with the fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> and the fourth decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> As a result, data decrypted by second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> and third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> decrypted by fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> are inputted into the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight>. Then, the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> decrypts the data using third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and refers this encrypted data to the second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> The reason why the data decrypted by second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> is further encrypted is to prevent the contents from being viewed by a person who has not made a viewing contract (to provide a use limit for contents). In other words, only a person who has made a viewing contract with the contents agent and has obtained storage medium M storing third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can remove the viewing limit to the contents by the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> But third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> read from the storage medium M as described above is a decryption key provided by the contents agent, but is not always a decryption key for the contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> That is, if the third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> read from storage medium M is a decryption key for the contents, the data decrypted by the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> (data with the viewing limit removed) is inputted into the second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>: YES&rarr;S <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>). On the other hand, in case third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> read from storage medium M is not a decryption key for the contents, the third decryption will fail. Therefore, data encrypted by the third encryption method (data with the viewing limit) is inputted into second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>: NO). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> As the third decryption key, the physical features of a person who makes a viewing contract may be used. In this case, the contents agent also uses the physical features of the contract viewer to encrypt contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> For example, the contents agent encrypts contents using the fingerprint of the viewing contract person. When the contract person views contents, the viewer inserts the storage medium M into the third apparatus and has the fingerprint read by a fingerprint reader provided in the storage medium M. The fingerprint read by storage medium M is inputted into third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> via reading means <highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> in third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> Thus, the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> is provided with functions possessed by the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> in Embodiment 1, while fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> is provided with functions possessed by the judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of set top box <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> It is noted that the fingerprint reader may be provided in third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> and not in the storage medium M. If the fingerprint reader is provided in third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, the viewer does not have to insert the storage medium into the third apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in case contents encrypted with the physical features are decrypted, it is not necessary to provide third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> with the fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> and fourth decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> As described above, the encrypted contents and the user&apos;s fingerprint are inputted into the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight>. Only in case the inputted fingerprint is a fingerprint used for encryption of contents, the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> can decrypt contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> Now, if data is inputted into second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> from the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> as described above, second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> encrypts the data using second encryption key Ke<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and then refers this encrypted data to sending means <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Steps S <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> And since the data referred to the sending means <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is encrypted by the second encryption method, the data is inputted into second decryption means <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> via receiving means <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> in the second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>). Hereby, the second decryption means <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> decrypts the data using second decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>), and then passes this decrypted data on to digital/analog conversion means <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> Finally, the digital/analog conversion means <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> converts into an analog signal the data received from second decryption means <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> and inputs the signal into display means <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>, and then the contents is displayed on this display means <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, Steps S <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> But in case third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> read from storage medium M is not a decryption key for the contents, the data referred to the digital/analog conversion means <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> from second decryption means <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> as described above is data encrypted by the third encryption method (data with a viewing limit). Therefore, needless to say, normal display can not be obtained in the display means <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in such a case. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> As set forth above, the present invention is so arranged that the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> which functions as removal means <highlight><bold>339</bold></highlight> is provided in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. Then, as long as each contents agent follows specific rules (for example, inputted data is decrypted by second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>, and data to be outputted is encrypted by second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>), the agent, in addition, can offer the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> provided with the use limit using its own means or its own algorithm. That is, each contents agent can decide to adopt what kind or intensity of encryption method as third encryption method or whether to encrypt third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, as set forth above, the following rules are promised in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> to which the present invention is applied. That is, inputted data is decrypted by the second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>, and data to be outputted is encrypted by the second encryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is possible to connect the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> via a plurality of the third apparatuses <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> as via connecting third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>offered by contents agent A, third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>offered by contents agent B, third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>offered by contents agent C as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. In this case, for example, to remove the use limit on contents offered by contents agent B, removal information (third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) is inputted into removal means (third decryption means) <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> provided in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EMBODIMENT 6 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> An arrangement may be so made that only in case trebly encrypted data by first to third encryption methods as in Embodiment 5 is broadcast together with the physical features of viewers and the physical features of viewers who have made a viewing contract is inputted into the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, the data can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> In this case, if a viewer makes a viewing contract, the broadcasting station broadcasts the work key Kw encrypted with the master key Km registered with the master key management means <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> in third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the work key Kw encrypted with the master key Km is received by separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> via first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of the viewer and receiving means <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>. The separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> inputs into decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> the work key Kw encrypted with the received master key Km. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> If work key Kw encrypted with the master key Km is inputted, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> takes out the master key Km from the master key management means <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>, decrypts work key Kw and registers the decrypted the work key Kw with the work key management means <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> As Embodiment 1, the trebly encrypted data (encrypted by first to third encryption methods) is multiplexed with the physical features of all the viewers encrypted with the work key Kw and broadcast. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> As in Embodiment 5, the trebly encrypted data is received by the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> via the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and the receiving means <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> in third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, while the physical features of all the viewers encrypted with the work key Kw is received by the separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in a state encrypted with the work key Kw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> The separating means <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> inputs the trebly encrypted data into the second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> and inputs in decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> the physical features of all the viewers encrypted with work key Kw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> The second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> decrypts the received data with second decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as described above and passes the data on to the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> Meanwhile, if the physical features of all the viewers encrypted with work key Kw is inputted, the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> takes out work key Kw from the work key management means <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, decrypts the physical features and transfers the decrypted physical features to the judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> When a viewer is going to use data, the user inserts into the third apparatus the storage medium M distributed by the broadcasting station as in Embodiment 5. In the present Embodiment 6, the storage medium M stores the physical feature N of viewers to whom the storage medium M is distributed as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> and third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> If storage medium M is inserted, the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> provided in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> acquires the physical feature N stored in the storage medium M and third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and inputs into the judgment means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> the acquired physical feature N and third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> If the physical features are inputted from the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> judges whether it can be considered that the physical features inputted from the decryption means <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and those from the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> are the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> If they are judged as identical, the judgement means <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> gives the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> inputted from the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> Receiving third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> decrypts data transferred from second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> using the third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The removal means <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> gives the decrypted data to second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> in third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> as in Embodiment 5. The subsequent processing is identical with that in Embodiment 5. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> As set forth above, only in case the physical feature N of a viewer who has made a viewing contract is inputted into the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, data will be decrypted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> In the above description, the storage medium M stores physical feature N. In case the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is provided with feature the reading sensor <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> the storage medium M does not have to store physical feature N. In this case, the acquisition means <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> acquires physical feature N through the feature reading sensor <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EMBODIMENT 7 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a schematic function diagram of the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> in the present embodiment. The arrangement will be described limiting to the points different from those in Embodiment 5. The first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> are identical with those in Embodiment 5 and will not be described in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> First, the data passed on to the sending means <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> in the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> in the same procedure as in Embodiment 5 is already encrypted by the second encryption method, and will be inputted into the second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> through the receiving means <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> in third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, Steps S <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&rarr;S<highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>). Hereby, the second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> decrypts the data using second decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) and then refers this decrypted data to the analysis means <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> The data that is passed on to analysis means <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> is separated into contents, viewing limit flag information and other information which will be described hereunder (contents agent information, for example) (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>). And viewing limit flag information is inputted into the third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> while other information (that is, contents and other information) is inputted into the second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;viewing limit flag information&rdquo; is information indicating whether it is possible to view the content. For example, if the viewing limit flag information is set to &ldquo;1,&rdquo; it indicates that it is possible to view the contents. Hereunder, therefore, such viewing limit flag information shall be called &ldquo;viewable flag information.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, if viewing limit flag information is set to &ldquo;0,&rdquo; it means that the viewing of the contents is prohibited. Hereunder, therefore, such viewing limit flag information shall be called &ldquo;viewing prohibiting flag information.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> Now, if the storage medium M is inserted into the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, the reading means <highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight>, which detects that, reads &ldquo;viewing permitting information A encrypted by the fourth encryption method&rdquo; stored in storage medium M and passes the information on to the fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>. Hereby, the fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> decrypts &ldquo;viewing permitting information A encrypted by the fourth encryption method&rdquo; using fourth decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and passes this viewing permitting information A to flag information altering means <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> Now, viewing limit flag information extracted from data by the analysis means <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> and viewing permitting information A decrypted by the fourth decryption means <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> have been inputted into flag information altering means <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. Then, in case the viewing limit flag information is viewing prohibiting flag information, flag information altering means <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> alters this viewing prohibiting flag information into viewable flag information and passes this information on to second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> Viewing permitting information A read from the storage medium M as mentioned above is viewing permitting information A offered by the contents agent but is not always viewing permitting information A for the contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> That is, if viewing permitting information A read from the storage medium M is viewing permitting information A for the contents, viewing prohibiting flag information is altered into viewable flag information and inputted into second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>: YES&rarr;S<highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>). On the other hand, viewing permitting information A read from storage medium M is not viewing permitting information A for the contents, viewing prohibiting flag information will be inputted into the second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> without being altered (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, Step S <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>: NO). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> Now, if viewing limit flag information is inputted into the second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> from the flag information altering means <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> as mentioned above, the second encryption means <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> combines contents and other information inputted from the analysis means <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> and viewing limit flag information inputted from the flag information altering means <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. And the combined data thus obtained is encrypted using second encryption key Ke<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and then this encrypted data is passed on to the sending means <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, Steps S <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> After data is sent to second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> by sending means <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight>, the contents will be displayed on display means <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> or not be normally displayed. This is the same as in Embodiment 1 (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, Steps S <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>&rarr;S <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, as described above, the flag information altering means <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> which functions as third decryption means <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> is provided in the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. Hereby, each contents agent can offer the third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> provided with the use limit using its own means or its own algorithm. In the present embodiment, needless to say, it is also possible to connect the first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and the second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> via a plurality of the third apparatuses <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> The above description shows an example where third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or viewing permitting information A is stored in storage medium M and distributed, but the distribution of third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or the like is not limited to that arrangement. For example, the viewer himself or herself may input third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or the like using operating means (not shown) (bar code reader, fingerprint identifier etc.), or third decryption key Kd<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or the like may be embedded in incidental information of data. The same results can be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing description, encryption methods are distinguished using the terms first to fourth. But it is not always necessary that the methods are different from each other. For example, even if the second and fourth encryption methods are identical, the present invention will produce the same results. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0171" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0171&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, while no mention is made in the foregoing description in particular, the values of decryption key and encryption key may be fixed or variable. Needless to say, if the values are variable, it is necessary to have a means to change the values of a decryption key and encryption key, but such technique is well known and not the object of the present invention, and will not be explained in detail here. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0172" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0172&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing description, in addition, the flow of data is from first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> to second apparatus <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, but the present invention is not limited to that. For authentication of equipment, for example, two way communication has to be possible. A reverse path (that is, a path toward first apparatus <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>) may be provided within third apparatus <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0173" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0173&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in the foregoing description, limitation of viewing of contents is shown by way of example. The present invention is not limited to that. In examples where contents are used where the expression &ldquo;viewing&rdquo; does not fit (printing of contents, for example), the present invention can produce the same results. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0174" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0174&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the contents is not a TV program but may be confidential information that can be disclosed to a specific person only. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0175" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0175&rsqb;</number> As set forth above, if the use limit of contents and physical features for removal of the use limit of contents are used, the problems with the prior art will not be encountered. With the prior art, it can happen that the user forgets the decryption key and can not use contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0176" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0176&rsqb;</number> It can also happen that a third party steals the IC card in which the decryption key is stored and uses contents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0177" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0177&rsqb;</number> As long as each contents agent follows specific rules, the agent can offer a third apparatus provided with the use limit using its own means or its own algorithm. That is, each agent itself can decide what kind or intensity of encryption method should be adopted as third encryption method, or whether the third decryption should be encrypted or not. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0178" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0178&rsqb;</number> In the third apparatus to which the present invention is applied, furthermore, the following rules are prescribed. That is, inputted data is decrypted by the second decryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>, and data to be outputted is encrypted by the second encryption means <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0179" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0179&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is possible to connect the first apparatus and the second apparatus via a plurality of the third apparatuses. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A sending apparatus in a transmission system confirming that use permit information included in contents is identical with use permit information in a receiver and making it possible to use said contents, said sending apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>storage means for storing physical features of a contents user as said use permit information and </claim-text>
<claim-text>multiplexing means for multiplexing said physical features and contents. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The sending apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> which further comprises scrambling means for scrambling said contents. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The sending apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> which further comprises encryption means for encrypting said physical features. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The sending apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said physical features include at least one of fingerprint, palm print, hand print, voiceprint, pattern of the retina, pattern of the iris, form of the face, and DNA (deoxyribo nucleic acid). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A receiving apparatus which comprises: 
<claim-text>receiving means for receiving multiplexed information in which the physical features of a contents user and contents are multiplexed, </claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring means for acquiring the physical features of the content user included in said multiplexed information, </claim-text>
<claim-text>judging means for judging whether the physical features of said contents user acquired by said acquiring means are identical with the physical features of a contents user received by said receiving means, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removal means that makes it possible to use contents included in multiplexed information received by said receiving means if said judging means judges that the physical features are identical. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> which further comprises removal means for descrambling contents if the contents included in said multiplexed information is scrambled. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> which further comprises decryption means for decrypting physical features if the physical features of a contents user included in said multiplexed information is encrypted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> which further comprises a feature reader for reading the physical features of said contents user, said reader being fixable on and detachable from said acquiring means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said physical features include at least one of fingerprint, palm print, hand print, voiceprint, pattern of the retina, pattern of the iris, form of the face, and DNA. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A receiving apparatus which comprises: 
<claim-text>storage means storing the physical features of a contents user as use permit information, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sending apparatus comprising multiplexing means for multiplexing said physical features and contents, </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving means for receiving multiplexed information where said physical features and contents are multiplexed, </claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring means for acquiring the physical features of a contents user, </claim-text>
<claim-text>judging means for judging whether the physical features of said contents user acquired by said acquiring means are identical with the physical features of a contents user received by said receiving means, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removal means that makes it possible to use contents included in multiplexed information received by said receiving means if said judging means judges that the physical features are identical. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A contents sending method used in a transmission system confirming that use permit information included in contents is identical with use permit information in a receiver and making it possible to use said contents, said sending method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>scrambling contents and </claim-text>
<claim-text>multiplexing said physical features and scrambled contents. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A receiving apparatus in a system handling contents provided with a use limit for the transmission, a use limit for the reproduction and a use limit for contents, said receiving apparatus comprises: 
<claim-text>reading means for reading a removal key to remove the use limit for the contents when contents with the use limit for the transmission removed is obtained, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removal means for removing the use limit for the contents using the removal key read by said reading means, and transferring the contents to an apparatus where the contents is used. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> which further comprises reading means for reading removal information from a storage medium and inputting the information into said removal means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> which further comprises operating means for inputting removal information into said removal means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> or <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> which further comprises removal information decryption means for decrypting removal information if the removal information is encrypted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said removal means is flag information altering means for converting use prohibiting flag information set on contents into use permitting flag information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The receiving apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said removal means is contents decryption means for decrypting encrypted contents. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A use limit system handling contents provided with a use limit the transmission, a use limit for the reproduction and a use limit for contents, said use limit system comprises: 
<claim-text>first apparatus for removing a use limit for transmission, </claim-text>
<claim-text>third apparatus for removing a use limit for contents when the contents with the use limit for the transmission removed is obtained, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>second apparatus for removing a use limit for the reproduction when the contents with a use limit for contents is removed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The use limit system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein after removing a use limit for the reproduction, said third apparatus sets a use limit for the reproduction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The use limit system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> wherein said first apparatus and said second apparatus are connected via a plurality of said third apparatuses.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030005311A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
