<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000250A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000250A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000250A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000250A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000250</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09881185</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010614</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>C03B018/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>065</class>
<subclass>029190</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>065</class>
<subclass>162000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Glass melting furnace</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alfonso</given-name>
<family-name>Arechaga</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Llodio</city>
<country-code>ES</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jesus</given-name>
<middle-name>Maria</middle-name>
<family-name>Ugarte</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Llodio</city>
<country-code>ES</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BIERMAN MUSERLIAN AND LUCAS</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>600 THIRD AVENUE</address-1>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10016</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Glass melting furnace, of the type consisting of a melting chamber, inside which is found the liquid glass mass, with an outlet, and at least one flue gas recuperative chamber, a means for supplying the influx of fuel, featuring at least one mass temperature gauge immersed in the liquid glass mass and placed approximately at a height (h<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) with respect to the bottom of the melting chamber of &frac13; to &frac15; of the height (h) of the level of the liquid glass mass, and &frac15; h&lE;h<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&lE;&frac13; h on the longitudinal axis of the melting chamber at a distance (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) with respect to the wall of the chamber opposite the outlet, of between 0.6 and 0.85% of the length of the melting chamber 0.61&lE;1<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&lE;0.85 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">For application in the manufacture of glass containers. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> In a glass melting furnace the burdens and temperature of the molten mass need to be controlled and regulated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The control and regulation of the burdens currently in use give acceptable results, but this is not the case with the control and adjustment of the temperatures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> It should be borne in mind that temperatures in a glass furnace are extremely high, usually above 1,300&deg; C., the molten mass of glass has an enormous thermal inertia, and glass containers are rejected because of flaws if they are not drawn from a glass mass at the right temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> This all leads to huge uncontrolled energy consumption and great losses &ldquo;a posteriori&rdquo; in rejected containers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The applicant has investigated the origin of the problems described above and considers that they are caused by the real temperatures of the glass mass in liquid form being unknown and that this is due to the fact that the current arrangement of the temperature gauges on the periphery of the liquid mass is basically inadequate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is considered that with these current arrangements no account is taken of the uncontrollable fluctuations in temperature inside the mass, the internal convention of the liquid glass mass, nor the variations in temperature in a synchronous disconnexion in the same liquid mass. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is also considered that the gauges used are not the right ones and fundamentally, as mentioned above, that the location of the temperature gauges is absolutely inadequate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The temperature gauges should be immersed in the liquid glass in the area that provides the best information regarding temperatures and detects the fluctuations in temperature in the mass as fast as possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> This area has been discovered by the applicant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> For this reason, the glass melting furnace in this invention is of the type that have a melting chamber with an outlet holding the liquid glass mass, and at least one flue gas recuperative chamber, means for supplying the influx of fuel, and featuring at least one temperature gauge for measuring mass immersed in the liquid glass mass and placed approximately: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> a) at a height with respect to the bottom of the melting chamber of &frac13; to &frac15; of the height of the level of the liquid glass mass, and </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&frac15; h&lE;h<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&lE;&frac13; h </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> b) on the longitudinal axis of the melting chamber at a distance with respect to the wall of the chamber opposite the outlet of between 0.6 and 0.85% of the length of the melting chamber </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>0.61&lE;1<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&lE;0.85 1 </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> It also features a means of calculating the derivative of the temperature in the liquid mass and the derivative of the temperature in the gases with regard to time based on the data provided by the mass temperature gauge(s) and the gas temperature gauge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In order to gain a better understanding of the current invention, diagrams are provided illustrating the best way to do this in practice, which are susceptible to additional modifications without affecting its fundamental basics.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a schematic front view of the glass melting furnace with the temperature gauges currently in existence and that proposed in this invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a schematic, partial plan view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> An example will now be provided of the practical and non-restrictive use of this invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> It is assumed that the furnace is installed with the corresponding monitoring devices for burdens such as silica, carbonates, lime or boron components, etc, for instance, by means of a level gauge (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) in the tap hole (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the liquid glass (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), which gives the corresponding orders to the bath hoppers of these burdens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The furnace itself is conventional with its melting chamber (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and flue gas recuperative chamber(s) (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) arranged so as to recover heat along with a corresponding saving in energy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> It is absolutely vital in a glass furnace that the temperature is controlled for the gases (g) and liquid glass (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Conventional furnaces have come with gas temperature gauges (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) located in the upper part of the melting chamber (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and several pairs of temperature gauges ( (a<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) for mass located at the bottom. In each pair of mass gauges, one of the gauges (a<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) is the main one and after passing the refractory (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>), protrudes very slightly above the liquid glass (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) to a height (h<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) of 2 or 3 cm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Contact with the liquid glass (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) deteriorates the lower protruding gauge (a<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) in three years, and in order for the furnace to go on working, there was another mass gauge (a<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) that replaces it and functions in its place. This second gauge (a<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) does not penetrate the molten glass (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and thus it is not as useful as the gauge it replaces (a<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> This method of measuring the temperature of the liquid glass has been shown to be inadequate in practice. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The applicant considers that the right gauges are not being used, nor are they being situated in the proper place, possibly because no account has been made up til now when this patent is being applied for, of some of the features of the molten glass mass in the melting chamber (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). We shall now examine three of these features: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> 1).&mdash;on the surface of the refractory, the temperature is usually about 1,300&deg; C. and on the surface (S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the liquid glass it is usually around 1,459&deg; C., each with substantial variations and great inertia. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> 2).&mdash;inside the mass of molten glass convection currents (C) are produced which, given the great viscosity&mdash;normally over 100 poises&mdash;of the liquid glass, produce speeds of virtually nothing in its contact with the refractory (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) and clearly noticeable inside the molten mass. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> 3).&mdash;given the great inertia of the mass of the liquid glass, its possible fluctuations are transmitted very slowly, being detected very late and only in part by the lower gauge (a<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> All of these considerations indicate that the dissatisfaction of glass manufacturers for the late and inadequate perception of what is happening in the glass mass is due, at least in part, to the mass temperature gauges (a<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>), (a<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The applicant has considered the previous features and has managed to ascertain the optimum area for placing the corresponding mass temperature gauge (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) in the mass of liquid glass, so that the user of the furnace can find out quickly and in the proper fashion what is happening inside. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The coordinates are approximately as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> OZ axis: the mass temperature gauge (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) should be immersed deep down inside the liquid mass to a height (h<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) with respect to the bottom of the refractory (S<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) of &frac13; to &frac15; of the height (h) of the level of the liquid mass &frac15;&lE;h<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&lE;&frac13;h, preferably being h<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&sime;&frac14; h. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> OY axis: Y&equals;O </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> OX axis: the temperature gauge (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) should be placed along the OX axis (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) of symmetry (longitudinal) of the melting chamber (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and outlet (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) towards the tap hole (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) as illustrated in the diagram and with respect to the wall (p) opposite the outlet (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) at a distance (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) of 0.6 to 0.85% of the length (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the melting chamber (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>0.61&lE;1<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&lE;0.85 1 </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In principle and given its optimum location, a single mass temperature gauge (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) is sufficient for the molten mass. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In order to avoid the gauge (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) from deteriorating in such an aggressive medium, it should be placed inside a molybdenum casing (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As an additional safety precaution, the molybdenum casing may house several gauges (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>), (b<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), (b<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>) so that the group will continue working despite the deterioration of the first one (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>), which can be removed easily. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The other gauges (b<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), (b<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>) can be treated in the same way as the first gauge (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>), as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The invention has been designed in such a way as to place two molybdenum casings in a series (one behind the other) each with its corresponding gauge in such a way that if the one immersed in the molten mass deteriorates, the other casing will push it completely inside the mass and take its place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> It is also important to know the temperature of the gases (g) produced by combustion in the melting chamber (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In order to avoid interferences of heat radiation from the walls of the melting chamber (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>), convection effects and so on, the gauge for measuring the temperature of the gases (g) or fumes should preferably be placed in a receptacle (r) set up outside the flue gas recuperative chamber (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>), for instance, on the walls of its refractory. A gauge (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) should be placed in each existing chamber (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Monitoring </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The temperature (&thgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) in the liquid mass of glass varies with the time (t): &thgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;f (t) with its corresponding derivative (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) being obtained from the data provided by the mass temperature gauge (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The temperature (&thgr;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) in the gases (g) varies with the time (t): &thgr;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&equals;f (t), with its corresponding derivative (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) being obtained from the data provided by the gas temperature gauge (b<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The corresponding software should be available programmed with a decision algorithm for regulating the influx of fuel into the melting chamber (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> At each moment, with the corresponding inertia and safety thresholds, the algorithm determines that:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="105PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SPEED OF CARRYING OUT</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>ORDER</entry>
<entry>ORDER</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="14PT" align="right"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="105PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>&plus;</entry>
<entry>positive</entry>
<entry>&plus;</entry>
<entry>&nabla; reduce</entry>
<entry>slowly</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&equals;</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>fuel</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&minus;</entry>
<entry>negative</entry>
<entry>&minus;</entry>
<entry>&Dgr; increase</entry>
<entry>quickly</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&equals;</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&equals;</entry>
<entry>fuel</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&plus;</entry>
<entry>positive</entry>
<entry>&minus;</entry>
<entry>alarm, furnace</entry>
<entry>fast</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&minus;</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&plus;</entry>
<entry>working at</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>abnormal rate</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In such a way that: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> 1. If the derivative (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) of the temperature of the gases and the derivative (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>) of the temperature of the liquid mass increase or do not change, the influx of fuel is slowly decreased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> 2. If one of the derivatives (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) decreases and the other fails to increase, the influx of fuel is rapidly increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> 3. If one of the derivatives increases and the other decreases, the alarm is set off for rapid intervention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The following considerations should be taken into account: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> A temperature is considered to be &ldquo;constant&rdquo; if its fluctuations are below 1.5&deg; C. and its period of fluctuation is less than 10 minutes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The furnace is accepted as stable if the temperatures of the mass gauge (&thgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) and the gas gauge (&thgr;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) remain constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Once an anomaly has been corrected by the system, the furnace adopts a steady rate for a certain period of time. The new values (&thgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) and (&thgr;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) of this new stable period (period of stability) are retained as a reference for the future. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The diagrams are schematic and explicative, so that the comparative dimensions of the elements are not real, for instance, the size of the mass gauge (b<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) or its casing (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) are smaller than as shown in the diagrams. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Glass melting furnace of the type consisting of a melting chamber, inside which is found the liquid glass mass, with an outlet, and at least one flue gas recuperative chamber, means for supplying the influx of fuel, featuring at least one mass temperature gauge immersed in the liquid glass mass and placed approximately: 
<claim-text>a) at a height (h<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>)with respect to the bottom of the melting chamber of &frac13; to &frac15; of the height (h) of the level of the liquid glass mass, and </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>&frac15; h&lE;h<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&lE;&frac13; h </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>b) on the longitudinal axis of the melting chamber at a distance (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) with respect to the wall of the chamber opposite the outlet, of between 0.6 and 0.85% of the length of the melting chamber </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>0.61&lE;1<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&lE;0.85 1 </in-line-formula></claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Glass melting furnace, according to the previous claim, featuring a mass temperature gauge housed inside a molybdenum casing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Glass melting furnace, according to the previous claims, featuring molybdenum casing housing several mass temperature gauges. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Glass melting furnace, according to the first claim, featuring a receptacle containing a gas temperature gauge connecting with each flue gas recuperative chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Glass melting furnace, according to the previous claims, featuring a means of calculating the derivative of the temperature inside the liquid mass (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) and the derivative of the temperature inside the gases (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) based on the data furnished by the temperature gauge(s) for mass and for gases, with respect to the time, with the decision of how best to supply the fuel being based on these derivatives (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>), (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Glass melting furnace, according to the fifth claim, featuring a decision based on these derivatives(&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>), (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), which is based on an algorithm, in such a way that: 
<claim-text>a) if the derivative (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) of the temperature of the gases and the derivative (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) of the temperature of the liquid mass increase or do not change, the influx of the fuel is slowly decreased. </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) if one of the derivatives (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) (&thgr;&prime;<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) decreases and the other fails to increase, the influx of fuel is rapidly increased. </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) if one of the derivatives increases and the other decreases, the alarm is set off for rapid intervention.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000250A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000250A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
