<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001328A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001328A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001328A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001328A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001328A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001328A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001328A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001328A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001328A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001328A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001328A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001328A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001328</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09882002</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010615</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B65H005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>271</class>
<subclass>010010</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>271</class>
<subclass>010090</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and method for separating sheet material by means of a reciprocating disk separator</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hall</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Plattsburgh</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HESLIN ROTHENBERG FARLEY &amp; MESITI PC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>5 COLUMBIA CIRCLE</address-1>
<city>ALBANY</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>12203</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A feeding and conveying system for feeding and conveying sheet material for printing, collating, or binding the sheet material, among other processes. The feeding and conveying system includes at least one feeder having a magazine containing a plurality of articles of sheet material, for example, signatures, a rotatable disk for separating the sheet material from the magazine, and a feed drum for transferring the sheet material from the magazine to a conveyor. The rotatable disk, having at least one separating blade, is reciprocally rotated to separate the sheet material from the magazine. The separation of the sheet material from the magazine may be aided by applying a source of vacuum to the sheet material, for example, by means of suckers. The feed drum may include one or more grasping devices for grasping and retaining the sheet material, for example, one or more grippers. The rotation of the separator disk may be controlled by a programmable controller. The feeding and conveying system provides for increased throughput while minimizing or eliminating misalignment of the sheet material during handling. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to sheet material handling systems, and more particularly to devices for separating signatures during the collating and binding of, for example, books. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The binding and printing industries often rely on high-speed sheet material handling systems for printing, collating, and binding and otherwise handling sheet material, for example, sheets of paper. This sheet material, for example, individual sheets, newspapers, magazines, inserts and &ldquo;onserts&rdquo; (that is, referring to sheet material used when collating newspapers), books, brochures, and the like, is typically, stacked in containers or &ldquo;magazines&rdquo; or &ldquo;hoppers&rdquo; and withdrawn from the magazines or hoppers for further processing. One particular sheet material that is handled in the binding and printing industry is what is known in the art as &ldquo;signatures&rdquo;. Signatures are sheets of paper, that may have a spine fold, that contain at least two pages of text. Typically signatures contain 4 or more pages of text, for example, 30 or more pages of text. In the manufacture of books it is common to assemble the book on a collecting conveyor by sequentially withdrawing signatures from magazines, or hoppers, containing stacks of signatures. In producing a book, typically, a plurality of serially-arranged magazines, separating devices, and feeders are employed for gathering the printed sheets of, for example, signatures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Typically, the separating devices separate and withdraw the sheet material from the magazines and feed the sheet material to a rotating drum. The rotating drum then feeds the sheet material to a conveyor which collects and transfers the separated printed sheets for collation, binding, or other operations. The separation of the sheet material from the stacked sheet material can be effected by a rotating disk separator aided by a suction device, known in the art as a &ldquo;sucker&rdquo;. One typical disk-type separator is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,193,229 B1, the disclosure of which is incorporated by reference herein in its entirety. The disk separator separates and feeds the sheet material to a rotating drum which accepts and retains the sheet material and conveys it to the conveyor. The disk separator, typically with the aid of the suction device, deflects the edge of the lower-most article of sheet material in the magazine stack. When the sheets to be withdrawn from the magazine are in the form of signatures, the deflected edge is typically the spine fold portion of the sheet. The rotating drum positioned below the disk separator typically includes some means of retaining the sheet material as it rotates, for example, devices known in the art as &ldquo;grippers&rdquo;. The conveyor which receives the sheet material is typically a horizontal conveyor. This horizontal conveyor may also receive sheet material from other, typically serially-positioned, feeding drums. A common drive mechanism typically drives the separator, suction device, feed drum, and the conveyer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The throughput of such systems is dependent upon on how closely together the sheet material is spaced, and on how fast the sheet material is moved. Accordingly, the throughput of such systems may be optimized by spacing the sheet material as closely together as possible and by maximizing the speed of operation of each of the components. For example, the rotational speed of the separator disk is of fundamental importance to performance of such sheet material handling systems. The faster the separator disk can rotate from the position where it enters the stack of sheet material to the position where the sheet material is separated, the better the system throughput. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Another important considering in the operation of disk-type separators is the alignment of the sheet material with separator disk. Since the disk separators of such devices rotate at high speed and typically &ldquo;bite into&rdquo; the stack of sheet material in the magazine, misalignment of the sheet material and the disk can cause misfeeds, jamming, or even damage to the equipment. According to the prior art methods the disk separators rotate in one direction and thus repeatedly impact the stack of sheet material in essentially one direction. This repeated engagement of the disk with the stack can cause the stack or individual articles within the stack to migrate or move in the direction of rotation of the disk. This migration of the sheet material can result in the misalignment and its potential consequences mentioned above. This disadvantage of the prior art is overcome by one aspect of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Commonly-assigned U.S. Pat. No. 6,193,229 B1 discloses a method and apparatus for improving the throughput of a sheet material feeding system having a disk-type separator. This improvement is provided by using a servo-motor-driven disk separator to vary the speed of rotation of the disk separator. The speed of the servo-motor is monitored and controlled by means of a servo-control system, that is, an automated feed-back control loop. Though the method and apparatus for feeding disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,193,229 B1 provides an effective means for controlling and feeding sheet material, the present invention provides improvements which further enhance the effectiveness of disk-type sheet-material feeders. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides methods and apparatus which address many of the limitations of prior art methods and apparatus. One aspect of the present invention is a feeder for delivering at least one article of sheet material to a conveyer. The feeder includes: a rotatable separator disk for separating stacked articles of sheet material; a servomotor mechanically coupled to the separator disk adapted to impart reciprocating rotation to the separator disk; and a rotatable feed drum oriented to receive the article separated by the separator disk and to transfer the article of sheet material to the conveyor. The articles of sheet material may be sheets of paper, signatures, newsprint, magazines, inserts, onserts, flyers, or brochures. It will be understood by those familiar with the art that the conveyor may be a collator or a gatherer. In one aspect of the invention, the servomotor reverses the rotation of the separator disk after the disk enters the stacked articles of sheet material. The feeder may further include a servo-control system coupled with the servomotor. The servomotor is typically adapted to rotate the disk in a first direction and rotate the disk in a second direction, opposite the first direction. The servo-control system is typically programmable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> One advantage of the present invention compared to the prior art is that the back and forth motion of the separator tends to prevent movement or migration of the sheet material in the magazine, which can characterize prior art systems having non-reciprocating motion of the disk. For example, the return stroke of the disk helps to compensate for any deflection of the stack of sheet material that occurs due to the separating stroke. Thus, according to one aspect of the present invention, misalignment of the sheet material with the separator disk or drum, which can cause misfeeds or otherwise interfere with proper operation of the feed system, is minimized or eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention is a method for separating articles of sheet material. The method includes: providing a separator disk for separating at least one article of sheet material from a stack of sheet material; providing a servomotor for rotating the separator disk; and reciprocatingly rotating the separator disk to separate the articles of sheet material from the stack of sheet material. Reciprocatingly rotating is typically practiced by a) rotating the separator disk in a first direction and b) rotating the separator disk in a second direction, opposite the first direction. Steps a) and b) are typically repeated, for example, b) may be practiced immediately after a). Also, a) is typically practiced by accelerating the disk to first rotational speed and b) is practiced by accelerating the disk to second rotational speed; the first rotational speed may be about equal to the second rotational speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention is a method for separating articles of sheet material and feeding the articles of sheet material to a conveyor. The method includes: providing a magazine containing at least one article of sheet material; providing a separator disk for separating at least one article of sheet material in the magazine; providing a feed drum oriented to receive the at least one separated article of sheet material and transfer the at least one separated article to the conveyor; reciprocatingly rotating the separator disk to separate the at least one article of sheet material from the magazine; transferring the at least one separated article of sheet material from the magazine to the feed drum; and transferring the separated at least one article of sheet material from the feed drum to the conveyor. This method may further include deflecting the edge of the article of sheet material prior to transferring the separated article from the magazine to the feed drum, for example, by applying a source of vacuum to the article of sheet material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A still further aspect of the present invention is a system for separating articles of sheet material. The system includes: a rotatable separator disk for separating stacked articles of sheet material; a motor operatively connected to the separator disk for rotating the separator disk; and a programmable controller for controlling the operation of the motor. The programmable controller is typically programmed to operate the motor whereby the separator disk is reciprocatingly rotated, that is, the separator disk is rotated in a first direction and then rotated in a second direction, opposite the first direction, for example, immediately after rotating the disk in the first direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> An even further aspect of the present invention is a feeder for delivering articles of sheet material to a conveyer. The feeder includes: a rotatable separator disk for separating stacked articles of sheet material; a motor operatively connected to the separator disk for rotating the separator disk; a programmable control system for controlling the operation of the motor; and a rotatable feed drum oriented to receive the articles of sheet material separated by the separator disk and transfer the articles of sheet material to the conveyor. The programmable control system is typically programmed to control at least the speed of rotation of the motor. In one aspect of the invention, the programmable control system is programmed to operate the motor whereby the separator disk is reciprocatingly rotated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A still further aspect of the present invention is a method for separating articles of sheet material and feeding the articles of sheet material to a conveyor. The method includes: providing a magazine containing articles of sheet material; providing a separator disk driven by a motor for separating at least one article of sheet material in the magazine; providing a programmable controller system for controlling the rotation of the separator disk; providing a feed drum oriented to receive at least one separated article of sheet material and transfer the separated article of sheet material to the conveyor; rotating the separator disk in response to the programmable controller to separate at least one article of sheet material from the magazine; transferring the at least one separated article of sheet material from the magazine to the feed drum; and transferring the at least one separated article of sheet material from the feed drum to the conveyor. This method may further include deflecting an edge of the article of sheet material prior to transferring the separated article of sheet material from the magazine to the feed drum. Transferring the separated article of sheet material from the magazine to the feed drum is typically practiced by grasping the article with grippers mounted on the feed drum. Again, in one aspect of the invention, rotating the separator disk in response to the programmable controller is practiced by reciprocatingly rotating the separator disk. For example, in one aspect of the invention, reciprocatingly rotating the separator disk is practiced whereby misalignment of the articles of sheet material in the magazine is minimized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> These and other embodiments and aspects of the present invention will become more apparent upon review of the attached drawings, description below, and attached claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The subject matter which is regarded as the invention is particularly pointed out and distinctly claimed in the concluding portion of the specification. The invention, however, both as to organization and method of practice, together with further objects and advantages thereof, may best be understood by reference to the following detailed descriptions of the preferred embodiments and the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side view of a feeding and conveying system for sheet material which incorporates one aspect of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side view of the sheet material feeder shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in accordance with one aspect of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of a separator disk that can be used with one aspect of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top view of a separator disk that can be used with another aspect of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is graph of various feed system parameters as a function of degree of drum rotation according to one aspect of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic block diagram of a servo-control system which can be used to control the feeding and conveying system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in accordance with one aspect of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a feeding and conveying system, generally designated with the reference numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, for feeding and conveying sheet material that employs one aspect of the present invention. The sheet material that can be fed and conveyed includes, but is not limited to, individual sheets, signatures, newspapers, magazines, books, booklets, brochures, inserts, or onserts, among other types of sheet material. Feeding and conveyer system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> typically includes a conveyer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and at least one, typically more than one, sheet material feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Each feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes a rotatable feed drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a magazine <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and a separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) driven by a servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> separates sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> from the magazine <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and feeds it via drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be collating conveyor, that is, a collator, or a gathering conveyor, that is, a gatherer, among other types of conveyors. For example, in one aspect of the invention, conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> receives onserts from feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> which are placed on top of articles of sheet material, for example, other onserts, that are already on conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The conveyer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is positioned with respect to the feed drums <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for receiving sheet material from feed drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Feed drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> rotates and delivers sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, typically one at a time, to conveyer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Conveyer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, in accordance with one aspect of the invention, functions to gather, collate, or otherwise handle sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. For example, feeding and conveying system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> includes multiple feeders <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and is configured to enable conveyer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to gather and collate sheet material for a binding machine, though the system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> may be used to convey sheet material to other types of machines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a detailed view of the components that comprise sheet material feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> which feeds conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a collating-type of conveyor, though other types of conveyors may be used. As noted above, feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes a rotatable feed drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a magazine <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and a separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> driven by a servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> typically also includes means for deflecting the edge of an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> from the magazine <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. One means for deflecting the edge of an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> from the magazine <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be means for selectively applying a source of vacuum to the lower-most article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> in magazine <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. In the aspect shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> known in the art as a &ldquo;sucker&rdquo; is used for selectively applying a source of vacuum. Sucker or suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is operatively connected to a source of vacuum (not shown) and is adapted to selectively apply the vacuum to the sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, for example, as a synchronized function of the relative rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is also typically pivotally mounted for rotation as indicated by double arrow <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, that is, suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> may be raised and lowered to engage and deflect sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> typically applies a vacuum to the surface of an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> that varies from about 18 inches of Hg (that is, inches of mercury) to about 25 inches of Hg. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is mechanically coupled to servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> typically rotates disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> at maximum speeds of between about 900 rpm and about 1200 rpm. Separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is positioned adjacent to magazine <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> whereby at least a portion of the surface of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> engages and separates at least one article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, typically only one article <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> at a time. After an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is engaged and deflected by suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> engages and deflects article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> whereby article <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> can be engaged and retained by drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Typically, only an edge of an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is deflected by suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and each article <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is drawn out of the magazine by the rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. According to one aspect of the present invention, the rotation of servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and thus separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is controlled whereby disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is reciprocatingly rotated, that is, disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is rotated in a first direction and then in a second direction, opposite the first direction, and preferably repeatedly. Each repeated rotation in one direction and then rotation in the second, opposite direction comprises a machine cycle for servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and disk and typically undergoes between about 250 and about 350 machine cycles per minute. This reciprocal rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will be discussed further with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> After sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is engaged by and deflected by suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> engages and further deflects and separates an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is positioned to be captured by feed drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The separated article of sheet material on drum <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is identified by reference number <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In the view shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, feed drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> rotates in a counter-clockwise direction as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Typically, feed drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes some means for grasping and capturing article of sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from magazine <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and transferring it to conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. One means of grasping, capturing, and transferring sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is by means of hinged linkages <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> that are selectively opened and closed to grasp and release an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Linkages <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are known in the art as &ldquo;grippers&rdquo;. Drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may have one or more grippers, and typically two or more grippers evenly spaced about the periphery of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. For example, in one aspect of the present invention three grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are used. Grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> retain the separated sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and transfer it with the rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. When the sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is in position over conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, gripper <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> opens allowing sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to fall, typically, simply under the force of gravity, upon conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The position of grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, that is, either opened or closed, is typically controlled and synchronized with the relative rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the operation of suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to ensure the uninterrupted movement of articles of sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from magazine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> having a single protrusion or blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> that can be used to effect the present invention. Blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a leading edge <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and a trailing edge <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> also includes a recess <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and a axial hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> for mechanically coupling disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. According to one aspect of the present invention, separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is reciprocally rotated by servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. During operation, after the edge of the sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is deflected by suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), the rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> causes leading edge <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to contact stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> whereby the edge of the lower-most sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> enters recess <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. Further rotation of separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> causes blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to &ldquo;bite&rdquo; into stacked sheet -material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, separating sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from the stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. After separation of sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from the stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is complete, trailing edge <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> exits stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the present invention, after blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> separates an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from the stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, for example, after trailing edge <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> passes through stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is slowed, stopped (typically momentarily) and then reversed by servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> whereby blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> passes through the stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. That is, the direction of rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is reversed. After blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> passes through stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in the direction arrow <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, for example, after leading edge <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> passes through stacked sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, the rotation of blade <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is again slowed and reversed whereby the next article of sheet material is engaged and deflected by blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. According to one aspect of the present invention, this cycle of rotating disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and then in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, that is, in reciprocally rotating disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, is essentially continuously repeated as long as necessary, for example, at a rate of between about 250 and about 350 machine cycles per minute. In addition to effectively separating sheet material, this reciprocal rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, among other things, minimizes the misalignment, or mis-registration, of the stacked sheet material that can occur when a separator disk, such as disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, is continuously rotated in a single direction. Repeatedly engaging the stack of sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in the same direction, as would happen when disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is only rotated in one direction, that is, not reciprocated, can physically move or shift the stack <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> from its desired position in the feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, causing mis-alignment of, among other things, the stack <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the stack <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the suction device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. This mis-alignment is minimized or eliminated entirely when the rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is reciprocated according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates another separator disk <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> that can be used for the present invention, which is a variation of separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Separator disk <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> has two opposing protrusions or blades <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>&prime;. Blades <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>&prime; oppose each other to enable separator disk <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> to selectively rotate in either of the two directions indicated by double arrow <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Blades <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>&prime; have leading edges <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>&prime; and trailing edges <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>&prime;, respectively. Disk <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> includes two recesses <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>&prime; and an axial hole <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>. Blades <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>&prime;; leading edges <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>&prime;; trailing edges <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>&prime;; recesses <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>&prime;; and axial hole <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> all operate and function in the same fashion as the corresponding features described with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Rotation in the two directions indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is desirable depending on how articles of sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are stacked in feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. For example, having two reciprocating blades <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>&prime; on disk <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> doubles the throughput of feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> compared to the single-bladed disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The reciprocal motion of disk <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> also provides the same magazine sheet material alignment benefits discussed with respect to the reciprocation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> above. The double-bladed disk <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> can also be used in &ldquo;gatefold&rdquo; applications, that is, wherein the fold edge of the sheet material (for example, signature) is located on the feeder side of hopper <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. In gatefold applications, the operation of the feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is controlled so that the edge <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>&prime; first engages the stack of sheet material in a counter-clock-wise direction as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. According to one aspect of the present invention, for example, having a programmable system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, this reversal of disk <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> operation can be effected by a simple electronic switch, for example, either a manual or an automated switch, for instance, a switch that changes the direction of rotation of servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a graph <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> showing profiles of various parameters of the feeding and conveying system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of one aspect of the present invention as a function of the rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The profiles that appear in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> were computed for a feeder and conveyor system having the following parameters:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="105PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="98PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Drum 16 diameter:</entry>
<entry>17 inches</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Corresponding circumference</entry>
<entry>53.4 inches</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>of drum 16:</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>No. of grippers 26:</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Corresponding length of</entry>
<entry>120 degrees or 17.8 inches</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>drum arc between grippers:</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Maximum length of signature:</entry>
<entry>13.5 inches.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Curve <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is a typical representation of a rotational speed profile of separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as a function of the rotation of the drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> according to one aspect of the present invention. As shown on the left side of graph <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is approximately stationary at a time when the position of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is at a point A, for example, at approximately &minus;13 degrees from a reference position of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. This position of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is sometimes referred to as the &ldquo;disk home position&rdquo;. As controlled by servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, in response to servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>), disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> accelerates in a generally uniform fashion (for example, at a relatively constant angular acceleration) to a maximum speed B, for example, a speed of from about 600 rpm to about 900 rpm, depending upon the size and configuration of the sheet material being handled. The speed of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is typically maintained for a predetermined time interval, for example, speed B may be maintained for time interval corresponding to about 45 to about 55 degrees of rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. As shown by curve <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the speed of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> then decelerates in a generally uniform fashion (again, for example, at a relatively constant angular acceleration) whereby disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> comes to a momentary stop and then reverses direction and accelerates to a speed C rpm in the opposite direction, for example, a speed of from about 600 rpm to about 900 rpm. The magnitude of speed C may be the same as the magnitude of speed B. Again, the speed C is typically maintained for a predetermined time interval, which may be the same interval at which the speed B is maintained, for example, speed C may be maintained for time interval corresponding to about 45 to about 55 degrees of rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The speed of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> then decelerates in a generally uniform fashion (again, for example, at a relatively constant angular acceleration) and is stopped at a time corresponding to the position of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of from about 300 to about 310 degrees. Disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is then held stationary for a time period corresponding to about 20 to about 30 degrees of the rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> then accelerates again and the above disk speed profile is repeated. Curve <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> represents the corresponding profile of the displacement of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as a function of the rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The position of suckers <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are also illustrated in graph <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Curve <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> represents a typical profile of position of suckers <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, for example, &ldquo;up&rdquo; or &ldquo;down&rdquo;, as a function of the rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. As shown by curve <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, at a time corresponding to when drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is oriented in line with the reference, that is, at the zero degree position, suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are &ldquo;up&rdquo;, that is, rotated into contact with the lower-most article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. At this position in the profile, a vacuum is typically applied to suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Shortly thereafter, suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are deflected at a relatively uniform speed and attain the &ldquo;down&rdquo; position at a time interval corresponding to drum position D, for example, between about 20 and about 30 degrees beyond the zero reference position. Typically, when the suckers are in the &ldquo;down&rdquo; position, that is, displaced from the lower-most article of sheet material <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the vacuum is turned off from suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. As shown by curve <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> remain in the &ldquo;down&rdquo; position until the drum reaches orientation E, for example, at between about 320 degrees and about 330 degrees of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> rotation. The suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are then raised at a relatively uniform velocity to the &ldquo;up&rdquo; position at about 360 degrees, or after one full rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. During this deflection of suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> the vacuum is again applied to suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The position of sucker <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> then repeats this schedule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The state of grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, that is, &ldquo;opened&rdquo; or &ldquo;closed&rdquo;, is represented by curve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, again as a function of the rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. At a point corresponding to drum orientation A, grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are in the &ldquo;opened&rdquo; positioned. Grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> remain opened until drum <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> reaches a position F, for example, between about 70 degrees and 80 degrees of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> rotation, at which point grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> begin to close. At point G, for example, between about 80 and about 90 degrees, grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are &ldquo;closed&rdquo;. Grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> then remain closed until drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> reaches a position H, for example, between about 215 degrees and about 225 degrees. Grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> then partially open to an intermediate position to release an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> before fully opening beginning at a point E in preparation for subsequent closing on the next article of sheet material. Again, as shown by curve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>; this gripper position profile is then repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> also includes other reference information for the feeding and conveying system of the present invention. For example, point J is the position of the drum corresponding to the time when blade <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) enters the stack <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, for example, at a position of between about 30 degrees and about 40 degrees. Note that at this point, J, per curve <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is rotating at is maximum speed; per curve <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is approximately midway in its deflection from its reference location; per curve <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are closing; and per curve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are open. According to the present invention the reciprocating rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and the corresponding operation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, suckers <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are synchronized. This synchronization can be practiced mechanically, for example, via cams and timing belts, or electro-mechanically, for example, via linkages operated by actuators that are controlled by electronics, for example, by digital control software. In one aspect of the invention, the speed and position of separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is monitored and controlled by means of the servo-control system shown schematically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a servo-control system generally designated with the reference numeral <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> that can be used to practice one aspect of the present invention. Servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes a servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a position transducer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, a servo-amplifier <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, a comparator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, and a command signal generator <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> regulates and controls the operation of servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to regulate and control the displacement, speed, and acceleration of separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is programmable, for example, command signal generator <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> may be programmable. Servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may be programmed to regulate and control the displacement, speed, or acceleration of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in order to optimize the operation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and feeder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. In one aspect of the invention, servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is programmed to regulate the displacement, velocity, and acceleration of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to the schedules shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, though servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be programmed for any displacement, velocity, or acceleration schedule desired. Servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may be manually operable at the feeder, may be controlled from a desktop computer, may be integrated into a network of control systems designed to optimize handling system throughput, or controlled by means of any conventional programmable device, for example, a computer or programmable logic controller (PLC). It will be apparent to those in the art that servo-control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be integrated with new feeder systems or be retrofit to existing feeders. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> drives separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in response to the control algorithm of control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Position transducer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> provides an indication of the position of separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The position sensed by position transducer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is fed to comparator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> via feed back loop <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. Command signal generator <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> receives a position indication from drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> via electrical connection <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> and transfers a command position to comparator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> via electrical connection <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. Comparator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, via an appropriate algorithm, compares the command position and the feed back position of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and generates and error signal that is forwarded to amplifier <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> via connection <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. Servo-amplifier <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> amplifies this error signal and provides an amplified error signal to servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> via connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> which increase or decreases the speed of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to eliminate the error and conform to the desired speed schedule for disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, for example, the schedule defined by curve <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. As a result, control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> coordinates the rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> with the rotation of drum <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, so that, among other things, grippers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) are open and ready to receive an article of sheet material separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> separates an article of sheet material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from the stack of sheet material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is typically a variable speed servomotor that is mechanically coupled to and rotates separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. According to one aspect of the invention, servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes an absolute encoder coupled with comparator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> to deliver the position of separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to comparator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. According to an alternate aspect of the invention, servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes an incremental encoder, or a resolver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the present invention, control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> controls the operation of servomotor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to effect a reciprocating rotation to separator disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. One such reciprocating rotation is shown by curve <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. This reciprocal rotation of disk <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> according to one aspect of the present invention provides an effective means of separating sheet material for feeding to, for example, a sheet-material-collating conveyor. Compared to prior art methods, this reciprocal separation, among other things, minimizes or eliminates misalignment of the sheet material in the magazine that can occur during non-reciprocating separation that characterizes the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been particularly shown and described with reference to preferred embodiment, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes in form and details may be made to the invention without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention described in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A feeder for delivering at least one article of sheet material to a conveyer, comprising: 
<claim-text>a rotatable separator disk for separating stacked articles of sheet material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a servomotor mechanically coupled to the separator disk adapted to impart reciprocating rotation to the separator disk; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotatable feed drum oriented to receive the article separated by the separator disk and to transfer the article of sheet material to the conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the servomotor reverses the rotation of the separator disk after the disk enters the stacked articles of sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a servo-control system coupled with the servomotor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising at least one gripper mounted to the feed drum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the servomotor is adapted to rotate the disk in a first direction and rotate the disk in a second direction, opposite the first direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the servomotor rotates the disk at a first rotational speed in the first direction and rotates the disk at a second rotational speed in the second direction,. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first rotational speed and the second rotational speed are about equal in magnitude. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the servo-control system is programmable. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the articles of sheet material are one of sheets of paper, signatures, newsprint, magazines, inserts, onserts, flyers, and brochures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method for separating articles of sheet material, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a separator disk for separating at least one article of sheet material from a stack of sheet material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a servomotor for rotating the separator disk; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>reciprocatingly rotating the separator disk to separate the articles of sheet material from the stack of sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein reciprocatingly rotating is practiced by a) rotating the separator disk in a first direction and b) rotating the separator disk in a second direction, opposite the first direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a) and b) are repeated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein b) is practiced immediately after a). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a) is practiced to separate at least one article of sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a) is practiced by accelerating the disk to first rotational speed and b) is practiced by accelerating the disk to second rotational speed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first rotational speed is about equal to the second rotational speed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first rotational speed is between about 600 rpm and about 900 rpm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second rotational speeds are between about 600 rpm and about 900 rpm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a) and b) are practiced to separate articles of sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method for separating articles of sheet material and feeding the articles of sheet material to a conveyor, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a magazine containing at least one article of sheet material-; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a separator disk for separating at least one article of sheet material in the magazine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a feed drum oriented to receive the at least one separated article of sheet material and transfer the at least one separated article to the conveyor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>reciprocatingly rotating the separator disk to separate the at least one article of sheet material from the magazine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the at least one separated article of sheet material from the magazine to-the feed drum; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the separated at least one article of sheet material from the feed drum to the conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising deflecting an edge of the article of sheet material prior to transferring the separated article from the magazine to the feed drum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein deflecting the edge of the article of sheet material is practiced by applying a source of vacuum to the article of sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein applying a source of vacuum to the article of sheet material is practiced using suckers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein transferring the separated article of sheet material from the magazine to the feed drum is practiced by grasping the article of sheet material with grippers mounted on the feed drum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A system for separating articles of sheet material, comprising: 
<claim-text>a rotatable separator disk for separating stacked articles of sheet material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor operatively connected to the separator disk for rotating the separator disk; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a programmable controller for controlling the operation of the motor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the programmable controller is programmed to operate the motor whereby the separator disk is reciprocatingly rotated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein reciprocatingly rotating comprises rotating the separator disk in a first direction and rotating the disk in a second direction, opposite the first direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein rotating the disk in a second direction is practiced immediately after rotating the disk in the first direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising means for deflecting at least a portion of the article of sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for deflecting at least a portion of the article of sheet material comprises at least one source of vacuum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A feeder for delivering articles of sheet material to a conveyer, comprising: 
<claim-text>a rotatable separator disk for separating stacked articles of sheet material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor operatively connected to the separator disk for rotating the separator disk; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a programmable control system for controlling the operation of the motor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotatable feed drum oriented to receive the articles of sheet material separated by the separator disk and transfer the articles of sheet material to the conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the programmable control system is programmed to control at least the speed of rotation of the motor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the programmable control system comprises a command signal generator, a comparator, and a servo-amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the programmable control system is programmed to operate the motor whereby the separator disk is reciprocatingly rotated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein reciprocatingly rotating comprises rotating the separator disk in a first direction and rotating the disk in a second direction, opposite the first direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein rotating the disk in the second direction is practiced immediately after rotating the disk in the first direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising means for deflecting an edge of the article of sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for deflecting comprises at least one source of vacuum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising at least one gripper mounted on the feed drum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one article of sheet material comprises one of sheets of paper, signatures, newsprint, magazines, inserts, onserts, flyers, and brochures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A method for separating articles of sheet material and feeding the articles of sheet material to a conveyor, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a magazine containing articles of sheet material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a separator disk driven by a motor for separating at least one article of sheet material in the magazine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a programmable controller system for controlling the rotation of the separator disk; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a feed drum oriented to receive at least one separated article of sheet material and transfer the separated article of sheet material to the conveyor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>rotating the separator disk in response to the programmable controller to separate at least one article of sheet material from the magazine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the at least one separated article of sheet material from the magazine to the feed drum; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the at least one separated article of sheet material from the feed drum to the conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising deflecting an edge of the article of sheet material prior to transferring the separated article of sheet material from the magazine to the feed drum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein deflecting an edge of the article of sheet material is practiced by applying a source of vacuum to the article of sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein transferring the separated article of sheet material from the magazine to the feed drum is practiced by grasping the article with grippers mounted on the feed drum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein rotating the separator disk in response to the programmable controller is practiced by reciprocatingly rotating the separator disk. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein reciprocatingly rotating the separator disk is practiced whereby misalignment of the articles of sheet material in the magazine is minimized. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conveyor is one of a collating conveyor and a gathering conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conveyor is one of a collating conveyor and a gathering conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The feeder as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conveyor is one of a collating conveyor and a gathering conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conveyor is one of a collating conveyor and a gathering conveyor.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001328A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001328A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001328A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001328A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001328A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001328A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
