<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003207A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003207A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003207</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10186434</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A23G001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>426</class>
<subclass>421000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Ultrasonic forming of confectionery products</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10186434</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020701</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09716575</doc-number>
<document-date>20001119</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6431849</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09716575</doc-number>
<document-date>20001119</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09233773</doc-number>
<document-date>19990119</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6231330</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09233773</doc-number>
<document-date>19990119</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>08757589</doc-number>
<document-date>19961127</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>5861185</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>08757589</doc-number>
<document-date>19961127</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>08701394</doc-number>
<document-date>19960822</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>5871783</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Roberto</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Capodieci</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Glen Ellyn</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MCANDREWS HELD &amp; MALLOY, LTD</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>500 WEST MADISON STREET</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 3400</address-2>
<city>CHICAGO</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60661</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The invention provides for the manufacture of food products. In one preferred form, methods and apparatus are provided for cutting individual confectionery products from a slab or strip of product material into a product with a particular silhouette. In another form, the invention provides methods and apparatus for both cutting and forming individual confectionery products from strips or ropes. The process can be used for simply forming products from pre-cut segments or other blanks of confectionery material, including imparting a relatively precise texture, finish or detail to such products. The products may, but need not, be subsequently enrobed in chocolate or another coating. In still other embodiments, the confectionery material may comprise grains of a puffed cereal. In some instances, a matrix of plasticizable material holds the grains together and the confectionery material may also include, in addition to the puffed cereal, candied fruit bits, dry fruits, nuts, or the like. In some cases, the puffed cereal may be held together by surface contact between adjacent grains instead of being held by the matrix. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of application Ser. No. 08/701,394, filed Aug. 22, 1996. The present invention relates generally to the manufacture of food products. In one preferred form, the invention relates to methods and apparatus for cutting individual confectionery products from a slab or strip of product material into a product with a particular silhouette. In another form, the invention relates to methods and apparatus for both cutting and forming individual confectionery products from strips or ropes. Still further, the process can be used for simply forming products from pre-cut segments or other blanks of confectionery material, including imparting a relatively precise texture, finish or detail to such products. The products may, but need not, be subsequently enrobed in chocolate or another coating. In still other embodiments, the confectionery material may comprise grains of a puffed cereal. In some instances, a matrix of plasticizable material holds the grains together and the confectionery material may also include, in addition to the puffed cereal, candied fruit bits, dry fruits, nuts, or the like. In some cases, the puffed cereal may be held together by surface contact between adjacent grains instead of being held by the matrix. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The methods and apparatus are adapted to create individual confections which have the same taste, consistency and eating characteristics as those of the supply stock, i.e., they are &ldquo;true analogs&rdquo; of the supply stock. These methods and apparatus advantageously involve the utilization of ultrasonic energy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The simplest form of apparatus involves cutting shapes from a slab or suitably wide strip of material on a flat surface to create products having a given silhouette but opposed flat sides. More complex forms of the apparatus use one or more forming tools, each of which includes a cavity having interior surfaces which will impart a desired shape and surface detail or texture to the finished product. Where advantage is taken of a number of features of the invention, a continuous extruded strip or &ldquo;rope&rdquo; of confectionery material is continuously advanced and then intermittently engaged by a cutting and forming tool whose cutting edges and interior surfaces vibrate ultrasonically at a desired amplitude. As used herein, &ldquo;tool&rdquo; simply means the portion of an ultrasonically energized apparatus that cuts or imprints a shape to the product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> This enables a finished product of a desired shape and surface texture to be accurately formed by the tool and then released from the tool without having any residue from the product adhere to the interior of the tool, and without affecting the sensory characteristics of the product. The apparatus and methods can be used to create products which are the true analogs of other products made from the same ingredients but shaped or sized differently. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Where the cutting and forming tools are formed and sized appropriately, and moved in a desired sequence, and where the cross-section of the confectionery stock is controlled properly, the process can achieve so-called &ldquo;flashless molding&rdquo; of product and also virtually or completely eliminate scrap or the like by forming the entire strip into individual products, without leaving a web or other residue from which the individual pieces were formed. In the case of puffed cereal products, this may be referred to as &ldquo;flashless formation&rdquo; in that little or no scrap is created by the forming operations. Forming of puffed cereals is done by rearranging the shape or contours of the product, but without compressing the confectionery stock. This avoids any change in eating characteristics which might result from compressing or collapsing the cereal grains. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Many commercially produced confectionery products, such as, for example, candy bars, are formed by providing a slab which is then slit into multiple strips or what are sometimes termed &ldquo;ropes.&rdquo; These strips or ropes are cut into individual lengths and enrobed with a continuous coating, such as, for example, chocolate. Such cutting steps can be carried out at high speed but these steps do not customarily involve forming the product into any shape except that of simple geometric figures, usually a parallel piped or rectangular bar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Although it is known to be possible to form unusual shapes and to impart a great variety of surface finishes or textures to candy products, this is not able to be done with most candy products on a rapid, continuous basis. This is because such shapes are normally created by molding, which involves melting the candy product and allowing it to re-solidify. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In the candy business, a great deal of research and effort has been undertaken in an attempt to create products which have taste, consistency and eating characteristics of a particularly desired kind. Thus, candy bar centers are commonly made as layered products and include a variety of materials each having its own characteristic taste. These ingredients include nuts of various kinds, fruit inclusions, coconut, peanut butter, nougat, caramel, most or all of which are layered and then enrobed in dark or light chocolate, or the like. It has been found through research that the mere presence of the same or similar ingredients in two different products is not enough to ensure that they will have the same taste, consistency and eating characteristics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Thus, if the ingredients in one product are arranged in distinct layers, and in other products the same ingredients are simply intermixed, consumers will very often strongly prefer one product and not the other, in spite of the virtual identity of their ingredients on an overall basis. Many manufacturers have been unable to offer truly analogous products in shapes which differ significantly from those in which the products are customarily made. Accordingly, there has been a desire in the industry to be able to provide different versions or true analogs of particular, commercially popular candy bars in shapes different from their usual prior shapes. By &ldquo;true analogs&rdquo; as used herein is meant a product which does in fact have the same formulation, taste, consistency and eating characteristics as an original or reference product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Assuming that a product itself could be made into two or more analog forms, each having significantly different shapes, another question is whether the equipment used to make such analog products could be readily incorporated into existing production lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Consequently, the operational flexibility that could be achieved by simply inserting the apparatus necessary to make an analog product into a production line that need not otherwise be modified would be a significant advantage in the industry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> While it is known that three dimensional products or those with complex detail or surface texture can be formed from continuous slabs of material as described above without encountering the above-referenced difficulties to an extent considered significant, these known manufacturing methods have several of their own drawbacks. Such methods often termed &ldquo;flex molding,&rdquo; for example, are expensive and complex. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Flex molding is so-named because the molds which actually form the product are made from a flexible material, such as rubber. Consequently, it is possible to impart a somewhat complex decorative or like shape to the product and to remove a product, even one including undercuts or complex surface shapes from the mold as long as the mold sidewalls are flexible enough to be removed from the product without damaging it. However, there are a number of drawbacks to this method. First, it involves fluent, plasticized or even liquid state products, and such liquid state products cannot by their nature be true analog products. The time required to allow products to solidify sufficiently to allow their removal is a process requirement that militates strongly against high production rates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The size and complexity of flex molding equipment makes it expensive, causes it to occupy a great deal of space and makes it difficult to integrate into existing process equipment. Maintenance in some cases is difficult and expensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> At least one other prior art method has presented certain disadvantages and drawbacks. Among these are problems of adhesion between the tool cavity interior or other forming surface that can become very significant. Even the most minor amount of adhesion will prevent complete product release, and in this case, deposits can progressively build up until an unacceptable level of residual material is present. Then, the process must be stopped to clean the forming surfaces. Anything hampering the continuity of such a process is clearly a serious drawback. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Problems continue to arise in the confectionery industry when it is necessary to cut individual pieces from continuous slabs, strips or extrudable ropes of products. Another aspect of the difficulty in cutting pieces relates to commercially produced frozen confections such as ice cream or frozen yogurt. The present invention allows effortless cutting of slabs, strips or extrudable ropes without producing distortion or adhesions, even where there are inclusions such as nuts, bits of fruit and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The puffed cereal material may be presented in several ways. Where the cereal grains are received and held within a plasticizable matrix, the strip or slab of such product may be reformed at any time after the strip or slab itself is formed, inasmuch as the grains can be moved about when the matrix is plasticized. The operations include cutting individual pieces from a larger mass such as the strip or slab and forming them into characteristic shapes or products with visible surface texture. In those circumstances wherein there is no plasticizable matrix, it is customary to form an extruded rope of grains bound together at their outer surfaces without an adhesive matrix. This extruded rope is still pliable for a very short time immediately after merging from the extruder. It is only at this point that the rope may be formed into a confection of a shape determined by the tool contours without altering the texture or volume of the grains and without altering the eating characteristics of the final product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing and other disadvantages and the failure generally of the prior art to provide optimum methods and apparatus for forming individual food products from continuous strips or slabs, it is an object of the present invention to provide improved methods and apparatus for this purpose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide an improved apparatus and method for simultaneously cutting and forming confectionery products such as, for example, candy bars. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> One other object of the present invention is to provide an apparatus which will rapidly and readily cut a product having a given silhouette from a continuous web of material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide improved methods and apparatus for cutting and forming frozen confectionery products, with or without inclusions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the present invention is to provide methods and apparatus for ultrasonically cutting and forming three dimensionally shaped and/or surface textured or embossed confectionery products, both &ldquo;frozen&rdquo; or &ldquo;ambient&rdquo; (&ldquo;non-frozen&rdquo;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide an improved method and apparatus for ultrasonically energizing one or more &ldquo;acoustic tools&rdquo; (such as an ultrasonic horn) used to cut and form intricately shaped, surface textured confectionery products from a continuous slab, rope or strip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to use an acoustic tool for forming confectionery products, including puffed cereal products, from pre-cut, metered, or dosed portions of confectionery stock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Yet another object of the invention is to provide an improved method and apparatus for minimizing distortion of layered feedstock materials during the forming process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide a method and apparatus for cutting and forming intricately shaped and/or textured confectionery products in a single step, such methods and apparatus employing ultrasonic energy and specially designed forming tools. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the present invention is to provide an improved method and apparatus for cutting individual confectionery products from a strip or extruded rope of confectionery stock and simultaneously forming individual products by contacting the supply of material with a cutting and forming tool having ultrasonically vibrating surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Yet another object of the present invention is to provide a method and apparatus for forming confectionery products which readily fill a cavity of a complex shape to provide a product that is substantially free of voids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide a method and apparatus whereby confectionery products of a given height, length and width can be produced from a continuous strip of confectionery stock having a different height and width, all without disturbing the taste, consistency and eating characteristics of the feedstock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> An additional object of the invention is to provide an improved cutting and product forming system for making selectively shaped confectionery products, which system can easily be integrated into or installed on existing production lines with a minimum of capital expenditure and which can enable such production lines to achieve desirably high production rates, especially in relation to flex molding techniques and to maintain or improve quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a method and apparatus for substantially reducing the forces required to form novel confectionery shapes, thereby increasing the life of tools and other process equipment, and enabling products to be made at higher rates without increased cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> A still further object is to provide a process that is capable of concurrently producing both regular or conventional shapes as well as novelty shapes from the same feedstock, preferably on side-by-side lines using basically the same equipment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Yet another object of the present invention is to provide a confectionery forming method and apparatus wherein ultrasonic energy is used to achieve movement of the cavity defining surfaces to ensure that the product is fully and completely released from the mold thereby eliminating build-up of product residue on the working faces of the forming tools. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide a method of operating an ultrasonically energized tool so as to achieve the required energy transfer without waste of energy or degrading or damaging to the product or the tooling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention is to provide methods for operating ultrasonically energized equipment which include selectively varying the amplitude of vibration undergone by certain of the product contact surfaces during the cutting and forming cycles so as to utilize ultrasonic energy in the most effective way. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the invention is to provide a method of imparting ultrasonic energy to an ultrasonically vibrated mold in a definite sequence so as to achieving desired or necessary plasticity and secure complete mold release without unduly raising the surface and/or interior temperature of the product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> An additional object of the present invention is to provide methods for utilizing pairs of opposed, cooperating, ultrasonically energized forming tools in a synchronized relation to form products of complex shapes, including full three-dimensional shapes, in a continuous process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention is to enable the same process equipment to be used in forming finished products such as fudge or chocolate products, as is used in producing toffee or other shaped centers for a subsequently applied final coating such as chocolate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide a molding tool which will cut profile or silhouette shapes from a slab of continuous confectionery feedstock, creating a product with a flat top and bottom and a contoured outline or silhouette formed by a precise, ultrasonic vibration-assisted cutting action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Yet another object of the invention is to provide a method of substantially &ldquo;flashless&rdquo; molding of confectionery products from a continuous strip, rapidly forming a succession of individual products and utilizing the entire volume of the strip so that no residual web or non-product residue is created. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention is to utilize a multiple cavity tool to produce plural flashless, silhouette products from a slab to leave a web of minimum volume that can be recycled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Yet another object of the invention is to use an array of single or multiple cavity tools for producing silhouette products or cut and molded products from a slab of confectionery material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide certain apparatus and methods that will cut and/or form confectionery stock such as candy bar forming stock, and in modified or unmodified form, that will function equally well in cutting and/or forming puffed cereal slabs, strips or ropes of various kinds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the present invention is to provide a method of incorporating the intermittent motion of a pair of opposed tool sets into a process that includes supplying feedstock in continuous or rope form in order to make individual products from such continuous rope without creating waste, leftovers, and without unduly deforming the feedstock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The foregoing and other objects and advantages are achieved in practice by providing a method which includes using one or more ultrasonically energized forming tools to create individual confectionery products, including puffed cereal products, from a continuous slab of product by cutting and forming such individual uses through the use of a desired motion sequence, and the use of the ultrasonic energy to plasticize the product and impart a desired shape and surface texture thereto at high speed while securing complete release of the product from the forming tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The objects are also achieved by providing control of the amplitude of the ultrasonic energy supplied to the tools during product forming operations and by coordinating the motion sequence of some of the process equipment with other process equipment to achieve substantially flashless molding. In addition, the invention provide methods and apparatus involving the use of a reciprocating tool moving in cooperation with an indexable companion tool or anvil as a part of a continuous forming process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The manner in which the foregoing and other objects and advantages are achieved in practice will become more clearly apparent when reference is made to the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments of the invention set forth by way of example and shown in the accompanying drawings, wherein like references numbers indicate corresponding parts throughout. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view, with portions broken away, showing certain important elements of a preferred form of apparatus for forming individual confectionery products from a continuous supply of confectionery feedstock; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, showing certain of the structural and operational aspects thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A, 3B</cross-reference> &amp; <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>C illustrate detailed forms of confectionery products respectively formed by associated cutting and forming tools having shaped and textured interior forming surfaces; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view, partly diagrammatic in nature, showing the use of a pair of opposed, ultrasonically energized tools used to form individual products from a continuous strip of confectionery material that is advanced and formed intermittently; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a fragmentary elevational view of a portion of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a front elevational view of a pair of the ultrasonically energized, reciprocable tool sets of the invention forming a part of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> is a fragmentary elevational view similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, but showing one reciprocable tool set and one fixed tool set; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is perspective view, partly diagrammatic in character, showing a further modified form of apparatus, using a reciprocating, ultrasonically energized tool periodically moved into registry with one of a series of intermittently advanced anvils; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an enlarged front elevational view of the ultrasonically energized tool and one of the anvils used with the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic view illustrating how ultrasonic energy applied to a forming tool creates low-amplitude, high frequency movement of the tool forming surfaces, and also schematically showing a standing wave with node and anti-node portions; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference> is a perspective view of one form of an apparatus made according to the invention and utilized to create multiple rows of single silhouette products from multiple continuous slabs of confectionery stock, leaving multiple continuous webs of reusable confectionery stock; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</cross-reference> is a view similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, but showing multiple rows of ultrasonically energized cutting tools used to form multiple groups of cut products from continuous slabs of confectionery stock, leaving plural, recyclable residual webs of confectionery stock; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10C</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic vertical sectional view of a portion of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A and showing an ultrasonically energized cutting tool in a position of use relative to a slab of confectionery stock; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>D are amplitude-time curves showing a variation in the amplitude of ultrasonic motion undergone by the cutting or cutting and forming tools of the invention during certain portions of the product forming and release cycles of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference> are diagrammatic illustrations of the relationship between the length, height, width and volume of a portion of a confectionery feed strip and the volume of a finished product made from such feed strip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a forming tool with a cavity adapted to produce the form of confectionery products shown adjacent the forming tool; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is an illustrative example of a form of confectionery product having a finely detailed relief face on its upper surface and made according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is another illustration of a typical form of confectionery product able to be made using the apparatus and method of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating the various steps of one preferred form of process embodying the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a perspective view, with portions broken away, showing a puffed cereal product and a portion of the forming tool used to make the product, which is shown as being of decreased height and increased width relative to the stock from which the product was formed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a fragmentary perspective view of one portion of a strip of puffed cereal material wherein the grains are embedded in a plasticizable matrix and thus adhered to one another; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a illustration similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, but showing a portion of a strip of puffed cereal containing various inclusions within the plasticizable confectionery matrix; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19A</cross-reference> is a view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>, and also showing nuts or other particular kinds of inclusions; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a fragmentary sectional view of a portion of a &ldquo;rope&rdquo; of confectionery product wherein puffed cereal grains have just been extruded and are held together by surface contact; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a side view, partly in elevation and partly in section, and also somewhat diagrammatic in character, showing an ultrasonic forming tool for cutting an end portion from an advancing continuous strip of a puffed cereal material and forming it into individual products of decreased height and increased width, and also showing portions of the product infeed and outfeed conveyors of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The apparatus of the present invention is capable of being embodied in a number of forms, and the inventive process includes several methods all falling within the general ambit of the inventive concept. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, by way of example only and not by way of limitation, a description will be given of several different forms of apparatus, each capable of practicing the invention and each having individual components capable of being varied in constructional details and arrangement. Illustrative methods, the steps of which may also be modified or altered somewhat in use, are also described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the drawings in greater detail, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> show the invention to be embodied in a confectionery product cutting and forming apparatus generally designated <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and shown to include a lower support frame portion generally designated <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, an upper frame section generally designated <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and a pair of conveyor units, a food product input conveyor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and a food product output conveyor <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, the lower frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes plural spaced apart vertically extending legs <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> supporting substantially identical front and rear transverse cross members <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, on which a tabletop <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is positioned. The upper frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> includes vertical supports <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and horizontal members <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, such members being adapted to receive and position a pair of substantially identical horizontal actuator assemblies generally designated <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B. The actuators <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B reciprocate a support plate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> which in turn supports a vertical actuator generally designated <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for a support plate <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> to which are attached a pair of spaced apart brackets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, the actuators move the support plate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> with a laterally reciprocating motion, i.e., to the left and right as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A drive arrangement for the actuators <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B includes a traversing motor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> driving a reduction gear box assembly <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> having a drive shaft <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> that rotates one carrier gear <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in each actuator <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B. The gears operate toothed timing belts <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> (only one shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), the lower runs of which are attached to the support plate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, the vertical actuator includes a servo plunge motor <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, a gear box <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> cooperating in use with a vertical actuator drive shaft <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> that also moves a reciprocable timing belt <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to which the support plate <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and mounting brackets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> for the ultrasonic stack <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are attached. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Referring particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, it will be noted that a power supply (not shown) furnishes electrical energy through a radio frequency cable <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to a converter <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> wherein high frequency (20 KHz or higher) electric energy is transduced into vibratory mechanical motion, preferably by a plurality of piezoelectric transducer devices. The output of the converter <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is amplified, if needed, in what is termed a booster assembly <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, which also provides a second clamping point at its nodal ring for mechanical stability. The output end face of the booster <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is secured by suitable means to the upper or input end of an ultrasonic horn generally designated <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The horn <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> includes contoured surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> forming a product shaping cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and in particular to the input conveyor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, this unit is shown to include a drive motor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, a reduction gear transmission <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, a primary drive roller <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> that is operative to advance a continuous serpentine belt generally designated <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> which is trained around a plurality of guide pulleys <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. When the belt <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is disposed as shown, there is a lower run <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and an upper run <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> which in use is trained over a backing plate <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> and which run <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> in turn supports a continuous supply or strip of confectionery feedstock <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. Prior to coming in contact with the belt forming the upper run <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of the conveyor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the strip advances along one or more intermediate supports <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> which may optionally include or be formed from a plurality of overlapping rollers (not shown in detail) or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> A mixer/extruder, or other source (not shown) may be used to form a continuous supply or slab of confectionery material having a uniform cross-section and a self-sustaining shape, arising by proper temperature control both in the case of an ice cream or other frozen confection, and in the case of a candy bar or like product. It will be understood that the continuous strip <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> may be only one of several strips formed from a slab of much greater width but of the same height and consistency. In other words, the process may call for forming a slab from which several strips are cut and advanced as indicated herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the second or outfeed conveyor <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, this unit is shown to be analogous to its counterpart on the infeed conveyor side, with the unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> having a motor <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, gear reduction unit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, a drive roller <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, plural guide rollers <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (only one numbered), and a drive belt generally designated <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> forming upper and lower runs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> respectively. This belt ill is substantially identical to its counterpart except that, as will appear, it is intentionally driven at a somewhat higher speed. In keeping with the invention, the cavity portion <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the tool <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is used to form a plurality of substantially identical, individual confectionery products <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> from the continuous rope or strip of confectionery material <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. The manner in which this forming is done will now be described in detail, reference being had in particular to the illustrations of the product in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A, 3B</cross-reference> and the schematic or flow diagram <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. The manner of sizing and shaping the cavity for the product is also illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, there is shown an ultrasonic horn generally designated <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> having a surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> forming a product-shaping cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> within its lower portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Where the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, merely by way of example, has an inner sidewall <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> with some relatively smooth portions <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, a series of decorative embossments or the like <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and a identifiable relief <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 124, a</cross-reference> finished product generally designated <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>made using this tool <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> will have the reverse image of these elements, including a reverse element <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the relief image <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, a smooth portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on the product sidewall <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and debossments or depressions <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed by the counterpart embossments or image formations <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> on the walls <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. According to the invention, a very thin knife-edge cutting section <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is provided in the places where an exterior wall segment <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> approaches and virtually meets a counterpart interior wall surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, typically at the trailing edge of the tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> shows another form of cavity generally designated <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>having a trailing, sharp cutting edge <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>defined by the junction of exterior surfaces <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and inner cavity surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, a turtle <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 116</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is shown to be produced by the turtle shape of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. In addition, a decorative relief surface <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is shown to be formed on the figure by counterpart formations <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>within the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> shows still another form of tool <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>having a cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>g </italic></highlight>adapted to form a product <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>wherein the cutting edges or surfaces <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are used to form vertical sides <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> of the product similar to those of the silhouette type. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> The foregoing descriptions illustrate that individual cavities may have irregular or complex shapes that may include relief and/or recessed portions adapted to create on the formed piece respectively depressions and/or relief figures, and that any part or all of the cavity surface may be textured as desired to make the preferred form of product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> If the pieces are to be sold as formed, the relief or finish surface may be fine or coarse. If the pieces are to be enrobed, the nature and extent of surface detail will be selected so that a desired image will remain visible through the coating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the operating sequence and method of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating the process of the invention in a general way. As shown in the first block, a strip of material is advanced at a predetermined rate. The next step comprises moving the tool <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> at a synchronous rate with the advancing strip and then, while the tool continues to advance, moving it downwardly with a rapid motion into contact with the strip <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. Here, the product is formed when the tool moves through the strip segment and meets the upper run <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of the belt <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, where the belt is supported by the backing plate <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>. In the next step, the tool remains in a down position and is accelerated forwardly away from the remainder of the strip <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> for a brief time before the tool is raised and returned to the initial point. Finally, in the last step, the previously formed, released, and separated piece <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is transferred to the faster moving output conveyor for further separation while at the same time, the tool <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> (and in fact the entire stack) is lifted and rapidly reset to its initial position before beginning the synchronous forward-and-down movement sequence described above. The apparatus then repeatedly carries out the cycle just described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In the machine shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, therefore, as the strip of material <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> is advanced, the transverse and vertical movement mechanisms for the ultrasonic stack <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are both actuated. The stack is advanced as its support plate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> moves it forward under the control of a programmable servo motor or otherwise such that its translational speed is identical to the advance speed of the infeed conveyor belt <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Consequently, beginning in an initial part of the stroke which corresponds generally to a flat segment <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> of the conveyor illustrated as just above the backing plate <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> lying between rollers <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, the tool <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> moves downwardly at a rapid rate, stroking to a position wherein its cutting edge <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>) is substantially in contact with the upper surface of the belt <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The vertical travel mode of the servo driven plunge motor <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> moves the plate <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> to accomplish this movement sequence. As will be described in detail later, this movement sequence simultaneously cuts and forms a shaped product <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> through a combination of compressive force and vibrational energy transfer, without affecting the texture or sensory characteristics of the product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> As the cutting edge <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> approaches or just contacts the belt <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, the traversing motor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> accelerates the belt <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> controlling movement of the support plate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, advancing the edge <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> slightly in respect to the linear speed of belt <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. This desirably separates the just-formed piece <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> from the leading edge <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference>) of the strip or rope of confectionery product <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The individually formed product <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and the leading edge <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> of the strip are now moving forward at the same speed but are slightly spaced apart. Thereupon, with continued operation of the input conveyor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> at its rate and the continued operation of the output conveyor <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> at its own higher rate, an overdriven velocity is created in the output belt <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. The articles <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> just formed are thus picked up, further separated and moved away to a remote section of the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as shown at the right hand sides of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. As the ultrasonic stack <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is lifted to free the product <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> from the interior of the cavity <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, the traversing motor <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> actuates the mechanism to rapidly reset the stack to an upstream or far left position as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The advancing (or left to right as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) synchronous motion is then the first step in a new cycle, and so on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, and as will be described elsewhere herein, the movement profile of the tool <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is such that its cutting edge <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> will contact the continuously advancing rope of confectionery product <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> a distance spaced inwardly of its leading edge an amount sufficient to cut an individual portion of a desired volume. The movement sequence thus described is a simple one which is periodically repeated, with each individual confection being made from a predetermined volume of the strip or other supply of confectionery stock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> According to the preferred form of the invention, a servo motor or other programmable sequence drive arrangement is provided so that individual portions are made, each of which is of an identical size, and the advancing and retreating motion as well as the downward or plunge stroke of the ultrasonic stack are coordinated such that a piece of the desired volume, but different shape, is cut with each cutting sequence and then molded into a different shape of identical volume. As will appear, this enables the process to be carried on without leaving a web or other waste in what is essentially a flashless, rapid forming operation not requiring any compromise in the analog characteristics of the finished product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Referring now to a corollary of the concept that flashless molding is possible, and that waste formation can be eliminated, reference is made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference>. Here, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference> is an elevational view, partly in section and showing the bottom portion of the tool <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> having interior surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> forming a cavity generally designated <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference> to possess a volume V<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference> shows that the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is also defined by and includes a trailing, cutting edge portions <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and a leading edge <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>, so named in view of the travel direction of the stick or strip <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> of confectionery product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>A, the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> has a length L<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. A selected length L<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>forms a strip segment <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that is shown to have a volume V<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>which in the illustrations of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference> is shown to result from its also having a height H<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and a width W<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>. In the illustrated form, H<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>is greater than the maximum height H<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the width maximum W<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is greater than the width W<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>of the strip <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Given that the volume V<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is able to be predetermined by simple volumetric measurement, as having, for example, a volume of 25 cc, then theoretically, a flashless product could be made if an individual piece of the confectionery strip <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is of a suitable cross-section, such as a rectangular cross-section, and also has a volume of 25 cc. This is what is in fact done according to the present invention, wherein, given the volume V<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, the width, height and length of the strip segment <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are selected so that its volume is the same as that of the cavity, and so that exact filling can be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> In this connection, it is customary to have the strip segment <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>somewhat higher, shorter, and narrower than the cavity to achieve precise results. In other words, the strip segment and cavity are shaped and sized so that the entire volume V<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>of the strip segment <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>will initially fit with the cavity. Since, after one cutting and forming cycle is completed, the leading edge of the strip of confectionery product <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> will have an arcuate configuration, when the process of cutting and separating is repeated, the leading edge will continue to have such configuration, and exact matching of the volume of the strip segment <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and that of the cavity interior will result so as to permit precise flashless molding. Repetition can be accomplished in proportion to the ability of the process machinery to hold tolerances on the height and width of the strip. Experience has proven that this is very easily accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, while the reforming of the entire volume of the product into a cavity of the same volume and a different shape renders it practical to achieve virtually 100% product utilization and to eliminate or at least significantly minimize generation of scrap, the invention can be practiced without using this capability. Thus, if the invention is used to produce silhouette products by using an ultrasonic tool in &ldquo;cookie cutter&rdquo; fashion from a slab of confectionery product, it is implicit, as will be discussed in connection with later examples, that desirable products can be made by a process wherein a web of unused product will still remain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, another form of apparatus generally designated <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is shown as being suitable for the practice of the invention. Here, there is somewhat schematically shown a process for extruding a rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of a confectionery material from a given source (not shown). A feed belt <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is trained over drive and guide wheels <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> that are shown to be provided for advancing the rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of just-formed product on a continuous basis. Such a continuous extrusion and advancement are considered one desirable and effective way to maintain the uniform cross-section of product which is desired for maintenance of quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> The rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of product travels over a groove formed in the outer margin <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of a rotary feed wheel <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> journalled on an axle <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> that is supported by a bearing <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> at the upper end <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> of a shaft <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> moved by a linear actuator <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. The axle <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> is driven by a motor <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> such that the speeds of the feed belt <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and the outer diameter of the wheel <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> are the same. The actuator <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is moved controllably to intermittently alter the feed rate of the rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> As shown in the phantom lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, the pulley or feed wheel <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is movable between a solid line position P<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> and a phantom line position P<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>also shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> and also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, it is shown that sections of the rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> are formed into individual contoured products <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, etc., by a cutting and forming apparatus generally designated <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. Each product <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, etc. is substantially identical to every other product and all are carried away by the upper run <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> of a conveyor (not shown in detail). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, it will be noted that a pair of substantially identical but mirror image, left and right hand forming assemblies <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are shown. The parts being essentially identical, only the parts comprising the left hand portion <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are described in detail herein. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> bracket <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> is shown schematically as being adapted to reciprocate an ultrasonic stack generally designated <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight> comprising a converter <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, a booster <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>, and a horn assembly <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> in a horizontal plane. The ultrasonic horn <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> is shown to include a carrier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, a forming tool <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having a contoured cavity <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>forming a part thereof; tool <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a cavity <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. As shown, the cavities <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>resemble their counterparts shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference>, and each includes contoured or otherwise desirably shaped inner surfaces and sharp cutting edges not shown in detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> In use, it is desired to move the two ultrasonically energized forming tools toward each other periodically to contact a desired portion <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> of the rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of product disposed therebetween to perform a combination cutting and forming operation analogous to that described in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In this instance, considering that two horns must be manipulated, it is strongly desired not to attempt to synchronize movement of both ultrasonic stacks with respect to a continuously advancing rope or stick of product. Hence, a compensating drive assembly of the type shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> is utilized to alter the feed rate of the rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> by changing a constant advance rate to an intermittent, advancing motion. This is accomplished by periodically moving the shaft <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> at an appropriate time and with an appropriate velocity such that the peripheral groove <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the pulley <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> rises vertically at a rate exactly equal to the advance rate of the belt <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. During the short period when this is occurring, forward motion of the end portion <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> of the rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is arrested just as forming assemblies <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>carrying the tools <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are moved together to form the product, and to begin their separation to permit the product to be ejected from the single cavity formed jointly by the two tool segments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> As the stacks are separated, the shaft <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> moves downwardly, in effect permitting the new leading edge of the rope portion <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> to move down, and in effect, feed another segment of the rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to the forming tools. As the portion <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> completes the advancing movement, the shaft <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is moved up again by the actuator <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, and the process is repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> The foregoing apparatus illustrates the application of the principles of the invention to the cooperative use of a multiple stacks of ultrasonically energized cutting and forming tools in the production of confectionery products. The size and shape of the rope relative to the configuration of the cavities and the size of the final product are able to be controlled in a manner analogous to that described above in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, or otherwise as described. Other continuous-to-intermittent motion devices may be used for the purpose described above, but the preferred apparatus is one of a type wherein the rope is supported throughout the major portion of its extent, with only a free end portion hanging down as shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> If this were not the case, the cross-section of the rope <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> or other extruded shape might be deformed by undue gravitational-force elongation. The form of continuous-to-intermittent drive mechanism shown is merely one presently preferred form, it being understood that those skilled in the art are well aware that other mechanisms may be constructed and arranged for this purpose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Where the two tools containing opposed cavities meet, a composite material, such as a carbon fiber material, may be bonded to the end face of one or both of the tools for purposes of shock and vibration absorption. It is not desirable to permit two hard metal, ultrasonically energized parts contact each other while energized, particularly, under a substantial force, inasmuch as such contact may be damaging to the components. Therefore, a stiff but resilient, shock-proof material such as the composite materials just referred to may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A, a</cross-reference> slightly modified form of the apparatus shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is shown. Here, a left-hand forming assembly <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is shown and a portion of a right-hand forming assembly <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is also illustrated. These mirror-image parts are essentially identical to their counterparts <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and to each other except that in this embodiment, part <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is fixed in position and does not reciprocate. Accordingly, in assembly <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>there is a counterpart (not shown) to the bracket <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> to reciprocate the stack. However, in respect to the stack <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>such a bracket is fixed and serves to fixedly support the non-movable stack <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A, it will be understood that the assembly <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>might also be passive, i.e., not ultrasonically energized, if this were desired for some reason, such as if the product did not present any risk of sticking or if the right-hand assembly were only a flat surface rather than having a cavity intended to provide a contoured or decorative relief surface to the product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, a further modified form of apparatus is shown. Here, a cutting and forming apparatus generally designated <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is shown to include drive means in the form of a powered drum or sprocket <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> supporting a belt generally designated <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and having upper and lower runs <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, each carrying a plurality of substantially identical anvils <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as shown includes, as illustrated in phantom lines, a conditioning chamber or the like generally designated <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> through which products <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> formed by the process may pass during operation. The product removal belt <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> picks up the fully formed and in some cases conditioned products <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> from the upper run <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> of the belt <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and positions them for transfer to packaging or other processing stations as desired. These steps could, but need not, include enrobing in chocolate or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows that in the apparatus <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, a feed source generally designated <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is shown to contain plural, spaced apart individual pre-cut blanks <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> to be formed into finished products <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> by the inventive process. Each of the pieces <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is to be fed individually to one anvil of a series of identical anvils <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> passing beneath the feed source <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, an ultrasonically energized stack generally designated <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> (similar to its counterpart in the other examples) is shown to be carried by a pair of brackets <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> secured to a reciprocable plunge bar <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>. The stack <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> includes a converter <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, a booster <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>, and a horn generally designated <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> having a tool <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> with a forming cavity <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. The anvil <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> includes an upwardly directed contact surface <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight>. Where necessary, a thin gasket or layer of other material, such as a polyurethane elastomer (not shown) may be provided on the anvils if contact between opposed surfaces would be damaging to the tool. In addition, the anvils thereunder may be made from a tetrofluoroethylene (TFE) material so that they would not be damaged by contact with the ultrasonic tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> As will be understood by reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, the object of this apparatus is to obtain the benefit of forming a highly contoured product without requiring a pair of ultrasonically energized cavities. As one way of achieving increased mechanical simplicity, the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference> does not require the stack and the anvils to have their movement sequences synchronized by precise timing arrangements or servo mechanisms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> The conveyor belt <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> is advanced in steps by an intermittent drive (not shown in detail) and as each individual blank or piece <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>etc. of feedstock is taken from the feed source and placed onto the anvil <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, the belt advances the cavity through one or more idler stages and then stops the belt in a position of registration beneath the ultrasonic stack <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>. During the momentary period of registration when the anvil <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is stopped beneath the stack <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>, the drive for the reciprocable plunge bar <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> causes the bar to move downwardly, carrying the bracket-mounted stack <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> with it and engaging the blank or piece of feedstock <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> received on the anvil with the opposed forming surfaces <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> in the tool <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> and on the surface <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight> of the anvil <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. The anvil may have a contoured recess and a retaining mechanism, if desired, to prevent the piece from moving during indexing of the belt. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the anvils are shown widely spaced apart for purposes of illustration. In practice, their position would depend on process parameters. Customarily, in this apparatus, since individual blanks of feedstock are pre-cut, cutting edges need not be provided on the tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> However, the forming, which is done through the application of ultrasonic energy, is carried out in a very short time, such as from about 60 to 150 milliseconds (m sec), with the dwell time depending on the type, consistency and conditioning of the material, etc. The ultrasonic action facilitates shaping by suitably plasticizing the product and by preventing the product from sticking to the vibratory cavity. The ultrasonic energy also vibrates the cavity sufficiently to secure product release. Accordingly, simply inverting the anvil normally permits the product to drop onto the other belt <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> for one or more subsequent or downstream operations. If the anvil contains a cavity, dislodging the product can be achieved by tapping the anvil, by knockouts, or otherwise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10A and 10C</cross-reference>, there is illustrated a relatively simple way in which the invention can be practiced. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, an apparatus generally designated <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> is shown for producing three rows of individual products generally designated <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, each having a precisely cut silhouette from three continuous strips generally designated <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of confectionery material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment, a full width supply conveyor generally designated <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> is shown to include a continuous belt <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>, and one or more drive and/or tensioning pulleys <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. The conveyor <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> has an upper run <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> and a lower run <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>. A product outfeed conveyor generally designated <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> is shown to be oppositely arranged and include a continuous belt <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> trained over a drive and tensioning pulley <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> and serving to divide the continuous belt <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> into upper and lower runs <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>. The individual pieces <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> of confectionery are supported on the upper run <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> of the conveyor <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> where they are taken to a site (not shown) for further processing or packaging. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, an array of individual forming tools each generally designated <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> is provided. Each tool makes precise cuts at selected points in each strip <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, etc. of confectionery material. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>C, each forming tool <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> includes a body portion <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight>, a continuous sidewall <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> of thin cross-section terminating in a continuous sharp lower edge <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight>. The body and the sidewalls <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> of the tool <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> are energized ultrasonically in a manner similar to that described in connection with the other embodiments. As the sidewalls <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> and cutting edges <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> of each tool <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> descend, the cutting edges <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> engage the associated strip <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> of confectionery material, cutting individual articles <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> each having a characteristic silhouette from the remainder of the stock <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. This operation leaves a continuous remainder or web <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> of confectionery material which is able to be recycled or reprocessed. In this embodiment, the lower edges <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> of the sidewalls <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> move downwardly in operation until they contact the upper surface of the upper run <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> of the <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> of the conveyor belt. Thereupon, by the use of vacuum or otherwise, such as by the type of amplitude profiling referred to elsewhere herein, each piece <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> having the precisely cut silhouette is in turn picked up and transferred to the outbound conveyor <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> The ultrasonic actuation of the walls and their lower edges serves to form a precise cut, and the schematically illustrated tooling is capable of making a product having a silhouette of very fine detail. Unlike the apparatus used in other illustrated embodiments, no attempt is made to reform or reshape the product, nor to emboss, deboss or otherwise add texture, relief or surface finish to the top or sidewall surfaces of the product. The embodiment just described illustrates the operational principle of utilizing the vibratory edges for purposes of product cutting only. As pointed out in connection with the other examples, an important advantage is that the vibratory action totally eliminates build up of residues on the cutting edges and enhances the cutting process where inclusions are encountered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> A movement mechanism (not shown in detail) similar to that illustrated in connection with FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is utilized to control the plunging or descent movement of the cutting apparatus, its synchronous movement with the conveyor belt and its lifting and transferring of the freshly cut part to an adjacent conveyor or other suitable location. It is possible to incorporate vacuum and/or air pressure as an aid to picking up and releasing the individual products being formed. Other suitable mechanisms known to those skilled in the art may be used for this purpose. Such mechanisms do not form a novel part of the present invention, and accordingly, not being necessary for an understanding of the instant inventive principles, a detailed description of them is omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>B, an apparatus generally designated <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> is shown to be provided for producing groups <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> of products from each of a plurality of forming tools <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> arranged for movement of the type described and illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and shown by the directional arrows in the drawings. Here, the supply conveyor <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> includes a continuous belt <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight>, trained over one or more drive and/or tensioning pulleys <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight>. The feed or supply conveyor <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> also includes an upper run <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> and a lower run <highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight>. An adjacently disposed product outfeed conveyor generally designated <highlight><bold>566</bold></highlight> is also shown to include provide continuous withdrawal of form products. The conveyor <highlight><bold>566</bold></highlight> includes a drive continuous operation over drive and tensioning pulley <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight> dividing the belt <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> into upper and lower runs <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight>, as well as other runs shown only partially. Individual groups <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> of confectionery products, each including plural products <highlight><bold>551</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>551</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>551</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, etc. are supported on the upper run <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight> of the conveyor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> Here, as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, there are a plurality of forming tools <highlight><bold>576</bold></highlight>, each having a body portion <highlight><bold>578</bold></highlight> provided with multiple cavities defined in part by multiple continuous thin sidewalls <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> and continuous sharp lower edges <highlight><bold>582</bold></highlight>. Their manner of being energized and their motion sequence is the same as that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the same as that described in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference>. The only difference is that the residual webs of material <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> contain plural groups of openings <highlight><bold>585</bold></highlight> rather than plural individual openings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> Of course, in keeping with the invention, it is possible to use multiple cavity apparatus in multiple tool arrays in order to make products that are cut and formed as well as merely cut. In such instance, the operational principles remain the same and only the type or style of cavity would be different. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing the form of operation or method carried out with the apparatus of FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A and/or <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>AA. As is apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16, a</cross-reference> strip of confectionery material is continuously advanced, as by a conveyor. At a selected point, the strip is engaged by the tool which moves downwardly into engagement with the strip and which is moving at a synchronous rate relative to the strip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Ultrasonic energy applied during contact between the tool and the strip assist the tool in cutting and forming a piece of product. After this strip is completed, the tool is accelerated forward so as to separate the just-formed product from the still advancing, leading edge of the strip. Thereupon, the tool is lifted out of contact with the strip. The tool is then returned to its initial position for repetition of the cycle, while the just-formed product is transferred to the output conveyor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, there is shown an ultrasonic tool generally designated <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> which includes an attaching fastener <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> for attachment to a booster or the like. The body portion <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> of the tool <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> includes a cavity generally designated <highlight><bold>705</bold></highlight> defined by inner end walls <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>, inner side walls <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of divider walls <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight>. According here to the inventive concept, the divider walls <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight> terminate in lower edges <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight> which are somewhat raised in respect to the extent of the bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight> of the side and end walls <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight>. The inner or top wall <highlight><bold>716</bold></highlight> of the cavity <highlight><bold>705</bold></highlight> may or may not be embossed or otherwise textured, depending on the form of final products sought to be made using the tool <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> As is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, the main purpose of forming the tool <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> in the manner illustrated is to produce a segmented bar <highlight><bold>718</bold></highlight> having portions generally designated <highlight><bold>720</bold></highlight> of reduced cross-section or weakness lying between the individual segments <highlight><bold>722</bold></highlight> making up the bar <highlight><bold>718</bold></highlight> as a whole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, an illustration is presented of a form of confectionery product such as a candy piece or bar generally designated <highlight><bold>830</bold></highlight> having a body <highlight><bold>832</bold></highlight> defined in part by plain or unadorned side walls <highlight><bold>834</bold></highlight> and shown to include a contoured or relieved design <highlight><bold>836</bold></highlight> on the upper surface <highlight><bold>838</bold></highlight> of the bar or piece <highlight><bold>830</bold></highlight>. Such a generally flat but relieved upper surface is readily formed using an ultrasonically activated tool having a cavity with the reverse image of the product shown. In the type of product shown, it is assumed that the side walls <highlight><bold>834</bold></highlight> are formed by use of ultrasonic cutting edges on the cutting and forming tool (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15, a</cross-reference> novelty-type candy or other confectionery product generally designated <highlight><bold>860</bold></highlight> is shown. Here, the body <highlight><bold>862</bold></highlight> of the product is shown to include side walls <highlight><bold>864</bold></highlight> and end walls <highlight><bold>866</bold></highlight> of different heights, and to include an upper surface <highlight><bold>868</bold></highlight> that is heavily contoured. In the illustrated case, the form of a rabbit <highlight><bold>870</bold></highlight> is shown to have relatively deep relief. Such a product may be formed using a deeply contoured cavity but the potential for making deep relief products, with or without flat side walls made by ultrasonic cutting is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> and FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>C, another important aspect of the present invention is shown. This aspect results from the realization that it is not necessary to energize the forming cavity continuously with the maximum ultrasonic amplitude attainable. Instead, the amplitude of the ultrasonic motion of the cavity surfaces, which is indicative of the energy being transferred, is varied periodically. In particular, it is not necessary to maintain the maximum amplitude when the forming horn is not in contact with the product. According to the invention, therefore, the horn is preferably operated at two or more different amplitude levels during processing, depending on the makeup of the product and other forming parameters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> Thus, and referring for example to a sequence of the type described in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the energy fed from the power supply to the converter is controlled in such a manner that during indexing of the ultrasonic stack to a position in alignment with and above the stick of material, a lower amplitude is used, perhaps 20 to 30% of the maximum available amplitude. Just before the tool is moved adjacent and into contact with the stick of confectionery product, the power supply output rapidly ramps up to achieve an amplitude which is a high percentage of the maximum amplitude theoretically available, and is equal to what could be termed the normal design amplitude of the tool. Energy is then supplied at this amplitude until the cutting and forming operation is complete, with the power supply then returning to its low amplitude mode until the remainder of the cycle is repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>A, there is shown in graphic form an illustration of the concepts referred to generally above. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference> shows graphically that there is a maximum design amplitude level A<highlight><subscript>maxD</subscript></highlight>, a maximum normal or duty cycle amplitude A<highlight><subscript>maxN </subscript></highlight>which may be 70% to 85% of A<highlight><subscript>maxD</subscript></highlight>, and another amplitude A<highlight><subscript>MIN </subscript></highlight>which is the minimum amplitude at which the forming tool will operate. This level may typically be some 30% of A<highlight><subscript>maXD</subscript></highlight>. Thus, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference> illustrates attaining two operative levels A<highlight><subscript>MIN </subscript></highlight>and A<highlight><subscript>maxN </subscript></highlight>between zero level and a maximum design amplitude, i.e. the maximum amplitude A<highlight><subscript>maxD </subscript></highlight>at which a tool could be made to operate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> The actual amplitude level achieved from time-to-time is shown by a line generally designated <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> and shown to have an initial, idling or off-duty portion <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>, an inclined portion <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> wherein the amplitude ramps up until it reaches and levels off at the A<highlight><subscript>maxN </subscript></highlight><highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>. Here, it remains for a significant time before ramping down as at <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> to the idling level <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> which is equal to its energized but low output level just discussed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>A and the legends beneath the curve illustrating the amplitudes, it will be noted that one complete cycle is designated T<highlight><subscript>C</subscript></highlight>. This cycle time, which is repeated periodically during operation of the machine, comprises a number of components which are listed at the bottom of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference>. From left to right, these are the T<highlight><subscript>RU </subscript></highlight>or &ldquo;ramp up&rdquo; time, a dwell time T<highlight><subscript>D </subscript></highlight>wherein the tool is actually in contact with the confectionery product and fully energized, the time T<highlight><subscript>RD </subscript></highlight>is a transient, &ldquo;ramp down&rdquo; period during which the amplitude decreases from A<highlight><subscript>maxN </subscript></highlight>to A<highlight><subscript>min</subscript></highlight>. Thereafter, T<highlight><subscript>A </subscript></highlight>or the &ldquo;air&rdquo; time is the time at which the forming tool is in the air, i.e. disengaged from the product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> The air time is used for the return and reset portion of the cycle. Accordingly, and referring for example to a cycle of the type of illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the acoustic tool <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> would be continually energized, but maintained at the relatively low level amplitude A<highlight><subscript>min </subscript></highlight>until just prior to entering the work, i.e. being plunged into the strip of confectionery material. During the time just prior to this movement, the energy level would ramp up so that, upon first contact, the amplitude would be at A<highlight><subscript>maxN</subscript></highlight>. This amplitude is then maintained until such time as the tool is withdrawn. Thereafter the amplitude ramps down to the idling or low amplitude level A<highlight><subscript>min </subscript></highlight>until the tool is repositioned and the cycle is to be repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference> shows a concept similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference> except that the total cycle time T<highlight><subscript>C </subscript></highlight>is divided differently. Here, there are two peaks of different duration, each accompanied by a ramp up and ramp down period. The ramp up and ramp down times are not illustrated in the lower portion of the legend, wherein the duty or dwell cycle is subdivided into different components. Thus, a time period T<highlight><subscript>F </subscript></highlight>is shown wherein maximum amplitude is achieved during the forming portion of the cycle, which includes the initial entry into the confectionery strip and extends through the time at which the entire inner cavity surfaces have contacted appropriate portions of the strip and completed the formation of the product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, there may be a period T<highlight><subscript>I </subscript></highlight>or an idling time wherein the acoustic tool has completed forming the product but is still in contact with it. After time, T<highlight><subscript>I </subscript></highlight>has elapsed and it is desired to achieve or insure separation of the formed product from the leading edge or surrounding portions of the strip, the tool is again energized at a higher level for a period of time illustrated as T<highlight><subscript>R </subscript></highlight>or, release time. When the maximum amplitude is again applied to the tool, the formed piece is released from the horn cavity. Thereafter, a period T<highlight><subscript>A </subscript></highlight>or &ldquo;air time&rdquo; of the tool occurs that is the same as that discussed in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11C, a</cross-reference> similar concept is illustrated, except that some of the ramp up and ramp down times are shown as exponential. This is because, for practical reasons, the ramp up rates may actually taper off, or it may be desired to modulate the rate of ramping up or down. In the illustrated case, one ramp down portion of the cycle is a partial or incomplete ramp down, i.e., the amplitude does not go as low as the initial or air time minimum amplitude. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> Here, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>C, the expressions beneath the curves have the same meaning as their counterparts above, namely, T<highlight><subscript>RU </subscript></highlight>and T<highlight><subscript>RD </subscript></highlight>are ramp up and ramp down times respectively and, T<highlight><subscript>D </subscript></highlight>is the dwell time or forming and or cutting time while T<highlight><subscript>R </subscript></highlight>is the release time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11D, a</cross-reference> similar concept is shown wherein three separate levels of amplitude are shown, as well as a zero or inactive state. This profile might be used in a &ldquo;pick and place&rdquo; operation. In the profile illustrated, the portion of the curve <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> is an &ldquo;air&rdquo; time which occupies a given duration prior to beginning of the forming cycle. This is followed by a ramp up time <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight> and a dwell time <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> wherein formation of the product is taking place. The ramp down time <highlight><bold>456</bold></highlight> follows forming of the product and terminates at a zero level whereat the tool is de-energized. Thereafter, a ramp up time occurs just after which a maximum or release amplitude <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> is created for a brief duration, following which a ramp down time <highlight><bold>462</bold></highlight> elapses as the tool is thereafter returned to an active but idle or air time amplitude as shown at <highlight><bold>464</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11D</cross-reference> shows that various levels may be achieved for particular desired purposes and that it is not necessary that the maximum or minimum useful amplitudes be the same as their counterparts in the other illustrations. In other words, the energy level for formation and that for release may be different; the idle or air time amplitude may be the same but may also be zero (no ultrasonic energy) between portions of the cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> One application is a &ldquo;pick and place&rdquo; sequence wherein it is desired to have no post-formation energy imparted during a transfer time, after which the cavity is energized strongly to secure product release. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> Depending on the exact nature of the product and the application, variations in dwell times and amplitude values may be desired by those skilled in the art. This process may be referred to collectively as &ldquo;amplitude profiling.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> This ability to achieve different levels of amplitude at the horn face cavity is easily accomplished by the combination of a dedicated controller and a standard power supply. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> The amplitudes of vibration may vary depending upon the power and tool design. However, with frequencies of 20 KHZ being used to mold larger pieces and another frequency, such as 40 KHZ, being used to make smaller pieces, the amplitudes that have been found useful have ranged from 5 microns at an &ldquo;off duty&rdquo; or idle level such as that illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>D, and up to 15-20 microns at the 80% level shown at <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference>. Representative amplitudes that are believed useful on an overall basis vary from 5 to 100 microns as a probable maximum with from about 5 up to about 20 to 35 microns being the presently preferred range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> In this connection, reference is made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. This illustration is very schematic, but it shows that, when power is applied to the ultrasonic stack, standing wave generally designated <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is developed in the forming tool or horn. Such a wave <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> has a node point <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> and a pair of anti-nodes or high amplitude portions <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>. As the amplitude of such a wave increases, at the same frequency, (as shown by the dotted line wave form <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>), the applied power or energy increases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> When a forming tool <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> is designed so that a standing wave is present in the tool, as illustrated, the node portion <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> of the forming tool will be substantially stationary, regardless of the amplitude of the other portions of the wave. As the amplitude of the standing wave increases, the displacement of the anti-node portion of the wave also changes, causing the cavity face and edges of the tool <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>614</bold></highlight>, to move, within limits, to different excursion levels, i.e., higher amplitude vibrations. Once a certain amplitude has been reached, additional energy input may raise the force of the vibrations without increasing their amplitude. Energy application is controlled by the power supply as necessary, usually resulting in an amplitude that ranges within those limits described in connection with FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>D. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the use of the inventive methods and apparatus to make puffed cereal products, FIGS. <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> illustrate such materials and methods of manufacture. Basically, the process illustrated in these figures is similar to that carried out by the apparatus of FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, or that of FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>AA. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, for example, an individual confectionery product in the form of a contoured <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1016</cross-reference> is shaped in a cavity generally designated <highlight><bold>974</bold></highlight> and shown to be defined by contoured inner surfaces <highlight><bold>972</bold></highlight> on a portion of an ultrasonic horn generally designated <highlight><bold>970</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> It is understood that the horn <highlight><bold>970</bold></highlight> with the cavity <highlight><bold>974</bold></highlight> is positioned in abutting relation to a powered booster (not shown). As illustrated by the double headed sets of arrows in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>, the entire ultrasonic stack assembly, including the horn/booster and converter is movable both in a plunge-and-retract or vertical mode, and in a horizontal mode. In this instance, the assembly including the horn <highlight><bold>970</bold></highlight> and the cutting and/or forming surfaces <highlight><bold>972</bold></highlight> are moved by a mechanism (not shown) which is the same as or similar to that shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>AA, for example. The sequence of movement is also the same. Thus, the apparatus includes an infeed or supply conveyor generally designated <highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight> having an infeed belt generally designated <highlight><bold>984</bold></highlight>. The belt is trained over various rollers, including a guide roller, <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight> and is made to form an upper run <highlight><bold>996</bold></highlight> and a lower run (not shown). A backing plate <highlight><bold>995</bold></highlight> supports the portion of the upper run <highlight><bold>996</bold></highlight> of the belt <highlight><bold>984</bold></highlight> near the roller <highlight><bold>990</bold></highlight>. A continuous supply or strip of confectionery feedstock <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight>, similar to its counterpart <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> (except that the feedstack <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight> comprises puffed cereal grains), is fed forward as the belt <highlight><bold>984</bold></highlight> moves. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> An outfeed conveyor generally designated <highlight><bold>928</bold></highlight> is shown to have at least one guide roller <highlight><bold>1010</bold></highlight> serving to guide a drive belt generally designated <highlight><bold>1011</bold></highlight>, the upper run <highlight><bold>1012</bold></highlight> of which supports newly formed products <highlight><bold>1016</bold></highlight> and removes them from the formation area in which the tool with the horn <highlight><bold>970</bold></highlight> moves in the sequence just referred to. As in its counterparts shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the linear speed of the outfeed conveyor <highlight><bold>928</bold></highlight> is higher than that of the infeed conveyor <highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight>. This enables the just-formed products <highlight><bold>1016</bold></highlight> to be spaced apart from one another and to be accelerated away from the forming area just after the products are made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> The movement sequence of the cutting and forming tool is similar to that described in connection with FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in that the horn follows the advancing strip of material at the rate of advance, plunges down into the material to cut and form a piece, and then accelerates to separate the just-formed piece from the leading edge of the continuously advancing stick. Thereafter, the stack lifts and returns to its original position before beginning another cutting and forming sequence. Furthermore, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference>, the feedstock <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight> may be and preferably is of generally higher and narrower cross section than the finished product generally designated <highlight><bold>1016</bold></highlight>. Likewise, the cavity <highlight><bold>974</bold></highlight> is somewhat longer than the initial length of the end portion <highlight><bold>1117</bold></highlight> that will be severed from the feedstock strip <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight>. This is illustrated by comparing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17 and 21</cross-reference> with FIGS. <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> Thus, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, there is shown a strip <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of confectionery product having a height &ldquo;H&rdquo; and a width &ldquo;W&rdquo;, and a segment length &ldquo;L&rdquo;. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, the height &ldquo;H&rdquo; of the product <highlight><bold>1016</bold></highlight> illustrated is lower, the width &ldquo;W&rdquo; greater than that of the forming stock <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and the length &ldquo;L&rdquo; of the product (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>) longer than the end portion <highlight><bold>1117</bold></highlight>. The volume of the end portion <highlight><bold>1117</bold></highlight> is such that it exactly matches the volume of the tool cavity <highlight><bold>974</bold></highlight>, and hence the cavity will be filled by the just-cut end <highlight><bold>1117</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> The material, through the application of ultrasonic energy, becomes plasticized sufficiently to enable it to be reformed without changing the essential texture of the puffed cereal product, or destroying the adhesion between the individual grains of product provided by the matrix. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> By comparing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference>, which also shows a forming process, the similarities in the processes can be seen. Thus, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A and 12B</cross-reference>, the trailing edge of the tool cuts a leading edge <highlight><bold>1113</bold></highlight> of the strip of product. Volume matching is achieved because the finished product is of decreased length and height, and increased width, relative to the generally rectangular end section of the stick of puffed cereal stock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, an illustrated segment <highlight><bold>1117</bold></highlight> of the puffed cereal generally designated <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is illustrated. As shown, the individual grains of the puffed cereal, which by nature have relatively low compressive strength, are bonded together by surface contact. The binding for such product may be achieved by the action of gluten, starch or other component of the cereals having similar inherent adhesive properties, especially as these are developed during the heating and processing of the cereal. In this case, no adhesives are intentionally added. If surface adhesives are utilized, they usually constitute a very thin coating for the grains of cereal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> Referring to such adhesives, a coating of a suitable binder material is sometimes added to the prepuffed cereal grains prior to compression. Such a coating may, for example, comprise a cereal flour, a sugar or an edible gum. Suitable cereal flours include rice flour, wheat flour and corn flour. Suitable sugars include dextrans, maltodextrins, syrups of glucose, fructose, maltose, sucrose or mixtures thereof, and caramels. Suitable edible gums include xantham gum, guar gum, carrageenan, locust beam gum and mixtures thereof. Other adhesives include zein and modified vegetable fats. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> Preferably, most or all such binders comprise aqueous liquids. One preferable coating comprises at least 80% w/w of water, most preferably at least 95% of water. The aqueous liquid coating may contain dissolved vitamins, colorants or flavoring agents. Preferably, the aqueous liquid is sprayed onto the puffed cereal grains shortly before the compression step, preferably no more than 60 seconds before the compression step, and most preferably no more than 20 seconds before the compression step. It is thought that water assists the binding of the prepuffed cereal grains by softening and partially dissolving components at the surface of the grains, including local activation of the starch. In addition, water is a good susceptor for ultrasound and will tend to localize ultrasonic heating at the surfaces of the puffed grains, where bonding takes place. Because water absorption can cause a loss of crispness or chewability in puffed cereals&mdash;thus compromising favorable eating characteristics&mdash;steps should be taken to insure that this does not occur. Preferably, the grains of cereal are coated with a moisture barrier to prevent water absorption if either the matrix or a flavoring coating is formulated so as to allow water to migrate from the matrix or coating into the grains. The permissible amount of water used can be determined by those skilled in the art when addressing the makeup of the particular binder, adhesive, flavoring coating, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> In some cases, the binder coating is applied to the prepuffed cereal grains in an amount of from 0.1 to 100% by weight, more preferably 5 to 50% by weight, and most preferably 10 to 30% by weight based on the dry weight of the prepuffed cereal grains. The binder coating may also be applied to the edible inclusions, where these are added to the cereal grains. Preferably, the binder does not make up more than 10% by volume, more preferably not more than 2% by volume, and most preferably not more than 1% by volume of the puffed cereal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> Referring to caramels, and some syrups or sugars, these may form the illustrated matrix rather than being merely a binder. Of course, it is understood that these binding steps have taken place in order to form the sticks, ropes or slabs of stock before they are post-formed by the processes described herein and illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>AA, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> shows the end portion of a strip generally designated <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>wherein inclusions <highlight><bold>999</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>997</bold></highlight> are shown among an array of puffed grains <highlight><bold>1001</bold></highlight>, all held together by a plasticizable matrix <highlight><bold>1003</bold></highlight>. A stick of such material is plasticized, cut or formed just as is its counterpart in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, using the ultrasonically energized tool of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> or <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, for example. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> shows the end portion of a strip generally designated <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>which is the same as that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> in all respects except that the inclusions <highlight><bold>1005</bold></highlight> are shown as being nuts or other relatively hard inclusions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> The end portion of an extruded rope generally designated <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>. The rope differs from the slabs or sticks of FIGS. <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>A. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>, no inclusions are shown, and the rope <highlight><bold>998</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is held together by surface binding. There is no plasticizable matrix of material present between individual grains of puffed cereal <highlight><bold>1001</bold></highlight>. The puffed cereal material is formed in a rope configuration such as that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> as it leaves the extruder. If the rope is engaged by three dimensional tools as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, while it is still pliable, surface texture or a particular shape may be imparted to the product. If it is not processed within a second or two, usually a fraction of a second, it will set into a characteristic shape in cross-section and cannot be further shaped. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> Depending on the nature and extent of binder, the ultrasonic energy can be used in the cutting and/or forming process to achieve types of product formation that has heretofore been deemed impossible or impractical. The use of ultrasonic energy is a non-destructive manner of effectively plasticizing the adhesive matrix components of a strip to enable the puffed grains to be rearranged without being destroyed, and this ability enables shapes of altered depth or width relative to an initially formed product stick to be made. In particular, the method and apparatus enable products of widely varying contours and surface textures to be made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> With the recent popularity of puffed rice and other puffed cereal products, the ability to create shapes that are attractive, particularly to younger consumers, is very important, and this is a significant feature of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> Referring now to other aspects of the invention, for confectionery use, it has been found preferable to form the tooling from titanium alloys. The-mechanical properties of these alloys, and their compatibility with confectionery products combine with their desirable acoustic properties to render them highly suitable for use with the apparatus of the invention. Regarding the form of confectionery products with which the process and apparatus are effective, candy bars, &ldquo;frozen&rdquo; confectionery products, and other confectionery products such as fudge, chocolate, toffee, caramel, nougats, etc. can be cut and formed using the apparatus of the invention. Some such products can be used as formed, and others can be enrobed with chocolate. Various high production, continuous type methods having been described in detail, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that if it is desired for any reason to conduct manufacturing on a reduced scale, this is also possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> While the applicant does not wish to be bound by any particular principle or theory of operation, it is believed that the combination of mechanical forces and ultrasonic energy combine to plasticize a confectionery product in the form of a strip, rope or slab sufficiently to reform it but without melting the strip. The plasticity enables the product to be shaped under comparatively moderate forces and to achieve virtually 100% cavity filling. The amplitude of the vibration of the molding surfaces is such that a fine surface finish can be imparted to the product and yet virtually 100% cavity release can be achieved. Normally, there is no detectable product build up on the interior of the forming cavity even after a substantial period of time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> The temperature of the extrusion or slab for most candy products is commonly maintained just above room temperature, usually in the 18 to 35&deg; C. range. Other products are processed at different temperatures. The vibratory motion imparted to the cutting edges of the tool of the forming tool enable relatively hard inclusions, such as nuts or the like, to be cut without incident. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> The comparatively simple positioning of the ultrasonic stack for movement and the availability of servo motors or other control mechanisms renders the process equipment capable of inclusion into existing production lines without disruption or addition of significant cost. Thus, existing extruders, packagers, and the like may be utilized without change or modification. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0171" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0171&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 1A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, an output conveyor operating at a higher speed than the input conveyor is illustrated, but as long as the individual products made are spaced from the leading edge of the slab, such conveyor speed is not absolutely necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0172" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0172&rsqb;</number> The apparatus and method described have been proven capable of rendering a strip or slab of confectionery material usable to create a particular taste, consistency and eating characteristics in a given product as the feedstock for producing true analog products, i.e. those having those same characteristics in a product of an entirely different shape. Complex shapes and shapes with rounded bottoms, textured surfaces and the other characteristics described herein can readily be made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0173" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0173&rsqb;</number> It will thus be seen that the present invention provides several methods and apparatus for forming confectionery products and representative embodiments having been described by way of example, it is anticipated that variations to the described forms of apparatus and method will occur to those skilled in the art and variations and that changes may be made in such methods and forms of apparatus without departing from the spirit of the invention or scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of forming individual pieces of confectionery product having a characteristic shape and surface finish, said method including the steps of creating an ultrasonic product forming tool having node and antinode portions, forming a cavity in the vicinity of said anti-node portion, said cavity having a desired interior shape, surface finish and being defined in part by margins forming at least one cutting edge portion, positioning said forming tool adjacent a continuously advancing strip of confectionery stock moving along a given path, energizing said forming tool so as to cause said cavity surface and said cutting edge to vibrate through a given amplitude at an ultrasonic frequency, and periodically moving said forming tool into contact with and through an end portion of said advancing strip of confectionery stock so as to simultaneously cut said stock into individual pieces, and form each individual piece into a finished confectionery product having a shape and surface finish corresponding to that of said forming tool, and separating each of said pieces thus formed from said strip of confectionery stock. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said tool is ultrasonically vibrated at a frequency of at least 10 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the frequency of vibration is from about 20 kHz to about 40 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said tool is in contact with said supply of confectionery feedstock for a period of from about 30 to about 200 milliseconds. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said tool is in contact with its supply of confectionery feedstock for a period of from about 80 to about 180 milliseconds. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the amplitude of vibration of said tool surface in contact with said strip is from about 10 to about 100 microns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the amplitude of vibration of said surface is from about 10 to about 50 microns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the frequency, contact time and amplitude of vibration of said tool are sufficient to plasticize said stock of confectionery material in contact with said tool without substantial heat generation, whereby the taste, consistency and eating characteristics of the ingredients of said confectionery stock are not significantly altered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> which further includes the steps of depositing a confectionery coating onto said individual confectionery products cut and formed as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said stock of confectionery material comprises plural individual grains of a puffed cereal, the outer surfaces of said grains being in surface contact with the outer surfaces of adjacent grains. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said confectionery material comprises a rice cake material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said confectionery material is a material containing puffed rice grains, said material further including a substantially continuous, edible, heat plasticizable matrix securing said grains of puffed rice to one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A flashless molding method for forming a plurality of substantially identical, individual finished confectionery products each having a given finished volume from a continuous supply of a confectionery product feedstock having a given taste, consistency and eating characteristics, said method comprising the steps of determining the cross-sectional area of said feedstock, advancing said continuous supply of confectionery product feedstock, and, utilizing a cutting and forming tool having a cutting edge portion and a cavity of a given volume and having interior surfaces of a desired shape and texture, imparting an ultrasonic vibratory motion to said cutting and forming tool, periodically forming sections of said feedstock to the shape and texture of said cavity inner surface and cutting said sections to a length such that, given said cross-sectional area of said feedstock, the volume of each of said cut sections will equal said given volume of said cavity, and whereby said individual finished confectionery products will be substantially flash-free. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said feedstock has a height greater than that of said cavity and wherein each section has a width and length less than that of said cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said tool is ultrasonically vibrated at a frequency of at least 10 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the frequency of vibration is from about 20 kHz to about 40 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said tool is in contact with said supply of confectionery feedstock for a period of from about 30 to about 200 milliseconds. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the frequency, contact time and amplitude of vibration of said tool are sufficient to plasticize said stock of confectionery material in contact with said tool without substantial heat generation, whereby the taste, consistency and eating characteristics of the ingredients of said confectionery stock are not significantly altered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said continuous supply of confectionery product feedstock comprises a supply of a puffed cereal material wherein the individual grains of puffed cereal are bonded to one another by a surface coating of a material having an adhesive character. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said individual grains of puffed cereal are embedded in a substantially continuous matrix of an edible, heat plasticizable material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said edible, heat-plasticizable material includes caramel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cereal comprises rice. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a plurality of individual confectionery products each having a desired three dimensional shape and desired surface finish, said method including providing a pair of opposed ultrasonic product forming tools each having a product forming cavity in its end face, each of said cavities having a desired interior shape and surface finish and each being defined in part by margins forming at least one cutting edge portion, positioning said pair of forming tools with said cavities in opposed facing relation and spaced apart by a predetermined distance, continually advancing a continuous supply of confectionery product from a supply source and over a support surface along a given feed path at a predetermined continuous rate, periodically lengthening said feed path by moving said support surface in a direction opposite the direction of said advancing feedstock at a rate equal to said feedstock advancing rate, thereby rendering said feedstock strip immobile for a given duration, and during said given duration, contacting a portion of said feedstock with said cutting edges and said cavity interiors to cut and form a finished piece, subsequently withdrawing said tools from each other and moving said support surface in the direction of said feedstock advance so as to shorten said feed path by an amount equal to the amount said feed path was previously lengthened, and continually repeating said feeding, cutting and forming cycles to create a succession of individual confectionery products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said movable support comprises a roller having a peripheral, product-engaging surface, said and wherein lengthening said feed path comprises moving said roller vertically by means of a linear actuator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said feed path includes a portion downstream of said support surface wherein said continuous supply of said confectionery product moves vertically under the influence of gravity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A method of forming individual pieces of confectionery material from a continually advancing continuous rope of confectionery material, said method including periodically shortening and lengthening the effective feed path of the article to periodically start and stop the motion of the strip leading edge and an adjacent portion of said rope, moving at least one an ultrasonically energized forming tool into contact with said adjacent portion of said rope during the time said leading edge and adjacent portion are stationary and periodically repeating this cycle to form said individual pieces of confectionery material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one ultrasonically energized forming tool comprises a pair of opposed forming tools. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A method of making formed confectionery products including pre-cutting confectionery stock into individual pieces of a desired shape and length, periodically positioning said pieces thus formed onto an anvil unit having a desired shape and surface finish, successively contacting said individual pieces on said anvil with a forming tool having a cutting edge and a forming cavity of a predetermined shape and surface texture, and energy said forming tool by ultrasonic vibration during the portion of said forming cycle in which pieces are supported on said anvil and in contact with said tool. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said ultrasonic vibration occurs at a frequency of from about 10 kHz to about 40 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said portion of said forming tool energized by said ultrasonic vibration moves through an amplitude of from about 10 to about 50 microns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a frequency, contact time and amplitude of vibration of said tool are sufficient to plasticize said stock of confectionery material in contact with said tool without substantial heat generation, whereby the taste and consistency and eating characteristics of the ingredients of said confectionery stock are not significantly altered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A method as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said individual pieces of confectionery stock comprise pieces of a puffed rice cake material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for continuous manufacture of confectionery products, said apparatus including a frame, an input conveyor secured to said frame and including upper and lower run portions and a drive mechanism adapted to operate said conveyor at a first given speed; an output conveyor secured to said frame and having an upper run, a lower run and a drive mechanism adapted to operate said output conveyor at a second higher speed, said output conveyor being positioned adjacent and downstream of said input conveyor, said output conveyor being adapted to receive products formed on a downstream end portion of the upper run of said input conveyor, an ultrasonic stack including an energy converter for changing electrical energy into ultrasonic vibration, a booster for increasing the amplitude of said vibration and an ultrasonic horn having surfaces defining a cutting edge and a forming cavity with a predetermined interior shape and surface finish, a carrier for said stack, said carrier being positioned by a portion of said frame, and at least one motor and control for moving said stack generally parallel to said downstream end portion of the said upper run of said input conveyor, a mechanism for plunging said stack from a raised initial position to a lowered position adjacent said upper run of said input conveyor, thus enabling said stack to be lowered into contact with a portion of a continuous supply of confectionery material positioned on said upper conveyor run at said first rate so as to be synchronized with the movement rate of said upper run, said mechanism also being capable of accelerating said stack away from the leading edge of said continuous supply of confectionery material so as to space an individual piece formed by said cavity from said leading edge and into a position adjacent the upstream end said upper run of said output conveyor, and said mechanism further being adapted to move said cavity out of engagement with of stack and to return said stack to said initial position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said input conveyor further includes a support plate beneath its upper run adjacent said downstream end of said conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said motor and control is in form of a programmable servomotor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. An apparatus including a feeder for providing a continuous rope of confectionery product of given a cross-section and advancing said rope along a feed path, a positioner permitting said rope to extend vertically under the influence of gravity while being advanced along said feed path, a control for said positioner adapted to alter the length of said feed path so as to lengthen and shorten said path from time-to-time, whereby said path may be lengthened at a rate equal to said feed rate to stop movement of said rope along said feed path, and shortened so as to accelerate said feed rate, said apparatus further including at least one ultrasonically energized stack comprised of a converter, a booster and a confectionery product forming tool, a stack positioner for moving said forming tool into engagement with at least the portion of the rope adjacent its leading edge when said leading edge is stopped, and for releasing a formed product prior to shortening said feed path of said rope means to permit resumption of advancement by said leading edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A method of forming individual confectionery products, said method including providing an ultrasonically energizable cutting and forming tool having a cavity of a predetermined shape, surface texture and a cutting edge portion, imparting an ultrasonic vibration to said cutting and forming tool at a given frequency and a first amplitude, adding power to said tool so as to increase said amplitude to a second higher amplitude and moving said cutting and forming tool into contact with a strip of confectionery material while said surfaces and edge portions are being energized at said higher amplitude, thereby forming an individual confectionery product, releasing said product from said cavity, and decreasing said amplitude to said first amplitude until said cavity and cutting edge are again positioned for engagement with said strip of confectionery material.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>ONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003207A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
