<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003993A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003993A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003993</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10194807</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020715</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A63F009/24</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>463</class>
<subclass>039000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Wireless game control units</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10194807</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020715</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09708213</doc-number>
<document-date>20001108</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09708213</doc-number>
<document-date>20001108</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09092489</doc-number>
<document-date>19980605</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6280327</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09708213</doc-number>
<document-date>20001108</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09023813</doc-number>
<document-date>19980213</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alan</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Leifer</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Dix Hills</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<family-name>Leifer</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Melville</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chi-Fu</given-name>
<family-name>Peng</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chung Li</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KEUSEY, TUTUNJIAN &amp; BITETTO, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>14 VANDERVENTER AVENUE, SUITE 128</address-1>
<city>PORT WASHINGTON</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>11050</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A wireless control unit includes a controller having wireless transmitter circuitry for transmitting game information, and a console interface/adapter for converting one of the communication ports of the game console into a wireless receiver/transmitter. The console interface/adapter also includes an additional communication port so as to provide the user with access to the used communication port while the interface/adapter is operably disposed within the communication port of the game console. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation of co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/708,213 filed Nov. 8, 2000, which is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/023,813, filed Feb. 13, 1998, now U.S. Pat. No. 6,280,327.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present application generally relates to electronic device controllers. More particularly, it relates to wireless electronic device control units for gaming environments. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE RELATED ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Home video game systems generally have a game console coupled to a television monitor and one or more game controllers connected to the console which permit user interaction with a game being played. Most video game systems are sold with game controllers that are connected to the console through a hard-wire link. More recently, wireless game controller accessories have been developed which provide players with more freedom of movement. Such wireless controller accessories replicate the basic control features found on conventional hard-wired controllers but use infrared (IR), radio frequency (RF) or other electromagnetic radiation to send signals to the console. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> To operate the video game system, a user (or player) inserts a game program which may be stored in a game cartridge or on a compact disc into the console and typically depresses a start switch to begin play of the particular game programmed into the cartridge or on the compact disc. As a game is played, a player or players control various visual aspects of the game using either the hard-wired or wireless controllers. For example, certain video games allow players to maneuver persons or aliens over various types of terrain, through tunnels, under water and over other various obstacles in order to score points. Some of these video games allow players to fly planes, helicopters, tanks and the like to attack various installations and score points. Other video games allow players to maneuver a person and to fire weapons at program generated images or at images of a person controlled by another player. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To allow players to continuously fire a weapon some conventional hard-wired video game systems include an auto fire function. In the hard-wired systems, the auto fire function can be activated by a single switch or the activation of a sequence of switches on the game controller. Activation of the auto fire function causes the game controller to continuously send to the game console a fire signal which results in the continuous firing of one or more game weapons. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Some current wireless game controllers include a power save (or sleep) function intended to conserve battery power when the controller is not in use for a predetermined period of time. The sleep function was mainly developed to conserve battery power when a controller&apos;s power switch is inadvertently left on after a player finishes playing a game. The sleep function automatically monitors the activity of the controller switches and turns off the power to the internal circuits of the controller after a predetermined period of time elapses without any switches on the controller being actuated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> However, since certain current wireless game controllers include the sleep function it is impractical to also include the auto fire function because if the auto fire function is activated and a user stops playing a game but fails to turn the controller power switch off, the auto fire function will continue to function so that the controller continues to generate and send the fire signal. The fire signal would then be detected by the sleep circuitry so that the sleep function does not activate and the controller would continue to draw battery power to generate and send the fire signals. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present application provides various embodiments of wireless game control units that provides an auto activate function that is activated by a controller in the game control unit and maintained by a console interface in the game control unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the wireless control unit includes a controller having at least one user operable switch and wireless transmitter circuitry for transmitting game information, including an auto fire start signal, and a console interface having wireless receiver circuitry for receiving the game information, including an auto activate start signal, from the controller and for modifying the game information so that an activate signal is continuously sent from the console interface to the console and at least one object, such as a weapon, in a game being played with the video game system is continuously activated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment, the wireless control unit can be configured for multiple player operation. The control unit includes a plurality of controllers each having at least one user operable switch and wireless transmitter circuitry for transmitting game information, including an auto activate start signal, and at least one console interface having wireless receiver circuitry for receiving the game information, including the auto activate start signal, from each of the plurality of controllers and for selectively modifying the game information from each controller so that when the auto activate start signal is received at least one fire signal is continuously sent from the console interface to the console and at least one object, such as a weapon, in a game being played with the video game system is continuously activated. The console interface can also include at least one connection port to receive at least one memory cartridge for storing game information associated with a game being played with each controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present application also provides a video game system that includes a game console, a controller having at least one user operable switch and wireless transmitter circuitry for transmitting game information, including an auto activate start signal, and a console interface connectable to the game console and having wireless receiver circuitry for receiving the game information, including the auto activate start signal, from the controller and for modifying the game information so that an activate signal is continuously sent from the console interface to the console and at least one weapon in a game being played with the video game system is continuously activated. The video system may also include a connection port for receiving a memory cartridge that stores game information. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In the drawings wherein like reference numerals denote similar elements throughout the views: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a video game system incorporating a wireless controller unit according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side-elevational view of a controller for the wireless control unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the present application; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of the controller of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a front elevational view of the controller of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram of transmitter circuitry for the controller of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a console interface for the wireless control unit <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a top view of the console interface of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a block diagram of receiver circuitry for the console interface of the wireless controller unit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a block diagram of an alternative embodiment for the wireless control <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> unit according to the present invention, illustrating a console interface which supports multiple player use of the system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a block diagram of an alternative embodiment for the wireless control unit according to the present invention having separate console interfaces which support multiple player use of the system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a block diagram of another alternative embodiment of the wireless controller unit for bi-directional communication between the controller and the console interface; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic representation of a game console in accordance with an embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternative console interface according to an embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is an end view of the console interface according to the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is an opposing end view of the console interface according to the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the console interface according to another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is an end view of the console interface according to the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is an opposing end view of the console interface according to the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the console interface according to another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is an end view of the embodiment of the console interface depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the console interface according to yet another embodiment of the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is an end view of the console interface depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The present application provides a wireless control unit for video game systems that provides an auto fire function that does not interfere with the proper operation of a sleep function incorporated into the wireless control unit. Preferably, the wireless control unit transfers game information by infrared (IR) transmissions. However, other known electromagnetic radiation techniques, such as radio frequency (RF) transmissions, may be employed. In accordance with other embodiments (to be discussed later), the combined use of IR and RF wireless communication protocols provides superior communication results between a game controller and a game console. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an exemplary embodiment of a video game system incorporating the wireless control unit of the present application is shown. In this embodiment, the video game system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a video outputting device <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, such as a television monitor, and the wireless control unit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a housing having at least one controller (or game) connection port and a game cartridge port. A game cartridge has a video game program stored therein. Alternatively, the console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may include a disc drive mechanism in which a disc, such as a compact disc, has stored thereon a video game program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> also includes known circuitry for executing the video game program stored in the cartridge or on disc. For example, the console may include a processor, memory and stored system programs for controlling the operation of the console, controller interface circuitry, and audio/video generating and outputting circuitry. An example of suitable game consoles are included in the Nintendo N64&reg;, SEGA Genesis and Sony Playstation&trade; and Playstation II&trade; game systems. In the video game system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to this embodiment of the present invention, the console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is connected to a video outputting apparatus <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via a direct wire link. Further, the wireless control unit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can be connected to the console by, for example, a direct wire link or by mating connectors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring generally to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the wireless control unit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> according to one embodiment of the present application includes a controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. As seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has a housing <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> defined by a control section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, left and right side handles <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> extending out from the control section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and then angled downwardly, and a center handle <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extending from a center portion of the control section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Since in this embodiment signals are transmitted from the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> via infrared, the housing <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> preferably includes a transmission window <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for emitting infrared signals. However, if the transmission of control information from the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is by other electromagnetic radiation techniques then a transmission window may not be necessary. A plurality of user activated switches <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are mounted to the housing <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and accessible from outer surface portions of the housing <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also includes a battery (not shown) that supplies power to the internal components of the controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Typically, a player grips the center handle <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and one of the side handles <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> during play and operates the switches corresponding to the handles gripped. A player may also grip the left and right side handles <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, where rocker switch <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and push-button switches <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are the user activated switches. Rocker switch <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> can be used for two or three dimensional movement of an object controlled by the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and push-button switches <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be used for performing control functions associated with the object. Further, the orientation of the switches <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the three handle configuration of the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also facilitates single handed as well as two handed gripping and operation of the controller by a player. For single handed gripping and operation, a player can grip the center handle <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and joystick <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and trigger switch <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are the user activated switches, Joystick <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can be used for two or three dimensional movement of an object controlled by the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and trigger switch <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> can be used for performing at least one control function associated with the object. In this embodiment, trigger switch <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is typically used to fire weapons during a game. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also includes transmitter circuitry <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> operatively connected to the various switches, which receives game information from the switches, formats the game information into, for example, bit streams for wireless transmission, and transmits the game information to the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The transmitter circuitry <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> includes control logic <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, transmitter driver logic <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and at least one transmitter source <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The control logic <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> receives the game information from the various switches, and encodes the game information into, for example, a serial bit stream which is suitable for wireless transmission preferably by infrared. The bit stream may be configured such that one or more bits in the stream represents one switch on the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The transmitter circuitry <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> receives the bit stream from the control logic <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and amplifies (if necessary) and modulates the bit stream at a predefined frequency band (e.g., 38 kHz) to energize at least one infrared source <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> (e.g., an LED) which emits infra-red signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> To conserve battery power in the controller, the control logic <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> can be configured control battery power to the internal components of the controller and to monitor the activation of the switches and if none of the switches are activated for a predetermined period of time, e.g., about 2 minutes, the control logic shuts off the battery power to the internal circuits of the controller. This function is also known as a sleep function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has a housing <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> that includes a cartridge port <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and, if necessary, a transmission window <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> for receiving the infra-red transmissions from the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The cartridge port <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is configured to receive a memory cartridge (or memory card) <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and includes a connector <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> that connects to a connector in the memory cartridge. An example of a suitable memory cartridge is the N64&reg; CONTROLLER PAK&trade; manufactured by Nintendo. A cable <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> extending from the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes a connector <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> adapted to be connected to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, connector <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is coupled to a game controller port on the game console. Alternatively, communication ports other than the game controller ports of the game console may be used to connected the console interface to the game console. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Game information from the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and game condition information saved on the memory cartridge <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are transferred to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for subsequent processing via cable <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> or a connector extending from the console interface. In addition, when a player wants to end a game, the player can instruct the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to save the current game conditions in the memory cartridge <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> in the interface console. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> also includes receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> that receives the transmitted bit stream, extracts the game information from the bit stream, formats the game information into a form suitable for processing by the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and transfers the game information to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. More particularly, in an IR embodiment, the receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> includes a sensor <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, such as a photosensitive transistor, which receives the infrared signals from the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and receiver logic <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> that amplifies the received bit stream, demodulates the amplified bit stream and decodes the game information from the bit stream. Console interface logic <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> then formats the game information for transfer to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> via, for example, cable <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>). In a contemplated RF embodiment, sensor <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> would be an RF antenna. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As noted, the auto activate function in hard-wired systems is actuated and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> generated at the controller so that the controller continuously sends an activate signal to the game console. In the wireless control unit according to the present application, the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> sends an auto activate start signal which is included in the bit stream to the receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, which decodes the game information from the bit stream. The console interface logic <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> also monitors the bit stream for the auto activate start signal, and when it is detected in the stream the console interface automatically includes in the game information to be transmitted to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> an activate signal so that one or more objects, such as weapons, in the game being played and controlled by the controller is continuously activated. The console interface logic <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> continues to insert the activate signal into the game information signals sent to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> until the receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> detects auto activate stop signal from the controller. When auto activate stop signal is detected by the receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> the receiver circuitry stops inserting the activate signal into the game information sent to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> By having the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> send a signal to start the auto activate function in the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to continuously provide the activate signals to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the auto activate function does not prevent the activation of the sleep function in the controller. That is, the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the wireless control unit according to the present application does not continuously send the activate signals when the auto activate function is active and therefore, the sleep circuitry in the controller does not continuously detect the auto activate start signal even after a player has stopped playing a game but has inadvertently left the controller power switch on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The embodiment discussed above for the controller and console interface is for single player applications. For single player applications the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are pre-configured to transmit and receive the bit streams at one frequency band, e.g., 100 KHZ using one data coding scheme. However, many game programs executed by the game console permit multiple players to play at one time. For multiple player applications, a plurality of controllers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and either a single console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> having receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to receive game information from the plurality of controllers (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>), or a plurality of console interfaces in one to one correspondence with the plurality of controllers (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) are used. In either configuration, the game information transmitted from a controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to its corresponding receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is differentiated from game information transmitted from other controllers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to their corresponding receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> so as to avoid cross-talk between the controllers. To achieve this, the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> for each player may be configured to transmit and received the bit streams at the same frequency band but the frequency band for each controller and corresponding receiver circuitry is different. Alternatively, each controller may transmit the game information at the same frequency but the data coding scheme used by each controller and corresponding receiver circuitry is different. To select the operational frequency band or data coding scheme for the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and corresponding receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> for each player, player select switches are provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In an exemplary embodiment for two players in which the frequency band used is different for each player, the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes player select switch <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, which allows a player to select a frequency band for player <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) or player <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) operation. Similarly, player select switch <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> on the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, allows the player to select a frequency band for player <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) or player <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) operation. In this embodiment, by selecting player <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> on the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the controller is set to transmit and the console interface to receive at one operational frequency band, for example, about 38 KHZ. By selecting player <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> the controller is set to transmit and the console interface to receive at another operational frequency band, for example, about 100 KHZ. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> For multiple player applications, the transmitter driver logic <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, is modified to be able to transmit the bit stream at different frequencies which can be selected by the player select switch <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the receiver logic <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, is modified to receive bit streams at different frequencies. Such receiver logic may include for example a band pass filter which sets the frequency band for receiving the bit stream before the stream is demodulated. More detailed descriptions of the transmitter and receiver circuitry can be found in U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,435,573 and 5,605,505, both of which are incorporated herein in their entirety by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As noted, an alternative embodiment for the wireless control unit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. In this embodiment, the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of sensors <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and a plurality of corresponding receiver logic blocks <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> each block being reconfigured to receive bit streams at one frequency band. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows two sensors <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and two corresponding receiver logic blocks <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> which are used to separately receive game information from two controllers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for two player operation. However, the present application contemplates using more than two controllers so that more than two sensors and corresponding receiver logic blocks may used for more than two players. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, in order to allow each player to save his own game information, multiple memory cartridges <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> may be used, one for each player. However, a single memory cartridge may also be used to store game information for every player. Data transfers between each memory card and the game console would be by separate cables <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> (or connectors) connected to the player port on the game console. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, an another alternative embodiment of the wireless control unit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> according to the present invention is shown. In this embodiment, the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are configured for bi-directional wireless communication. For bi-directional wireless communication, the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> both would include the transmitter logic <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>) and the receiver logic <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>). As discussed above, the transmitter and receiver circuitry for each player playing a game would operate at different frequency bands (or use different coding schemes). Information transmitted from the controller to the console interface includes game information, and information from the console interface to the controller includes information to, for example, reconfigure the functions of the switches and information that provides interaction between the controller and a game being played. The information from the console interface to the controller is collectively defined as controller information. Thus, the controller can include a connection port <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> (seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</cross-reference>) for connecting different peripheral devices to the controller which are responsive to the controller information transmitted by the console. Such peripheral devices include memory cartridges, vibrating members (e.g., a rumble pack), and other devices that can respond to controller information transmitted by the console. To illustrate, the vibrating mechanism can be excited at times during play which coincide with certain conditions of the game, such as during a crash. When a crash occurs, the console sends an information signal to the controller to energize the vibrating member so that the entire controller vibrates and the vibrations are felt by the player. A suitable vibrating member is the Rumble Pak&trade; manufactured by Nintendo. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> also illustrates using a single memory cartridge for storing <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> the game condition information for each player at one time. However, as noted above multiple memory cartridges may also be used. Further, in this embodiment gun controllers which require bi-directional communication with the game console can be substituted for the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Such gun controllers would include the transmitter and receiver circuitry discussed above and information transfers would operate in a similar manner as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> In the two player embodiments, each controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the wireless control unit according to the present application can send an auto fire start signal which is included in the bit stream to the corresponding receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> which decodes the game information from the bit stream. Similar to the above-described embodiments, the console interface logic <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> for each controller monitors the bit stream for the auto activate start signal, and when it is detected in the stream, the console interface logic automatically inserts an activate signal into the game information to be transmitted to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> so that one or more objects, such as weapons, in the game being played is continuously activated. The console interface logic <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> for each controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which sends the auto activate start signal continues to insert the activate signal into the corresponding bit stream until the receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> detects an auto activate stop signal for the corresponding controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. When auto activate stop signal is detected by the receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, the receiver circuitry stops inserting the activate signal into the game information sent to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As noted above, by having the controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> send a information to start the <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> auto activate function and the receiver circuitry <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> in the console interface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to continuously provide the activate signals to the game console <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the auto activate function does not prevent the activation of the sleep function in the controllers. That is, the controllers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of each wireless control unit according to this embodiment does not continuously send the activate signals when the auto activate function is active and the sleep circuitry in each controller does not continuously detect the auto activate start signal even after a player has stopped playing a game but has inadvertently left the controller power switch on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> shows a video game console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the invention. Console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a power on/off/reset button <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and a door open button <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> for controlling access to the media tray <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Game controller ports <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are provided for receiving wired game controllers and include corresponding memory slots <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for providing the user with the ability to add memory to the system. Console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> also includes other communication ports, such as, for example, universal serial bus (USB) ports <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and an IEEE 1394 FireWire&trade; port <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may also include an IR window <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and an RF antenna <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and corresponding circuitry which enables console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to communicate with a wireless controller via IR, RF or a combination of both. It is also contemplated that other communication ports such as a fiber optic port, PCMCIA slots, and broadband high speed communication ports may also be incorporated into the game console. Those of skill in the art recognize that such other ports are within the scope of this disclosure and the console interface may be operatively configured for such ports. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and similar video game consoles, such as, for example. The SONY Playstation II&trade; are advancing to the point where they are no longer dedicated video game playing devices. This means that console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is now capable of playing other media, such as Digital Video (Versatile) Discs (DVD). These DVD type gaming consoles will likely include and IR receiver <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> or RF receiver <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> adapted to receive remote control codes for the DVD functions of the console and not primarily for wireless game controllers. Although these receivers could be used for receiving wireless controllers, they do not include wireless transmitters for transmitting information to the wireless controllers. This information can include, but is not limited to, controlling internal vibration members of the game controller, programming the controller, etc. As such, there is a need to provide IR and/or RF transmission capability to the game console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, which is provided by the wireless adapters of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> show various different embodiments of a console interface/wireless adapter according to the invention. Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, there is shown a wireless adapter/reciever <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> according to one embodiment of the present invention. Adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes a housing <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, a male plug <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> on one end for connection to one of the game controller ports <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of a game console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>) and an infrared (IR) receiver/transmitter portion <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> opposite plug <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. In addition, adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes a radio frequency (RF) antenna <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and corresponding RF circuitry so that adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> can be used with RF or a combination of IR and RF technology (to be discussed later). An indicator light <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> is included for indicating when adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is receiving or transmitting information via IR or RF from or to the game controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> converts the game controller port <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of a video game console into an IR receiver/transmitter capable of receiving and inputting control commands into the game console and transmitting control commands to the controller such as, for example, commands to provide feedback to the game controller, for example, to control an internal vibration member (e.g., internal rumble pack). In this embodiment, when adapter/receiver <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is in its operable position within the game controller port <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the used game controller port is no longer available for use with a game controller. However, in accordance with a preferred embodiment, adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes an additional female game port <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> that effectively provides the user with another game controller port for connecting a wired game controller or other accessory items to the game console while adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is in its operable position within the game controller port <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes IR window <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and corresponding circuitry for receiving IR commands from and to the wireless controller. As such, adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> will provide IR transmission capability to the console and enable the console to wirelessly transmit control commands to the game controller. Again, these control commands can include, but are not limited to, programming/configuration commands and feedback commands for controlling internal elements of the game controller, such as an internal vibration member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may also include and RF antenna <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and corresponding circuitry for receiving RF signals. As such, the wireless adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> can be used to send either IR or RF signals to the controller and the controller can send RF signals directly back to the console. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In accordance with other embodiments of the invention, the console interface or wireless adapter can be operably disposed within any one of the communication ports of the game console. For example, referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, there is shown an embodiment of the wireless adapter <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> having a housing <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> and a plug end <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> adapted to be inserted into one of the memory slots <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the game console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>). Wireless adapter <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> also includes the IR communication means <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> along with the RF antenna <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> and corresponding RF circuitry to enable the use of RF, IR or a combination of both. An additional memory slot or plug <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> may also be included to provide the user with the ability to add memory as desired. In yet another embodiment, adapter <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> includes an internal memory <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> of variable size. The inclusion of an internal memory <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> would enable the elimination of the additional memory slot <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and provide adapter <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> with the additional functionality of adding memory to the system while enabling the wireless communication with the game controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> show another embodiment of the adapter <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> having a housing <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> and a male plug end <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> adapted to be inserted into one of the USB ports <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the game console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>) and an infrared (IR) receiver/transmitter portion <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> opposite plug <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>. In addition, adapter <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> includes a radio frequency (RF) antenna <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> so that adapter <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> can be used with IR, RF or a combination of both IR and RF technology (to be discussed later). An indicator light <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is included for indicating when adapter <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is receiving or transmitting information via IR or RF from or to the game controller. According to a preferred embodiment, a female USB receptacle <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> is included on adapter <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> so as to provide the user with another USB port while adapter <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is using one of the USB ports <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the game console. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> show another embodiment of the adapter <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> having a housing <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and a male plug end <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> adapted to be inserted into the IEEE 1394 FireWire&trade; port <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the game console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>) and an infrared (IR) receiver/transmitter portion <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> opposite plug <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. In addition, adapter <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> includes a radio frequency (RF) antenna <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> so that adapter <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> can be used with IR, RF or a combination of both IR and RF technology (to be discussed later). An indicator light <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is included for indicating when adapter <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is receiving or transmitting information via IR or RF from or to the game controller. According to another preferred embodiment, a female IEEE 1394 FireWire&trade; receptacle <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> is also included on adapter <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> so as to provide the user with another IEEE 1394 FireWire&trade; port while adapter <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is using the IEEE 1394 FireWire&trade; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the game console. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In each of the above described embodiments, RF antennae <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> are shown disposed external to their respective housings. Those of skill in the art understand that these antennae may be internally disposed in their respective housings so as to eliminate the possibility of accidental breaking or damage during handling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> As mentioned, it is contemplated herein to utilize a combination of IR and RF technology in order to effect the most efficient and cost effective wireless communication between the console <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and the game controllers. Those of skill in the art will recognize that the use of each technology (i.e., IR and RF) comes with their own advantages and disadvantages. For example, IR is generally the wireless method of choice because it is cheaper to implement than RF, and therefore is suitable for keeping products costs down during manufacturing and subsequent sale prices low. However, those of skill in the art will appreciate the &ldquo;line of sight&rdquo; limitation associated with IR. This limitation requires a clear line of sight between the game controller and the game console. Without a clear line of sight, the IR wireless commands cannot reliably be received by the IR receiver. Radio frequency (RF), on the other hand, has proven most reliable in a wireless gaming and remote control environments, however it is generally more expensive to implement and therefore is not desirable when attempting to keep product manufacturing costs and sale prices down. RF effectively eliminates the &ldquo;line of sight&rdquo; limitation on IR. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, wireless communication from the game controller to the console is performed using RF and wireless communication from the console to the game controller is performed using IR. Thus, the game controller includes an RF transmitter and an IR receiver, while the console interface (i.e., adapter of FIGS. <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) includes the RF receiver and the IR transmitter. As mentioned above, the IR transmitter may be included in the console and need not be included in the adapter. In this manner, the more reliable communication method (RF) is utilized for game playing, while the less reliable (&ldquo;line of sight&rdquo;) IR is used for transmitting control commands to the game controller. Since the one way communication from the console to the game controller during game play is primarily to provide feedback to the game controller (e.g., through an internal vibration member <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>&mdash;<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), the need for highly reliable communication in this direction is not as important as the need in the other direction (i.e., from the controller to the console). This is because if the game controller does not provide feedback to the user once in a while due to a line of sight failure of the IR transmission from the console, the user&apos;s ability to control the game is still not effected. Those of ordinary skill in the art will recognize that the combined use of RF and IR can be implemented in many different ways, including the reverse of the above description wherein RF is used for communication from the console to the controller and IR is used for communication from the controller to the console. Other possible implementations include the disposition of both RF and IR circuitry in the console and corresponding circuitry within the game controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Since the disclosed adapters <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> will all contain wireless transmitting capability in one form or another (i.e., IR, RF or both) it is necessary for these adapters to have power. In one embodiment, each adapter can obtain the power necessary for wireless transmitting from the game console via the corresponding male plug <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. In yet another contemplated embodiment, each adapter can have its own on board power supply. For example, each adapter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> can have internal batteries <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>193</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, respectively, which provide the necessary power to the adapter. The batteries may be removable through the releasable removal of the adapter housing (e.g., by sliding) or may be rechargeable through the connection of an appropriate charger and a charging jack <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Those of ordinary skill in the art will recognize that the concepts described herein may been applied to various different types of game controllers without departing from the spirit of the invention. These different types of game controllers include standard, enhanced, programmable and genre specific game controllers, such as, for example, racing controllers, fighting controllers, shooting controllers (e.g., first person shooter), platform/adventure controller, flight simulator, motorcycle/bike controllers, pool cues, fishing, snow boards, golf, and baseball controllers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> It will be understood that various modifications can be made to the embodiments of the present application without departing from the spirit and scope thereof. For example, various types of game consoles executing various types of game programs and interacting with various video outputting apparatus may be used with the wireless control unit. Likewise, various memory cartridges and other peripheral devices may be used with the wireless control unit. Further, the wireless control unit may use other transmission techniques for transferring game information and/or controller information. Therefore, the above description should not be construed as limiting the invention, but merely as disclosing preferred embodiments thereof. Those skilled in the art will envision other modifications within the scope and spirit of the invention as defined by the claims appended hereto. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A wireless control unit for converting a video game system having a game console with game controller ports and being adapted to operate with wired game controllers connected to the game controller ports into a system operable with wireless controllers, the wireless controller unit comprising; 
<claim-text>a game controller having at least one user operable switch, a memory cartridge receptacle, wireless transmitter circuitry for transmitting game information, and wireless receiver circuitry for receiving controller information; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a console interface connected to the game console via at least one of the game controller ports and having wireless receiver circuitry for receiving the game information from the game controller, said console interface including wireless transmitter circuitry for wirelessly transmitting controller information to the game controller. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The wireless control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the console interface further comprises a connection port for receiving a memory cartridge for storing game information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The wireless control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said memory cartridge receptacle receives a memory cartridge for storing at least one of said game information and said controller information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A wireless control unit for converting a video game system having a game console with game controller ports and being adapted to operate with wired game controllers connected to the game controller ports into a system operable with wireless controllers, the wireless control unit comprising: 
<claim-text>a game controller having at least one user operable switch, a memory cartridge receptacle, wireless transmitter circuitry for transmitting game information, wireless receiver circuitry for receiving controller information, and a connection port for receiving a peripheral device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a console interface having wireless receiver circuitry for receiving the game information, from at said game controller, said console interface including wireless transmitter circuitry for transmitting controller information including control signals for activating the peripheral device disposed in said connection port. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The wireless control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the console interface further comprises a connection port for receiving a memory cartridge for storing game information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The wireless control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said peripheral device comprises a memory cartridge for storing at least one of said game information and said controller information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The wireless control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said peripheral device comprises a vibrating member and said controller information includes control signals for activating said vibrating member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A wireless control unit for converting a video game system having a game console with game controller ports and being adapted to operate with wired game controllers connected to the game controller ports into a system operable with wireless controllers, the wireless controller unit comprising; 
<claim-text>a game controller having at least one user operable switch, a memory, wireless transmitter circuitry for transmitting game information, and wireless receiver circuitry for receiving controller information; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a console interface connected to the game console via at least one of the game controller ports and having wireless receiver circuitry for receiving the game information from the game controller, said console interface including wireless transmitter circuitry for wirelessly transmitting controller information to the game controller, said memory for storing at least one of said game information and said controller information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The wireless control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said game controller further comprises a vibrating member, said controller information including control signals for activating sai vibrating member.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030003993A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
