<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003726A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003726A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003726A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003726A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003726A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003726A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003726A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003726A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003726A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003726A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003726A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003726A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003726A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003726A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003726</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10186902</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-39041</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010630</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>672000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Metal lines of semiconductor devices and methods for forming</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hyung</given-name>
<middle-name>Jun</middle-name>
<family-name>Kim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyoungki-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Hynix Semiconductor Inc.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Kyoungki-do</city>
<country>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TOWNSEND AND TOWNSEND AND CREW, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>TWO EMBARCADERO CENTER</address-1>
<address-2>EIGHTH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>SAN FRANCISCO</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94111-3834</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Metal lines of a semiconductor device and methods of forming same are disclosed. During a damascene process filling up a metal line in an insulating film, a low-k layer is used as an insulating film. An anchor groove is formed in one portion of the low-k layer. The anchor groove is filled up with an anchor layer. A metal line is formed, which contacts one or more underlying layers through the anchor layer and the interlayer isolation film. As a result, it is possible to prevent a distortion of a metal line and/or damage to a hard-mask layer, thereby improving device productivity and yield. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to semiconductor devices and methods of forming same, and in particular, to devices, methods and technologies for preventing a metal line from becoming distorted or a hard-mask layer from being removed during a subsequent chemical-mechanical polishing (CMP) process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A semiconductor device generally comprises a capacitor and a transistor. In order to operate the capacitor and the transistor as a circuit, a metal line is required. According to a conventional method of forming a metal line, a lower insulating layer comprising a word line, a bit line and a capacitor is formed on a semiconductor substrate. Then, a lower insulation film and a material for a metal line are formed. The material for the metal line is patterned to form a metal line pattern. The metal line may be patterned by etching using a metal line mask. To achieve a high-integration of the semiconductor device, a microscopic metal line is used. However, it is difficult to form such a metal line of microscopic scale by etching processes using the metal line mask. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Recently, in order to form a micro-pattern sufficient for high-integration, a metal line is formed using a damascene process. The damascene process includes forming an interlayer isolation film, etching a predetermined region of the interlayer isolation film where a metal line will be formed, and filling up the etched portion of the interlayer isolation film with a metal line material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In the damascene process of forming a metal line, an insulating layer with a low dielectric constant (k) is used as an interlayer isolation film to prevent deterioration of the device characteristics. An insulating layer with a low dielectric constant also typically has very low stiffness. As a result, during a subsequent chemical-mechanical polishing (CMP) process, the metal line is distorted due to shear stress. Also, an oxide film or nitride film used as a hard-mask formed on an upper part of the low-k layer may be undesirably removed by shear stress during the CMP process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a picture illustrating a metal line formed according to a conventional method, which is distorted by CMP shear stresses. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present invention provides methods of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device so that a device can be formed easily without destroying a pattern or a stacked layer during a CMP process. The present invention will be particularly useful for damascene processes using a low-k isolation layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the present invention, a method of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device includes forming a lower insulating layer on a semiconductor device having a substructure, forming an interlayer isolation film with a low-k layer on the lower insulating layer, forming an anchor groove by etching one portion of the interlayer isolation film to expose the lower insulating layer, filling up the anchor groove by forming an anchor layer on the whole surface of the resulting structure, and planarizing an upper portion of the anchor layer. The method further includes forming a groove by sequentially removing a portion of the anchor layer and a second portion of the interlayer isolation film, and forming a metal line filling up the groove by a damascene process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, the low-k layer includes a spin on polymer (SOP), and in another aspect the anchor layer includes a silicon oxide or silicon dioxide (SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) film which has a stiffness that is stronger than the low-k layer stiffness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the present invention involves a method of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device. The method includes forming a lower insulating layer on a semiconductor substrate having a substructure, and forming an interlayer isolation film comprising a low-k layer over the lower insulating layer, with the interlayer isolation film having an anchor layer pattern defining an anchor hole therethrough to the lower insulating layer. A hard-mask layer is formed over exposed portions of the anchor layer pattern and interlayer isolation film, and a groove is formed by sequentially removing a portion of the hard-mask layer and the interlayer isolation film. The method includes forming a metal line filling up the groove by a damascene process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, the hard-mask layer comprises a SiO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>film. In some aspects, the anchor layer pattern comprises a plurality of anchors formed in a plurality of anchor holes through the interlayer isolation film. In one aspect, the anchor layer pattern further includes a substantially planar anchor film overlying at least some of the plurality of anchors. The groove for the metal line may be formed by also removing a portion of the anchor film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In still another embodiment of the present invention, a method of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device includes forming a lower insulating layer on a semiconductor device having a substructure, forming an anchor layer on the lower insulating layer, removing a portion of the anchor layer to define a plurality of spaced apart anchors, and forming a second insulating layer over the lower insulating layer. A hard mask layer is formed over the second insulating layer and over the spaced apart anchors, and a groove is formed in the hard mask layer and second insulating layer at a location spaced apart from the plurality of anchors. A metal line is formed in the groove. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, the second insulating layer also is formed over the spaced apart anchors, and then planarized to expose the spaced apart anchors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The present invention further provides exemplary semiconductor devices, and metal lines of a semiconductor device. In one embodiment the metal line comprises a lower insulating layer formed on a semiconductor substrate having a substructure, an interlayer isolation film formed of a low-k layer disposed on the lower insulating film, an anchor layer connected to the lower insulating layer through a hole formed in a first portion of the interlayer isolation film, and a metal line filling up a groove defined in a portion of the anchor layer and in a second portion of the interlayer isolation film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, a hard-mask layer is provided between the anchor layer and the metal line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Other features and advantages of the invention will appear from the following description in which the preferred embodiments have been set forth in detail in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The present invention will become better understood with reference to the accompanying drawings which are given only by way of illustration and thus are not limiting of the present invention, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a photograph illustrating problems of a conventional method of forming a metal line; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E are diagrams illustrating methods of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>E are diagrams illustrating methods of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagram illustrating still another method of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> With reference to the accompanying drawings, semiconductor devices and methods of forming same in accordance with the present invention will now be described in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2E</cross-reference> are diagrams illustrating methods of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. Metal lines of the present invention may be formed in a circuit device formed on a substrate (not shown), such as a silicon substrate. The substrate typically has one or more substructures (not shown), such as a field oxide defining an active region, a word line, a bit line, a capacitor and the like. A planarized lower insulating layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is formed over the whole surface of the structure, and a low-k layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is formed on the lower insulating layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Low-k layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is used as an interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In a particular embodiment, interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> comprises a spin-on polymer (SOP), although it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that additional materials also may be used for interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, an anchor groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, where an anchor can be formed, is formed in one portion of the low-k layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Here, anchor groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is formed on a portion where a metal line is not to be formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>C, an anchor layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> filling up the anchor groove <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is formed on the whole surface of the structure to contact the lower insulating layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, anchor layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is formed with a material having a stronger stiffness than the stiffness of low-k layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In a particular embodiment, anchor layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> comprises silicon dioxide (SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>D, an upper portion of the anchor layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is planarized by a CMP process. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2E, a</cross-reference> groove is formed by sequentially removing, at a predetermined region for a metal line, portions of anchor layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Then, a metal line <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is formed by a damascene process using a metal line mask, with the metal line <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> filling or substantially filling the groove. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A through 3E</cross-reference>, which depict methods of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device, another embodiment of the present invention will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, an anchor layer <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is formed on a planarized lower insulating layer <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, which is formed on the semiconductor substrate comprising substructures such as a field oxide defining an active region of a semiconductor device, a word line, a bit line, a capacitor and the like. In one embodiment, anchor layer <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is composed of a silicon oxide film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>B, an anchor layer pattern is formed, such as by etching the anchor layer <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> with a photolithography process using a mask for the anchor layer (not shown). The mask for the anchor layer is designed to form an anchor layer pattern in a region other than a metal line region formed in a subsequent process. Here, anchor layer <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> pattern is formed in a region other than a contact region of a metal line. Anchor layer <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> pattern has a structure that is vertical or substantially vertical to the planarized lower insulating layer <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, and is disposed in an interlayer isolation film formed in a subsequent process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>C, an interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is formed on an upper portion of the whole surface. In one embodiment, interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprises a low-k layer such as a SOP. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D, a</cross-reference> hard-mask layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is formed on an upper portion of the whole structure by removing an upper portion of the interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> with a CMP process to expose anchor layer <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> pattern. In a particular embodiment, the hard-mask layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> includes or consists of a silicon oxide film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3E, a</cross-reference> metal line <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is formed with a damascene process using a metal line contact mask and a metal line mask. Metal line <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is formed by penetrating hard-mask layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. For example, a trench, hole, groove or the like may be formed through hard-mask layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and interlayer isolation film <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> at a desired metal line location. The trench, hole, groove or the like is subsequently filled with a metal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagram illustrating another method of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. It shows a process of forming a low-k layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> after the process of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference>. Low-k layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> may be formed, for example, using a chemical vapor deposition (CVD) process. A metal line is formed by performing a process shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference> as a subsequent process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As described earlier, in accordance with the present invention, in a damascene process of forming a metal line using a low-k layer as an interlayer isolation film, an anchor layer is formed in an interlayer isolation film. The anchor layer prevents or helps prevent a metal line from being distorted during a subsequent CMP process. The anchor layer also prevents or helps prevent an oxide film or a nitride film used as a hard-mask layer from coming off. As a result, characteristics and reliability of the device are improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The present invention has been described in an illustrative manner, and it is to be understood that the terminology used is intended to be in the nature of description rather than of limitation. Many modifications and variations of the present invention are possible in light of the above teachings. By way of example and not limitation, the anchor layer may have an upper portion coupled to some or all anchors as can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2D and 2E</cross-reference>, or it may not. Further, a hard mask layer may be used, within the scope of the present invention, in the embodiment described in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E. Therefore, it is to be understood that within the scope of the appended claims, the invention may be practiced in ways other than those specifically described. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a lower insulating layer on a semiconductor device having a substructure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an interlayer isolation film with a low-k layer on the lower insulating layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an anchor groove by etching a first portion of the interlayer isolation film to expose the lower insulating layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>filling up the anchor groove by forming an anchor layer on the whole surface of the resulting structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>planarizing an upper portion of the anchor layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a groove by sequentially removing a portion of the anchor layer and a second portion of the interlayer isolation film; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a metal line filling up the groove by a damascene process. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the low-k layer comprises a spin-on polymer (SOP). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anchor layer comprises a silicon dioxide (SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) film which has a stiffness that is stronger than a low-k layer stiffness. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a lower insulating layer on a semiconductor substrate having a substructure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an interlayer isolation film comprising a low-k layer over the lower insulating layer, the interlayer isolation film having an anchor layer pattern defining an anchor hole therethrough to the lower insulating layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a hard-mask layer over exposed portions of the anchor layer pattern and interlayer isolation film; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a groove by sequentially removing a portion of the hard-mask layer and the interlayer isolation film; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a metal line filling up the groove by a damascene process. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anchor layer comprises a SiO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the low-k layer comprises a SOP. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the hard-mask layer comprises a SiO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anchor layer pattern comprises a plurality of anchors formed in a plurality of anchor holes through the interlayer isolation film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anchor layer pattern further comprises a substantially planar anchor film overlying at least some of the plurality of anchors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the groove further comprises removing a portion of the anchor film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A metal line of a semiconductor device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a lower insulating layer formed on a semiconductor substrate having a substructure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an interlayer isolation film formed of a low-k layer disposed on the lower insulating film; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an anchor layer connected to the lower insulating layer through a hole formed in a first portion of the interlayer isolation film; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a metal line filling up a groove defined in a portion of the anchor layer and in a second portion of the interlayer isolation film. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The metal line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a hard-mask layer is provided between the anchor layer and the metal line. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The metal line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anchor layer is a silicon oxide film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a metal line of a semiconductor device, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a lower insulating layer on a semiconductor device having a substructure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an anchor layer on the lower insulating layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing a portion of the anchor layer to define a plurality of spaced apart anchors; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second insulating layer over the lower insulating layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a hard mask layer over the second insulating layer and over the spaced apart anchors; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a groove in the hard mask layer and second insulating layer at a location spaced apart from the plurality of anchors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a metal line in the groove. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the second insulating layer further comprises forming the second insulating layer over the spaced apart anchors, and then planarizing the second insulating layer to expose the spaced apart anchors.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3D</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003726A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003726A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003726A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003726A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003726A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003726A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003726A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
