<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002229A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002229A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002229</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896342</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11B005/39</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>360</class>
<subclass>324200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>029</class>
<subclass>603140</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method of making a tunnel junction sensor with a smooth interface between a pinned or free layer and a barrier layer</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mustafa</given-name>
<family-name>Pinarbasi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Morgan Hill</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES CORPORATION</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Ron Feece</name-1>
<name-2>INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES CORPORATION</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Dept. L2PA</address-1>
<address-2>5600 Cottle Road</address-2>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95193</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of making provides a smooth surface of a pinned or free layer interfacing a barrier layer in a tunnel junction sensor wherein the smooth surface is an oxidized monolayer of the pinned or free layer. After sputter depositing the pinned or free layer the layer is subjected to an oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) atmosphere which is extremely low for a very short duration. In a preferred embodiment of the invention a partial thickness of the barrier layer is provided with a smooth surface by the same process after which a remainder thickness of the barrier layer is deposited and the barrier layer is exposed to oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) to form an oxide of the deposited metal. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method of making a tunnel junction sensor with a smooth interface between a pinned or free layer and a barrier layer and, more particularly, to such a method which reduces a coupling field between the pinned and free layers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The heart of a computer is a magnetic disk drive which includes a rotating magnetic disk, a slider that has read and write heads, a suspension arm above the rotating disk and an actuator arm that swings the suspension arm to place the read and write heads over selected circular tracks on the rotating disk. The suspension arm urges the slider into contact with the surface of the disk when the disk is not rotating but, when the disk rotates, air is swirled by the rotating disk adjacent an air bearing surface (ABS) of the slider causing the slider to ride on an air bearing a slight distance from the surface of the rotating disk. When the slider rides on the air bearing the write and read heads are employed for writing magnetic impressions to and reading magnetic field signals from the rotating disk. The read and write heads are connected to processing circuitry that operates according to a computer program to implement the writing and reading functions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> An exemplary high performance read head employs a tunnel junction sensor for sensing the magnetic field signals from the rotating magnetic disk. The sensor includes an insulative tunneling or barrier layer sandwiched between a ferromagnetic pinned layer and a ferromagnetic free layer. An antiferromagnetic pinning layer interfaces the pinned layer for pinning the magnetic moment of the pinned layer 90&deg; to an air bearing surface (ABS) wherein the ABS is an exposed surface of the sensor that faces the rotating disk. The tunnel junction sensor is located between ferromagnetic first and second shield layers. First and second leads, which may be the first and second shield layers, are connected to the tunnel junction sensor for conducting a tunneling current therethrough. The tunneling current is conducted perpendicular to the major film planes (CPP) of the sensor as contrasted to a spin valve sensor where the sense current is conducted parallel to or parallel to the major film planes (CIP) of the spin valve sensor. A magnetic moment of the free layer is free to rotate upwardly and downwardly with respect to the ABS from a quiescent or zero bias point position in response to positive and negative magnetic signal fields from the rotating magnetic disk. The quiescent position of the magnetic moment of the free layer, which is parallel to the ABS, occurs when the tunneling current is conducted through the sensor without magnetic field signals from the rotating magnetic disk. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> When the magnetic moments of the pinned and free layers are parallel with respect to one another the resistance of the tunnel junction sensor to the tunneling current (I<highlight><subscript>T</subscript></highlight>) is at a minimum and when the magnetic moments are antiparallel the resistance of the tunnel junction sensor to the tunneling current is at a maximum. Changes in resistance of the tunnel junction sensor is a function of cos &thgr;, where &thgr; is the angle between the magnetic moments of the pinned and free layers. When the tunneling current (I<highlight><subscript>T</subscript></highlight>) is conducted through the tunnel junction sensor resistance changes, due to field signals from the rotating magnetic disk, cause potential changes that are detected and processed as playback signals. The sensitivity of the tunnel junction sensor is quantified as magnetoresistive coefficient dr/R where dr is the change in resistance of the tunnel junction sensor from minimum resistance (magnetic moments of free and pinned layers parallel) to maximum resistance (magnetic moments of the free and pinned layers antiparallel) and R is the resistance of the tunnel junction sensor at minimum resistance. The dr/R of a tunnel junction sensor can be on the order of 40% as compared to 10% for a spin valve sensor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Tunnel junction sensors are classified as either a top tunnel junction sensor or a bottom tunnel junction sensor. In a bottom tunnel junction sensor the pinning layer is closer to the first shield layer than the second shield layer and in a top tunnel junction sensor the pinning layer is closer to the second shield layer than to the first shield layer. In either type of sensor the first and second shield layers may engage the bottom and the top respectively of the tunnel junction sensor so that the first and second shield layers serve as leads for conducting the tunneling current through the tunnel junction sensor perpendicular to the major planes of the layers of the tunnel junction sensor. The tunnel junction sensor has first and second side surfaces which are normal to the ABS. First and second hard bias layers abut the first and second side surfaces respectively for longitudinally biasing the magnetic domains of the free layer. This longitudinal biasing maintains the magnetic moment of the free layer parallel to the ABS when the read head is in the quiescent condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An inherent characteristic of the tunnel junction sensor is the existence of a ferromagnetic or antiferromagnetic coupling field between the pinned and free layers across the barrier layer. Unfortunately, this coupling field urges the magnetic moment of the free layer from its parallel position to the ABS in the quiescent condition. Accordingly, it is desirable that the coupling field be minimized in the tunnel junction sensor. In the spin valve sensor this is accomplished by providing one or more thick oxide seed layers which improve the microstructure of the layers deposited thereon which, in turn, can be employed for minimizing the coupling field. Unfortunately, this approach cannot be employed in reducing the coupling field in a tunnel junction sensor since the tunneling current is conducted perpendicular to the major thin film planes of the sensor and the thick oxide seed layers would increase the resistance of the tunnel junction sensor to the tunneling current thereby reducing sensitivity of the sensor to field signals. Another approach to reduce the coupling field in a tunnel junction sensor is to increase the thickness of the oxide barrier layer. This increases the distance between the pinned and free layers so that the coupling field is reduced. Unfortunately, this approach is not practical since an increase in the thickness of the oxide barrier layer again increases the resistance of the sensor to the tunneling current which, in turn, reduces the sensitivity of the sensor. Accordingly, there is a strong-felt need to provide a tunnel junction sensor with a low resistance and a low coupling field. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a tunnel junction sensor with a low coupling field between the pinned and free layers and a low resistance to the tunneling current. This is accomplished by providing the pinned or free layer with a smooth surface where it interfaces the oxide barrier layer, depending upon whether the tunnel junction sensor is a bottom tunnel junction sensor or a top tunnel junction sensor. In a bottom tunnel junction sensor the pinned layer is provided with a smooth surface where it interfaces the oxide barrier layer and in a top tunnel junction sensor the free layer is provided with a smooth surface where it interfaces the oxide barrier layer. The smooth surface of either the pinned or free layer is accomplished by exposing the surface of the layer next to the barrier layer with oxygen. This oxidizes the top layer of atoms wherein the oxidation is a monolayer (one atom thick coverage) or less. It is important that the pinned or free layer not be oxidized throughout any further portion of its thickness since this will essentially destroy the operation of the pinned or free layer. Further, when multiple monolayers are oxidized this results in an increase in the resistance of the tunnel junction device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The oxide barrier layer of the present invention is obtained by a method of making of the present invention in a sputtering chamber. After the ferromagnetic material of the pinned or free layer is deposited the ferromagnetic layer is exposed to oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) for a very short period of time and at a very low pressure. A preferred oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) partial pressure is 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>Torr for a duration of 30 seconds. An acceptable range of oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) partial pressures is from 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>Torr to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>Torr. The oxygen atoms that are adsorbed on the surface may be trapped during the next layer deposition or may float to the upper surfaces. Pressures and times that are too high will oxidize a thickness of the ferromagnetic layer rendering the sensor less sensitive or inoperable. The smooth ferromagnetic layer, whether it be a free layer or a pinned layer, enables a reduction in the thickness of the oxide barrier layer which, in turn, decreases the resistance of a tunnel junction sensor to the tunneling current and increases its sensitivity to field signals from the rotating magnetic disk. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the invention the same method is employed for additionally providing a material layer for the oxide barrier layer with a smooth surface intermediate the beginning and ending of the sputter deposition of the material layer wherein the material layer is typically aluminum. While the smooth surface of the ferromagnetic pinned or free layer enhances the texture of the barrier layer, it is believed that this enhancement decreases with an increase in thickness of the barrier layer. Accordingly, by providing the aluminum layer with a smooth surface intermediate its sputtered thickness the enhancement of the texture of the aluminum layer is rekindled. This can be done multiple times throughout the thickness of the barrier layer. After completing the deposition of the full thickness of the aluminum layer it is oxidized to form aluminum oxide (Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a method of making a tunnel junction sensor with a low coupling field between free and pinned layers and a low resistance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Another object is to provide a method of making a pinned layer or a free layer of a tunnel junction sensor with a smooth surface interfacing the barrier layer for improving the texture of the barrier layer so as to reduce a coupling field between the pinned and free layers and enable a barrier layer with a reduced thickness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A further object is to accomplish the aforementioned objective as well as providing the barrier layer with a smooth surface intermediate a commencement and termination of its deposition for improving the texture of the barrier layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Still another object is to provide tunnel junction sensors made according to the aforementioned objectives. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Other objects and attendant advantages of the invention will be appreciated upon reading the following description taken together with the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view of an exemplary magnetic disk drive; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an end view of a slider with a magnetic head of the disk drive as seen in plane <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an elevation view of the magnetic disk drive wherein multiple disks and magnetic heads are employed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an isometric illustration of an exemplary suspension system for supporting the slider and magnetic head; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an ABS view of the magnetic head taken along plane <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a partial view of the slider and a merged magnetic head as seen in plane <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a partial ABS view of the slider taken along plane <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> to show the read and write elements of the merged magnetic head; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a view taken along plane <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> with all material above the coil layer and leads removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an enlarged ABS illustration of the tunnel junction read head; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an enlarged ABS illustration of one embodiment of the present tunnel junction read head; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an enlarged ABS illustration of another embodiment of the tunnel junction read head; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematic illustration of a sputtering chamber wherein a smooth surface has been obtained at the top of a pinned or free layer according to a method of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is the same as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> except a smooth surface has been obtained at the top of a partial thickness of the oxide barrier layer according to a method of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is the same as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> except the material layer has been sputter deposited to its full thickness and oxidized to form the oxide barrier layer. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Magnetic Disk Drive </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the drawings wherein like reference numerals designate like or similar parts throughout the several views, FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> illustrate a magnetic disk drive <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The drive <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes a spindle <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> that supports and rotates one or more magnetic disks <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The spindle <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is rotated by a spindle motor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> that is controlled by a motor controller <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A slider <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has a combined read and write magnetic head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and is supported by a suspension <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and actuator arm <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> that is rotatably positioned by an actuator <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. A plurality of disks, sliders and suspensions may be employed in a large capacity direct access storage device (DASD) as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The suspension <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and actuator arm <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are moved by the actuator <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> to position the slider <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> so that the magnetic head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is in a transducing relationship with a surface of the magnetic disk <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. When the disk <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is rotated by the spindle motor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> the slider is supported on a thin (typically, 0.05 &mgr;m) cushion of air (air bearing) between the surface of the disk <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the air bearing surface (ABS) <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The magnetic head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may then be employed for writing information to multiple circular tracks on the surface of the disk <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as well as for reading information therefrom. Processing circuitry <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> exchanges signals, representing such information, with the head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, provides spindle motor drive signals for rotating the magnetic disk <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and provides control signals to the actuator for moving the slider to various tracks. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> the slider <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is shown mounted to a suspension <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The components described hereinabove may be mounted on a frame <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of a housing <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an ABS view of the slider <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and the magnetic head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The slider has a center rail <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> that supports the magnetic head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and side rails <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The rails <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> extend from a cross rail <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. With respect to rotation of the magnetic disk <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the cross rail <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is at a leading edge <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the slider and the magnetic head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is at a trailing edge <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> of the slider. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side cross-sectional elevation view of a merged magnetic head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which includes a write head portion <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and a read head portion <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, the read head portion employing a tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an ABS view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is sandwiched between ferromagnetic first and second shield layers <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. In response to external magnetic fields, the resistance of the spin valve sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> changes. A tunneling current (I<highlight><subscript>T</subscript></highlight>) conducted through the sensor causes these resistance changes to be manifested as potential changes. These potential changes are then processed as readback signals by the processing circuitry <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The tunneling current (I<highlight><subscript>T</subscript></highlight>) may be conducted through the tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> perpendicular to the planes of its major film surfaces by the first and second shield layers <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which serve as first and second leads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The write head portion <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the magnetic head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes a coil layer <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> sandwiched between first and second insulation layers <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. A third insulation layer <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> may be employed for planarizing the head to eliminate ripples in the second insulation layer caused by the coil layer <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The first, second and third insulation layers are referred to in the art as an &ldquo;insulation stack&rdquo;. The coil layer <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and the first, second and third insulation layers <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> are sandwiched between first and second pole piece layers <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. The first and second pole piece layers <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are magnetically coupled at a back gap <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and have first and second pole tips <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> which are separated by a write gap layer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> at the ABS. In a piggyback head (not shown) the second shield layer <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the first pole piece layer <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> are separate layers and an insulation layer is located therebetween. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</cross-reference>, first and second solder connections <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> connect leads from the spin valve sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> to leads <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> on the suspension <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, and third and fourth solder connections <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> connect leads <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> from the coil <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>) to leads <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> on the suspension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an enlarged isometric ABS illustration of the read head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The read head <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes the tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. First and second insulation layers <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, such as alumina (Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>), cover the first shield layer <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> on each side of the tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> as well as slightly covering first and second side walls <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> of the sensor. First and second hard bias layers <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> are on the insulation layers <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and are adjacent the side walls <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. The hard bias layers <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> cause magnetic fields to extend longitudinally through the sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> for stabilizing the magnetic domains therein. The sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the first and second hard bias layers <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> are located between ferromagnetic first and second shield layers <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which may serve as leads for conducting the tunneling current I<highlight><subscript>T </subscript></highlight>through the sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an enlarged ABS illustration of one embodiment of the present tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> which is located between the first and second shield layers <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, which is a bottom tunnel junction sensor, includes an oxide barrier layer (B) <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> which is located between a pinned layer (P) <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and a free layer structure <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. The pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is preferably cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>) which has a high magnetostriction so that after lapping the head the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> has a stress-induced anisotropy perpendicular to the ABS which supports an exchange coupling between a pinning layer <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. The pinning layer <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> pins a magnetic moment <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> of the pinned layer perpendicular to the ABS either out of the head or into the head as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. A seed layer of tantalum (Ta) <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> may be located between the pinning layer <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and the first shield layer <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> for improving the microstructure of the layers of the tunnel junction sensor deposited thereon. The free layer structure <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> may include a nanolayer (NL) <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> of cobalt iron (CoFe) and a free layer (F) <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> of nickel iron (NiFe). A cap layer <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> of tantalum (Ta) may be located on the free layer structure <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> for protecting the free layer structure from subsequent processing steps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The free layer structure <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> has a magnetic moment <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> which is directed from right to left or from left to right, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. When a field signal from the rotating magnetic disk rotates the magnetic moment <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> of the free layer structure into the head the magnetic moments <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> become more parallel which reduces the magnetoresistive coefficient dr/R of the head and when the field signal rotates the magnetic moment <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> out of the head the magnetic moments <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> become more antiparallel which increases the magnetoresistive coefficient dr/R of the head. These resistance changes are processed as playback signals by the processing circuitry <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Exemplary thicknesses of the layers are 30 &angst; of tantalum (Ta) for the seed layer (SL) <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, 150 &angst; of platinum manganese (Pt<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>Mn<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>) for the pinning layer <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, 30 &angst; of cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>) for the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, 10 &angst; of aluminum oxide (Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>) for the barrier layer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, 15 &angst; of cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>90</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>10</subscript></highlight>) for the nanolayer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, 35 &angst; of nickel iron (Ni<highlight><subscript>83</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>17</subscript></highlight>) for the free layer <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> and 50 &angst; of tantalum (Ta) for the cap layer <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> has a smooth surface <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, represented by a heavy line, which interfaces the barrier layer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The smooth surface <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is an oxidized monolayer of the ferromagnetic material of the pinned layer which is preferably cobalt iron (CoFe). The monolayer has the thickness of an atom. An additional thickness of the pinned layer should not be oxidized since this will reduce the effectiveness of the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and increase the roughness of the surface of the pinned layer where it interfaces the barrier layer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The smooth surface <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is obtained by a method according to the present invention which will be described in detail hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is the same as the tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> except the layers <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> have been inverted. The tunnel junction sensor <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is referred to in the art as a top tunnel junction sensor whereas the tunnel junction sensor in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is referred to as a bottom tunnel junction sensor. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> the nanolayer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is provided with the aforementioned smooth surface <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> which interfaces the barrier layer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. A typical ferromagnetic material for the nanolayer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>90</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>10</subscript></highlight>) and a typical material for the free layer <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> is nickel iron (Ni<highlight><subscript>83</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>17</subscript></highlight>). The smooth surface <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an oxidized monolayer of the ferromagnetic material of the nanolayer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. The smooth surface <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is also made by the present method which is described in detail hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> It should be understood that the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may alternatively be an antiparallel (AP) pinned layer structure with first and second ferromagnetic layers, such as cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>90</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>10</subscript></highlight>), separated by a thin (i.e. 8 &angst;) separation layer, such as ruthenium (Ru), which is fully described in commonly assigned U.S. Pat. No. 5,768,069. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> It should further be understood that while the ferromagnetic material of the pinned and free layers is preferably cobalt iron (CoFe) the invention can be practiced with other ferromagnetic materials, such as any cobalt based or nickel iron based materials. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Method of Making </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The method of making the smooth surfaces <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</cross-reference> is accomplished with a sputtering system <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> which is schematically illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. The sputtering system <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes a sputtering chamber <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> through which there is located an ion beam gun <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. The ion beam gun <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> receives a noble gas, such as xenon (Xe), and accelerates xenon ions toward a target <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> which may be cobalt iron (CoFe), whether the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> or the free layer structure <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> is formed on previously formed one or more underlying seed layers <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, such as the seed layer <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> or a substrate (not shown). When forming the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10 a</cross-reference> cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>) target may be employed and xenon ions are accelerated from the ion beam gun <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> to dislodge cobalt iron atoms from the target <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> which are sputter deposited to form the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. The sputtering chamber is then vacuumed (not shown) via opening <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and then oxygen atoms (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) are introduced into the chamber <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> through the opening <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> which forms the smooth surface <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The smooth surface <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is an oxidized monolayer of the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. This is accomplished by maintaining a specific low partial pressure of the oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) for a very short duration. This is to ensure that additional monolayers are not oxidized which will cause degradation of the pinned layer and a rough surface instead of the smooth surface <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. In the preferred embodiment the preferred partial pressure is 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>Torr and the duration is 30 seconds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> If the free layer structure <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is to be formed instead of the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10 a</cross-reference> cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>90</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>10</subscript></highlight>) target may be employed at <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. Xenon ions are then accelerated toward the cobalt iron target which causes atoms of cobalt iron to be sputtered and deposited to form the nanolayer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. The nanolayer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is then subjected to an oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) atmosphere to form a smooth surface <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in the same manner as described hereinabove to form the smooth surface <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In either embodiment (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> or <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>) the same sputtering chamber <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is employed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> for forming the barrier layer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The target <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> for the barrier layer is aluminum. Xenon atoms sputter aluminum atoms from the target <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> which are deposited to form a partial thickness of the preoxidized barrier layer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. A smooth surface <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is then formed on the partial thickness of the preoxidized barrier layer by the method described hereinabove for the smooth surfaces <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The process of providing the partial thickness of the barrier layer with a smooth surface is optional but is a preferred method of the present invention. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> the aluminum target <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> is further bombarded with xenon atoms to sputter aluminum atoms which form the remainder of the preoxidized barrier layer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The partial thickness deposits and oxygen exposure processes can be repeated to form the full thickness barrier layer. The preoxidized barrier layer, which is aluminum (Al), is then exposed to an oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) atmosphere by the introduction of oxygen through the opening <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. This then forms the barrier layer of aluminum oxide (Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>). The smooth surfaces <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> enhance the texture of the barrier layer and the smooth surface <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> further enhances the texture of the barrier layer which causes a reduced coupling field between the pinned and free layers <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> in either of the embodiments shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> or <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Discussion </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Preferred materials are cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>) for the pinned layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, nickel iron (Ni<highlight><subscript>83</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>17</subscript></highlight>) for the free layer <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>, cobalt iron (Co<highlight><subscript>90</subscript></highlight>Fe<highlight><subscript>10</subscript></highlight>) for the nanolayer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and aluminum oxide (Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>) for the barrier layer <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. With the present invention the barrier layer can be maintained extremely thin for reducing the resistance of the tunnel junction sensor to the tunneling current (I<highlight><subscript>T</subscript></highlight>) while reducing the magnetic coupling field between the pinned and free layers <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. A lower coupling field reduces the magnetic force which urges the magnetic moment <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> from its parallel position to the ABS in a quiescent condition of the tunnel junction sensor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Clearly, other embodiments and modifications of this invention will occur readily to those of ordinary skill in the art in view of these teachings. Therefore, this invention is to be limited only by the following claims, which include all such embodiments and modifications when viewed in conjunction with the above specification and accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head which has an air bearing surface (ABS), comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>making a tunnel junction sensor including the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a ferromagnetic pinned layer structure with a magnetic moment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an antiferromagnetic pinning layer exchange coupled to the pinned layer structure for pinning the magnetic moment of the pinned layer structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a ferromagnetic free layer structure with a magnetic moment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a nonmagnetic electrically insulative barrier layer between the free layer structure and the pinned layer structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the pinned layer structure or the free layer structure with an oxidized monolayer that interfaces the barrier layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein any oxidized monolayer is formed in a sputtering chamber with an oxygen partial pressure of 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>Torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pinned layer structure includes a cobalt based layer which is formed with said oxidized monolayer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cobalt based layer is cobalt iron (CoFe). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> including the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming ferromagnetic first and second shield layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the tunnel junction sensor between the first and second shield layers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of forming the barrier layer includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming at least a first portion of the barrier layer in an unoxidized state; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming said at least a first portion of the barrier layer with an oxidized monolayer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least a second portion of the barrier layer in an unoxidized state on said oxidized monolayer of said at least a first portion of the barrier layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>oxidizing said at least first and second portions of the barrier layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein any oxidized monolayer is formed in a sputtering chamber with an oxygen partial pressure of 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>Torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the barrier layer is formed of aluminum oxide (Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>) after oxidizing said at least first and second said portions of the barrier layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pinned layer structure includes a cobalt based layer which is formed with said oxidized monolayer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cobalt based layer is cobalt iron (CoFe). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> including the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming ferromagnetic first and second shield layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the tunnel junction sensor between the first and second shield layers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic head assembly having an air bearing surface (ABS), comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>making a write head including the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming ferromagnetic first and second pole piece layers that have a yoke portion between a pole tip portion and a back gap portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a nonmagnetic write gap layer located between the pole tip portions of the first and second pole piece layers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an insulation stack with at least one coil layer embedded therein between the yoke portions of the first and second pole piece layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the first and second pole piece layers at their back gap portions; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>making a read head including the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a first shield layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a tunnel junction sensor located between the first shield layer and the first pole piece layer; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>making the tunnel junction sensor including the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a ferromagnetic pinned layer structure that has a magnetic moment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an antiferromagnetic pinning layer structure exchange coupled to the pinned layer structure for pinning the magnetic moment of the pinned layer structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a ferromagnetic free layer structure which has a magnetic moment; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a nonmagnetic electrically insulative barrier layer between the free layer structure and the pinned layer structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the pinned layer structure or the free layer structure with an oxidized monolayer that is adjacent the barrier layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic head assembly as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein any oxidized monolayer is formed in a sputtering chamber at or less than 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;5 </superscript></highlight>Torr/minute. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic head assembly as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the barrier layer is formed of aluminum oxide (Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>) after oxidizing said first and second said portions of the barrier layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic head assembly as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pinned layer structure includes a cobalt based layer which is formed with said oxidized monolayer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic head assembly as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cobalt based layer is cobalt iron (CoFe). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method of making a magnetic head assembly as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> including the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming ferromagnetic first and second shield layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the tunnel junction sensor between the first and second shield layers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A magnetic read head which has an air bearing surface (ABS), comprising: 
<claim-text>a tunnel junction sensor including: 
<claim-text>a ferromagnetic pinned layer structure that has a magnetic moment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an antiferromagnetic pinning layer exchange coupled to the pinned layer structure for pinning the magnetic moment of the pinned layer structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ferromagnetic free layer structure which has a magnetic moment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a nonmagnetic electrically insulative barrier layer located between the free layer structure and the pinned layer structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the pinned layer structure or the free layer structure having an oxidized monolayer that is adjacent the barrier layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pinned layer structure includes a cobalt based layer that has said oxidized monolayer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cobalt based layer is cobalt iron (CoFe). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A magnetic read head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> including: 
<claim-text>ferromagnetic first and second shield layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the tunnel junction sensor being located between the first and second shield layers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A magnetic head assembly having an air bearing surface (ABS), comprising: 
<claim-text>a write head including: 
<claim-text>ferromagnetic first and second pole piece layers that have a yoke portion located between a pole tip portion and a back gap portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a nonmagnetic write gap layer located between the pole tip portions of the first and second pole piece layers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an insulation stack with at least one coil layer embedded therein located between the yoke portions of the first and second pole piece layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first and second pole piece layers being connected at their back gap portions; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a read head including: 
<claim-text>a first shield layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tunnel junction sensor located between the first shield layer and the first pole piece layer; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the tunnel junction sensor including: 
<claim-text>a ferromagnetic pinned layer structure that has a magnetic moment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an antiferromagnetic pinning layer structure exchange coupled to the pinned layer structure for pinning the magnetic moment of the pinned layer structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ferromagnetic free layer structure which has a magnetic moment; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a nonmagnetic electrically insulative barrier layer located between the free layer structure and the pinned layer structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the pinned layer structure or the free layer structure having an oxidized monolayer that is adjacent the barrier layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A magnetic head assembly as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pinned layer structure includes a cobalt based layer that has said oxidized monolayer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A magnetic head assembly as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cobalt based layer is cobalt iron (CoFe). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A magnetic head assembly as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> including: 
<claim-text>ferromagnetic first and second shield layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the tunnel junction sensor being located between the first and second shield layers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A magnetic disk drive including at least one magnetic head assembly that has an a write head, a read head and an air bearing surface (ABS) comprising: 
<claim-text>the write head including: 
<claim-text>ferromagnetic first and second pole piece layers that have a yoke portion located between a pole tip portion and a back gap portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a nonmagnetic write gap layer located between the pole tip portions of the first and second pole piece layers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an insulation stack with at least one coil layer embedded therein located between the yoke portions of the first and second pole piece layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first and second pole piece layers being connected at their back gap portions; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the read head including: 
<claim-text>a first shield layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tunnel junction sensor located between the first shield layer and the first pole piece layer; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the tunnel junction sensor including: 
<claim-text>a ferromagnetic pinned layer structure that has a magnetic moment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an antiferromagnetic pinning layer exchange coupled to the pinned layer structure for pinning the magnetic moment of the pinned layer structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ferromagnetic free layer structure which has a magnetic moment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a nonmagnetic electrically insulative barrier layer located between the free layer structure and the pinned layer structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the pinned layer structure or the free layer structure having an oxidized monolayer that interfaces the barrier layer; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a magnetic disk rotatably supported in the housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a support mounted in the housing for supporting the magnetic head assembly with said ABS facing the magnetic disk so that the magnetic head assembly is in a transducing relationship with the magnetic disk; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a spindle motor for rotating the magnetic disk; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator positioning means connected to the support for moving the magnetic head assembly to multiple positions with respect to said magnetic disk; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor connected to the magnetic head assembly, to the spindle motor and to the actuator for exchanging signals with the magnetic head assembly, for controlling movement of the magnetic disk and for controlling the position of the magnetic head assembly. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A magnetic disk drive as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pinned layer structure includes a cobalt based layer that has said oxidized monolayer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A magnetic disk drive as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cobalt based layer is cobalt iron (CoFe). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A magnetic disk drive as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> including: 
<claim-text>ferromagnetic first and second shield layers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the tunnel junction sensor being located between the first and second shield layers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>9</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002229A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
