<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001351A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001351A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001351A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001351A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001351A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001351A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001351A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001351A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001351A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001351A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001351A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001351A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001351</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893821</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B62M001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>280</class>
<subclass>087050</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>280</class>
<subclass>087041</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and method for stowing, for securing for travel, and for transporting omnium-gatherum personal effects</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gregory</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Schauble</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lori</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Young</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Tod R. Nissle, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>TOD R. NISSLE, P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 55630</address-1>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<postalcode>85078</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A scooter is provided for stowing, securing, and transporting omnium-gatherum. The scooter includes a telescoping handle attached to a base or platform that a user stands on during use of the scooter. The handle is pivoted between a deployed operative position so the user can stand on the platform and used the handle and a stowed operative position with the handle folded to a position adjacent the platform. A pliable storable container is attached to the handle such that the container remains on the handle while the handle is telescopically adjusted and while the handle is folded into position adjacent the platform. A portion of the pliable storage container slides along the handle when the handle is telescopically adjusted. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to apparatus for stowing, securing, or transporting omnium-gatherum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> More particularly, the invention relates to a scooter apparatus for stowing, securing, or transporting omnium-gatherum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Automobiles, motorcycles, and bicycles have long utilized baskets and other containers for carrying and transporting personal effects. Scooters, however, have apparently not included such containers. A scooter includes a horizontally oriented platform and includes an upstanding handle which is mounted on and extends upwardly from the front of the platform. One ground engaging wheel, the back wheel, is attached to the back of the platform. A second gound engaging wheel, the front wheel, is mounted at the front of the platform on the bottom of the handle. When a user turns or rotates the handle, the front wheel turns simultaneously with the handle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In one well known type of scooter, sometimes called a &ldquo;RAZOR&rdquo; scooter after the RAZOR trademark found on some such scooters, the handle includes a telescoping shaft. The upper end of the shaft includes a pair of grips (one for each hand), typically spaced only three to four inches apart. The lower end of the telescoping shaft is pivotally attached to the platform so that after the shaft is telescoped together to reduce the length of the shaft, the shaft can be folded against the platform to compact the scooter for travel. Mounting a basket or other container on this type of scooter is believed impractical because the basket cannot be mounted on the grips, because there is not sufficient spaced on the handle, and because the handle is folded telescopically and pivotally&mdash;which means the basket would have to be removed before the handle was telescopically reduced in length and folded. Another disadvantage of attempting to mount a basket on a scooter is that the front wheel of the scooter is small and has a diameter in the range of three to five inches, typically only about three and a half inches to four inches. A conventional basket or other container would usually extend outwardly from the handle past this wheel, making the scooter unstable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Although containers are apparently not utilized on scooters for the foregoing reasons and other reasons, there are many scooters in use. Accordingly, it would be highly desirable to provide an apparatus and method for carrying, simple and safely, personal effects on scooters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is a principal object of the instant invention to provide an improved method and apparatus for stowing and for transporting omnium-gatherum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide an improved apparatus for stowing and transporting omnium-gatherum on a scooter of the type including a telescoping, folding handle which turns simultaneously with a wheel mounted on the handle and including closely spaced grips on the handle.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> These and other, further and more specific objects and advantages of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description thereof, taken in conjunction with the drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side elevation view illustrating a scooter apparatus constructed in accordance with the principles of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front view of the scooter of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> from the perspective of arrow A and further illustrating the upper portion of the handle body of the scooter of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and construction features thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of the upper portion of the handle body of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> further illustrating construction details thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a front view of the scooter of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> from the perspective of arrow A and further illustrating the upper portion of the handle body after the top member of the body has been telescopically extended from the lower member of the body; and, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side elevation view of the scooter of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrating the handle body in a folded configuration.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Briefly, in accordance with the invention, I provide an improved scooter apparatus for stowing, securing for travel, and transporting omnium-gatherum. The apparatus includes a platform for a user to stand on. The platform has a front and a rear. The apparatus also includes a ground engaging wheel mounted on the rear of the platform, and a stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly connected to the front of the platform. The stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly includes an elongate body including a elongate first and second members slidably telescopically interconnected such that the first member can be moved between at least two operative positions, a first operative position with the first member in a storage position which shortens the body, and a second operative position with the first member telescopically extended from the first member to increase the length of the body such that the body can be utilized as support by a user standing on the base. The first member includes a distal end and the second member includes a distal end. The stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly also includes a ground engaging wheel mounted on the distal end of the second member, and includes a handlebar mounted on the distal end of the first member. The handlebar includes a neck attached to the distal end of the first member and includes a pair of outer ends each extending outwardly a short distance from the first member. A pair of handles are each mounted on and extend outwardly from a different one of the distal ends of the neck. The steering&mdash;handle assembly also includes apparatus connected to the front of the platform for moving pivotally the body between at least a pair of operative positions. One of the operative positions is a deployed operative position such that a user can stand on the platform, grasp the handles, and use the body for support. The other operative position is a stowed operative position with the first member in the first operative position and said body pivotally moved from the deployed operative position to the stowed operative position and folded toward the platform. The apparatus also includes a pliable deformable container for storing omnium-gatherum. The container includes a front, back, top, and bottom, includes first fastening apparatus attached to the top of the container to secure the container to at least one of the outer ends of the neck, and includes a second fastening apparatus attached to the container to secure slidably the container to the second member of the body such that when the first member is moved from the first to the second operative position, the second fastening apparatus slidably moves along the second member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another embodiment of the invention, I provide an improved scooter apparatus for stowing, securing for travel, and transporting omnium-gatherum. The apparatus includes a platform for a user to stand on. The platform has a front and a rear. The apparatus also includes a ground engaging wheel mounted on the rear of the platform, and a stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly connected to the front of the platform. The stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly includes an elongate body including a elongate first and second members slidably telescopically interconnected such that the first member can be moved between at least two operative positions, a first operative position with the first member in a storage position which shortens the body, and a second operative position with the first member telescopically extended from the first member to increase the length of the body such that the body can be utilized as support by a user standing on the base. The first member includes a distal end and the second member includes a distal end. The stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly also includes a ground engaging wheel mounted on the distal end of the second member, and includes a handlebar mounted on the distal end of the first member. The handlebar includes a neck attached to the distal end of the first member and includes a pair of outer ends each extending outwardly a short distance from the first member. A pair of handles are each mounted on and extend outwardly from a different one of the distal ends of the neck. The steering&mdash;handle assembly also includes apparatus connected to the front of the platform for moving pivotally the body between at least a pair of operative positions. One of the operative positions is a deployed operative position such that a user can stand on the platform, grasp the handles, and use the body for support. The other operative position is a stowed operative position with the first member in the first operative position and said body pivotally moved from the deployed operative position to the stowed operative position and folded toward the platform. The apparatus also includes a pliable deformable container for storing omnium-gatherum. The container includes a front, back, top, and bottom, includes first fastening apparatus attached to the top of the container to secure the container to at least one of the outer ends of the neck, and includes second fastening means attached to the container to secure slidably the container to the body. The container is shaped and dimensioned such that when the body is moved to the stowed position, the container is compressed between the body and the platform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a further embodiment of the invention, I provide an improved scooter apparatus for stowing, securing for travel, and transporting omnium-gatherum. The apparatus includes a platform for a user to stand on. The platform has a front and a rear. The apparatus also includes a ground engaging wheel mounted on the rear of the platform, and a stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly connected to the front of the platform. The stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly includes an elongate body including a elongate first and second members slidably telescopically interconnected such that the first member can be moved between at least two operative positions, a first operative position with the first member in a storage position which shortens the body, and a second operative position with the first member telescopically extended from the first member to increase the length of the body such that the body can be utilized as support by a user standing on the base. The first member includes a distal end and the second member includes a distal end. The stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly also includes a ground engaging wheel mounted on the distal end of the second member, and includes a handlebar mounted on the distal end of the first member. The handlebar includes a neck attached to the distal end of the first member and includes a pair of outer ends each extending outwardly a short distance from the first member. A pair of handles are each mounted on and extend outwardly from a different one of the distal ends of the neck. The steering&mdash;handle assembly also includes control apparatus connected to the front of the platform for moving pivotally the body between at least a pair of operative positions. One of the operative positions is a deployed operative position such that a user can stand on the platform, grasp the handles, and use the body for support. The other operative position is a stowed operative position with the first member in the first operative position and said body pivotally moved from the deployed operative position to the stowed operative position and folded toward the platform. The control apparatus also permits the body to rotate between at least a pair of operative positions, a forward operative position with the front of the body facing outwardly away from the platform, and a rearward operative position with the body rotated 180 degrees from the forward operative position such that the front of the body faces the platform. The apparatus also includes a pliable deformable container for storing for storing omnium-gatherum and including a front, back, top, and bottom, includes first fastening apparatus attached to the top of the container to secure the container to at least one of said outer ends of the neck, and includes second fastening apparatus attached to the container to secure slidably the container to the body. The container is shaped and dimensioned such that when the container is on the front of the body and the body is in the rearward position and is moved to the stowed position, the container is compressed between the body and the platform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In still another embodiment of the invention, I provide an improved method of storing, of securing for travel, and for transporting omnium-gatherum, including the steps of providing the apparatus of claim 1; placing the body in the deployed position; telescopically extending the first member to the first operative position; placing omnium-gatherum in the container; using the apparatus such that the wheels roll over the ground a selected distance; placing the first member in the second operative position; folding the body to the stowed operative position; carrying the apparatus a selected distance; and, removing at least some of the omnium-gatherum from the container. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Turning now to the drawings, which illustrate the presently preferred embodiments of the invention for the purpose of illustrating the practice thereof, and not by way of limitation of the scope of the invention, and in which like reference characters refer to corresponding elements throughout the several views, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates scooter apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> constructed in accordance with the invention and including a platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, steering&mdash;handle assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and support apparatus <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for pivotally foldably stowing the steering&mdash;handle assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Support apparatus <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> includes hollow cylindrical collar <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, connecting member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is fixedly connected to the top of platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Cylindrical pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is spring-loaded and is mounted in groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> extends outwardly into and seats in the bottom of notch <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> in the manner shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, but can be displaced in the direction of arrow V in groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to compress spring <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. Displacing pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow V moves pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> out of notch <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> so pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can slide along groove <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and seat in notch <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> when handle&mdash;steering assembly is being folded into the configuration shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can be manually displaced to compress spring <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow V. Arcuate slot <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> extends through upstanding flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and interconnects notches or apertures <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> formed through flange <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> along with slot <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Pin <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is fixedly secured to flange <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and extends into member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> such that member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can pivot about pin <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, front end <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and rear end <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is fixedly connected to and extends outwardly from end <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Ground engaging wheel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is rotatably mounted on pin <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Pin <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is fixedly mounted on member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Steering&mdash;handle assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including an elongate body which includes elongate cylindrical first member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and elongate hollow cylindrical second member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is telescopically mounted in member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and slides into and out of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> between at least first and second operative positions. The first operative storage position is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 3</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, where member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is slid into member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The second operative deployed position is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> where member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is slid out of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow I. A notch <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is formed in the top of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A clamp assembly <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> compresses the top of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> against telescoping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to maintain member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in a desired position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The clamp assembly <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> includes collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> includes depending outwardly projecting flanges <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>B. Apertures are formed through flanges <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>B such that the threaded portion <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of bolt <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> can extend through the apertures in the manner shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The threaded end of portion <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> threads into an internally threaded aperture (not visible) formed through pin <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The ends of pin <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> extend through apertures (not visible) formed through latch member <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. When latch member <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is in the open position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can freely slide up and down in hollow member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. When latch member <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is displaced in the direction of arrow G in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, flanges <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>B are pressed together, and notch <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is squeezed and reduced in size to reduce the inside diameter of the top of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and, consequently, to squeeze the inner surface of the top of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> against member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to maintain member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in a desired position. Any other desired fastening means can be utilized in place of the clamp assembly <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> in order to maintain telescoping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in a desired position with respect to member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The distance K from the inner end of grip or handle <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is in the range of 0.5 inch to 2.0 inches, and typically is about one inch. The distance L from the inner end of grip or handle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> to member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is in the range of 0.5 inch to 2.0 inches, and typically is about one inch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Neck <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes ends <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B. The front <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> of neck <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is the front of steering handle&mdash;assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The back <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of neck <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is the back of steering handle&mdash;assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> One inch wide detachable pliable bendable strip <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is attached around end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>A between grip <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. One inch wide detachable pliable bendable strip <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is attached around end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B between grip <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and end member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. One inch wide detachable pliable bendable strip <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is attached around member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> beneath the clamp assembly <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Strip <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> can slide along member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the directions indicated by arrows M. Strips <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> can be made using Velcro, can be made using clips or buckles, or can be made with any other desired detachable or non-detachable fastening means which can be secured around ends <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>B and member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Pliable container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is attached to strips <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> with thread, adhesive, or other desired fasteners. Container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is preferably made from a fabric or other pliable, bendable material such that when the apparatus of the invention is folded in the manner shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be at least partially compressed between steering handle assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The container includes a top <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, a bottom <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, front <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, and back <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. Top <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is attached to strips or straps <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Bottom <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is attached to strip or strap <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. Container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can include pockets, flaps, a top, compartments, etc. Top <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> must be narrow enough to fit between the inner ends <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>A of grips <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The distance R between ends <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>A is in the range of two to four inches, and is typically about three inches. The length S (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> must be sufficient so that when member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is in the extended position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, strip <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is on member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In other words, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> must extend from neck <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to the top of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. It is important that container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extend from neck <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to the top of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> because otherwise strip <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> ordinarily must be fastened about the lower part of member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which means that before member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can be telescopically collapsed to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, strip <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> must be removed from member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to avoid damaging container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> when clamp assembly <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is opened and member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is slid in the direction of arrow O to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As indicated by arrows D and E in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can be rotated in hollow collar <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> three hundred and sixty degrees from the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. When member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is rotated, member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, wheel <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and each of the other components of the steering&mdash;handle assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> rotate simultaneously with member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the steering handle assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has been rotated one hundred and eighty degrees from the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In use, container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is mounted on steering&mdash;handle assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> by attaching strips <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> to neck <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, as the case may be, in the positions shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Latch member <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is opened to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, and member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is slidably telescopically extended from member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow I to the position shown by dashed lines <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. When member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is extended in the direction of arrow I, strip <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> slides up member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow T to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Once member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is extended to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, latch member <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is displaced in the direction of arrow G to close assembly <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and secure member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The user puts one of his feet on platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, grasps grips <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> with his hands, and pushes the scooter apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a conventional manner with his or her other foot to travel a selected distance. The user then steps off apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, opens latch <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, telescopically moves member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow O to the position sown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, and displaces member <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow G to close assembly <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> to secure member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in position. The user rotates the handle&mdash;steering assembly from the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in the direction of arrows D and E through an arc of one hundred and eighty degrees so that the front <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> of handle&mdash;steering assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is facing platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The user manually displaces pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow V to compress spring <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. The user then pushes handle&mdash;steering assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow B to slide pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> along notch <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and fold assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. When assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is in the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is at least partially compressed between handle&mdash;steering assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In addition, when the handle&mdash;steering assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is moved to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, spring <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> expands and causes pin <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> to seat in notch <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The user then picks up and carries apparatus a selected distance in its folded configuration, after which the user can remove container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> from apparatus <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> or can remove all or a portion of the omnium-gatherum from container <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>.</paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">Having described the invention in such terms as to enable those of skilled in the art to understand and practice the invention, and having described the presently preferred embodiments thereof, I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A scooter apparatus for stowing, securing for travel, and transporting omnium-gatherum, the apparatus including 
<claim-text>(a) a platform for a user to stand on, said platform having a front and a rear; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a ground engaging wheel mounted on said rear of said platform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly connected to said front of said platform and including 
<claim-text>(i) an elongate body including a elongate first and second members slidably telescopically interconnected such that said first member can be moving between at least two operative positions, 
<claim-text>a first operative position with said first member in a storage position which shortens said body, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second operative position with said first member telescopically extended from said first member to increase the length of said body such that said body can be utilized as support by a user standing on said base, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first member including a distal end and said second member including a distal end, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) a ground engaging wheel mounted on said distal end of said second member, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) a handlebar mounted on said distal end of said first member and including 
<claim-text>a neck attached to said distal end of said first member and including </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of outer ends each extending outwardly a short distance from said first member, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of handles each mounted on and extending outwardly from a different one of said distal ends of said neck, and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iv) means connected to said front of said platform for moving pivotally said body between at least a pair of operative positions, 
<claim-text>a deployed operative position such that a user can stand on said platform, grasp said handles, and use said body for support, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a stowed operative position with said first member in said first operative position and said body pivotally moved from said deployed operative position to said stowed operative position and folded toward said platform; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a pliable deformable container for storing omnium-gatherum and including a front, back, top, and bottom and 
<claim-text>(i) first fastening means attached to said top of said container to secure said container to at least one of said outer ends of said neck, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) second fastening means attached to said container to secure slidably said container to said second member of said body such that when said first member is moved from said first to said second operative position, said second fastening means slidably moves along said second member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A scooter apparatus for stowing, securing for travel, and transporting omnium-gatherum, the apparatus including 
<claim-text>(a) a platform for a user to stand on, said platform having a front and a rear; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a ground engaging wheel mounted on said rear of said platform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly connected to said front of said platform and including 
<claim-text>(i) an elongate body including a elongate first and second members slidably telescopically interconnected such that said first member can be moving between at least two operative positions, 
<claim-text>a first operative position with said first member in a storage position which shortens said body, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second operative position with said first member telescopically extended from said first member to increase the length of said body such that said body can be utilized as support by a user standing on said base, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first member including a distal end and said second member including a distal end, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) a ground engaging wheel mounted on said distal end of said second member, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) a handlebar mounted on said distal end of said first member and including 
<claim-text>a neck attached to said distal end of said first member and including </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of outer ends each extending outwardly a short distance from said first member, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of handles each mounted on and extending outwardly from a different one of said distal ends of said neck, and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iv) means connected to said front of said platform for moving pivotally said body between at least a pair of operative positions, 
<claim-text>a deployed operative position such that a user can stand on said platform, grasp said handles, and use said body for support, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a stowed operative position with said first member in said first operative position and said body pivotally moved from said deployed operative position to said stowed operative position and folded toward said platform; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a pliable deformable container for storing omnium-gatherum and including a front, back, top, and bottom and 
<claim-text>(i) first fastening means attached to said top of said container to secure said container to at least one of said outer ends of said neck, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) second fastening means attached to said container to secure slidably said container to said body, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said container being shaped and dimensioned such that when said body is moved to said stowed position, said container is compressed between said body and said platform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A scooter apparatus for stowing, securing for travel, and transporting omnium-gatherum, the apparatus including 
<claim-text>(a) a platform for a user to stand on, said platform having a front and a rear; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a ground engaging wheel mounted on said rear of said platform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a stowable steering&mdash;handle assembly connected to said front of said platform and including 
<claim-text>(i) an elongate body having a front and a back and including a elongate first and second members slidably telescopically interconnected such that said first member can be moving between at least two operative positions, 
<claim-text>a first operative position with said first member in a storage position which shortens said body, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second operative position with said first member telescopically extended from said first member to increase the length of said body such that said body can be utilized as support by a user standing on said base, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first member including a distal end and said second member including a distal end, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) a ground engaging wheel mounted on said distal end of said second member, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) a handlebar mounted on said distal end of said first member and including 
<claim-text>a neck attached to said distal end of said first member and including </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of outer ends each extending outwardly a short distance from said first member, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of handles each mounted on and extending outwardly from a different one of said distal ends of said neck, and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iv) means connected to said front of said platform 
<claim-text>to permit so body to rotate between at least a pair of operative positions, 
<claim-text>a forward operative position with said front of said body facing outwardly away from said platform, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a rearward operative position with said body rotated 180 degrees from said forward operative position such that said front of said body faces said platform, and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>for moving pivotally said body between at least a pair of operative positions, 
<claim-text>a deployed operative position such that a user can stand on said platform, grasp said handles, and use said body for support, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a stowed operative position with said first member in said first operative position and said body pivotally moved from said deployed operative position to said stowed operative position and folded toward said platform; and, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a pliable deformable container for storing omnium-gatherum and including a front, back, top, and bottom and 
<claim-text>(i) first fastening means attached to said top of said container to secure said container to at least one of said outer ends of said neck, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) second fastening means attached to said container to secure slidably said container to said body, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said container being shaped and dimension such that when said container is on said front of said body and said body is in said rearward position and is moved to said stowed position, said container is compressed between said body and said platform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method of storing, of securing for travel, and for transporting omnium-gatherum, including the steps of 
<claim-text>(a) providing the apparatus of claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) placing said body in said deployed position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) telescopically extending said first member to said first operative position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) placing omnium-gatherum in said container; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) using said apparatus such that said wheels roll over the ground a selected distance; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) placing said first member in said second operative position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) folding said body to said stowed operative position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) carrying said apparatus a selected distance; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(i) removing at least some of said omnium-gatherum from said container.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001351A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001351A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001351A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001351A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001351A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001351A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
