<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-P00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-P00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-P00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-P00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-P00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-P00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-P00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-P00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-P00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-P00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-P00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000142A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000142A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000142</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10228371</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020821</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A01G009/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>047</class>
<subclass>072000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Floral wrapper having printed design with shaded and highlighted areas</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10228371</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020821</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09895958</doc-number>
<document-date>20010629</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09895958</doc-number>
<document-date>20010629</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09665567</doc-number>
<document-date>20000919</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09665567</doc-number>
<document-date>20000919</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09374648</doc-number>
<document-date>19990813</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09374648</doc-number>
<document-date>19990813</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09021216</doc-number>
<document-date>19980210</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Donald</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Weder</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Highland</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>DUNLAP, CODDING &amp; ROGERS P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO BOX 16370</address-1>
<city>OKLAHOMA CITY</city>
<state>OK</state>
<postalcode>73114</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of forming a decorative cover, a sleeve or a preformed pot cover for a floral grouping or flower pot from a sheet of material having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern contains shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three-dimensional appearance. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to methods of wrapping floral groupings and flower pots with a sheet of material to provide a decorative cover for such floral groupings and flower pots, and more particularly but not by way of limitation to methods of wrapping floral groupings and flower pots with a sheet of material having a printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance. In one aspect, the present invention relates to a sheet of material having a printed pattern thereon for providing a decorative sleeve, a preformed pot cover or a decorative cover for a flower pot or floral grouping wherein the printed pattern has shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed design with a visual perception of depth.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an enlarged, fragmental, perspective view of a sheet of material for providing a decorative cover for a floral grouping or a flower pot, a decorative sleeve or a preformed pot cover in accordance with the present invention, the sheet of material having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern contains shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the sheet of material of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> having a floral grouping disposed thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a sheet of material having a printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) and having a bonding material disposed along one edge thereof and a floral grouping disposed on the sheet of material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the floral grouping being wrapped with the sheet of material having a printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> by one method of wrapping the sheet of material about the floral grouping. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a decorative cover for the floral grouping formed from the sheet of material of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> wherein the decorative cover formed from the sheet of material has a conical configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a decorative cover formed from the sheet of material of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> wherein the floral grouping is wrapped with the sheet of material by a second method of wrapping so that the decorative cover formed from the sheet of material has a substantially cylindrical configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a flower pot containing a potted plant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is perspective view of a decorative cover positioned about the flower pot of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> wherein the decorative cover is formed from a sheet of material having a printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas so as to provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a flower pot cover former and band applicator apparatus having the sheet of material of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> disposed above an opening of the flower pot cover former and band applicator and having a flower pot disposed above the sheet of material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a floral sleeve formed from a sheet of material having a printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas so as to provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the floral sleeve of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> disposed about a floral grouping. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a floral sleeve having a cinching member wherein the floral sleeve is formed from a sheet of material having a printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas so as to provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the floral sleeve of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> disposed about a floral grouping. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a side view of a sleeve having a detachable portion wherein the sleeve is formed from a sheet of material having a printed pattern having a three dimensional appearance which is created by shaded and highlighted areas in the printed pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the sleeve of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> having a flower pot disposed therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a flower pot disposed in the sleeve of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> wherein an upper portion of the sleeve has been removed to provide a decorative cover having a skirt. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a preformed pot cover formed from a sheet of material having a printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas which produce a visual perception of depth and thus provides the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the preformed pot cover of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> having a flower pot disposed therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic, cross-sectional view of a male and female mold having a sheet of material disposed therebetween for forming the preformed pot cover of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The present invention comprises methods of wrapping floral groupings, flower pots containing potted plants, or other pots with a sheet of material having a printed pattern thereon to provide a decorative cover or sleeve for such floral groupings, flower pots containing potted plants or other pot means wherein the printed pattern contains shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance. In one aspect, the present invention comprises a sheet of material having a printed pattern thereon for providing a decorative cover for a floral grouping or a flower pot or other pots, a sleeve or a preformed pot cover wherein the printed pattern contains shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Floral grouping&rdquo; as used herein means cut fresh flowers, artificial flowers, a single flower or other fresh and/or artificial plants or other floral materials and may include other secondary plants and/or ornamentation or artificial or natural materials which add to the aesthetics of the overall floral grouping. Further, the &ldquo;floral grouping&rdquo; may comprise a growing potted plant having a root portion as well. However, it will be appreciated that the floral grouping may consist of only a single bloom or only foliage, or a botanical item (not shown), or a propagule. The term &ldquo;floral grouping&rdquo; may be used interchangeably herein with the term &ldquo;floral arrangement&rdquo;. The term &ldquo;floral grouping&rdquo; may also be used interchangeably herein with the terms &ldquo;botanical item&rdquo; and/or &ldquo;propagule.&rdquo; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;flower pot&rdquo; as used herein refers to any type of container for holding a floral grouping, or a plant, or even another pot type container. Examples of flower pots and/or pot type containers include, but are not limited to, clay pots, wooden pots, plastic pots, pots made from natural mad/or synthetic fibers, or any combination thereof. Such flower pots and or pot-type containers are provided with a retaining space for receiving a floral grouping. The floral grouping may be disposed within the retaining space of the flower pot with a suitable growing medium described in further detail below, or other retaining medium, such as a floral foam. It will also be understood that in some cases the floral grouping, and any appropriate growing medium or other retaining medium, may be disposed in a sleeve formed from the sheet of material having the printed pattern printed thereon if the sleeve is adapted to contain a medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;growing medium&rdquo; when used herein means any liquid, solid or gaseous material used for plant growth or for the cultivation of propagules, including organic and inorganic materials such as soil, humus, perlite, vermiculite, sand, water, and including the nutrients, fertilizers or hormones or combinations thereof required by the plants or propagules for growth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;botanical item&rdquo; when used herein means a natural or artificial herbaceous or woody plant, taken singularly or in combination. The term &ldquo;botanical item&rdquo; also means any portion or portions of natural or artificial herbaceous or woody plants including stems, leaves, flowers, blossoms, buds, blooms, cones, or roots, taken singularly or in combination, or in groupings of such portions such as bouquet or floral grouping. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;propagule&rdquo; when used herein means any structure capable of being propagated or acting as an agent of reproduction including seeds, shoots, stems, runners, tubers, plants, leaves, roots or spores. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;polymer film&rdquo; when used herein means a synthetically derived polymer, such as a polypropylene, or a naturally occurring polymer such as cellophane. A polymer film is relatively strong and not as subject to tearing (substantially non-tearable), as might be the case with paper or foil. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Cling Wrap or Material&rdquo; when used herein means any material which is capable of connecting to the sheet of material and/or itself upon contacting engagement during the wrapping process and is wrappable about an item whereby portions of the cling material contactingly engage and connect to other portions of another material, or, alternatively, itself, for generally securing the material wrapped about at least a portion of a flower pot. This connecting engagement is preferably temporary in that the material may be easily removed, i.e., the cling material &ldquo;clings&rdquo; to the flower pot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;bonding material&rdquo; when used herein can mean an adhesive, frequently a pressure sensitive adhesive, or a cohesive or any adhesive/cohesive combination, having adhesive qualities (i.e., qualities of adhesion or adhesion/cohesion, respectively) sufficient to cause the attachment of a portion of the sheet of material to itself, to a floral grouping, or to a flower pot. Since the bonding material may comprise either an adhesive or an adhesive/cohesive combination, it will be appreciated that both adhesives and cohesives are known in the art, and both are commercially available. When the bonding material is a cohesive, a similar cohesive material must be placed on the adjacent surface for bondingly contacting and bondingly engaging with the cohesive material. The term &ldquo;bonding material&rdquo; also includes materials which are heat sealable and, in this instance, the adjacent portions of the material must be brought into contact and then heat must be applied to effect the seal. The term &ldquo;bonding material&rdquo; also includes materials which are sonic sealable and vibratory sealable. The term &ldquo;bonding material&rdquo; when used herein also means a heat sealing lacquer or hot melt material which may be applied to the material and, in this instance, heat, sound waves, or vibrations, also must be applied to effect the sealing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;bonding material&rdquo; when used herein also means any type of material or thing which can be used to effect the bonding or connecting of the two adjacent portions of the material or sheet of material to effect the connection or bonding described herein. The term &ldquo;bonding material&rdquo; may also include ties, labels, bands, ribbons, strings, tapes (including single or double-sided adhesive tapes), staples or combinations thereof. Some of the bonding materials would secure the ends of the material while other bonding material may bind the circumference of a wrapper, or a sleeve, or, alternatively and/or in addition, the bonding materials would secure overlapping folds in the material and/or sleeve. Another way to secure the wrapping and/or sleeve is to heat seal the ends of the material to another portion of the material. One way to do this is to contact the ends with an iron of sufficient heat to heat seal the material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, a cold seal adhesive may be utilized as the bonding material. The cold seal adhesive adheres only to a similar substrate, acting similarly as a cohesive, and binds only to itself. The cold seal adhesive, since it bonds only to a similar substrate, does not cause a residue to build up on equipment, thereby both permitting much more rapid disposition and use of such equipment to form articles and reducing labor costs. Further, since no heat is required to effect the seal, the dwell time, that is, the time for the sheet of material to form and retain the shape of an article, such as a flower pot cover or flower pot, is reduced. A cold seal adhesive binds quickly and easily with minimal pressure, and such a seal is not readily releasable. This characteristic is different from, for example, a pressure sensitive adhesive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;bonding material&rdquo; when used herein also means any heat or chemically shrinkable material, and static electrical or other electrical apparatus, chemical welding apparatus, magnetic apparatus, mechanical or barb-type fastening apparatus or clamps, curl-type characteristics of the film or materials incorporated in material which can cause the material to take on certain shapes, cling films, slots, grooves, shrinkable materials and bands, curl materials, springs, and any type of welding method which may weld portions of the material to itself or to the pot, or to both the material itself and the pot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Detaching element&rdquo; as used herein, means any element, or combination of elements, or features, such as, but not by way of limitation, perforations, tear strips, zippers, and any other devices or elements of this nature known in the art, or any combination thereof. Therefore, while perforations are shown and described in detail herein, it will be understood that tear strips, zippers, or any other &ldquo;detaching elements&rdquo; known in the art, or any combination thereof, could be substituted therefor and/or used therewith. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, designated generally by the reference numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a sheet of material having an upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a lower surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and an outer peripheral edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the outer peripheral edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a first side <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a second side <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a third side <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and fourth side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A bonding material <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>) may be disposed on at least a portion of one or both surfaces of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, such as the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> thereof as shown and as further illustrated in U.S. Pat. No. 5,181,364, the specification of which is hereby expressly incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> on at least a portion of one of the upper or lower surfaces <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> thereof, such as the lower surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, which contains shaded and highlighted areas so as to provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance, may be of any geometrical shape or design which will enhance the aesthetic qualities of a decorative cover <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, respectively) formed from the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. That is, the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may be a lace pattern, curlicues, paisleys, swirls, squiggles, and any shape generally associated with botanical items such as leaves, petals, stems, roots, fruits and any other biomorphic shapes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is produced by printing a web or sheet of material with different colors of ink so that at least one portion of the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is printed in one color and other portions of the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are printed in different colors which results in the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> having the desired shaded and highlighted areas. By providing the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> with shaded and highlighted areas, the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> has a three dimensional appearance due to the depth perception created in the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> by the shaded and highlighted areas in the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may cover only a portion of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, or may cover an entire surface of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, or may cover all exposed and/or interior surfaces of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The ink compositions applied to a web or sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to produce the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> containing shaded and highlighted areas can be any ink compositions, either solvent-based or water-based, which are compatible with the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Such ink compositions are well known in the printing art. However, for environmental reasons it is preferred that the ink compositions be water-based ink compositions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Water-based ink compositions which can be employed to produce the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> on the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> contains shaded and highlighted areas which create the desired visual perception of depth to the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, are disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,594,048, the specification of which is hereby expressly incorporated in its entirety herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The ink compositions may be applied to the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in any conventional manner. The method of application may be manual or mechanical. If the material is in the form of a roll, then gravure, flexographic procedures, or Mayer rod procedures may be used to apply the ink compositions to the material which, when cut into sheets of material provide the sheets of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> thereon. The ink forming the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is provided in a substantially two-dimensional arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The sheets of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> containing shaded and highlighted areas may then be employed to provide a decorative cover for a floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>) or a decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for a flower pot (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>); or the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be employed to provide a sleeve <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for wrapping or covering a floral grouping (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 13</cross-reference>) or a flower pot (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15 and 16</cross-reference>); or the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be employed to form a preformed flower pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> for covering a flower pot (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17 and 18</cross-reference>). The use of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to form a decorative cover for a floral grouping or a flower pot, to form a sleeve for a floral grouping or a flower pot, or to form a preformed flower pot cover will be described in more complete detail hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As noted above, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> containing shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance can be utilized to form a decorative cover for a floral grouping or a flower pot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In the embodiments shown in the drawings, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> thereon is a square sheet of material. It will be appreciated, however, that the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> can be of any shape, configuration or size as long as the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is sufficiently sized and shaped to wrap and encompass a flower pot or a floral grouping. For example, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may have a rectangular, round, oval, octagonal or asymmetrical shape. Further, multiple sheets of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be used in a single circumstance to provide a decorative cover or sleeve for a flower pot or a floral grouping. Moreover, when multiple sheets of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are used in combination, the sheets of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> need not be uniform in size or shape. Finally, it will be appreciated that the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> shown in all embodiments herein is a substantially flat sheet and the ink compositions applied to the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are of substantially uniform thickness, whereby the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are produced by the application of different colors of ink to create the visual perception of depth and thus the three dimensional appearance of the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Any thickness or stiffness of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be utilized in accordance with the present invention as long as the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> containing shaded and highlighted areas printed thereon may be wrapped about at least a portion of a flower pot or a floral grouping, as described herein. Stiffer sheets of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be used if such stiffer sheets of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are scored to facilitate folding. The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> preferably has a thickness of from about 0.1 mil to about 30 mil. Typically, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a thickness in a range of about 0.5 mil to about 2.5 mil. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is constructed from any suitable wrapping material that is capable of being wrapped about a flower pot or floral grouping. Preferably, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is paper (untreated or treated in any manner), cellophane, metal foil, polymer film, non-polymer film, fabric (woven or nonwoven or synthetic or natural), cardboard, burlap, or laminations or combinations thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also be constructed, in whole or in part, from a cling material. The cling material is constructed and treated if necessary, from polyethylene such as Cling Wrap made by Glad&reg;, First Brands Corporation, Danbury, Conn. The thickness of the cling material will, in part, depend upon the size of sleeve and the size of the flower pot in the sleeve, i.e., generally, a larger flower pot may require a thicker and therefore stronger cling material. The cling material will have a thickness of at least about 0.1 mil, and preferably a thickness of from about 0.5 mil to about 2.5 mil. However, any thickness of cling material may be utilized in accordance with the present invention which permits the cling material to be printed with ink compositions so as to provide the cling material with a printed pattern having shaded and highlighted areas which produce a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance to the printed pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, a sleeve may be constructed from two polypropylene films wherein at least a lower or outer surface of one of the sheets of polypropylene film is provided with a printed pattern having shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern. The sheets of polypropylene film having such printed pattern may be connected together or laminated or may be separate sheets. In an alternative embodiment, the sleeve may be constructed from only one sheet of polypropylene film having a printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may vary in color. Further, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may comprise other decorative patterns or designs in addition to the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> which are printed, etched, and/or embossed thereon. In addition, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may have various colorings, coatings, flocking and/or metallic finishes, applied separately or simultaneously or may be characterized totally or partially by pearlescent, opaque, translucent, transparent, tinted, iridescent or the like, qualities. Each of the above-named characteristics may occur alone or in combination. Moreover, each surface of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may vary in the combination of such characteristics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Referring more specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a width <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extending generally between the first side <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the second side <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>; and a length <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extending generally between the third side <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the fourth side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is sufficiently sized so that the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> extends over a substantial portion of the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> when the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has been wrapped about the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention, as described in detail herein. The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also be wrapped about a flower pot to substantially wrap and cover the flower pot in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> A plurality of sheets of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be connected together to form a roll as is shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,459,976, the specification of which is hereby expressly incorporated herein in its entirety by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The wrapping of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> thereon about the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to provide a decorative cover <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> will now be described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The three dimensional appearance of the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is produced by application of ink compositions to the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in such a manner that the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> with a perception of depth. The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (which may optionally have the strip of bonding material <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> disposed upon the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the lower surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or both, such as the strip of bonding material <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> disposed along at least a portion of the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> so as to be disposed substantially adjacent the fourth side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) is provided, either as an individual sheet or from a pad or roll by any means or otherwise as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The bonding material <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, if present, may have a backing or release strip (not shown). The backing or release strip may be left applied for a period of time to the bonding material <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> after it is disposed on a surface of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> prior to its use as a wrapping material, to protect the bonding qualities of the bonding strip. In operation, an operator may dispose the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> on a support surface (not shown), the lower surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> contacting the support surface. Referring more specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is placed upon the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a diagonal orientation. The floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has an upper bloom or foliage portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a lower stem portion <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is then wrapped about the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> by the operator, the operator overlapping a portion of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> over another portion of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. That is, for example, the operator places the first side <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> over the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The operator continues to roll the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the direction toward the second side <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> until the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> near second side <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> firmly engages the lower surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, whereby the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is substantially encompassed by the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and wherein the bonding material <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> contacts a portion of the overlapped sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to provide the decorative cover <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which substantially encompasses and surrounds a substantial portion of the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> wrapped in a conical fashion with the bloom end <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> exposed near the open upper end of the decorative cover <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the stem end <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> exposed near the lower end of the decorative cover <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is utilized to wrap the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is disposed upon the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> approximately parallel to third side <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is then wrapped generally about the stem portion <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to a position wherein the third side <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> generally overlaps the fourth side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a cylindrical fashion. It should be noted that the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be wrapped a plurality of times about the stem portion <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> before the overlapping of the third side <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the fourth side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As before, the portion of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> near the third side <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is disposed generally adjacent another portion of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the two adjacent portions then are brought into contact where they may be bondingly engaged, thereby securing the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> generally about the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> so as to provide a decorative cover <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for the floral grouping <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the invention, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> thereon may be used to wrap a flower pot or pot-type container, as noted above. Shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flower pot designated by the reference numeral <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, which has an open upper end <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, a bottom end <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, an outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, and an inner retaining space <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> within which may be disposed a growing medium. The flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may contain a botanical item, such as a plant <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> thereon may be wrapped about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> by any one of numerous methods used to wrap sheets of material about flower pots to form decorative pot covers for flower pots, such as a decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> disposed about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may, for example, be formed by hand about the outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) of the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to produce the decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> can then be secured about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> by a bonding material, such as elastic band <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, so that the open upper end <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> remains substantially uncovered by the decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9, a</cross-reference> flower pot cover former and band applicator apparatus <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> for forming the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into the decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is illustrated. The flower pot cover former and band applicator device <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> comprises a band applicator <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and a flower pot cover former <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The flower pot cover former and band applicator device <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> has a support platform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> with an opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> formed therein. A band, such as elastic band <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, is disposed circumferentially about the opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in the support platform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The lower surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned on an upper surface <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> on the support platform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> such that the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned over the opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in the support platform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is then positioned above the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and is moved in a direction <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> into the opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the flower pot cover former and band applicator device <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. As the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is moved into the opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is pressed about the outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> thereby forming the decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is then secured about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> by the elastic band <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> having the decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> secured thereto is then moved in a direction <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> out of the opening <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in the support platform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The elastic band <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> can be applied manually or automatically such as by the method shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,105,599, which is hereby incorporated herein by reference. The band <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> can be applied as a tie using a method such as described in U.S Pat. No. 5,609,009, the specification of which is hereby incorporated herein by reference. The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be applied automatically about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, for example, by methods shown in U.S. Pat. Nos. 4,733,521 and 5,291,721, both of which are hereby incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Instead of securing the decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> via the band <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, the decorative cover <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> formed from the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be secured to the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> by the use of one or more bonding materials. For example, the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may have a bonding material disposed upon a portion thereof. When the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is disposed about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, at least a portion of the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> contacts the outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and is thereby bonded and held about the flower pot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> via the bonding material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The bonding material may cover a portion of the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or the bonding material may entirely cover the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The bonding material may be disposed on the upper surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the form of a strip or in the form of spaced-apart spots. One method for disposing a bonding material on the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,111,637, which is expressly incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a decorative cover designated therein by the general reference numeral <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> which comprises a flexible bag or sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> of unitary construction having a printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>printed thereon in accordance with the present invention. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may be used to provide the decorative cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> for a floral grouping or a flower pot. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> initially comprises a flexible flat collapsed piece of material which is openable in the form of a tube or sleeve. Such sleeves are well known in the floral industry. Further, in accordance with the present invention, the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> has the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, as previously described herein, printed upon at least a portion thereof. That is, the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which produce a three dimensional appearing pattern due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and high-lighted areas in the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> has an upper end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, a lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and an outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may be tapered outwardly from the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> toward a larger diameter at its upper end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. In its flattened state the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> generally has an overall trapezoidal or modified trapezoidal shape and when opened is substantially frusto-conical to coniform. It will be appreciated, however, that the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may comprise variations on the aforementioned shapes or may comprise significantly altered shapes such as square or rectangular, wherein the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> when opened has a cylindrical form, as long as the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> functions in accordance with the present invention in the manner described herein. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> (or any other sleeve disclosed herein) may have an angular or contoured shape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> has an opening <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> at the upper end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and may be open at the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, or closed with a bottom at the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> also has an inner peripheral surface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> which, when the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is opened, defines and encompasses an inner retaining space <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. When the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> has a closed lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, a portion of the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> may be inwardly folded to form one or more gussets (not shown) for allowing the lower portion of the inner retaining space <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> to be expandable, for example, for receiving the circular bottom of a pot or growing medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is generally frusto-conically shaped, but the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may be, by way of example but not by way of limitation, cylindrical, frusto-conical, a combination of both frusto-conical and cylindrical, or any other shape, as long as the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> functions as described herein as noted above. Further, the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may comprise any shape, whether geometric, non-geometric, asymmetrical and/or fanciful as long as it functions in accordance with the present invention. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may also be equipped with drain holes (if having a closed bottom) or side ventilation holes (not shown), or can be made from gas permeable or impermeable materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The material from which the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is constructed is the same as previously described above for the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Such materials used to construct the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> are further described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,111,637, which is expressly incorporated herein by reference. Any thickness of material may be utilized in accordance with the present invention as long as the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may be formed as described herein, and as long as the formed sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may contain at least a portion of a flower pot or a floral grouping, as described herein. Additionally, an insulating material such as bubble film, preferable as one of two or more layers, can be utilized in order to provide additional protection for the item, such as the floral grouping, contained therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is illustrated having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> printed on the outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. A floral grouping <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is disposed within the inner retaining space <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. Generally, an upper or bloom portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the floral grouping <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is exposed near the opening <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> and a lower or stem portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the floral grouping <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is exposed near the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. Either end of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may be closed about the floral grouping <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Generally, a portion of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is tightened about a portion of the stem portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the floral grouping <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for holding the decorative cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> about the floral grouping <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. For example, the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may be held by a tie <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> tied about the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> such as is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. Other means for binding a sleeve about a floral grouping may be employed such as the bonding means and materials described elsewhere herein. Similarly, it may generally be desired to use the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> as a decorative cover for a flower pot (not shown). The flower pot will generally contain a botanical item or plant. The flower pot can be deposited into the open sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> in a manner well known in the art, such as manually wherein the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is opened by hand and the flower pot deposited therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> As noted above, a bonding material may be disposed on a portion of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> or any sleeve described herein to assist in holding the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to the flower pot when the flower pot is disposed within the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> or to assist in closing the upper end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> or adhering the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to the flower pot after the flower pot has been disposed therein, as will be discussed in further detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> It will be understood that the bonding material, if present, may be disposed as a strip or block on a surface of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. The bonding material may also be disposed upon either the outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> or the inner peripheral surface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, as well as upon the flower pot. Further, the bonding material may be disposed as spots of bonding material, or in any other geometric, non-geometric, asymmetric, or fanciful form, and in any pattern including covering either the entire inner peripheral surface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and/or outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> and/or the flower pot. The bonding material may be covered by a cover or release strip which can be removed prior to the use of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> or flower pot. The bonding material can be applied by means known to those of ordinary skill in their art. One method for disposing a bonding material, in this case an adhesive, is described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,111,637, which is hereby incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> As noted above, a bonding material may be disposed on at least a portion of the inner peripheral surface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> (or any other sleeve described herein), or, alternatively, the bonding material may be disposed on the outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) of a flower pot contained within the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, while the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> may be free of the bonding material. In a further alternative, the bonding material may be disposed both on at least a portion of the flower pot as well as upon at least a portion of the inner peripheral surface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. In addition, a portion of the bonding material may also be disposed on the outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> as well. It will be understood that the bonding material may be disposed in a solid section of bonding material. The bonding material, when present, is disposed on the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> and/or flower pot by any means known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Certain embodiments of sleeves described herein may be used in combination with a preformed pot cover. For example, a preformed pot cover may be applied to the pot, then the covered pot wrapped or disposed within a sleeve. Either the cover, the sleeve, or both, may have the printed pattern printed thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced by application of ink compositions to the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> in such a manner that the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with a perception of depth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12, a</cross-reference> decorative cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is provided which comprises a sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>printed thereon. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is further provided with a cinching tab <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> having a bonding material <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> disposed upon a surface thereof. The cinching tab <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can be used to gather portions of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>together about the stem portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the floral grouping <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> for holding the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>tightly about the floral grouping <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Examples of sleeves which may be used in the practice of the present invention are disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,625,979, which is expressly incorporated herein by reference in its entirety. Equipment and devices for forming sleeves are commercially available, and well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14 and 15</cross-reference> is another embodiment of a decorative cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which comprises a sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>constructed in accordance with the present invention. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>printed thereon; and the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a &ldquo;detaching&rdquo; element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> in predetermined areas for detaching a portion of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>generally initially comprises a flexible, flat, collapsed piece of material which is openable in the form of a tube or sleeve. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is constructed of the same material and in the same way as described previously herein and may be described exactly the same as the other sleeves described herein except for the additional elements described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has an upper end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, a lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and an outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has an opening <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at the upper end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>thereof, and the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may be open at the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>or closed with a bottom at the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In a flattened state, the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a first side <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a second side <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>also has an inner peripheral surface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which, when the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is opened, defines and encompasses an inner retaining space <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. When the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a closed bottom, a portion of the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may be inwardly folded to form one or more gussets (not shown) for permitting a circular bottom of an object, such as a flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>), to be disposed in the inner retaining space <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the lower end <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is demarcated into an upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and a lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is generally sized to contain the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. The upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is sized to substantially surround and encompass a plant <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> contained in the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> disposed within the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is demarcated into the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> by a detaching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> for enabling the detachment of the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In the present embodiment, the detaching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is a plurality of generally laterally-oriented or alternately diagonally-oriented perforations which extend circumferentially across the outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from the first side <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the second side <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14 and 15</cross-reference>, the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>further comprises a base portion <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and a skirt portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The base portion <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> comprises that part of the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> which, when the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> is placed into the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, has an inner peripheral surface which is substantially adjacent to and surrounds the outer peripheral surface of the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. The skirt portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> comprises that part of the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> which extends beyond an open upper end of the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and adjacent at least a portion of the plant <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> contained within the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and which is left to freely extend at an angle, inwardly or outwardly, from the base portion <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> when the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is detached from the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>by actuation of the detaching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> In the intact sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the skirt portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> comprises an upper peripheral edge congruent with the detaching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> which is connected to a lower peripheral edge, also congruent with the detaching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, of the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14 and 15</cross-reference>, the upper peripheral edge of the skirt portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is congruent with a series of alternating diagonally-oriented lines of perforations which together form a zig-zag and comprise the detaching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may also have an additional detaching element <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> indicated as a plurality of vertical perforations for facilitating removal of the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and which are disposed more or less vertically therein extending between the detaching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and the upper end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is thereby separable from the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>by tearing the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> along both the vertical perforations <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and the detaching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, thereby separating the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> from the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>remains disposed as the base portion <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> about the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, and as the skirt portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> about the plant <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> forming a decorative cover <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> which substantially surrounds and encompasses the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and the plant <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> contained therein. The printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which has shaded and highlighted areas so as to provide the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with a visual perception of depth and thus provides a three dimensional appearance, may be printed upon only the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, for example, the base and skirt portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, while the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is left unprinted or is printed with another design. When the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is detached, the portion containing the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>remains. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> In a general method of use of sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as a decorative cover for a flower pot, an operator provides the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> having a plant <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> disposed in a growing medium contained within the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. The operator then disposes the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> having the plant <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> contained therein into the sleeve by opening the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at its upper end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and assuring both that the opening <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>therein is in an open condition, and that the inner peripheral surface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is somewhat expanded outward as well, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. The operator then manually or automatically disposes the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> into the opening <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> being disposed generally through the upper portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>into generally the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> remaining in the lower portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, permitting the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to substantially surround and tightly encompass the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. It will be understood that, alternatively, the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with an extension (not shown) may be utilized, the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being disposed on rods, or wickets (not shown) and the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> then being disposed in the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>either before or after the sleeve <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has been removed from the wickets. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EMBODIMENTS OF FIGS. <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17 and 18</cross-reference>, a decorative preformed flower pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is illustrated constructed from a sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> thereon. As previously described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is produced by application of ink to the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> such that the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is provided with a three dimensional appearance as a result of a perception of depth created by shaded and highlighted areas created in the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> The decorative preformed pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> has a base <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> with an upper end <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, a lower end <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, and an outer peripheral surface <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. A skirt <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> is connected to the upper end <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the base <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> so as to extend outwardly from the upper end <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the base <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and terminating with an outer periphery <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>. An opening <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> intersects the upper end <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, forming an inner peripheral surface <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> which defines and encompasses a retaining space within which the flower pot <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> containing the floral grouping or plant <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be disposed in a manner well known in the art and which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The decorative preformed flower pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be constructed of a single sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> printed thereon substantially as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, or a plurality of layers of the same and/or different types of material may be employed in the formation of the decorative preformed flower pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The thickness of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may vary widely and any thickness of the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be utilized in accordance with the present invention so long as the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is formable into the decorative preformed flower pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> as described herein. When the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is constructed of a plurality of layers of material, each layer of material may be connected to an adjacent layer of material via a bonding material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>, the decorative preformed flower pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be formed using a conventional mold system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> comprising a male mold <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and a female mold <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> having a mold cavity <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> for matingly receiving the male mold <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. The sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> printed thereon is positioned between the male and female molds <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, respectively. Movement of the male mold <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> in the direction <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> and into the mold cavity <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> forces the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to be disposed about the portion of the male mold <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> disposed in the mold cavity <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> of the female mold <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and thereby forms the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into the preformed decorative flower pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Methods for forming such preformed decorative pot covers are well known in the art. Two methods of forming such covers are described in U.S. Pat. Nos. 4,773,182 and 5,291,721, each of which is expressly incorporated herein by reference. It will be noted that in one preferred embodiment, overlapping folds <highlight><bold>149</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17 and 18</cross-reference>) are provided and a portion of the overlapping folds <highlight><bold>149</bold></highlight> can be connected, such as by an application of the bonding material <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, as discussed above, to the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> before forming the sheet of material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by way of the conventional mold system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Further, in accordance with the present invention, the preformed flower pot cover <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is constructed from the same materials described hereinabove, may have a bonding material disposed upon a portion thereof, and has printed upon at least a portion thereof the printed pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> described in detail above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Changes may be made in the construction and the operation of the various components, elements and assemblies described herein or in the steps or the sequence of steps of the methods described herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the following claims. 
<image file="US20030000142A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" id="EMI-00001"></image>
<image file="US20030000142A1-20030102-P00002.TIF" id="EMI-00002"></image>
<image file="US20030000142A1-20030102-P00003.TIF" id="EMI-00003"></image>
<image file="US20030000142A1-20030102-P00004.TIF" id="EMI-00004"></image>
<image file="US20030000142A1-20030102-P00005.TIF" id="EMI-00005"></image>
<image file="US20030000142A1-20030102-P00006.TIF" id="EMI-00006"></image>
</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for providing a decorative cover for a flower pot having a floral grouping disposed therein, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a flower pot having floral grouping disposed therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing the flower pot in the sleeve having the printed pattern containing shaded and highlighted areas whereby the sleeve substantially surrounds and encompasses the flower pot with the floral grouping disposed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance, the sleeve is a flexible sleeve having such printed pattern and a bonding material disposed thereon, at least a portion of the bonding material on the flexible sleeve disposed adjacent the flower pot for securing the flexible sleeve about the flower pot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the flexible sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance, the flexible sleeve is further defined as having a first end, a second end, and an outer periphery which forms an outer surface on which such printed pattern is disposed, the flexible sleeve having an opening which intersects both the first and second ends forming an inner surface defined by an inner periphery which forms a retaining space for receiving the flower pot containing the floral grouping therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and an bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance, the flexible sleeve is constructed from a material selected from the group consisting of paper, cellophane, metal foil, polymer film, non-polymer film, cloth, burlap, and laminations or any combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance, the material for constructing the flexible sleeve is further characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.1 mil to about 30 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance, the material for constructing the flexible sleeve is further characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.5 mil to about 2.5 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance, the material for constructing the sleeve is characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.1 mil to about 30 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth and thus a three dimensional appearance, the material for constructing the sleeve is characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.5 mil to about 2.5 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method for providing a decorative cover for a flower pot having a floral grouping disposed therein, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a flower pot having floral grouping disposed therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a sleeve having a printed pattern thereon, the printed pattern having shaded and highlighted areas to provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing the flower pot in the sleeve having the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance thereon whereby the sleeve substantially surrounds and encompasses the flower pot with the floral grouping disposed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern has shaded and highlighted areas to provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern, the sleeve is a flexible sleeve having a bonding material and such printed pattern thereon, at least a portion of the bonding material on the flexible sleeve disposed adjacent the flower pot for securing the flexible sleeve about the flower pot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern has shaded and highlighted areas to provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern, the flexible sleeve is further defined as having a first end, a second end, and an outer periphery which forms an outer surface on which such printed pattern is disposed, the flexible sleeve having an opening which intersects both the first and second ends forming an inner surface defined by an inner periphery which forms a retaining space for receiving the flower pot containing the floral grouping therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern has shaded and highlighted areas to provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern, the flexible sleeve is constructed from a material selected from the group consisting of paper, cellophane, metal foil, polymer film, non-polymer film, cloth, burlap, and laminations or any combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern has shaded and highlighted areas to provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern, the material from which the flexible sleeve is constructed is characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.1 mil to about 30 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern has shaded and highlighted areas to provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern, the material from which the flexible sleeve is constructed is characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.5 mil to about 2.5 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern has shaded and highlighted areas to provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern, the material from which the sleeve is constructed is characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.1 mil to about 30 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern has shaded and highlighted areas to provide the printed pattern with a three dimensional appearance due to the visual perception of depth created by the shaded and highlighted areas of the printed pattern, the material from which the sleeve is constructed is characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.5 mil to about 2.5 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method for providing a decorative cover for a flower pot having a floral grouping disposed therein, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a flower pot having floral grouping disposed therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing the flower pot in the sleeve having the printed pattern with shaded and highlighted areas whereby the sleeve substantially surrounds and encompasses the flower pot with the floral grouping disposed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing a sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth, the sleeve is a flexible sleeve having a bonding material and such printed pattern thereon, and wherein at least at least a portion of the bonding material on the flexible sleeve is disposed adjacent the flower pot for securing the flexible sleeve about the flower pot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the flexible sleeve having a printed pattern thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth, the flexible sleeve is further defined as having a first end, a second end, and an outer periphery which forms an outer surface on which the printed pattern is disposed, the flexible sleeve having an opening which intersects both the first and second ends forming an inner surface defined by an inner periphery which forms a retaining space for receiving the flower pot containing the floral grouping therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth, the flexible sleeve is constructed from a material selected from the group consisting of paper, cellophane, metal foil, polymer film, non-polymer film, cloth, burlap, and laminations or any combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth, the material from which the flexible sleeve is constructed is further characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.1 mil to about 30 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the flexible sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth, the material from which the flexible sleeve is constructed is further characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.5 mil to about 2.5 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth, the material from which the sleeve is constructed is further characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.1 mil to about 30 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, in the step of providing the sleeve having a printed pattern and a bonding material thereon wherein the printed pattern is produced on the sleeve by application of ink compositions such that the printed pattern is provided with shaded and highlighted areas which provide the printed pattern with a visual perception of depth, the material from which the sleeve is constructed is further characterized as having a thickness in the range of from about 0.5 mil to about 2.5 mils.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000142A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000142A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000142A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000142A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000142A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000142A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000142A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
