<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000534A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000534A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000534</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10145389</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020514</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61M016/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>128</class>
<subclass>207140</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Perilaryngeal oral airway</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10145389</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020514</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09409295</doc-number>
<document-date>19990929</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6386199</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Alfery</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Nashville</city>
<state>TN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SWANSON &amp; BRATSCHUN L.L.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1745 SHEA CENTER DRIVE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 330</address-2>
<city>HIGHLANDS RANCH</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80129</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An oral airway (<highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>) includes an elongate tubular member (<highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>) having a distal (<highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>) and a proximal end (<highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>), the oral airway being configured to place the distal end in a supraglottic position when operatively placed within the hypopharynx of a patient. A temperature sensor (<highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>) is operatively associated with the elongate tubular member to detect a core temperature of a patient with the distal end of the oral airway operatively placed in a superglottic position within the hypopharynx of the patient. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/409,295, filed Sep. 29, 1999, entitled &ldquo;Perilaryngeal Oral Airway.&rdquo;</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to a class of medical devices commonly referred to as oral airways and supraglottic airways which are inserted through a patient&apos;s mouth and into the patient&apos;s pharynx while the patient is undergoing general anesthesia or is undergoing respiratory treatment such as is carried out with cardiopulmonary resuscitation. More specifically, the present invention is directed to a perilaryngeal oral airway and perilaryngeal supraglottic airway which is capable of acting as an endotracheal tube guide and which seats deep in a patient&apos;s hypopharynx to prevent the soft tissue of the glottis and epiglottis from obstructing the airway. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Oral airways were introduced into the practice of anesthesia and cardiopulmonary resuscitation several decades ago for two basic purposes. First, they prevent the patient&apos;s biting down on and occlusion of a previously placed oral endotracheal tube. Second, and most important, oral airways help to provide a patent airway that allows positive pressure ventilation to be carried out by the practitioner. More recently, some oral airways have been developed to facilitate blind (not visually directed) placement of an endotracheal tube. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> For most patients, mask ventilation is carried out successfully by insertion of an oral airway and by a variety of physical adjustments, such as extension of the patient&apos;s neck and elevation of the patient&apos;s jaw. However, in some patients, no matter what physical adjustments are made or the particular oral airway which is inserted, mask ventilation cannot be successfully achieved. Such cases are literally life-threatening as hypoxemia and death can quickly ensue if the patient&apos;s blood is deprived of oxygen due to a lack of ventilation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> When mask ventilation (even with the use of an oral airway) cannot be carried out, there are multiple mechanisms responsible. Most significantly, soft tissue structures in the hypopharynx (the area between where conventional oral airways end and the glottis opens into the trachea) collapse inwardly and obstruct airflow. This collapse occurs from both an antero-posterior direction, as well as from the sides of the hypopharynx. Unfortunately, all oral airways which have been introduced into practice to date end bluntly well above the epiglottis (the cartilaginous structure just above the glottis or laryngeal opening) and glottis and thus place patients at risk for significant airway obstruction. Another mechanism of airway obstruction which occurs while using oral airways is the patient having large lips covering the outside opening of the oral airway with subsequent inadequate airflow through the nasal passages (due to the solid posterior wall of the airway limiting passage of air into the airway at the level of the nasopharynx). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Additionally, most known oral airways are comprised of a hard plastic material throughout their length with no variation in softness between one end of the oral airway and the opposite end. As a result, the distal end (i.e., the end which first enters the mouth and passes down into the pharynx of the patient) often bruises or otherwise damages soft mucosal surfaces of the patient during insertion or once the oral airway has been seated in place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Representative prior art airways include Baildon, U.S. Pat. No. 4,919,126, which discloses an oral airway formed of plastic which includes an air passageway extending longitudinally through the airway. The distal end has a projecting solid anterior portion which serves as an &ldquo;epiglottis elevator.&rdquo; As such, the oral airway is blunt-shaped in configuration and ends well above the glottis. For this reason, the Baildon oral airway suffers from the problems discussed above in that it fails to provide any structure to prevent the collapse of soft tissue structures in the hypopharynx. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Berman, U.S. Pat. Nos. 4,054,135 and 4,067,331, relate to an intubating pharyngeal airway having a side access for passage of an endotracheal tube. The airway includes a blunt end on the anteriorly extending wall which is designed to fit into the vallecula (area between the epiglottis and tongue). Accordingly, the devices disclosed in both of Berman&apos;s patents are similar to the device of Baildon in that they can detrimentally allow soft tissue structures to invaginate inward and thereby occlude the passage of air. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Moses, U.S. Pat. No. 3,908,665, discloses an oro-pharyngeal airway wherein the outer diameter of the body portion progressively increases from the end closest to the mouth to the opposite end thereof so as to relieve any obstruction to the flow of air by the base of the tongue falling back on the posterior pharyngeal wall. However, the airway of Moses likewise suffers from the problems discussed in detail above in that the blunt-shaped end terminates well above the glottis, thereby allowing possible soft tissue obstruction to occur. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Augustine, U.S. Pat. No. 5,203,320, discloses a tracheal intubation guide which similarly seats above the glottis. Moreover, the device of Augustine functions as a guide for placing an endotracheal tube in a &ldquo;blind&rdquo; manner and is neither designed for nor could it possibly function to allow mask ventilation to be carried out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In addition, for some patients it is important to use an airway device which provides a seal within the patient&apos;s airway (trachea, oro- or hypopharynx) in order to better allow positive pressure ventilation to be accomplished. These airways are referred to herein as supraglottic airways. Traditionally, this has been achieved by using an endotracheal tube passed between a patient&apos;s vocal cords. In an effort to avoid the deleterious effects of tracheal intubation (e.g., bronchospasm, dental injury and cardiovascular stimulation), the laryngeal mask airway (&ldquo;LMA&rdquo;) has been introduced into clinical practice. The LMA is illustrated and described in Brain, U.S. Pat. No. 4,509,514. While providing a seal with which to administer positive pressure ventilation, there are several potential problems when using an LMA. First, the device is easily malpositioned so that ventilation is not possible, for example, by virtue of the epiglottis bending back over the glottis and thereby obstructing air flow. Second, by directly covering the glottic aperture, trauma to the glottic structures (arrhytenoid cartilages, vocal cords) can occur. In addition, the cost of this product (over $200) becomes a factor when limitations to reuse occur due to physical damage of the device or accidental loss. Third, as a reusable product, the hazard of cross-contamination from one patient to another cannot be completely eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Because of the above-limitations of the LMA, a cuffed oro-pharyngeal airway has been introduced into clinical practice. Greenberg, U.S. Pat. No. 5,443,063, describes such a device as an oro-pharyngeal cuff placed over a conventional oral airway. However, this device has several significant limitations which prevent it from functioning adequately. First, the airway suffers from the problems of those previously discussed in that it ends well above the glottis, thereby allowing soft tissue obstruction to impair the flow of oxygen to the lungs. Second, with the cuff placed so far proximally in the oro-pharynx, the device tends to push itself out of the patient&apos;s mouth, thereby requiring that the device be secured in place by means of a strap placed around the patient&apos;s head. Finally, the cuff is positioned so far proximally in the patient&apos;s airway that it often allows leakage of oxygen and anesthetic gases around the cuff, thereby preventing the formation of an air-tight seal. This, of course, makes positive pressure ventilation impossible in those patients. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Several oral airways, including those described in the patents to Berman and Augustine, have been introduced into clinical practice in an effort to provide a means to accomplish blind intubation of a patient&apos;s trachea with an endotracheal tube (or to facilitate fiberoptic intubation). These devices end well above the glottic opening and thus function poorly in terms of reliably directing the end of an endotracheal tube into the glottis with blind passage. As a result, the hard distal end of the endotracheal tube may be directed against the structures which surround the glottic opening (arytenoid, cuneiform and corniculate cartilages, epiglottis, aryepiglottic folds) and cause damage to these structures or their soft tissue surfaces. Further, that damage may result in hemorrhage which obscures vision if subsequent placement of the endotracheal tube by means of a fiberoptic device is attempted. Other prior art has attempted to better direct an endotracheal tube into the glottis by having walls which surround and thus engage the arytenoid cartilages or which have projections which physically enter in between those cartilages. Representative are Patil, U.S. Pat. No. 5,720,275; Kr&uuml;ger, U.S. Pat. No. 4,612,927; and Williams, U.S. Pat. No. 4,338,930. However, these structures have hard advancing surfaces which can likewise cause trauma. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Recently, a version of the LMA which is meant to facilitate blind intubation with an endotracheal tube has been introduced into clinical use which attempts to surmount the problems of a misguided endotracheal tube causing trauma to perilaryngeal and glottic structures. This LMA is described in Brain, U.S. Pat. No. 5,896,858. However, in addition to sharing the above discussed problems common to all LMA&apos;s, this device relies on precise positioning so that a movable flap raises an obstructing epiglottis out of the way of an advancing endotracheal tube. Because the attached flap resides within the body of the LMA it does not physically contact the epiglottis upon insertion, but rather the advancing endotracheal tube pushes the flap up against the epiglottis to move it out of the way and thus open the glottic aperture for the endotracheal tube to enter. Perfect alignment of the recessed flap with the epiglottis is thus necessary to reliably accomplish blind placement of the endotracheal tube. However, LMA&apos;s occupy a somewhat variable and inconsistent position within the hypopharynx in relation to the precise anatomic location of the glottis (due to anatomic variability among patients as well as the distensible nature of the proximal epiglottis and hypopharynx where it resides). As a result, blind intubation with an endotracheal tube with this device can also result in tissue trauma by virtue of its advancing end being misdirected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The importance of monitoring and maintaining core body temperature when patients undergo general anesthesia is now being more clearly recognized. Significant reductions in body temperature (which are the common and usual course following induction of general anesthesia) in patients undergoing surgery are associated with an increased incidence of cardiac morbidity, increased rates of wound infection, impaired wound healing and alterations in blood coagulation status. In addition, although rare, a patient undergoing general anesthesia may have a sudden and dramatic rise in body temperature due to an abnormal acceleration of metabolic rate in a condition termed maligmant hyperthermia. This is a life-threatening syndrom which requires prompt recognition and treatment if a patient is to survive, and the rise in body temperature is one of the hallmarks used to diagnose its occurrence. Further, in order to reliably measure body temperature, a &ldquo;core&rdquo; temperature must be used. As such, a thermistor or thermal couple temperature probe must be in contact with a deep visceral cavity (e.g., urinary bladder, esophagus), blood, or an internal mucosal surface (e.g., hypopharynx, nasopharynx) which reflects inner body temperature as opposed to surface temperature of the patient. No supraglottic airway or oral airway which is currently in use provides measurement of core temperature by a temperature sensor incorporated into that device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Supraglottic airways are sometimes used in anesthetized patients undergoing surgery within the oral cavity or on the head and neck. As such, the presence of the breathing tube can be a physical impediment to the operating surgeon. Known oral airways are too rigid to allow the airway to be moved from the surgical field. Further, a version of the LMA which is made using a flexible reinforced breathing channel suffers from the limitations common to LMAs discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The present invention is intended to overcome one or more of the problems discussed above. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> One aspect of the present invention provides an oral airway wherein the distal end portion thereof is extended and shaped in order to seat deep in the hypopharynx and to actually surround the epiglottis and glottis (thus the name &ldquo;perilaryngeal oral airway&rdquo;). By extending around the epiglottis and the glottis, the perilaryngeal oral airway of the present invention is able to physically hold the patient&apos;s soft tissue in the hypopharynx away from the glottic opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In particular, the oral airway includes a curved hollow, tubular longitudinally extending body member, the body member having a distal end portion for insertion into the mouth and pharynx of a patient and a proximal end portion for location at the mouth of the patient, wherein the distal end portion of the body member is extended and shaped so as to be operative to seat deep in the patient&apos;s hypopharynx and terminate just above or surround the patient&apos;s epiglottis and glottis, thereby to hold the patient&apos;s soft tissue away from the patient&apos;s air channel opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the distal end portion of the body member is divided so as to form a pair of elongated extension walls which are operative to seat deep in the patient&apos;s hypopharynx and surround the patient&apos;s epiglottis and glottis, thereby to hold the patient&apos;s soft tissue away from the patient&apos;s air channel opening. More specifically, an opening, which may be rectangular, trapezoidal, U-shaped or V-shaped is formed in the distal end portion as a result of the division or separation of the distal end portion of the body member so as to form the two elongated extension walls and into which the epiglottis and glottis are positioned. The elongated extension walls at the distal end portion expand outward laterally to allow sufficient space in which to accommodate the epiglottis and glottis within the openings. The extreme distal ends of the elongated extension walls may be angled inward slightly, thereby providing a smooth contour. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the present invention further provides elongated lateral extension walls which are relatively flexible and soft so that there is at least some &ldquo;give&rdquo; as the oral airway is inserted into the patient. The particular firmness of the walls must strike a balance between the need to hold the hypopharyngeal and perilaryngeal structures away from the glottis, the need to move the soft tonsillar and oro-pharyngeal structures to the side as the oral airway is inserted, and the desire for the oral airway to be able to bend inwardly when inserted through the back of the patient&apos;s mouth. Likewise, the body member of the oral airway is of sufficient softness and pliability to bend during insertion and to accommodate different angles once successfully inserted into the patient, since a given patient&apos;s head and neck may be slightly flexed or extended to provide optimal positioning for mask ventilation. The most proximal end portion of the oral airway is much harder than the distal end portion in order to prevent occlusion by the patient biting down thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In a further embodiment, rather than dividing the distal end portion of the body member so as to form a pair of elongated extension walls, the posterior wall of the distal end portion is filled in. In this way, the posterior wall of the distal end portion serves to better hold tissue away from the larynx. Likewise, the anteriorly placed opening which is V-shaped, U-shaped, rectangular or trapezoidal, may be made smaller in order to cover and hold away the epiglottis while still allowing air passage into the glottis. Alternatively, a grate may cover the opening to keep the epiglottis and other tissue out of the opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Further, in any of the above-described embodiments, holes or fenestrations may be formed through the distal anterior wall of the body member of the oral airway in order to provide ventilation should the distal end portion be positioned directly over the glottic opening of the patient, as might occur if the practitioner has selected too large of an oral airway for a particular patient, or the patient has an abnormally high (rostrally) placed glottic opening. Moreover, holes may be formed through the anterior surface of the elongated extension walls and which function to allow ventilation should the oral airway be situated at an abnormal angle such that one of the elongated extension walls covers the glottis. Still further, additional air holes or fenestrations may be formed through the posterior wall of the body member of the oral airway at the region of curvature which is adapted to be positioned at the back of the oropharynx and which allow passage of air through the nasal passages of the patient and into the oral airway per se. Of course, the holes can be dispensed with entirely if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to a still further embodiment, the oral airway includes an inflatable cuff positioned just above the distally placed notch. Accordingly, the distal end of the perilaryngeal oral airway is easily seated around the larynx, thereby holding the soft tissues away from the glottic aperture, and the more distally positioned cuff is located within the hypopharynx and thereby allows the oral airway to be held in place without external means and avoids the airway leakage which can occur at the base of the tonsillar pillars and soft palate when using the conventional cuffed oro-pharyngeal airway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Also contemplated is a method of administering anesthesia or respiratory treatment using an anesthesia or respiratory circuit to a patient using the perilaryngeal oral airway of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention is an oral airway referred to as a grated oral airway or grated perilaryngeal oral airway includes an elongate tubular member having a distal and a proximal end with an enlarged wedge-shaped housing at the distal end. The wedge-shaped housing is for insertion into the mouth and pharynx of a patient with the proximal end of the tubular member extending from the mouth of the patient. The wedge-shaped housing has anterior and posterior walls forming an enlarged proximal portion tapering to a smaller distal portion with a leading opening separating the anterior and posterior walls at the distal end of the housing. A grate covers the leading opening. Sidewalls extend between the anterior and posterior walls and the wedge-shaped housing is configured so that the sidewalls abut the aryepiglottic folds as the wedge-shaped housing is inserted in to the hypopharynx of a patient to arrest insertion of the wedge-shaped housing and seat the wedge-shaped housing with the leading opening adjacent to the glottis. The grate is inclined between the posterior and anterior walls so that as a patient&apos;s epiglottis is engaged by the grate during insertion of the wedge-shaped housing into the hypopharynx, the epiglottis slides up the grate and into abutment with the anterior wall of the wedge-shaped housing. The elongate tubular member may further include a reinforced portion at its proximal end to act as a bite block when the wedge-shaped housing is seated within the hypopharynx of a patient. The tubular member is preferably substantially axially rigid and radially flexible to bend to the anatomic contours of the mouth and the pharynx during insertion into and upon being seated in a patient. The housing is preferably flexible and soft to provide some give as the housing is inserted into a patient and rigid enough to prevent collapse of the housing by the epiglottis and tissue surrounding the hypopharynx as the housing is inserted into and seated within a patient. An inflatable cuff is preferably provided around the proximal end of the wedge-shaped housing or the elongate tubular member proximate the proximal end of the wedge-shaped housing. A temperature sensor may be provided on the housing or on the inflatable cuff. An adaptor for facilitating fluid tight connection of the proximal end of the elongate tubular member to a respiratory circuit or an anesthesia circuit can be permanently or releasably attached to the proximal end of the elongate tubular member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the grated oral airway the grate is connected to the anterior wall of the housing by a hinge so that the grate is pivotable to uncover the leading opening. In this embodiment, the tubular member preferably extends within the housing and is positioned therein to direct an instrument inserted in the tubular member anteriorly, whereby with the wedge-shaped housing positioned adjacent to a patient&apos;s glottis, the instrument is directed toward the trachea as it is axially advanced within the elongate tubular member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In yet another embodiment of the grated oral airway the grate is made of a flexible material that is rigid enough to slide the epiglottis into abutment with the anterior wall of the wedge-shaped housing as the wedge-shaped housing is inserted into the hypopharynx and flexible enough to enable an endotracheal tube or other instrument to be axially driven between a gap defined by the grate by displacing the flexible grate material defining the gap. The grate preferably consists of a plurality of vertically oriented bars. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Yet another aspect of the present invention is a method of providing the grated oral airway to a patient. The method includes inserting the wedge-shaped housing into the mouth of the patient, axially advancing the wedge-shaped housing to slide the epiglottis over the grate and seating the wedge-shaped housing with a leading surface of the enlarged proximal portion abutting the patient&apos;s aryepiglottic folds, the anterior wall of the wedge-shaped housing abutting the epiglottis and the grate adjacent to the glottis. The method may further include axially inserting an endotracheal tube into the elongate tubular member and deforming the material forming the grate by axially advancing the endotracheal tube through a gap defined by the material forming the grate to locate a distal end of the endotracheal tube in the trachea of a patient, and attaching one of an anesthesia circuit and an airway circuit to a proximal end of the endotracheal tube. The method may further include, after seating the wedge-shaped housing, inflating the inflatable cuff. An anesthesia circuit or another airway circuit can be attached to the distal end of the elongate tubular member following inflation of the cuff. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Yet another aspect of the present invention is an elongate tubular member having a distal and a proximal end, the distal end having an opening that is inclined so that a posterior portion of the distal end extends beyond an anterior portion of the distal end. A grate covers the leading opening, the grate being configured so that as a patient&apos;s epiglottis is engaged by the grate during insertion of the distal end into the hypopharynx, the epiglottis slides up the grate and into abutment with an anterior portion of the tubular member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides an oral airway for reliably holding soft tissue structures away from the laryngeal opening to assure adequate airflow to a patient. The invention also provides a supraglottic airway which holds soft tissues in the vicinity of the laryngeal opening apart and which provides for seating of the distal end of the oral airway in a consistent and precise manner adjacent the larynx or glottis aperture for facilitating positive pressure ventilation by anesthesia circuit, resuscitation mask or ventilator. Furthermore, those embodiments providing either a flexible grate or a pivoting grate allow for reliable blind passage of an endotracheal tube into the trachea. These many advantages are provided by a structure which is rigid enough to assure proper placement and to prevent inadvertent kinking of the airway, yet soft enough to minimize the risk of injury to the sensitive tissue of the oral cavity, pharynx and hypopharynx. The present invention further includes embodiments to prevent occlusion of the breathing tube by a patient&apos;s teeth. Those embodiments with a temperature monitor allow for monitoring of the body temperature to guard against hypothermia and as an early warning of possible maligmant hyperthermia. The flexible breathing tube can be manipulated by an operating surgeon to remove it from the operating theater within an oral cavity or pharynx. Finally, all these many advantages are provided by an airway which is relatively easily manufactured from inexpensive materials, thereby promoting its widespread use and making its many advantages readily available.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view illustrating the use of a conventional oral airway inserted into a patient; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view illustrating the use of the perilaryngeal oral airway in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the pharynx of a patient wherein the posterior wall has been removed and the interior is viewed from behind, with the distal end portion of one embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention being shown seated in position and with an endotracheal tube E in situ; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing one embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is a posterior view of the perilaryngeal oral airway of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing a further embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is a posterior view of the perilaryngeal oral airway of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> illustrates the use of holes or fenestrations in one of the embodiments of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> is a posterior view of the perilaryngeal oral airway of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a cuffed embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> shows a cuffed embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention including a grate covering the opening; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows a proximal end of the perilaryngeal oral airway of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a grated embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a cross-section view of the distal end of the grated perilaryngeal oral airway taken along line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view identical to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> only with an endotracheal tube axially inserted in the elongate tubular member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a hinged grate embodiment of the housing of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a perspective view of another embodiment of the hinged grate housing of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view illustrating the grated perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention nested in the hypopharynx of a patient; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view identical to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> only with an endotracheal tube being guided into the trachea of a patient; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view identical to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> only with the hinged grate housing embodiment and an endotracheal tube extending into the trachea of a patient; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a schematic cross-sectional front view illustrating the grated perilaryngeal oral nested in the hypopharynx of a patient; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional side view of a reinforced elongate tubular member in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The invention will now be described with reference to the drawings; however, the position of a conventional oral airway is first briefly discussed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a simplified anatomical illustration of a patient&apos;s head, including the oral airway defined by the mouth <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the oral cavity <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the tongue <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and the epiglottis <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the trachea <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the esophagus <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the hypopharynx <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A conventional oral airway <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned within the patient&apos;s oral airway, with the distal end <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> ending well above the glottis so that no structure is provided to prevent the collapse of soft tissue structures T in the hypopharynx. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>B relate to one embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention. Note that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, like elements are denoted with like reference numerals with reference to the patient&apos;s oral airway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference>, the perilaryngeal oral airway <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a curved hollow, tubular longitudinally extending body member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The curvature of the body member preferably, but not necessarily, is between 100&deg; and 140&deg;. The body member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes a flanged proximal end portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> for location at the mouth of the patient (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). The body member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> further includes a distal end portion <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> for insertion into the mouth and pharynx of the patient. In the first embodiment, the distal end portion <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of the body member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is divided so as to form a pair of elongated extension walls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> which are operative to seat deep in the patient&apos;s hypopharynx and surround the patient&apos;s epiglottis and glottis (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>), thereby to hold the patient&apos;s soft tissue away from the patient&apos;s air channel opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> A U-shaped or V-shaped opening or notch <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is formed in the distal end portion <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of the body member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> so as to form the two elongated extension walls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> and into which the epiglottis and glottis are positioned. The elongated extension walls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> at the distal end portion preferably, but not necessarily, expand outward laterally to allow for sufficient space in which to accommodate the epiglottis and glottis within the U-shaped or V-shaped opening <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The extreme distal ends <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the elongated extension walls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>, respectively, may be angled inwardly slightly, thereby providing a smooth contour. The purpose of the inwardly angled extreme distal ends is to allow the ends to be safely inserted past the tonsillar pillars at the back of the patient&apos;s mouth. By forming the inwardly-shaped surface, the slightly narrower most distal end can push up against very large tonsils and move them laterally to the sides as the perilaryngeal oral airway is inserted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The elongated lateral extension walls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> are preferably, but not necessarily, formed to be relatively flexible and soft so that there is at least some &ldquo;give&rdquo; as the perilaryngeal oral airway is inserted into the patient. The particular firmness of the walls must strike a balance between the need to hold the hypopharyngeal and perilaryngeal structures away from the glottis, the need to move the soft tonsillar and oro-pharyngeal structures to the side as the oral airway is inserted, and the desire for the oral airway to be able to bend inwardly when inserted through the back of the patient&apos;s mouth. Likewise, the body member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the perilaryngeal oral airway <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is preferably, but not necessarily, of sufficient softness and pliability to bend during insertion and to accommodate different angles once it is successfully inserted into the patient, since a given patient&apos;s head and neck may be slightly flexed or extended to provide optimal positioning for mask ventilation. The most proximal end portion <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the oral airway is much harder than the distal end portion <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> in order to prevent occlusion by the patient biting down thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</cross-reference> show a further embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention wherein the distal end portion <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is modified in comparison to the oral airway of the previous embodiment. Note that like elements are denoted with like reference numerals, but preceded by the reference number &ldquo;2&rdquo;. In particular, in this embodiment, the distal end portion <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> has a &ldquo;filled-in&rdquo; distal posterior wall <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> in order to better hold tissue away from the larynx. The anterior wall includes a notched portion <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> as in the previous embodiment. The body member <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the oral airway preferably, but not necessarily, is of sufficient softness and pliability to bend during insertion and to accommodate different angles once successfully inserted into the patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A and 6B</cross-reference> illustrate a still further embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention. Again, like elements are denoted with like reference numerals, but preceded by the number &ldquo;3&rdquo;. In particular, holes or fenestrations <highlight><bold>385</bold></highlight> may be formed through the distal anterior wall of the body member <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of the oral airway in order to provide ventilation should the distal end portion <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> be positioned directly over the glottic opening of the patient, as might occur if the practitioner has selected too large of an oral airway for a particular patient, or where the patient has an abnormally high (rostrally) placed glottic opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Moreover, holes <highlight><bold>380</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>381</bold></highlight> may be formed through the anterior surface of the elongated extension walls <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>341</bold></highlight>, respectively, and which function to allow ventilation should the oral airway be situated at an abnormal angle such that one of the elongated extension walls covers the glottis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Still further, additional air holes or fenestrations <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight> may be formed through the posterior wall <highlight><bold>395</bold></highlight> of the body member <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of the oral airway at the region of curvature which is adapted to be positioned at the back of the oropharynx and which allows passage of air through the nasal passages of the patient and into the oral airway per se. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Of course, while the holes and fenestrations are shown in connection with the first embodiment of the present invention which includes the elongated extension walls <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>341</bold></highlight>, the holes or fenestrations may likewise be used with the second embodiment which includes the filled-in distal posterior wall. Of course, the holes can be dispensed with entirely in both the first and second embodiments if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the anterior and posterior U- or V-shaped grooves or notches receive an endotracheal tube E. When a patient is presently intubated with the endotracheal tube E, the body member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can receive a proximal end of the endotracheal tube and be axially inserted into the mouth and pharynx of a patient over the endotracheal tube and seated as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. When intubation is no longer required, the endotracheal tube E can be removed and body member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is properly seated to retain the surrounding soft tissue and maintain an oral airway as may be necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows yet a further embodiment which includes an inflatable cuff <highlight><bold>415</bold></highlight> placed just above the distally positioned anterior notch <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> further includes a plurality of bars <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight> forming a grate over the leading opening <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight>. Again, like elements are denoted with like reference numerals, but preceded with the number &ldquo;4&rdquo;. The grate or bars <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight> cause the epiglottis to slide into abutment with an anterior portion of the end portion <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> of the body member <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. As discussed below with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the bars are rigid enough to support the epiglottis but flexible enough to allow an endotracheal tube to be inserted therebetween. The cuff <highlight><bold>415</bold></highlight> is designed to be inflatable using a pilot tube <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> which includes a self-sealing proximal valve (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Upon inflation, the more distally positioned inflated cuff of the present invention is located within the hypopharynx and thereby allows the perilaryngeal oral airway of the present invention to be held in place without external means and avoids the airway leakage which can occur at the base of the tonsillar pillars and soft palate when using the conventional cuffed oro-pharyngeal airway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, in order to allow the cuffed airway <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to be attached to an anesthesia circuit or other airway circuit, an adapter <highlight><bold>425</bold></highlight> is inserted into the flanged proximal end portion <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> of the oral airway. In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, the adapter <highlight><bold>425</bold></highlight> is placed inside the flanged proximal end portion <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> of the oral airway <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> and held in by means of friction. However, many other mechanisms (e.g., Luer-lock, notched, snap, etc.) may be utilized to retain the adapter <highlight><bold>425</bold></highlight> in the proximal end <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> of the oral airway. Alternatively, the adapter may be made so as to fit over the end of the perilaryngeal oral airway and still accomplish the desired purpose. Of course, the proximal end piece for permitting attachment to an anesthesia circuit or other airway circuit may be molded into the oral airway itself. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> With respect to all of the above-discussed embodiments, the actual lumen or hollow portion of the perilaryngeal oral airway of the present invention may be dome-shaped (convex) at the posterior wall of the body member at least through the portion which is operative to be positioned within the patient&apos;s mouth in order to better approximate the anatomy of the oral passageway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Moreover, as an alternative, the oral airway may terminate in the hypopharynx (below the base of the tongue) but still end above the epiglottis, so that it would function to hold soft tissues away from the air passageway. A further embodiment of this particular alternative might have both the anterior and posterior notch absent since it could terminate just above the epiglottis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9, 10</cross-reference>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> relate to another embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway according to the present invention. Note that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14 and 15</cross-reference> as well as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, like elements are denoted with like reference numerals with reference to the patient&apos;s oral airway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The embodiment of the perilaryngeal oral airway illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> will be referred to herein as the grated oral airway or the grated PLA <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. The grated PLA <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> consists of an elongate tubular member <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> having a proximal end <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> and a distal end <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>. Attached to the distal end <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> of the elongate tubular member <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> is a wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. The wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> has an anterior wall <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>, a posterior wall <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> and sidewalls <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> extending therebetween. The anterior wall abuts an anterior portion of a patient&apos;s hypopharynx and the posterior position abuts a posterior portion of patient&apos;s hypopharynx when seated as illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. As best viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, the anterior and posterior walls <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> form an enlarged proximal portion <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> of the wedge-shaped housing which tapers to a smaller distal portion <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight>. The housing is sized to seat deep in the patient&apos;s hypopharynx. The leading opening <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> separates the anterior and posterior walls from the distal end of the housing and extends from the distal end of the posterior wall <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> to a recess in the anterior wall at <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the opening <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> is inclined between the distal end of the posterior wall and the recess <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> in the anterior wall. A grate <highlight><bold>537</bold></highlight> covers the leading opening, with the grate being inclined between the posterior and the anterior walls. In the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the grate comprises a plurality of parallel bars <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight> separated by a plurality of gaps <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> extending between the posterior wall <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> and anterior wall <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The grated PLA <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> including the elongate tubular member and the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> may be integrally formed in a single manufacturing step from polyvinyl chloride or another suitable thermoplastic. In the preferred embodiment, however, the wedge-shaped housing is manufactured in two pieces divided substantially along the line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, internal supports <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight> are integrally formed with each position of the housing and define circular orifices <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight> that receive the distal end of the elongate tubular member <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> therein. The elongate tubular member is heat staked, sonic welded or otherwise permanently bonded to the housing. In the embodiments illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the tubular member is shown as having a round cross-section, although the tubular member may have a number of cross-sectional configurations including oval, square or rectangular, provided the elongate tubular member includes a hollow lumen. The tubular member can be slightly contoured as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> or straight. The tubular member is preferably made of a material such as polyvinyl chloride or other thermoplastic that is substantially axially rigid yet radially flexible so that when inserted within the mouth, oral cavity and pharynx of a patient, it may follow the anatomical contours. It is also preferably sufficiently flexible so that a surgeon operating on the oral cavity or pharynx with the grated PLA in place can axially deflect the tubular member out of the operating theater. The tubular member further is radially robust to not kink during insertion or manipulation. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, the tubular member may include wire reinforcing <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight> wound into its wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> further includes an inflatable cuff <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight> that surrounds the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> radially about the enlarged proximal portion <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> of the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>, the inflatable cuff <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight> extends both proximal and distal of the largest effective diameter of the enlarged proximal portion <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the inflatable cuff <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight> may be located on the tubular member proximate the proximal end of the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> as illustrated with the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. A pilot tube <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> extends from the cuff along the elongate tubular member so as to be able to extend out of the mouth of a patient and terminates at its proximal end with a self-sealing proximal valve <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight>. With the cuff in its uninflated state, it closely envelops the exterior surface of the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. When in its inflated state, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, the cuff extends radially sufficiently to fully occlude the surrounding pharynx or hypopharynx so as to enable a practitioner to apply positive pressure ventilation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The grated PLA <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> preferably further includes a temperature sensor <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> shown mounted to the anterior wall <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> of the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. Alternatively, the temperature sensor <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> can be located on one of the sidewalls <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight>, the posterior wall <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> or even on the inflatable cuff <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight>. The temperature sensor <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> is connected to a lead <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> which extends along the length of the elongate tubular member <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> coupling to an external display or monitor (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> At the proximal end <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> of the elongate tubular member is a bite block <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> having a flanged end <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight>. The bite block <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> can be integrally formed from a thickened side of the tubular member <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> or be a more rigid plastic or metal collar that is slid over the proximal end <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> and held in place by friction or an adhesive. In addition, an adaptor <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> may be placed inside the flanged end <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight> of the bite block <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> and may be permanently affixed or releasably held in place by means of friction or other mechanisms such as a Luer-lock, notch, snap or the like. It may also be integrally formed with the bite block <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> in a single manufacturing step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates an alternate embodiment of the wedge-shaped housing referred to herein as the hinged grated PLA <highlight><bold>566</bold></highlight>. This embodiment is identical to that described above with regard to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference> except the grate <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> is attached only to the anterior wall <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> by a hinge <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>. By virtue of the hinge, the grate <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> can be pivoted open as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the hinged grate <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight> has a plurality of vertically extending bars <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, the hinged grate can be a solid flap with a plurality of holes <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> therein. Although not shown, the grate could also be a solid flap as opposed to a perforated grate. The hinge <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight> can be a separate structure joining the grate <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> onto the anterior wall <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> or a living hinge, under which circumstances the anterior wall <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> and the grate <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> are integrally formed in a single manufacturing step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a simplified anatomical cross-section of a patient&apos;s head and neck with the various anatomic features indicated by the same references numbers used with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Additional relevant anatomic features include the vocal chords <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the glottis or larynx generally indicated at <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The various cartilage and muscular tissue comprising the glottis or larynx, with the exception of the vocal chords <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, has been eliminated for the sake of clarity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> In use, the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> of the grated PLA <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> is axially inserted in the mouth <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of a patient and the elongated tubular member <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> bends to conform to the anatomical contours of the oral cavity <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, pharynx <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A, hypopharynx <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> so that the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> rests within the hypopharynx as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. The housing is made of a material that is flexible and soft to provide some give as it is inserted into a patient so as to prevent damage to the soft tissue of the pharynx and hypopharynx. However, the housing is sufficiently rigid to prevent its collapse by this same tissue as it is inserted into and seated within a patient. Likewise, the grate must be of sufficient rigidity to separate these tissues and to allow the epiglottis to ride up it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The grate <highlight><bold>537</bold></highlight> is inclined so that as the grate encounters the epiglottis <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the epiglottis rides up the grate and comes to rest abutting the anterior wall <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> of the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. More particularly, as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, the epiglottis abuts the inflatable cuff <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight>. The axial insertion of the wedge-shaped housing is intended to be arrested by the sidewalls of the enlarged proximal portion <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> coming into abutment with the aryepiglottic folds <highlight><bold>576</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>. As illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, with the grated PLA <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> or the hinged grated PLA <highlight><bold>566</bold></highlight> properly seated, the epiglottis abuts the anterior wall of the wedge-shaped housing and the leading opening <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> is adjacent to the vocal chords <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the glottis or larynx <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. In addition, the distal end of the housing may abut the tissue <highlight><bold>578</bold></highlight> dividing the trachea <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and esophagus <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. In this manner, all the soft tissue surrounding the hypopharynx an larynx is held back from the leading opening <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> and an unobstructed airway is provided to the trachea <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> for unassisted patient breathing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The PLA illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> can also be used to provide respiratory assist or anesthesia of a patient. In this application, once the PLA is seated as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, the inflatable cuff <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight> is inflated so as to form a seal in the patient&apos;s hypopharynx <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. In fact, the cuff is shown so inflated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. A principle advantage of placing the cuff at the enlarged portion of the housing is less air is required to inflate it to occlude the pharynx. Also, by having the cuff on the housing as it inflates it further serves to spread tissue and keep the airway formed by the PLA open. A respiratory circuit or anesthesia circuit (not shown), as conditions require, is attached to the distal end of the elongate tubular member by the adaptor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The grated PLA <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> is also intended to allow blind intubation of a patient with an endotracheal tube <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> having an inflatable cuff <highlight><bold>582</bold></highlight> or to insert some other instrument into the trachea of a patient. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the bars <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight> of the grate <highlight><bold>537</bold></highlight> are flexible enough so that an endotracheal tube can be inserted into a gap <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> between adjacent bars and deform the bars as shown at <highlight><bold>584</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> to extend axially therebetween. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, the distal end <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> of the tubular member <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> is received with in the housing so that as the endotracheal tube <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> is axially advanced through the bars <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight> of the grate <highlight><bold>537</bold></highlight>, it is directed anteriorly into the trachea <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of a patient. In this manner, a patient may be reliably blindly intubated with a high degree of confidence that the endotracheal tube will be properly seated in the trachea. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> illustrates the hinged grate embodiment <highlight><bold>566</bold></highlight> of the wedge-shaped housing <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> being used to intubate a patient with a endotracheal tube <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, as the endotracheal tube <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> is axially advanced into contact with the hinged grate <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> it pivots the hinged grate open anteriorly so that the endotracheal tube <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> can extend into the patient&apos;s trachea <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> as illustrated. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An oral airway comprising: 
<claim-text>an elongate tubular member having a distal end and a proximal end, the oral airway being configured to place the distal end in a supraglottic position when operatively placed within a patient; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a temperature sensor operatively associated with the elongate tubular member, the temperature sensor being positioned on the elongate tubular member to detect a core temperature of a patient with the distal end of the oral airway operatively placed in a supraglottic position within the patient. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the temperature sensor is positioned on the elongate tubular member to contact an internal mucosal surface of the hypopharynx with the distal end of the oral airway operatively placed a supraglottic position within the hypopharynx of the patient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the temperature sensor is coupled to an external display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the elongate tubular member comprises an enlarged housing at the distal end of the elongate tubular member, the temperature sensor being positioned on the enlarged housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the enlarged housing is wedge-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the wedge-shaped housing comprises anterior and posterior walls forming an enlarged proximal portion tapering to a smaller distal portion and side walls extending between the anterior and posterior walls, the wedge-shaped housing being configured so that the side walls abut the aryepiglottic folds with wedge-shaped housing operatively placed within the hypopharynx of a patient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the temperature sensor is attached to the wedge-shaped housing so that with the wedge-shaped housing operatively placed within the hypopharynx of a patient, the temperature sensor contacts a mucosal surface within the patient&apos;s hypopharynx. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method of delivering air to a patient comprising: 
<claim-text>providing an oral airway having a distal end and a proximal end with an air delivery opening near the distal end and a temperature sensor attached to the oral airway near the distal end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting the distal end into the mouth of the patient; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>seating the distal end in a supraglottic operative position within the patient with the opening adjacent the glottis and the temperature sensor contacting a mucosal surface within the patient&apos;s hypopharynx. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the oral airway comprises an elongate tubular member having an enlarged wedge-shaped housing at its distal end, the wedge-shaped housing having anterior and posterior walls forming an enlarged proximal portion tapering to a smaller distal portion, the method further comprising seating the distal end in a supraglottic operative position with a leading surface of the enlarged proximal portion abutting the patient&apos;s aryepiglottic folds. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising monitoring the patient&apos;s core temperature using the temperature sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the temperature sensor is spaced from the air delivery opening a distance sufficient to prevent air delivered from the air delivery opening from degrading the accuracy of a core temperature sensed by the temperature sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An oral airway comprising: 
<claim-text>an elongate tubular member having a leading distal end and a proximal end, the leading distal end leading the tubular member as it is inserted into the mouth and pharynx of a patient, there being an opening at the leading distal end that is inclined so that a posterior portion of the distal end extends beyond an anterior portion of the distal end; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a temperature sensor attached to the elongate tubular member, the temperature sensor being positioned on the elongate tubular member to detect a core temperature of a patient with the distal end of the oral airway in a supraglottic operative position within the hypopharynx of a patient. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a grate covering the opening, the grate being configured so that as a patient&apos;s epiglottis is engaged by the grate during insertion of the distal end into the hypopharynx, the epiglottis slides up the grate and into abutment with an anterior portion of the tubular member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the temperature sensor is positioned on the elongate tubular member to contact an internal mucosal surface of the hypopharynx with the distal end of the oral airway in a supraglottic operative position within the hypopharynx of a patient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The oral airway of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an inflatable cuff on the tubular member near the distal end, the temperature sensor being attached to the inflatable cuff so that with the distal end in the operative position within the hypopharynx and the cuff in an inflated state, the temperature sensor contacts an internal mucosal surface of the patient.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030000534A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
