<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002371A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002371A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002371</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10094611</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020312</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-38032</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11C007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>203000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Auto precharge apparatus having autoprecharge gapless function protecting circuit in semiconductor memory device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Seok Cheol</given-name>
<family-name>Yoon</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chungchongbuk-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JACOBSON HOLMAN</name-1>
<name-2>PROFESSIONAL LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANY</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>400 SEVENTH STREET, N.W.</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An auto precharge apparatus having an auto precharge gapless function protecting circuit in a semiconductor memory device which can prevent an externally-inputted illegal command from being executed, by disabling a row active peri signal earlier than a row active core signal in an auto precharge operation. The auto precharge apparatus includes: an internal cas command signal generator for receiving a bank address and an external cas command signal, and generating an internal cas command signal; a burst length counter for receiving the internal cas command signal and a burst stop signal, and generating a burst end signal representative of an end of a burst operation; an auto precharge signal generator for receiving the burst end signal, the internal cas command signal, an auto precharge end signal and an external address, and generating an auto precharge peri signal and an auto precharge core signal; and an internal row active signal generator for receiving the auto precharge peri signal, the auto precharge core signal, a precharge signal and an externally-inputted row active signal, and generating a row active peri signal and a row active core signal. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an auto precharge apparatus for a semiconductor memory device, and in particular to an improved auto precharge apparatus having an auto precharge gapless function protecting circuit, which can prevent a mis-operation of the semiconductor memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In general, a semiconductor memory device performs its operations according to an input command (for example, write/read command, precharge command, refresh command, etc.). Here, an illegal command can be inputted as the input command. The semiconductor memory device should not respond to the illegal command. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> However, when a write/read command is inputted to the semiconductor memory device after an auto precharge operation, a chip is mis-operated due to absence of a circuit for protecting a gapless function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A conventional auto precharge apparatus for a semiconductor memory device will be explained in detail with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating the conventional autoprecharge apparatus, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a timing diagram of the major signals developed in the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the conventional auto precharge apparatus includes a burst length counter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, an auto precharge signal generator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and an internal row active signal generator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The conventional auto precharge apparatus performs a write/read operation, and then automatically disables a word line after waiting for tDPL (data_in to precharge latency) although a precharge command is not inputted. If the tDPL time is not compensated, data are not fully written on a cell, which may generate a defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> However, while the auto precharge apparatus waits for the tDPL, if an illegal command is inputted to a bank, a new operation in accordance with the illegal command is executed in a state where the word line is not disabled, thereby causing a mis-operation. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is a primary object of the present invention to prevent a mis-operation due to an illegal command externally inputted during an auto precharge operation, by separating a path for controlling a peri circuit unit from a path for controlling a core circuit unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to prevent an externally-inputted illegal command from being executed by disabling a row active peri signal for controlling a peri circuit unit earlier than a row active core signal for controlling a core circuit unit during an auto precharge operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve the above-described objects of the invention, there is provided an auto precharge apparatus having an auto precharge gapless function protecting circuit in a semiconductor memory device, including: an internal cas command signal generating means for receiving a bank address and an external cas command signal and generating an internal cas command signal; a burst length counter for receiving the internal cas command signal and a burst stop signal, and generating a burst end signal representative of an end of a burst operation; an auto precharge signal generating means for receiving the burst end signal, the internal cas command signal, an auto precharge end signal and an external address and generating an auto precharge peri signal and an auto precharge core signal; and an internal row active signal generating means for receiving the auto precharge peri signal, the auto precharge core signal, a precharge signal and an externally-inputted row active signal and generating a row active peri signal for enabling a word line and a row active core signal for disabling the word line. The internal cas command signal generating means receives the row active peri signal for enabling the word line and determines generation of the internal cas command signal.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention will become better understood with reference to the accompanying drawings which are given only by way of illustration and thus are not limitative of the present invention, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a conventional auto precharge apparatus for a semiconductor memory device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a timing diagram of the major signals of the conventional auto precharge apparatus for the semiconductor memory device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating an auto precharge apparatus having an auto precharge gapless function protecting circuit in a semiconductor memory device in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating an embodiment of the internal cas command signal generator in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating an embodiment of the burst length counter in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating an embodiment of the auto precharge signal generator in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating an embodiment of the internal row active signal generator in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a timing diagram of the major signals of the auto precharge apparatus for the semiconductor memory device in accordance with the preferred embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> An autoprecharge apparatus having an auto precharge gapless function protecting circuit in a semiconductor memory device in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating the auto precharge apparatus having the auto precharge gapless function protecting circuit in accordance with the preferred embodiment of the present invention. The auto precharge apparatus includes: an internal cas command signal generator <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a burst length counter <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, an auto precharge signal generator <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and an internal row active signal generator <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Here, the internal cas command signal generator <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> receives an externally-inputted bank address BA, a row active peri signal ROWACT_PE and an external cas command signal CASP&lt;i&gt;, and generates an internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0:3&gt; in response to the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE. The row active peri signal ROWACT_PE is generated in a row active peri signal generator <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> that will be discussed later. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The burst length counter <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> receives the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0:3&gt;, a refresh flag signal REF_FLAG indicating a refresh operation, a burst length end signal BL_END and a burst stop signal YBST_STOP, and generates a burst end signal YBST_END representative of an end of a burst operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The auto precharge signal generator <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> receives the burst end signal YBST_END, the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0:3&gt;, an auto precharge end signal APCG_END and an external address ADD&lt;10&gt;, and generates an auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE and an auto precharge core signal APCG_CO. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The internal row active signal generator <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> receives the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE, the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO, a precharge signal PCG, a row active signal ROWACT and a row active core signal ROWACT_CO, and generates the row active core signal ROWACT_CO for disabling a word line and the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE for enabling the word line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Here, the row active core signal ROWACT_CO is generated in response to the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO, and the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE is generated in response to the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The structure and operation of the internal cas command signal generator <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> will be explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, in the internal cas command signal generator <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> logically combines the externally-inputted bank address BA, the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE that will be discussed later and the external cas command signal CASP&lt;i&gt;. An inverter IV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> inverts an output signal from the NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and generates the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;i&gt;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> When the external cas command signal CASP&lt;i&gt; is generated as a high pulse, a write/read operation is performed on the semiconductor memory device. For example, when a bank <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is activated and a bank <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> performs an auto precharge operation, a gapless write/read operation must be executed not on the bank <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> but on the bank <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, when the burst operation is ended, the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE of the bank <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> performing the auto precharge operation is disabled. Then, the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;i&gt; is not generated and thus the write/read operation is not carried out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> However, when the cas command signal of the bank <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (write/read operation) is executed, the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE is enabled at a high level. Thus, the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;i&gt; is generated as a high pulse, and the write/read operation is performed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In order to prevent execution of the illegal command inputted to the bank performing the auto precharge operation, the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE controlling a peri circuit unit is disabled earlier than the row active core signal ROWACT_CO controlling a core circuit unit, and thus the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;i&gt; must be not generated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, the auto precharge apparatus for the semiconductor memory device does not execute the illegal command inputted to the bank performing the auto precharge operation by generating the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;i&gt; in response to the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The structure and operation of the burst length counter <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> will be explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating the burst length counter <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> including a burst enable signal generator <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and a burst end signal generator <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The burst enable signal generator <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> receives the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0:<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&gt;, the refresh flag signal REF_FLAG indicating the refresh operation, the burst length end signal BL_END and the burst stop signal YBST_STOP, and generates a burst enable signal YBST. A burst end signal generator <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> receives the burst enable signal YBST, and generates the burst end signal YBST_END representative of an end of the burst operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In the burst enable signal generator <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, a NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> logically combines the internal cas command signals CASI&lt;0:3&gt;. An inverter IV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> inverts the refresh flag signal REF_FLAG. An inverter IV<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> inverts an output signal from the NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> logically combines an output signal from an inverter IV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and an output signal from an inverter IV<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> logically combines the burst length end signal BL_END and the burst stop signal YBST_STOP. A NAND gate latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> latches output signals from the NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Inverters IV<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and IV<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> consecutively invert an output signal from the NAND gate latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and output the burst enable signal YBST. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The burst end signal generator <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> includes: a plurality of inverters IV<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-IV<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for consecutively inverting the burst enable signal YBST; and a NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> for NORing an output signal from the inverter IV<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the burst enable signal YBST, and generating the burst end signal YBST_END representative of an end of the burst operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> When the refresh operation is performed by generating the refresh flag signal REF_FLAG showing the refresh operation state as a high pulse, the word line is enabled to carry out the write/read operation. Therefore, in the case of the refresh operation, the refresh flag signal REF_FLAG is generated as a high pulse and the burst enable signal YBST is not generated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> When the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0&gt; is generated as a high pulse, the refresh flag signal REF_FLAG, the burst length end signal BL_END and the burst stop signal YBST_STOP become at a low level. Then an output signal of the NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> becomes at a low level, and an output signal of the NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> becomes at a high level. Then, an output signal of the NAND gate latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> becomes at a high level, and thus the burst enable signal YBST becomes at a high level. Here, the NAND gate latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> maintains a high level. When the burst length end signal BL_END (signal generated after finishing the normal burst operation) or the burst stop signal YBST_STOP (signal forcibly stopping the burst operation when the normal burst operation is not finished) is generated as a high pulse, the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0:3&gt; and the refresh flag signal REF_FLAG are at a low level. Then, an output signal of the NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> becomes at a high level, and an output signal of the NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> becomes at a low level. Then, an output signal of the NAND gate latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> becomes at a low level, and thus the burst enable signal YBST becomes at a low level. When the burst enable signal YBST becomes at a low level, the burst end signal YBST_END becomes at a high pulse and immediately becomes at a low level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The auto precharge signal generator <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating the auto precharge signal generator <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> including an auto precharge peri signal generator <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and an auto precharge core signal generator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The auto precharge peri signal generator <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> receives the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0&gt;, the external address ADD&lt;10&gt; and the auto precharge end signal APCG_END, and generates the auto precharge flag signal APCG_FLAG representative of the auto precharge operation. Then it generates the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE by combining the auto precharge flag signal APCG_FLAG and the burst end signal YBST_END. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The auto precharge core signal generator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> receives the internal cas command signal CAS&lt;1:3&gt;, the auto precharge flag signal APCG_FLAG and the burst end signal YBST_END, and generates the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In addition, the auto precharge peri signal generator <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> generates the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE to perform the precharge operation before an input of the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0:3&gt;. The auto precharge core signal generator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> compensates for the tDPL (data precharge latency), and then generates the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO to perform the precharge operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In auto precharge core signal generator <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, an auto precharge flag signal generator <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> receives the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0&gt;, the external address ADD&lt;10&gt; and the auto precharge end signal APCG_END, and generates the auto precharge flag signal APCG_FLAG representative of the auto precharge operation. An NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> logically combines the auto precharge flag signal APCG_FLAG and an output signal from an inverter IV<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The inverter IV<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> inverts the burst end signal YBST_END. An inverter IV<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> inverts an output signal from the NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and generates the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In auto precharge flag signal generator <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, an inverter IV<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> inverts the external address ADD&lt;10&gt;. An NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> logically combines the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0&gt; and an output signal from an inverter. A PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has its source and drain respectively connected to a power supply voltage Vdd and a node SN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and has its gate connected to receive an output signal from the NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are connected between the node SN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a ground voltage Vss, and their gates connected respectively to receive the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0&gt; and the external address ADD&lt;10&gt;. A PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has its source and drain respectively connected to the power supply voltage Vdd and the node SN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and its gate connected to receive the auto precharge end signal APCG_END. An inverter latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> latches a signal from the node SN<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and generates the auto precharge flag signal APCG_FLAG. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In auto precharge core signal generator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, a NOR gate logically combines the internal cas command signals CAS&lt;1:3&gt;. An inverter IV<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> inverts the burst end signal YBST_END. A NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> logically combines an output signal from the NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and an output signal from an inverter IV<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> logically combines an output signal from the NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the auto precharge flag signal APCG_FLAG. A tDPL compensator <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> compensates for the tDPL by delaying an output signal from the NAND gate ND<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> for a predetermined time, and generates the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO. The tDPL compensator <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of inverters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The operation of the auto precharge peri signal generator <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and the auto precharge core signal generator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> will be explained in brief. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In order to perform the auto precharge operation, the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;0&gt; and the external address ADD&lt;10&gt; must be transited to high pulse. Here, the auto precharge flag signal APCG_FLAG becomes a high pulse (prepared to generate the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE and the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO). Thereafter, when the burst end signal YBST_END becomes a high pulse, the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE becomes a low pulse, and the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO compensates for the tDPL and becomes a high pulse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The structure of the internal row active signal generator <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> will be explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram illustrating the internal row active signal generator <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> including a row active core signal generator <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and a row active peri signal generator <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The row active core signal generator <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> receives the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO and the precharge signal PCG, and generates the row active core signal ROWACT_CO for disabling the word line. The row active peri signal generator <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> receives an inverted signal of the row active core signal ROWACT_CO, the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE, and the external row active signal ROWACT, and generates the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE for enabling the word line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In row active core signal generator <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, a NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> logically combines the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO and the precharge signal PCG. An NAND gate latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> latches an output signal from the NOR gate NR<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and an output signal from an inverter IV<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An inverter IV<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> inverts an output signal from the NAND gate latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and generates the row active core signal ROWACT_CO disabling the word line. An inverter IV<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> inverts the row active core signal ROWACT_CO. The inverter IV<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> inverts an output signal from the inverter IV<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In row active peri signal generator <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are connected between the power supply voltage Vdd and the ground voltage Vss, and has their gates connected to receive the output signal from the inverter IV <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and the externally-inputted row active signal ROWACT. A PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> has its source and drain respectively connected to the power supply voltage Vdd and a node SN<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and has its gate connected to receive the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE. An inverter latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> latches a signal from the node SN<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Inverters IV<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and IV<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> consecutively invert an output signal from the inverter latch circuit LT<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and output the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE enabling the word line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The operation of the row active core signal generator <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and the row active peri signal generator <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> will be explained in brief. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> When the auto precharge peri signal APCG_PE is generated as a low pulse, the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE is disabled in a low level. That is, the internal cas command signal CASI&lt;i&gt; shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is not generated, and thus the newly-inputted illegal command is not executed, to protect the auto precharge gapless function. Thereafter, the row active core signal ROWACT_CO compensates for the tDPL in response to the row active signal ROWACT having a high level. Then, when the auto precharge core signal APCG_CO is generated as a high pulse, the row active core signal ROWACT_CO is disabled in a low level. When the row active core signal ROWACT_CO is disabled in a low level, the word line is disabled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a timing diagram of the major signals of the auto precharge apparatus for the semiconductor memory device in accordance with the preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE is disabled in a low level earlier than the conventional one by a period A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As discussed earlier, in accordance with the present invention, the row active peri signal ROWACT_PE controlling the peri circuit unit is disabled earlier than the row active core signal ROWACT_CO controlling the core circuit unit in the auto precharge operation. Even if an illegal command is externally inputted, the illegal command is not executed to prevent a mis-operation of the semiconductor memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been shown and described with reference to certain preferred embodiments thereof, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes, modifications, substitutions and addition in form and details may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An auto precharge apparatus having an auto precharge gapless function protecting circuit in a semiconductor memory device, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an internal cas command signal generating means for receiving a bank address and an external cas command signal, and generating an internal cas command signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a burst length counter for receiving the internal cas command signal and a burst stop signal, and generating a burst end signal representative of an end of a burst operation; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an auto precharge signal generating means for receiving the burst end signal, the internal cas command signal, an auto precharge end signal and an external address, and generating an auto precharge peri signal and an auto precharge core signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an internal row active signal generating means for receiving the auto precharge peri signal, the auto precharge core signal, and an externally-inputted row active signal, and generating a row active peri signal for enabling a word line and a row active core signal for disabling the word line, 
<claim-text>wherein the internal cas command signal generating means determines the generation of the internal cas command signal in response to the row active peri signal for enabling the word line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the internal cas command signal generating means does not generate the internal cas command signal when the row active peri signal is disabled at a low level, and generates the internal cas command signal when the row active peri signal is enabled at a high level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the internal cas command signal generating means comprises a logic circuit for logically-combining the bank address, the external cas command signal and the row active peri signal, and generating the internal cas command signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the burst length counter comprises: 
<claim-text>a burst enable signal generator for receiving the internal cas command signal generated in the internal cas command signal generating means, a refresh flag signal, a burst length end signal and the burst stop signal and then generating a burst enable signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a burst end signal generator for receiving the burst enable signal, and generating the burst end signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the auto precharge signal generating means comprises: 
<claim-text>an auto precharge peri signal generator for generating an auto precharge flag signal representative of an auto precharge operation by receiving the internal cas command signal, the external address and the auto precharge end signal, and then generating the auto precharge peri signal by combining the auto precharge flag signal and the burst end signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an auto precharge core signal generator for receiving the auto precharge flag signal, the burst end signal and the internal cas command signal, and generating the auto precharge core signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the auto precharge peri signal generator generates the auto precharge peri signal so that the precharge operation can be performed before an input of the internal cas command signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the auto precharge peri signal generator comprises: 
<claim-text>an auto precharge flag signal generator for receiving the internal cas command signal, the external address and the auto precharge end signal, and generating an auto precharge flag signal representative of the autoprecharge operation; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a logic circuit for logic-combining the auto precharge flag signal and an inverted signal of the burst end signal, and generating the auto precharge peri signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the auto precharge core signal generator generates the auto precharge core signal so that the precharge operation can be performed after compensating for a data precharge latency time. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the auto precharge core signal generator comprises: 
<claim-text>a first logic device for logically-combining a part of the internal cas command signals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second logic device for logically-combining an inverted signal of the burst end signal and an output signal from the first logic device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third logic device for logically-combining the auto precharge flag signal and an output signal from the second logic device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a data precharge latency time compensator for compensating for the data precharge latency time by delaying an output signal from the third logic device for a predetermined time, and generating the auto precharge core signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the internal row active signal generating means comprises: 
<claim-text>a row active core signal generator for generating the row active core signal for disabling the word line in response to the auto precharge core signal and a precharge signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a row active peri signal generator for generating the row active peri signal for enabling the word line in response to the row active core signal, the auto precharge peri signal and the externally-inputted row active signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, the row active core signal generator disables the word line by disabling the row active core signal at a low level, when the auto precharge core signal is generated as a high pulse. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the row active core signal generator comprises: 
<claim-text>a logic device for logic-combining the auto precharge core signal and the precharge signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a latch circuit for latching an output signal from the logic device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first inverting device for inverting an output signal from the latch circuit, and outputting the row active core signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of second inverting units for inverting an output signal from the first inverting unit, and transmitting a resulting signal to the latch circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, the row active peri signal generator does not execute a newly-inputted illegal command by disabling the row active peri signal at a low level, when the auto precharge peri signal is generated as a low pulse. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the row active peri signal generator comprises: 
<claim-text>pull-up and pull-down devices connected between a power supply voltage and a ground voltage, for responding to an inverted signal of the row active core signal and the external row active signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transistor connected between the power supply voltage and an output node, for responding to the auto precharge peri signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a latch circuit for latching a signal of the output node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of inverters for consecutively inverting an output signal from the latch circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002371A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
