<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003744A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003744A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003744A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003744A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003744A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003744A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003744A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003744A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003744A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003744A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003744</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10187766</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>101 31 940.1</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/302</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>690000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Semiconductor chip configuration and fabrication method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gerd</given-name>
<family-name>Frankowsky</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Hohenkirchen-Siegertsbrunn</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>LERNER AND GREENBERG, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Post Office Box 2480</address-1>
<city>Hollywood</city>
<state>FL</state>
<postalcode>33022-2480</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In a semiconductor chip, conductive tracks run in a rewiring layer from contact pads to contact elevations. The contact pads are formed as vias. The conductive tracks are constructed in sections as bottom electrodes of trimming capacitors. The top electrode of the trimming capacitors is formed by a metal plane of the rewiring layer. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention lies in the semiconductor technology field. More specifically, the invention relates to a semiconductor chip configuration with a substrate on which a layer sequence is constructed with functional elements that can be contacted by way of contact pads, whereby conductive tracks run in a rewiring layer from the pads to contact elevations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The invention further relates to a method for constructing contacts on a semiconductor chip configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Owing to the contact elevations, such semiconductor chips can be mounted directly on PCBs. The contact elevations contact the contacts on the PCB. Accordingly, the spacings between the contact elevations are selected so that they correspond to the spacings between the contacts on the PCB. On the semiconductor chip side, the contact elevations are connected in a rewiring layer to contact points (pads), which are connected to the functional elements in the layer sequence. Each conductive track leads from a respective contact elevation to a respective pad. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The pads are usually designed such that they are suitable for bonding and contacting with test cards which are equipped with pins. The contact pads consequently occupy a relatively large area of some 90 &mgr;m&times;90 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In addition, trimming capacitors are arranged under the pads in the semiconductor chip, which serve to adapt the capacity of the pads to the prescribed specifications. A plurality of trimming capacitors are usually provided. The values for the capacity are adjusted by replacing the mask for a metal layer in a specified lithography step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Conventional pads require an appreciable proportion of chip space. In addition, the trimming of the capacitors is difficult and is no longer possible after fabrication. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is accordingly an object of the invention to provide a semiconductor chip configuration and a corresponding fabrication method, which overcomes the above-mentioned disadvantages of the heretofore-known devices and methods of this general type and which provides for an improved semiconductor chip configuration and an improved method for constructing contacts on it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> With the foregoing and other objects in view there is provided, in accordance with the invention, a semiconductor chip configuration, comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> a substrate carrying a layer sequence with electronic functional elements and including a rewiring layer on the substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> contact pads formed as vias connected to the functional elements; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> contact elevations; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> conductive tracks extending in the rewiring layer from the contact pads to the contact elevations; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> each of the conductive tracks widening in a portion remote from the respective the via to form a bottom electrode of a respective capacitor to which the via is connected; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> the capacitor further including an insulation layer arranged over the bottom electrode, and a top electrode above the insulation layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an added feature of the invention, the insulation layer and the bottom electrode are disposed between the substrate and the top electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an additional feature of the invention, the top electrodes of the capacitors form a contiguous metal layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another feature of the invention, the top electrodes of the capacitors of the semiconductor chip configuration are connected to a common contact elevation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> With the above and other objects in view there is also provided, in accordance with the invention, a method of producing contacts in a semiconductor chip configuration, which comprises: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> constructing electronic functional elements on a substrate; forming vias for contacting the electronic functional elements; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> constructing conductive tracks in a rewiring layer connected to the vias, and connecting the conductive tracks to capacitors remote from the vias; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> wherein the conductive tracks are widened into a widened portion to form a respective bottom electrode of the capacitors, and an insulation layer is formed over the respective widened portions of the conductive tracks, and a top electrode is formed thereabove. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Because the pads are constructed as vias, they occupy a negligible proportion of chip space, namely 0.005%, as opposed to 0.6% in the prior art. Furthermore, the trimming capacitors are no longer located in the functional layers or in the wiring layers within the chip which adjoin the functional layers; rather, they are located in the rewiring planes over the functional layers, and consequently additional space is opened up in the underlying wiring planes and functional planes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the invention, the capacitors that are allocated to the conductive tracks are constructed such that an electrode of the capacitors is positioned on the surface of the semiconductor chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The advantage of this configuration is that the electrode on the surface of the semiconductor chip can be post-trimmed. In other words, the top electrodes can configured to respectively adapt the capacitor to a predetermined capacitance value. Specifically, the capacitors can be trimmed subsequent to a function test of the functional elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Other features which are considered as characteristic for the invention are set forth in the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Although the invention is illustrated and described herein as embodied in a semiconductor chip configuration and a fabrication method, it is nevertheless not intended to be limited to the details shown, since various modifications and structural changes may be made therein without departing from the spirit of the invention and within the scope and range of equivalents of the claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The construction and method of operation of the invention, however, together with additional objects and advantages thereof will be best understood from the following description of specific embodiments when read in connection with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a contact side of a semiconductor chip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a plan view of the contact side from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> with the conductive tracks known from the prior art; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective representation of the pads that are known from the prior art; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block circuit diagram of the prior art pads; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the pads with the conductive tracks connected to them; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a block circuit diagram of the pads according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an exemplary embodiment of the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a plan view of the contact side of a semiconductor chip according to the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the figures of the drawing in detail and first, particularly, to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> thereof, there is shown a perspective view of a contact side <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of a semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on whose contact side <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In the present case, the contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are shaped approximately like truncated cones. The contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are arranged over an insulation layer <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which is located on a rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is above functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, which are disposed on a substrate <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in turn. The substrate <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are disposed in a common semiconductor body. The rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is an additional layer which is separate from the semiconductor body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> represents a plan view of the rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> underneath the insulation layer <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. In the rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, conductive tracks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> lead from contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The functional elements such as transistors, capacitors or resistors which are constructed in the functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be contacted by way of the pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The placement of the contact pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is predetermined by the placement of the functional elements in the functional layer <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and is not completely freely selectable. Fastening the semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on a PCB often requires contacts in a different configuration than that of the pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The pads are therefore connected at the contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, whose placement corresponds to the placement of contacts on the PCBs, with the aid of conductive tracks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> represents a perspective view of conventional prior art pads. As described above, the pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are connected to the contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> with the aid of conductive tracks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. At the center of the pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are vias <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, by means of which a connection <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is produced between the pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> arranged on the level of the rewiring layer and the functional elements below these on the level of the functional layer <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The term via or via hole refers to a through hole from one layer plane to another layer plane above or below the former. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are also connected to the pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> represents one of the trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, specifically its two electrodes <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. According to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> plurality of the trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are connected in parallel fashion. The trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> serve for setting the capacity values of the contact pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, the conductive track <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, and the contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in accordance with the specifications for the semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In order to connect the trimming capacitor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to or separate it from the pad <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, exposure masks for structuring a metal layer in the functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> must be so selected in a lithography step that bridges <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are set up according to the desired capacity values. The capacitors are located under the contact pads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> further illustrates a drive circuit <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> as an example of the functional elements in the functional layer <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The disadvantage of conventionally constructed pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is that they occupy a significant proportion of chip space. The space taken up by the pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is lost to the functional elements in the functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Besides this, it is expensive and complicated to set up the bridges <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> with the aid of the exposure masks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, the pads <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are constructed as vias <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The conductive track leads from these pads <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to the contact elevations as in the prior art. For trimming the capacity of the pads <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the conductive tracks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, and the contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> which are connected to the track <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are provided in the rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. For the sake of simplicity, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> includes only a single trimming capacitor <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> with its two electrodes <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> It is advantageous to construct the trimming capacitors in the rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, because the vias <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> occupy a negligible proportion of chip space in the functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. In the case of an SDRAM memory chip with 256 Mbits of memory (256M SDRAM), the conventional pads <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> take up approx. 0.6% of the total chip area. The same amount of vias <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> requires only 0.005% of the chip area. Given their small space requirement, the vias <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> can be arranged wherever they are needed in the functional layer <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Greater freedom in designing the functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is thus created when the contact pads <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are constructed as vias <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can also still be set or trimmed to the required capacity values during testing. For instance, laser trimming can be applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> This specific case is represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. In this exemplary embodiment, the conductive track <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is widened in sections into a bottom electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which is separated from a top electrode <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by an insulation layer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The top electrode <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is located directly below the insulation layer <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, so that the electrodes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can still be processed after the rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has been produced. This is advantageous particularly when the capacity values of the trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> must still be modified after the actual semiconductor chip <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is finished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Expediently, the top electrodes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> represent portions of a metal plane of the rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> as represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> represents various planes of the rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> from above. It is evident that the top electrodes <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> form a contiguous metal layer which is connected to one of the contact elevations <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Moving the trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> from the functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> into the rewiring layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> makes it possible to construct the contact pads <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> as vias <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. This produces greater flexibility in designing the functional layer. Furthermore, the trimming capacitors <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can be modified even after the functional layers <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are finished, for instance by trimming the top electrodes of the capacitors. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor chip configuration, comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate carrying a layer sequence with electronic functional elements and including a rewiring layer on said substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>contact pads formed as vias connected to said functional elements; </claim-text>
<claim-text>contact elevations; </claim-text>
<claim-text>conductive tracks extending in said rewiring layer from said contact pads to said contact elevations; </claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said conductive tracks widening in a portion remote from the respective said via to form a bottom electrode of a respective capacitor to which said via is connected; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said capacitor further including an insulation layer arranged over said bottom electrode, and a top electrode above said insulation layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor chip configuration according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said insulation layer and said bottom electrode are disposed between said substrate and said top electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor chip configuration according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said top electrodes of said capacitors form a contiguous metal layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor chip configuration according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said top electrodes of the capacitors of the semiconductor chip configuration are connected to a common contact elevation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method of producing contacts in a semiconductor chip configuration, which comprises: 
<claim-text>constructing electronic functional elements on a substrate; forming vias for contacting the electronic functional elements; </claim-text>
<claim-text>constructing conductive tracks in a rewiring layer connected to the vias, and connecting the conductive tracks to capacitors remote from the vias; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the conductive tracks are widened into a widened portion to form a respective bottom electrode of the capacitors, and an insulation layer is formed over the respective widened portions of the conductive tracks, and a top electrode is formed thereabove. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, which comprises trimming the top electrodes to respectively adapt the capacitor to a predetermined capacitance value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, which comprises trimming subsequent to a function test of the functional elements.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>7</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003744A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003744A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003744A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003744A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003744A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
