<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005192A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005192A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005192A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005192A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005192</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895506</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F013/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>710</class>
<subclass>104000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Self-extracting re-configurable interface used in modular electronic architecture</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Charles</given-name>
<middle-name>B.</middle-name>
<family-name>Swope</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Coral Springs</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>S.</middle-name>
<family-name>Mitrosky</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Margate</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Timothy</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Houston</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Plantation</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Frank M. Scutch, III</name-1>
<name-2>Motorola, Inc.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Law Department</address-1>
<address-2>8000 West Sunrise Boulevard</address-2>
<city>Fort Lauderdale</city>
<state>FL</state>
<postalcode>33322</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A re-configurable interface used in modular electronic architectures includes a host (<highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>) and one or more modules (<highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>) for interfacing with the host (<highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>) to provide additional functionality. A configuration controller (<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>) located in the host (<highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>) is for reading a memory device (<highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>) located in the module (<highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>) for providing configuration information to the host. The pin controller (<highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>) then is able to reconfigure pins of the host connector (<highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>) to communicate with the module (<highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates in general to configuration of modulator architectures and more specifically to re-configurable architectures in electronic systems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Many different types of electrical products today are modular and include one or more interface units to increase and/or enhance the operational characteristics of the product. These types of products generally have a dedicated type of interface module meaning the interface unit is specifically designed to be electrically integrated with a host device through the use of some type of electrical connector or the like. Each module must be designed such that the interface with be electrically compatible with the connector on the host device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> As seen in prior art <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the typical modular interface system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> would include a module <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> that may be a stand alone accessory device or similar interfacing with a host device <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The module <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> includes a module connector <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> that interfaces with a corresponding host connector <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> on the host device <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The module connector <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and host connector <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> connect through as dedicated serial interface <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>. The dedicated serial interface <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> connects one or more dedicated serial pins allowing the module <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> to communicate with the host device <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The remainder of the pins are configured to form a dedicated pin interface <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> in these connectors to provide communication and compatibility between the module <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and host device <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Any example of such an arrangement might be a remote control head used for a mobile public service radio. The control head communicates through the dedicated serial interface <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> while one or more additional pins are dedicated to other control or communications functions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The difficulty with this arrangement is that the dedicated pin interface <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> used for each module <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> cannot be reconfigured such that other modular or peripheral devices connected to the host <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> must now absolutely conform to the pin arrangement used by the host device in order to be compatible. This can lead to great difficulty since interface devices (not shown) must be configured between the module <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and host <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> in order for the module to interface properly and be fully functional. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Thus, the need exists to provide a re-configurable interface system that can self-extract module or accessory configuration information from a module or accessory interface enabling any interface module to electrically interface and/or communicate with a host device.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating the prior art interface system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating the self-extracting re-configurable interface used in modular electronic architectures according to the preferred embodiment of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> re-configurable interface system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> used in modular architectures according to the preferred embodiment of the invention includes a secondary module <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and primary host device <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. The secondary module <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> generally provides some increased functionality to the primary host device <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and connects through corresponding and/or mating connectors such as the module connector <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> and host connector <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>. The secondary module <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> may include a cable connected device or a modular type device physically integrated within an electrical connector. The pin configuration of host connector <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> is controlled by a pin controller <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. The pin controller <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> although generally controlled by a accompanying microprocessor <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> may also be integrated within a microprocessor device with portions of that device being appropriately programmed to control pin configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art will further recognize that any type of associated programmable logic can also provide the same function to microprocessor <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> and may also be used. The pin controller <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> would read configuration information or data from the memory device <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> through the dedicated pin interface <highlight><bold>217</bold></highlight>. Although a single memory device <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> is shown and described herein, any number of memory devices associated with the module <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In operation, the pin controller <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> receives pin configuration information, that is unique to each module <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>. The microprocessor <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> can work to interpret this configuration information to configure and/or electrically arrange the pins of the host connector <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> into any desired configuration in order to provide communications capability between devices. Generally, the pin interface <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight> will be in a dedicated state until initialization process. At this time, all of the pins of host connector <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> may be reconfigured to interface with any desired module device <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>. Additionally it should be noted that the pins providing voltage potential (B&plus;) (not shown) to the microprocessor <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> will also be dedicated, however these pins can also easily be reconfigured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> One example of such an arrangement might be an accessory that attaches to the host device such as a two-way radio. In accordance with the preferred embodiment of the invention, any fixed pin arrangement of the accessory would not be a hindrance since the host device <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> is able to reconfigure the pins on host connector <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> in order to accommodate and communicate with the accessory. It is the great benefit of this invention that all that is required to establish communication is for the host and module connectors to inter-connect in order to communicate. Thus, any module <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> having an associated memory device <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>, communicating configuration information to pin controller <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> can be compatible. This enables any type of module such as an accessory device to be used with the host device <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> without the need for constant &ldquo;hard&rdquo; wire interface compatibility. Moreover, no prior knowledge of connection information is required by software contained within the host <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> While the preferred embodiments of the invention have been illustrated and described, it will be clear that the invention is not so limited. Numerous modifications, changes, variations, substitutions and equivalents will occur to those skilled in the art without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention as defined by the appended claims. As used herein, the terms &ldquo;comprises,&rdquo; &ldquo;comprising,&rdquo; or any other variation thereof, are intended to cover a non-exclusive inclusion, such that a process, method, article, or apparatus that comprises a list of elements does not include only those elements but may include other elements not expressly listed or inherent to such process, method, article, or apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> What is claimed is: </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable interface used in modular electronic architectures comprising: 
<claim-text>a host; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one module for interfacing with the host to provide additional functionality to the host; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a configuration controller located in the host for reading at least one memory device located in the at least one module for providing configuration information to the host. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the configuration controller self-extracts the configuration information from the at least one memory device after interfacing with the at least one module with the host. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a dedicated serial interface for exchanging information from the at least one memory device to the configuration controller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including configurable logic operating with the configuration controller for configuring a host interface to operate with an at least one module interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a plurality of connector pins at the host and at least one module that are electrically configured using the configurable logic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a microprocessor for communicating with the configuration controller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable electronic interface system for providing communication between a primary host device and a secondary accessory device comprising: 
<claim-text>an interface controller including re-configurable logic associated with the primary host device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one memory device associated with the secondary accessory device for communicating configuration information to the interface controller; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the interface controller sets the re-configurable logic of the electronic interface based on information from the at least one memory device for allowing compatibility between the secondary accessory device and the primary host device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable electronic interface system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plurality of electrical interface pins for connecting the primary host device and the secondary accessory device are configured according to the re-configurable logic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable electronic interface system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the interface controller self-extracts the configuration information from the at least one memory device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable electronic interface system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the interface controller and at least one memory device communicate via a dedicated serial interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A re-configurable electronic interface system as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the interface controller communications with a microprocessor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method of reconfiguring an interface used in a modular electronic architecture between a primary host device and a secondary module device comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing an interface controller associated with the primary host device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>reading configuration information from at least one memory associated with the secondary module device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting configurable logic in the primary host device such that an electrical interface is established between the primary host device and the secondary module device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method of reconfiguring an interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>configuring a plurality of pins in the interface to provide capability between the primary host device and the secondary module device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method of reconfiguring an interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>self-extracting the configuration information from the at least one memory when the secondary module device is connected with the primary host device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method of reconfiguring an interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>communicating between the interface controller and the at least one memory via a dedicated serial interface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method of reconfiguring an interface as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>controlling the interface controller using a microprocessor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005192A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005192A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
