<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004629A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004629A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004629A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004629A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004629A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004629A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004629</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09897195</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B60R021/32</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>701</class>
<subclass>045000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>280</class>
<subclass>735000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Combined occupant characteristic and acoustic crash sensor arrangement</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stephen</given-name>
<middle-name>R.W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Cooper</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fowlerville</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kiran</given-name>
<middle-name>Ramanlal</middle-name>
<family-name>Magiawala</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hawthorne</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>TRW Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TAROLLI, SUNDHEIM, COVELL, TUMMINO &amp; SZABO L.L.P.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1111 LEADER BLDG.</address-1>
<address-2>526 SUPERIOR AVENUE</address-2>
<city>CLEVELAND</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>44114-1400</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An arrangement (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) is used in a vehicle (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>), and contains an occupant characteristic sensor (<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>), a filter (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) and a controller (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>). The sensor (<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>) senses an occupant characteristic and outputs a signal indicative thereof. The filter (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) and the controller (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) operate to monitor the signal for a frequency component indicative of a vehicle crash event. In one example, the arrangement (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) is part of an occupant protection system (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) that includes an actuatable protection device (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>). The controller (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) controlling actuation of the protection device (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) in response to the filtered frequency component. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to a combined occupant characteristic and crash sensor arrangement, and more particularly to an arrangement for acoustically sensing a crash event via the output of an occupant characteristic sensor. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Occupant protection systems are well known in the art and are employed in vehicles to protect vehicle occupants during crash events. Most occupant protection systems include one or more actuatable protecting components, such as air bags, seat belt pretensioners, side curtains, etc. During a crash event, these components may be actuated to physically engage an occupant and protect the occupant during a crash event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Deployment or actuation of an actuatable protection component is usually dependent upon numerous criteria, such as one or more vehicle crash conditions, and possibly one or more occupant characteristics. Vehicle crash conditions are indicative of the occurrence of a vehicle crash event. Further, the crash conditions may indicate whether a crash event is a deployment crash event. A deployment crash event is a crash event that warrants actuation or deployment of the actuatable protection component. In one example, a determination of whether a deployment crash event is occurring is based upon a determination of whether a sensed crash metric, such as crash acceleration, exceeds a threshold value. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> With respect to sensing crash conditions, multiple sensors are often placed at a variety of locations throughout the vehicle to sense crash conditions. These sensors usually sense the occurrence of a crash event and output signals indicative thereof. The signals are typically sent to a controller (typically a microprocessor or microcomputer) for a determination of whether the crash event is a deployment crash event. Most often, the controller discriminates between a deployment and a non-deployment crash event by applying a crash algorithm to the signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accelerometers are the type of sensors most often used to sense and indicate the occurrence of a crash event. U.S. Pat. No. 5,670,853, for instance, discloses an occupant protection system that uses an accelerometer to sense a crash event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Accelerometers are well known in the art and, therefore, their inter-workings are not discussed in great detail. Suffice it to say, most accelerometers have moving parts and sense acceleration through the movement of those moving parts relative to one another. Additionally, most accelerometers have an axis of sensitivity that corresponds to the direction in which the accelerometers sense acceleration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, to effectively sense a crash event that has an orientation along a particular direction with an accelerometer, the accelerometer is oriented in the same direction. For instance, to sense a side impact crash event, the accelerometer is typically oriented in the vehicle such that its axis of sensitivity corresponds to a side-to-side direction of the vehicle. Similarly, orienting the axis of sensitivity in front to rear direction of the vehicle enables the accelerometer to sense front to rear crash events. U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,826,903 and 5,746,444, for example, disclose crash event sensing with accelerometers oriented with their axes sensitivity from side-to-side or front-to-back in the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An acoustic sensor is another sensor type that is used to sense crash events. For instance, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,884,203, 4,842,301, and 4,346,914 disclose acoustic sensors that are used to sense crash events. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Acoustic crash sensors sense crash events off of vibrations that are introduced into a vehicle during a crash event. The vibrations, may, for example, be the result of acoustic waves that are caused by deformation of the vehicle body during a crash event. Acoustic sensors sense these vibrations and output signals indicative thereof. Acoustic sensors are often acoustic transducers, such as ultrasonic sensors which sense high frequency acoustic waves that propagate through the vehicle during the occurrence of a vehicle crash event. Ultrasonic sensors convert the sensed acoustic waves into signals having electrical characteristics indicative of the acoustic waves or vibrations transmitted through the vehicle during a crash event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Ultrasonic sensors typically do not rely on moving parts to be actuated. As such, they have a short response time relative to other sensors. Additionally, ultrasonic sensors are usually omni-directional, meaning that they detect acoustic waves or vibrations originating from any direction in the vehicle. As such, ultrasonic sensors can rapidly sense crash events originating from most any direction in the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> With regard to occupant characteristics, these often include the weight and/or position of the occupant (e.g. whether the sensed occupant is a large adult seated close to the vehicle dashboard). Numerous sensors are typically employed in occupant protection systems to sense the various criteria with regard to the occupant characteristics. These sensors sense the criteria and output signals indicative thereof. The signals are usually sent to the controller. The controller then uses these signals to determine control of the actuatable protection component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> With respect to sensing occupant characteristics, many different types of sensors and sensing methodologies are known to sense many different occupant characteristics, such as occupant weight and/or position. These sensors sense the occupant characteristics and output signals indicative thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Occupant characteristics, such as weight and position may be important because they can affect how and to what extent a protection component, such as an air bag should be deployed. With respect to occupant position, for example, if the occupant is moved in a direction toward the air bag during a crash event, it may be desirable to only partially inflate the air bag as the occupant&apos;s motion expedites the engagement of the air bag and the occupant. Alternatively, if the occupant is moved completely out of position during a crash event, such that deployment of the air bag would offer little or no protection to the occupant. Thus, the deployment of the air bag may be suppressed. With respect to sensing occupant position, U.S. Pat. No. 5,670,853, for example, discloses that occupant position may be sensed using different arrangements, such as with a plurality of ultrasonic sensors mounted at various locations within a vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> With respect to the weight of the occupant, the occupant&apos;s weight may affect how and to what extent a protection component, such as an air bag, should be deployed. A larger occupant may, for example, require full deployment to afford the desired protection to the occupant, whereas a smaller occupant may only require partial deployment to protection the occupant in a desired fashion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> With respect to sensing the weight of the occupant, numerous types of weight sensing devices have been developed to determine the weight of an occupant. Some weight sensors are mounted within the seat cushion of a vehicle seat while other weight sensors are mounted between the seat and the vehicle body. Typically, a transducer, such as a piezoelectric device, magnetostrictive device, or a strain gauge, is used to convert a load applied to the seat into an electrical signal indicative of the applied load (e.g. the occupant&apos;s weight). For instance, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,624,132, 5,494,311, and 5,232,243 disclose using force sense resistors to sense the weight of an occupant. U.S. Pat Nos. 5,991,676 and 5,474,32 disclose using variable resistance weight sensors to sense the weight of an occupant. U.S. Pat. No. 5,739,757 discloses using a magnetic weight sensor to sense the weight of an occupant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It is well known that vibrations present in a vehicle (resulting from a crash event or from simple road noise) typically propagate throughout the entirety of the vehicle. As such, these vibrations can affect the sensors within the vehicle. More particularly, the sensors sense these vibrations and frequency components indicative of the vibrations are embedded within the signals output by the sensors. These frequency components are undesirable and the signals output from these sensors are, therefore, usually filtered to filter out the effects of these vibrations. U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,739,757 and 5,624,132, for example, disclose that the output from weight sensors is filtered. U.S. Pat. No. 4,842,301 discloses that the output from an acoustic sensor is filtered to filter out noise, such as road noise and/or collision noise, such as noise that would result from collision with a deer. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one aspect, the present invention provides an arrangement for use in a vehicle. Occupant characteristic sensor means senses an occupant characteristic and outputs a signal indicative thereof. Means monitors the signal for a frequency component indicative of a vehicle crash event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect, the present invention provides an occupant protection system for use in a vehicle. The system includes an actuatable protection device. Occupant characteristic sensor means senses an occupant characteristic and outputs a sensor signal indicative thereof. Filter means, operatively connected to the occupant characteristic sensor means, passes a frequency component of the sensor signal indicative of a vehicle crash. Controller means, operatively connected to the protection device, the occupant characteristic sensor means and the filter means, controls actuation of the protection device in response to the sensor signal and the filtered frequency component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect, the present invention provides a method of sensing and monitoring for use in a vehicle. An occupant characteristic is sensed. A signal indicative of the sensed occupant characteristic is output. The signal is monitored for a frequency component indicative of a vehicle crash event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In accordance with yet another aspect, the present invention provides a method of protecting an occupant in a vehicle with an actuatable protection device. An occupant characteristic is sensed. A sensor signal indicative of the sensed occupant characteristic is output. The sensor signal is filtered to pass a frequency component of the sensor signal indicative of a vehicle crash. Actuation of the protection device is controlled in response to the sensor signal and the filtered frequency component.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The foregoing and other features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent to one skilled in the art upon consideration of the following description of the invention and the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic illustration of a vehicle that includes an occupant protection system wherein a combined occupant characteristic and crash sensor arrangement in accordance with the present invention is incorporated; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic illustration providing a plan view of a vehicle that includes an occupant protection system with another embodiment of a combined occupant characteristic and crash sensor arrangement in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF EXAMPLE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with an example occupant protection system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> that includes a combined occupant characteristic and crash sensor arrangement <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention. The protection system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes an actuatable protection device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated example, the protection device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is an air bag module <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The air bag module <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes a housing <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> that is mounted in an instrument panel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is stored in a folded condition within the housing <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and is configured for inflation to a deployed state <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; (shown in phantom) as is known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> An inflation fluid (e.g., nitrogen gas) source arrangement <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is provided to inflate the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated example, two sources <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B of inflation fluid are operatively connected to the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Each inflation fluid source (e.g., <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A) includes pyrotechnic material that is operatively connected to an electrically ignitable squib (e.g., <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A). Ignition of the squib (e.g., <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A) causes the pyrotechnic material of the respective fluid source (e.g., <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A) to combust and generate gas. Hereinafter, ignition and combustion is referred to as activation of an inflation fluid source. Of course, it is to be appreciated that the inflation fluid source arrangement <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be different (e.g., single source, pressurized fluid source, or hybrid pressurized fluid/fluid generation source). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Air bag deployment profile (e.g., rate at which the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is inflated and/or inflation pressure within the air bag) is changed by controlling how and when the two inflation fluid sources <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B are activated. For instance, a lower inflation pressure is achieved when only a single inflation fluid source (e.g., <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A) is activated. Alternatively, rapid deployment at a higher inflation pressure of the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is effected when both of the inflation fluid sources <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B are simultaneously activated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> One or more vent valves (e.g., <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A) are provided to also control the deployment profile of the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated example, two vent valves <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>B are provided, with each valve (e.g., <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A) being operatively connected to a respective one of the inflation fluid source (e.g., <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A). When opened, a vent valve (e.g., <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A) vents a portion of the inflation fluid away from the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, when a vent valve (e.g., <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A) is fully opened a fair amount of inflation fluid is vented away from the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the air bag receives a lesser volume of inflation fluid. Conversely, when a vent valve (e.g., <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A) is not opened or is only opened slightly, very little of the inflation fluid is vented away from the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the air bag receives a full amount of fluid from an associated inflation fluid source (e.g., <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A). It is to be appreciated that, although the illustrated example is shown with two inflation fluid sources <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B and two vent valves <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>B to provide a means by which adjustment to the deployment profile is achieved, different structures and/or configurations could be utilized to achieve deployment profile adjustment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> controls deployment of the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in response to the sensory input received from the combined sensor arrangement <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Upon a determination to deploy the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> generates one or two ignition signals. Each ignition signal is sent to a respective one of the squibs (e.g., <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A). Upon receipt of an ignition signal, the squib ignites and causes combustion of the pyrotechnic material. The controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> also generated control signal(s) for the vent valves <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>B to cause opening or closing accordingly in response to the sensory input received from the combined sensor arrangement <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In one example, the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is a microcomputer or microprocessor. The functionality of the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may, alternatively, be performed by one or more digital and/or analog circuits. The controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> also may be embodied in an application specific integrated circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Turning to the combined sensor arrangement <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the arrangement is located within a vehicle seat <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The weight sensor senses weight of an occupant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> by responding to load-force placed upon the seat <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Weight of an occupant is one example of an occupant characteristic. In one example of specific detail, the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> includes a variable resistance circuit whose resistance changes in response to the load place upon the seat. Accordingly, the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> provides an electrical signal indicative of the weight of the occupant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Specific structures for such a variable resistance weight type sensor are well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> A first filter <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is operatively connected <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to an output of the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and is operatively connected <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In general, the first filter <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> filters unwanted noise from the output of the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The filtering is to eliminate frequencies resulting from extraneous vehicle operating events and/or road noise. As examples, the first filter <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> comprises hardware, such as high-pass, low-pass, and/or bandpass filters, to accomplish the filtering function. In one example, the filtering function provides for a cut-off frequency at several hundred Hertz or less. Thus, for such an example, the first filter <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is a low-pass filter. The filtered signal provided by the first filter <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> to the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is thus indicative of the sensed occupant characteristic (e.g., weight). As mentioned above, the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> uses the sensed weight, as the occupant characteristic, to make determinations regarding control of the air bag <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> deployment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> It is to be noted that the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is interconnected to a seat frame <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and/or seat mounting brackets <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. In turn, the mounting brackets <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> are connected to a rigid structural member, such as the floor pan <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, of the vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Thus, the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is subject to vibrations, such as vibrations associated with a vehicle crash, that propagate through the vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> reacts to such vibrations and thus the output of the sensor is indicative of the vibrations. In one respect, the vibrations are acoustic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Turning back to the structure of the combined sensor arrangement <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a second filter <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is operatively connected <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and is operatively connected <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the second filter <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is between the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and receives the same output signal from the weight sensor as the first filter <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Thus, in some respects, the first and second filters <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are operating in parallel on the output signal of the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The second filter <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> permits passage of one or more certain frequencies that are indicative of a crash event. Thus, the controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> receives a signal that indicates the crash event. As mentioned, because the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is rigidly interconnect to portions (e.g. floor pan <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>) of the vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, vehicle-born vibrations, such as those that result from a crash event, are readily propagated to the weight sensor. Accordingly, the output from the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is also indicative of a crash, as indicated by the vibration. In sum, the weight sensor has acoustic sensor features. Further, the sensing is omni-directional crash sensing and has a rapid response time because of the propagation through the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Empirical testing is used to determine the one or more frequency values indicative of a vehicle crash. In part, the vehicle platform of interest is a factor in the relevant frequencies. In one example, the indicative frequency corresponds to the frequency of deforming metal. In one example, the one or more frequencies that pass through the second filter <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are in the ultrasonic range and/or on the order of 50-150 kHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> It is to be appreciated that the second filter <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be provided by any filtering arrangement to permit passage of the desired frequency component(s) (i.e., indicative of a crash event) within the weight sensor output signal. Thus, the second filter <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may comprise high-pass, low-pass, and/or band-pass filters, but preferably comprises a high-pass filter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The controller <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> monitors the filtered output from the first filter <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> for an indication of the occupant characteristic (e.g., occupant weight) and monitors the filtered output from the second filter <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for an indication of a crash event. Of course, the filtering by the first and second filters <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is applied to a single signal from a single sensor (e.g., the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>). Accordingly, the system provides for determination of both an occupant characteristic (e.g., occupant weight) and a crash event via a single sensor (e.g., the weight sensor <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows another embodiment of a combined occupant characteristic and crash sensor arrangement <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, in accordance with the present invention, within an occupant protection system <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> for a vehicle <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the occupant characteristic and crash sensor arrangement <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of sensors (e.g., <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D) that sense one or more occupant characteristics. In the illustrated example, the sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D sense occupant weight and occupant position. Each sensor (e.g., <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A) is located in a respective one of four corners or quadrants of a vehicle seat <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D are operatively connected <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>D, respectively, to a first filter <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, and are operatively connected <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>D, respectively, to a second filter <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. The first filter <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is operatively connected <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>D to a controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, and the second filter <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is operatively connected <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>D to the controller. The first and second filters <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> operate similar to the first and second filters <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, respectively, of the first embodiment (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), except for handling four inputs. In order to handle the four inputs (see the second embodiment, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), each of the first and second filters <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> provides for multiplexing into a single filter element or parallel filter elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> monitors the output of the second filter <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> for one or more frequency components indicative of a crash event, and controls actuation of an air bag module <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> in response thereto. Such an embodiment has a feature of providing an ability of determining directionality of the crash event. More particularly, where one sensor outputs a signal containing a frequency component indicative of a crash event before other sensors do, this may give an indication of the direction of the crash event. This is due to the fact that crash vibrations usually propagate away from the initial crash event and therefore affect the sensor nearest the crash event before propagating to and affecting sensors located away from the crash event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> For example, if vibrations propagate into the two sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>C located nearest the driver side of the vehicle <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> before propagating into the sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D, the two weight sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>C are affected before the sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D. The outputs of the two weight sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>C have frequency components indicative of the crash event before the outputs of the sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D have such frequency components. Such a timing pattern is indicative of the crash event occurred at the driver side of the vehicle <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Similarly, if vibrations propagate into the two sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D located nearest the passenger side of the vehicle <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> before propagating into the sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>C, the timing pattern is indicative of the crash event occurred at the passenger side of the vehicle <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In addition to using the order within which sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D are affected by a crash event, the controller may also use time measurement between sensor reaction (e.g., arrival of the signals containing frequency components) to determine the type and direction of a crash event (e.g. front, side, rear or oblique crashes). For instance, a specific lag time may exist between the arrival time of a filtered signal from one of the sensors (e.g., <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A) and the arrival time of a filter signal from another sensor (e.g., <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D). This lag time may be different for different types of crash events (e.g. front, rear or oblique crashes). The lag time between arrival of the signals may be empirically determined from test data. More particularly, experiments may be done to empirically determine the lag time for different crash events taking into account the location of the sensors relative to one another. This empirical data may then be stored in the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and used by the controller to determine a particular type of crash event depending upon the relative location of the sensors and the lag time. This data may also be developed taking into account different vehicle platforms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Consider the example of a first occupant characteristic sensor (e.g., <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A) outputting a signal containing a frequency component indicative of a crash event that is received at the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> at time T1, and a second occupant characteristic sensor (e.g., <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B) subsequently outputting a signal containing a frequency component indicative of a crash event that is received at the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> at time T2. Given the relative location of the sensors and the particular platform of interest, the lag time or difference between T1 and T2 may be used by the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> to give an indication of the type of crash event by comparing that information to empirically stored data for the same relative location of the sensors and the same vehicle platform. Therefore, depending upon the location of the sensors and the vehicle platform, the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> can use the difference between arrival times, in conjunction with the empirical data, to determine the type and direction of a crash event. The controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> can then control actuation of the air bag module <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> in response to the determined direction of the sensed crash event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As an optional feature, a separate crash sensor <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (e.g. an accelerometer) may be provided within the vehicle <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The crash sensor <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is operatively connected to the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, and the controller is programmed to receive a crash-indicative signal from the crash sensor. The crash-indicative signal is used as a safing signal. Specifically, the crash-indicative signal is used by the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> to verify that a crash event is, in fact, occurring. In one example, the controller processes (e.g., via a safing algorithm) the crash-indicative signal to make a determination regarding the verification of the crash event. Safing algorithms are known and are thus not discussed in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> As yet another, different, optional feature, a crash indication may be determined via determination of change in the occupant center of gravity (COG). COG is determined via analysis of weight distribution among the plurality of weight sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D located within the vehicle seat <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. This again reduces the need for additional sensors (e.g., a separate safing accelerometer). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As yet still another optional feature, in addition to sensing a crash event, the portions of the system <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may be adapted to sense an intrusion event (e.g., entering for the purpose of theft) at the vehicle. More particularly, the second filter <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, or yet a third filter) may be tuned or constructed with high, low, and/or band-pass filter elements to allow frequency components indicative of an intrusion event to be passed to the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> For instance, the second filter <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> (or other filter) may allow passage of frequencies corresponding to breaking a window glass <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> of the vehicle <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. As with deforming metal during a crash event, breaking glass would affect the sensors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D and the outputs thereby would contain frequency component(s) indicative of the breaking glass. The passed frequencies are provided to the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. An optional alarm <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, connected <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> to the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, is provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> When the vehicle <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is turned off, locked and a possibly a security system (not shown) has been set, the controller <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> would make determinations regarding intrusion. Upon receipt of frequency components indicative of breaking glass, a determination of intrusion is made, and the alarm <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> is sounded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides an ability of reducing the number of sensors used in occupant protection systems without sacrificing resolution of the sensed crash event and/or sensed occupant characteristic. Such an ability promotes cost savings and simplicity of configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> It is to be appreciated that any type of occupant characteristic sensor for sensing any type of occupant characteristic may be used in the present invention, provided that the signals output thereby contain a frequency component indicative of vehicle born vibrations, such as vibrations that result from a crash event. This may include, for instance, any type of position sensor, such as an ultrasonic sensor, that senses the position of the occupant and/or any type of weight sensor, such as a variable resistance sensor that senses the weight of the occupant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> From the above description of the invention, those skilled in the art will perceive improvements, changes and modifications. Such improvements, changes and modifications are intended to be included within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">Having described the invention, the following is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An arrangement for use in a vehicle, said arrangement comprising: 
<claim-text>occupant characteristic sensor means for sensing an occupant characteristic and outputting a signal indicative thereof; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for monitoring the signal for a frequency component indicative of a vehicle crash event. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An arrangement as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement is used for control in an occupant protection system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An occupant protection system for use in a vehicle, said protection system comprising: 
<claim-text>an actuatable protection device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>occupant characteristic sensor means for sensing an occupant characteristic and outputting a sensor signal indicative thereof; </claim-text>
<claim-text>filter means, operatively connected to said occupant characteristic sensor means, for passing a frequency component of the sensor signal indicative of a vehicle crash; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>controller means, operatively connected to said protection device, said occupant characteristic sensor means and said filter means, for controlling actuation of said protection device in response to the sensor signal and the filtered frequency component. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said occupant characteristic sensor means includes an occupant weight sensor means for sensing weight. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said weight sensor means is a first weight sensor means, the sensor signal is a first sensor signal, and said filter means is a first filter means, said system further comprises second weight sensor means, operatively connected to said controller means, for outputting a second sensor signal, and second filter means, operatively connected to said second weight sensor means and said controller means, for passing a frequency component of the second sensor signal indicative of a vehicle crash, and said controller means controlling actuation of said protection device in response to the first and second sensor signals and the first and second filtered frequency components. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first and second weight sensor means are disposed at different locations within the vehicle, and said controller means including means for determining a crash direction from the first and second filtered frequency components. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said controller means includes means for determining the crash direction from the order within which said controller means receives the first and second filtered frequency components. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said controller means includes means for determining the crash direction from the difference between arrival times of the first and second filtered frequency components at said controller means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said weight sensor means is a first weight sensor means, the sensor signal is a first sensor signal, and said filter means is a first filter means, said system comprises a plurality of weight sensor means, each operatively connected to said controller means and each for outputting a respective sensor signal, and a plurality of filter means, each operatively connected to a respective weight sensor means and said controller means and each for passing a frequency component of the respective sensor signal indicative of a vehicle crash, said controller means controlling actuation of said actuatable protection device in response to the plurality of sensor signals and the plurality of filtered frequency components. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the filtered frequency component lies within the ultrasonic range of frequencies. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising filter means, operatively connected to said occupant characteristic sensor means and said controller means, for passing a frequency component indicative of a vehicle intrusion event, and alarm means, operatively connected to said controller means, for providing an alarm warning, and said controller means including means for controlling said intrusion alarm means in response to the frequency component indicative of a vehicle intrusion event. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method of sensing and monitoring for use in a vehicle, said method comprising: 
<claim-text>sensing an occupant characteristic; </claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting a signal indicative of the sensed occupant characteristic; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring the signal for a frequency component indicative of a vehicle crash event. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising using the signal and the frequency component for control in an occupant protection system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method of protecting an occupant in a vehicle with an actuatable protection device, said method comprising: 
<claim-text>sensing an occupant characteristic; </claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting a sensor signal indicative of the sensed occupant characteristic; </claim-text>
<claim-text>filtering the sensor signal to pass a frequency component of the sensor signal indicative of a vehicle crash; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling actuation of the protection device in response to the sensor signal and the filtered frequency component. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of sensing an occupant characteristic includes sensing weight.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004629A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004629A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004629A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
