<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004520A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004520A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004520</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896822</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61F011/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>606</class>
<subclass>108000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>604</class>
<subclass>539000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Percutaneous access</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Brett</given-name>
<middle-name>T.</middle-name>
<family-name>Haarala</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Framingham</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Brian</given-name>
<family-name>Bergeron</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Worcester</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Paul</given-name>
<family-name>DiCarlo</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Middleboro</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TESTA, HURWITZ &amp; THIBEAULT, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>HIGH STREET TOWER</address-1>
<address-2>125 HIGH STREET</address-2>
<city>BOSTON</city>
<state>MA</state>
<postalcode>02110</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Medical devices and related methods enable physicians and/or other medical personnel to access percutaneously the interior of a patient. One particular device includes a housing which defines a cavity, a first opening into the cavity, and a second opening into the cavity. The housing is implantable in a patient. The cavity is placed subcutaneously within the patient. The first opening is substantially flush with the surface of the skin of the patient and creates a percutaneous passageway from the exterior of the skin of the patient into the cavity, and the second opening creates a passageway from the cavity into the interior of the patient. A connector is coupled to the second opening and disposed substantially within the cavity to enable a connection between a first device and a second device disposed within the interior of the patient. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates generally to percutaneous access, and more specifically to methods and devices associated with percutaneous access. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND INFORMATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Long term access to a patient&apos;s bloodstream (longer than one month, for example) is required for many medical treatments including antibiotic therapy, hemodialysis access, chemotherapy regimens, and other treatments that require repeated infusion or blood processing. In some cases, internal access to the patient is required for years. Current devices and methods generally negatively impact the quality of the patient&apos;s life, and the patient sometimes develops complications as a result of the long term access. Vascular access devices used for longer term treatments include tunneled central catheters (including dialysis catheters), implanted infusion ports (including dialysis ports), dialysis grafts, and fistulas. A cuffed catheter can be used for non-vascular access, such as to the abdominal cavity for peritoneal dialysis to prevent infection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Tunneled catheters can cause infection of the bloodstream or peritoneum and the skin entry site. The external portion of the catheter can fracture or otherwise fail due to its movement after placement. Also, the placed catheter can be accidentally or intentionally removed from the body, causing the patient pain and other complications. There is also the possibility of increased wear, damage, or disassembly caused by the patient &ldquo;playing with&rdquo; the placed device. The skin entry site requires constant maintenance and clamps are required to prevent bleeding through the catheter and to prevent air embolus. The portion of the catheter external to the patient&apos;s body frequently is uncomfortable for the patient. The external catheter and the skin entry site can prevent the patient from bathing normally or engaging in normal physical activities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Subcutaneously implanted access ports require the use of needles to access the port through the patient&apos;s skin. Using needles, such as the large needles used for dialysis ports, creates the potential for infection and causes the patient pain. The access port reservoir has the potential of accumulating debris and harboring infection. In the event an internally-connected catheter connecting to this type of port needs to be replaced, a surgical procedure is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Grafts and fistulas on the patient&apos;s arm are disfiguring, and they require frequent access with large bore needles which causes pain and eventually destroys the access route. Grafts and fistulas also require invasive vascular surgery to be created and revised. Additionally, interluminal declotting is often necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> With respect to medical devices that are permanently implanted into a patient, such as a pacemaker for example, access is limited to surgical means in order to reach the device to replace batteries or repair components. Electrical leads that pass through the skin to supply power and control for the internally-implanted device can cause infection. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The invention relates generally to percutaneous access, and more specifically to methods and devices associated with percutaneous access. In one embodiment, an access device allows physicians and other medical personnel to obtain long term percutaneous access to a patient&apos;s body. The access device reduces the opportunity for infection by completely shielding fluid connections (that extend into the interior of the patient&apos;s body) from the patient&apos;s skin and from the external environment. The access device has no protruding external elements, and can be protected by a low-profile cover that is substantially flush with the patient&apos;s skin. The access device thus is cosmetically appealing and allows substantially normal physical activity. The cover is difficult to remove accidentally or intentional from the access device. The access device allows access to the interior of the patient without requiring a needle to pierce the skin. Further, internal components, such as a catheter or a valve, can be replaced without a surgical procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, the invention involves a medical device. The medical device includes a housing defining a cavity, a first opening into the cavity, and a second opening into the cavity. The housing is implantable in a patient to dispose the cavity subcutaneously within the patient. The first opening is substantially flush with the surface of the skin of the patient and creates a percutaneous passageway from the exterior of the skin of the patient into the cavity. The second opening creates a passageway from the cavity into the interior of the patient. The medical device further includes a connector coupled to the second opening and disposed substantially within the cavity and allows for a connection between a first device and a second device disposed within the interior of the patient. In one embodiment, the housing defines a flange for extending subcutaneously into the patient to anchor the housing in the patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the medical device further includes a cover that is removably couplable to the housing. The cover selectively seals and exposes the first opening and is cover substantially coplanar with the surface of the skin of the patient when sealing the first opening. The cover is removable to allow the first and second devices to be connected via the connector. The cover includes a locking mechanism to prevent the cover from being inadvertently removed. In other embodiments, the cover is canoe or elliptically shaped. In one embodiment, the cover further includes an electrical connector. In another embodiment, the cover further includes a display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In yet another embodiment, the connector includes a luer connector. In other embodiments, the medical device further includes a valve. In still other embodiments, the medical device further includes a cap removably coupled to the luer connector to selectively seal and expose the luer connector. The cap removably couples to the luer connector with a threaded connection. In some embodiments, the luer connector is telescopic and capable of being extended out of the cavity when the cover is removed from the first opening. In other embodiments, the luer connector includes a pivoting luer connector which opens a fluid path through the second opening when pivoted to a first position and seals the fluid path through the second opening when pivoted to a second position. In yet another embodiment, the connector includes an electrical connector. In another embodiment, the connector is releasably couplable to the second opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In still another embodiment, the first device includes a connection tube and the second device includes a catheter. The catheter includes a single lumen catheter a multilumen catheter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the first device includes an infusion device for infusing medication into the patient. In another embodiment, the first device includes a device for removing bodily fluids of the patient. In still another embodiment, the first device includes a device for removing, purifying, and reintroducing blood into the patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the connector includes an electrical connector. In one embodiment, the electrical connector is releasably couplable to a battery disposable entirely within the cavity for supplying power to the second device. In another embodiment, the electrical connector is releasably couplable to a control device disposable entirely within the cavity for supplying control signals to the second device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, the invention relates to a method of obtaining percutaneous access to the interior of a patient. The method includes making a straight incision in the patient and implanting in the patient through the straight incision a medical device. The medical device includes a housing defining a cavity, a first opening into the cavity, and a second opening into the cavity. The housing is implantable in a patient to dispose the cavity subcutaneously within the patient. The first opening is substantially flush with the surface of the skin of the patient and creates a percutaneous passageway from the exterior of the skin of the patient into the cavity. The second opening creates a passageway from the cavity into the interior of the patient. The method further includes mating a connector to a proximal end of a catheter and inserting a distal end of the catheter through the second opening. The method further includes sliding the catheter through the second opening into the interior of the patient and coupling the proximal end of the catheter and the connector to the second opening thereby disposing the connector substantially within the cavity and sealing the second opening and creating a fluid path from the interior of the patient to the connector. The method further includes connecting a first device external to the patient to the connector through the first opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the method further includes anchoring the housing within the patient with sutures, The sutures include subcutaneous sutures </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the method further includes anchoring the housing within the patient with subcutaneous hooks.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In the drawings, like reference characters generally refer to the same parts throughout the different views. Also, the drawings are not necessarily to scale, emphasis instead generally being placed upon illustrating the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an illustrative perspective side view of a percutaneous access device according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an illustrative top view of the percutaneous access device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an illustrative perspective view of the percutaneous access device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an illustrative perspective front view of the percutaneous access device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional side view of a percutaneous access device according to another embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional side view of the percutaneous access device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, implanted in a patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional side view of the percutaneous access device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, implanted in a patient and connected to an external medical device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional view of a connector-catheter connection including a valve in a closed position according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional view of the connector-catheter connection shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>A, including the valve in an open position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional view of a percutaneous access device including a pivoting luer connector in an open position, according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional view of the percutaneous access device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>A, with the pivoting luer connector in a closed position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-section view of a percutaneous access device including a telescopic luer connector in an extended position, according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-section view of a percutaneous access device including a telescopic luer connector in a retracted position, according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an illustrative top view of a percutaneous access device according to another embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional side view of the percutaneous access device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is an illustrative top view of the percutaneous access device including two connectors, according to another embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional side view of the percutaneous access device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, implanted in a patient and connected to internally-implanted medical devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15A</cross-reference> is an illustrative top view of a housing cover, according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15B</cross-reference> is an illustrative cross-sectional side view of a housing including the housing cover shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16A</cross-reference> is an illustrative diagram of a percutaneous access device implanted in a patient and connected to internal and external medical devices, according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16B</cross-reference> is an illustrative diagram of the percutaneous access device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>A, implanted in a patient and connected to internal medical devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17A</cross-reference> is an illustrative top view of a housing cover with an elliptical shape, according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17B</cross-reference> is an illustrative top view of a housing cover with an canoe shape, according to another embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17C</cross-reference> is an illustrative top view of a housing cover with an almond shape, according to yet another embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The invention relates generally to percutaneous access, and more specifically to methods and devices associated with percutaneous access. In one embodiment, an access device allows physicians and/or other medical personnel to obtain long term percutaneous access to the interior of a patient&apos;s body. The access device reduces the opportunity for infection by completely shielding fluid connections (that extend into the interior of the patient&apos;s body) from the patient&apos;s skin and from the external environment. The access device has no protruding external elements, and can be protected by a low-profile cover that is substantially flush with the patient&apos;s skin. The access device thus is cosmetically appealing and allows substantially normal physical activity. The cover is difficult to remove accidentally or intentionally from the access device. The access device allows access to the interior of the patient without requiring a needle to pierce the skin. Further, internal components, such as a catheter or a valve, can be replaced without a surgical procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, in one embodiment, a medical device for allowing percutaneous access to a patient&apos;s body is an access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> which includes a housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, a cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, a first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, a flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and a connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> defines the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> (which leads into the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>), and the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> (which also leads into the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is implanted in a patient to dispose the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> subcutaneously within the patient. After the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is implanted in the patient, the first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is substantially flush with the surface of the skin of the patient and creates a percutaneous passageway from the exterior of the skin of the patient into the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> creates a passageway from the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> into the interior of the patient. The connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is coupled to the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and is disposed substantially within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> allows a first device which is external to the patient, such as an infusion pump for example, to be connected to a second device disposed within the interior of the patient, such as a catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> for example. The flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, which is coupled to the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, holds the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> in place once the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is implanted in a patient. In one embodiment, the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is made of a bio-compatible material such as Polysulfone or Titanium. The housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can also be made of a molded bio-compatible plastic material. In another embodiment, the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can made of a soft material that can be penetrated by sutures or needles. In some embodiments, the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is canoe shaped, elliptically shaped, or almond shaped, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17A, 17B</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>C. In other embodiment, the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> includes a concave bottom, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and in still other embodiments the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> include a flat bottom, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, in one embodiment, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is a luer connector and is coupled to the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. A proximal end <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is first positioned over a distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The catheter is held in place over the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> by a plurality of barbs <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> (or a raised ring) on the distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is fed through the opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> until the plurality of barbs <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> on the distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> engage a plurality of barbs <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> within the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is secured in place by engaging the plurality of barbs <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> with the plurality of barbs <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>. After the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is secured in place, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is positioned such that the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is disposed substantially within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Specifically, in some embodiments, a small portion of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> can extend out of the first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. However, in other embodiments, no portion of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> extends out of the first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and is disposed entirely within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In some embodiments, the connector <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is sealable when not in use. For example, the connector <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> can have a threaded or friction fit sealing cap that is removed during use and replaced when not in use. The cap can also include a penetrable surface, such as rubber or silicone for example, which can be penetrated by a needle. Further, the connector <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> can include a valve <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> which opens when the connector <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is connected to an external device and closes when the connector <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is disconnected from the external device. In some embodiments, the value <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> can be a slit valve made of foam or rubber. The connector <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is also compatible with typical medical luer attachments. In other embodiments, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> can include a single lumen or multiple lumens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 6</cross-reference>, in one embodiment, the percutaneous access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is implanted into a patient <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> as follows. First, a linear incision is made in the patient. Such an incision is less traumatic to the patient (as opposed to coring). A distal end of a guidewire is inserted through the incision, into the patient <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>, and into an area in which the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is to be placed, such as vein for example. If necessary, a dilator may be placed over the guidewire to dilate the area where the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is to be inserted. A proximal end of the guidewire is inserted through the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is then inserted into the patient <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> through the incision. The housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is positioned so that the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is axially aligned with the guidewire, the flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is subcutaneous, and the first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is substantially flush with the surface of the patient&apos;s skin <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>. The flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> promotes stability of the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and adhesion of the skin and subdermal layers immediately adjacent to the incision site. In some embodiments, subcutaneous sutures sewn through holes in the flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can be used to anchor the subdermal layers to the flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. In other embodiments subcutaneous hooks may be used to anchor the subdermal layers to the flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. In still other embodiments, the flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can be coated with materials that promote tissue growth to provide better sealing of the incision, such as collagen or other tissue growth catalysts, for example. Materials that promote ingrowth of cells, such as a permeable fabric, a textured polymer, or a steel mesh can also be bonded to or embedded in the flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The added ingrowth materials cause the skin surrounding the flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to bond securely with the flange <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The surface of the patient&apos;s skin <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> may also be secured to the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> by using glue, such as Dermabond (a trademark of and a product commercially available from Closure Medical Corporation of Raleigh, N.C.) or medical tape around the incision site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> After the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is anchored in place, the distal end <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is inserted through the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> over the guidewire and fed into the patient. Next, the guidewire is removed and the proximal end <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is coupled to the distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is fed through the opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and secured in place (as previously described) thereby sealing the opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and creating a fluid path <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> from the interior of the patient to the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The implanted access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can then be covered with a temporary dressing or Tegaderm (a trademark of and a product commercially available from 3M Health Care Ltd. of Loughborough, UK) which is a skin-like bandage. The cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can also be filed with gauze and/or antimicrobial agents. In another embodiment, the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can be covered with a low-profile housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>, which can be shaped to conform to the contour of the patient&apos;s skin. The housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> couples to an edge <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and creates a watertight seal and protects the connector <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> from debris and damage from the environment. In some embodiments, the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> includes a locking mechanism which prevents the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> from being accidentally or intentionally removed by the patient. For example, the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can be secured to the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> by using a friction fit or a thread fit. The housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can also be secured to the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> using clamps that clamp onto the edge <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The clamps can be configured to selectively engage and disengage the edge <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> when a key is inserted into the housing cover and turned. In other embodiments, the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can be coupled to the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> with a wire or a hinge, for example. Additionally, gauze can be placed around the first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> between the patient&apos;s skin and the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, after the linear incision is made, the guidewire is inserted into the vein (or other organ) and then the distal end <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is inserted into the vein over the guidewire. Next, the proximal end <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> of the catheter is inserted into the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and fed into the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The guidewire is removed and the distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is then coupled to the proximal end <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> of the catheter and then fed through the opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and secured. The housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is then implanted into the patient using the procedure previously described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is accessed by first removing the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. Next, an external medical device, such as a connection tube <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> to an infusion pump, is connected to the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> creating a fluid connection <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> through opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. After the procedure utilizing the infusion pump has been completed, the connection tube <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> is disconnected from the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> is placed back on the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to seal the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and protect the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be used with a variety of other medical devices, such as body fluid removal devices and blood purification devices, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, after initial surgical implantation, enables physicians and/or other medical personnel to repeatedly (and without further surgery) access various internal regions of the patient, such as veins, arteries, and various organs for example. The connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and fluid connection that extends into the patient&apos;s body is shielded from the patient&apos;s skin and from the external environment, and thereby reduces opportunity for infection. The access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> has no protruding external elements, and can be protected by the low-profile housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> which is substantially flush with the patient&apos;s skin and thereby allows the patient to engage in substantially normal physical activity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, if the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> remains implanted for an extended period of time, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and/or the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> may need to be replaced. Replacement of these components can be achieved without surgery. First, the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> is removed from the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Next, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is removed from the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is decoupled from the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. A guidewire is fed through the catheter into the patient. The catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is then removed from the patient. A new catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is inserted into the patient over the guidewire through the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the guidewire is then removed. A new connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is coupled to the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and secured in the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> as previously described. A benefit of this feature is that the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and/or the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> can be replaced without surgery, resulting in less trauma to the patient and reduced chance of infection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A and 8B</cross-reference>, in another embodiment, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is a luer connector and is coupled to the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. A proximal end <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is first positioned over a distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is held in place over the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> by a plurality of barbs <highlight><bold>804</bold></highlight> (or a rings) on the distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The distal end of the catheter <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is fed through the opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> until the plurality of barbs <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> on the distal end <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> meet a plurality of O-rings <highlight><bold>802</bold></highlight>. The connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is secured in place by engaging the plurality of barbs <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> with the plurality of O-rings <highlight><bold>802</bold></highlight>. After the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is secured in place, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is positioned such that the entire connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is disposed entirely within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> also includes a threaded locking cap <highlight><bold>808</bold></highlight> which engages threads <highlight><bold>806</bold></highlight>. The locking cap <highlight><bold>808</bold></highlight> is used to secure a connection between the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and an external medical device. The connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> can also include a valve <highlight><bold>810</bold></highlight> which remains sealed when no external medical device is connected to the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and opens when the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is connected to an external medical device, such as a connection tube <highlight><bold>812</bold></highlight> to an infusion pump. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A and 9B</cross-reference>, in another embodiment, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a pivoting luer connector <highlight><bold>902</bold></highlight>. The pivoting luer connector <highlight><bold>902</bold></highlight>, when pivoted to a first position, opens the fluid path <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> through the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and, when pivoted to a second position, closes the fluid path <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> through the second opening <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In operation, when the pivoting luer connector <highlight><bold>902</bold></highlight> is not in use, the pivoting luer connector <highlight><bold>902</bold></highlight> is pivoted to the second position thereby keeping the fluid path <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> closed. The pivoting luer connector <highlight><bold>902</bold></highlight> is only pivoted to the first position after an external medical device has been connected to the pivoting connector <highlight><bold>902</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A and 10B</cross-reference>, in still another embodiment, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a telescopic luer connector <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight>. The telescopic connector <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight>, when not in use, is disposed entirely within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. However, when the telescopic connector <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight> is in use, the telescopic connector <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight> can be extended out of the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to allow a physician or other medical personnel to connect an external medical device more easily. In another embodiment, the telescopic connector <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight> includes a stop or plug disposed inside the connector <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight>. The stop is coaxial with the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and acts as a valve which seals the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> when the telescopic connector is <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight> is retracted. When the telescopic connector <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight> is extended, the seal between the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and the stop is broken thereby allowing fluid to flow past the stop and through the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, in other embodiments, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes two luer connectors <highlight><bold>1304</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1304</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and two corresponding catheters <highlight><bold>1302</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1302</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>In this configuration, blood, for example, can be easily drawn out of a patient, purified, and put back into the patient. In another embodiment, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes two luer connections that both connect to a single catheter. The single catheter a single lumen catheter or multilumen catheter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In other embodiment, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a luer connector with a pressure-responsive slit valve. The valve includes a diaphragm including a slit which is flexed in one direction by hydrostatic pressure and flexed in an opposite direction by negative pressure to selectively open the slit. Examples of such a pressure-responsive slit valves are shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,205,834, U.S. Pat. No. 5,201,722, and U.S. Pat. No. 5,169,393 which are herein incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11, 12</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, in another embodiment, the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is used to store a small printed circuit board <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight> including electronics <highlight><bold>1108</bold></highlight> and/or a battery <highlight><bold>1106</bold></highlight> used in conjunction with one or more medical devices implanted in a patient, such as a pacemaker <highlight><bold>1402</bold></highlight> and/or a sensor <highlight><bold>1404</bold></highlight>, for example. In this configuration, the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is an electrical connector. The connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is positioned such that the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is disposed substantially within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Specifically, in some embodiments, a small portion of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> can extend out of the first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. However, in other embodiments, no portion of the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> extends out of the first opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and is disposed entirely within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Wires (or optical fiber) <highlight><bold>1202</bold></highlight> from the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> extend subcutaneously from the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and connect to the pacemaker <highlight><bold>1402</bold></highlight> and/or sensor <highlight><bold>1404</bold></highlight>. Wires (or optical fiber) <highlight><bold>1104</bold></highlight> extending from the connector <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> inside the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> connect to a connector <highlight><bold>1110</bold></highlight> on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight>. The printed circuit bard <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight> is coupled to the housing <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> inside the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> by mounting posts <highlight><bold>1204</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>B, in one embodiment, an infusion pump <highlight><bold>1616</bold></highlight> and a medication reservoir <highlight><bold>1618</bold></highlight> can be housed in the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The medication reservoir <highlight><bold>1618</bold></highlight> supplies medication to the infusion pump <highlight><bold>1616</bold></highlight> through tube <highlight><bold>1620</bold></highlight>. The infusion pump <highlight><bold>1616</bold></highlight> pumps medication though tube <highlight><bold>1622</bold></highlight>, through luer connector <highlight><bold>1626</bold></highlight>, and through catheter <highlight><bold>1628</bold></highlight> and into the patient&apos;s body <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>. Electronics <highlight><bold>1614</bold></highlight> (housed in the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>) can include a battery to power the infusion pump <highlight><bold>1616</bold></highlight> and control circuitry to control the infusion pump <highlight><bold>1616</bold></highlight>. In addition to the luer connector <highlight><bold>1626</bold></highlight>, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can also include one or more electronic connectors, such as electrical connector <highlight><bold>1630</bold></highlight>. Electronic connector <highlight><bold>1630</bold></highlight> can be used to connect power and control electronics to a sensor <highlight><bold>1624</bold></highlight>, or other device (via wires or optical fiber <highlight><bold>1626</bold></highlight>) implanted in the patient, for example. In another embodiment, the entire cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can be used as a medication reservoir. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, in another embodiment, the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight> (housed in the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>) can include control circuitry <highlight><bold>1108</bold></highlight> and a battery <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to control and power a pacemaker <highlight><bold>1402</bold></highlight> implanted in a patient&apos;s body <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>. In this configuration, the battery <highlight><bold>1110</bold></highlight> can be replaced without surgery by simply removing the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>, replacing the battery <highlight><bold>1110</bold></highlight>, and then replacing the cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the electronics <highlight><bold>1108</bold></highlight> controlling the pacemaker <highlight><bold>1402</bold></highlight> can also be repaired and/or adjusted with surgery. In other embodiments, the wires <highlight><bold>1202</bold></highlight> extending into the patent&apos;s body <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>, can fan out to connect to multiple medical devices such as the pacemaker <highlight><bold>1402</bold></highlight> and one or more sensors <highlight><bold>1404</bold></highlight>. In still other embodiments, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can include multiple electronic connectors <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As previously described, the electronics <highlight><bold>1108</bold></highlight> on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight> can include control and memory electronics for various sensors, such as pressure sensors and urine pH sensors for example. In another embodiment, these sensors (along with control circuitry and power) can be housed in the cavity <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, and the fluid to be analyzed (blood or urine, for example) is brought into the cavity <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> via an inlet luer connector and pumped back into the body via an outlet luer connector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>A, in still another embodiment, the access housing <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can include any combination of connectors. For example, the access housing <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can include an inlet luer connector <highlight><bold>1638</bold></highlight> and an outlet luer connector <highlight><bold>1636</bold></highlight>. The inlet connector <highlight><bold>1638</bold></highlight> is connected to a catheter <highlight><bold>1632</bold></highlight> which is also connected to a vein <highlight><bold>1602</bold></highlight>. The outlet connector <highlight><bold>1636</bold></highlight> is connected to a catheter <highlight><bold>1634</bold></highlight> which is also connected to the vein <highlight><bold>1602</bold></highlight>. The inlet connector <highlight><bold>1638</bold></highlight> is also connected to tube <highlight><bold>1606</bold></highlight> which is connected to a blood purification device <highlight><bold>1608</bold></highlight> external to the patient <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>. The outlet connector <highlight><bold>1636</bold></highlight> is also connected to a tube <highlight><bold>1604</bold></highlight> which is also connected to the blood purification device <highlight><bold>1608</bold></highlight>. In operation, the blood purification device <highlight><bold>1608</bold></highlight> draws blood through the catheter <highlight><bold>1632</bold></highlight>, through the inlet connector <highlight><bold>1638</bold></highlight>, through the tube <highlight><bold>1606</bold></highlight> and into the blood purification device. After the blood is purified, the blood purification device <highlight><bold>1608</bold></highlight> pumps the purified blood through tube <highlight><bold>1604</bold></highlight>, through outlet connector <highlight><bold>1636</bold></highlight>, through catheter <highlight><bold>1634</bold></highlight> and back into the vein <highlight><bold>1602</bold></highlight>. Further, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can include an electronic connector <highlight><bold>1640</bold></highlight> which connects control and power electronics <highlight><bold>1612</bold></highlight> to a medical device (via wires or optical fiber <highlight><bold>1642</bold></highlight>) such as a blood press sensor <highlight><bold>1610</bold></highlight> implanted in the patient <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be configured to house various electromechanical components of an artificial heart implanted in a patient. In this embodiment, the electromechanical parts are accessible (without requiring surgery) by removing the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments, the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can include electronics capable of wireless communication. In this embodiment, physicians and/or medical personnel can wirelessly communicate with electronics stored in the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (without removing the cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>) to download data from various sensors implanted in a patient, for example. The physician can also download a status of a medication reservoir or a status of battery power. Further, the electronics housed in the cavity used to communicate with and control various implanted medical devices can do so wirelessly. For example, a sensor used for sensing the pressure in a particular artery can transmit sensor data wirelessly to an electronic storage element in the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, or control circuitry used for controlling a pacemaker can transmit control signals wirelessly to the pacemaker. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, sensor signals can be transmitted through a fluid. For example, a pressure sensor is housed within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The sensor is in physical communication with a proximal portion of an elongated membrane that contains a fluid. The elongated membrane extends outside the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> into the interior of the patient. A pressure change in the patient causes pressure on a distal portion of the membrane which, in turn, causes the fluid within the membrane to flow back to the proximal portion of the membrane and be detected by the pressure sensor. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15A and 15B</cross-reference>, in another embodiment, the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can include low-profile electronic connectors <highlight><bold>1506</bold></highlight> and/or fiber optics connectors <highlight><bold>1508</bold></highlight> which can be used to access and read out sensor data stored in a memory chip on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight> without having to remove the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. The housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can also include a low-profile luer connector <highlight><bold>1510</bold></highlight> which enables a fluid connection to the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Such a fluid connection enables a physician and/or medical personnel to access a medical device implanted in the patient (through the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>) or refill a medication reservoir within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> without having to remove the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. Further, the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can also include indicator LEDs <highlight><bold>1502</bold></highlight> to indicate low battery power or low medication reservoir levels, for example. The housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can also include a battery connector <highlight><bold>1502</bold></highlight> to enable recharging of a battery <highlight><bold>1110</bold></highlight> stored in the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> without having to remove the cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. The housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can also include a low-profile liquid crystal or LED display for reading sensor data, providing a status of battery power, or providing a status of a medication reservoir stored in the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, for example. Moreover, the housing cover <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> can include an infrared or wireless communication port <highlight><bold>1514</bold></highlight> to allow wireless communication with electronics stored within the cavity <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and/or medical devices implanted in the patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Some of the benefits of utilizing the access device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to store such electronics and/or batteries include nonsurgical accessibility of the electronics for repair and/or replacement, nonsurgical battery replacement, patient comfort, and reduced chance of infection from electronic components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Variations, modifications, and other implementations of what is described herein will occur to those of ordinary skill in the art without departing from the spirit and the scope of the invention. Accordingly the invention is not to be defined solely by the preceding illustrative description. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A medical device, comprising; 
<claim-text>a housing defining a cavity, a first opening into the cavity, and a second opening into the cavity, the housing being implantable in a patient to dispose the cavity subcutaneously within the patient, the first opening being substantially flush with the surface of the skin of the patient and creating a percutaneous passageway from the exterior of the skin of the patient into the cavity, the second opening creating a passageway from the cavity into the interior of the patient; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector coupled to the second opening and disposed substantially within the cavity, the connector for allowing a connection between a first device and a second device disposed within the interior of the patient. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a cover removably couplable to the housing to selectively seal and expose the first opening, the cover being substantially coplanar with the surface of the skin of the patient when sealing the first opening and being removable to allow the first and second devices to be connected via the connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the connector comprises a luer connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first device comprises a connection tube and the second device comprises a catheter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the housing defines a flange for extending subcutaneously into the patient to anchor the housing in the patient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> further comprises a valve. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a cap removably coupled to the luer connector to selectively seal and expose the luer connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cap removably couples to the luer connector with a threaded connection. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the catheter comprises a single lumen catheter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the catheter comprises a multilumen catheter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the luer connector is telescopic and capable of being extended out of the cavity when the cover is removed from the first opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cover comprises a locking mechanism to prevent the cover from being inadvertently removed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first device comprises an infusion device for infusing medication into the patient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first device comprises a device for removing bodily fluids of the patient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first device comprises a device for removing, purifying, and reintroducing blood into the patient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the housing comprises a canoe shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the housing comprises an elliptical shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the luer connector comprises a pivoting luer connector opening a fluid path through the second opening when pivoted to a first position and sealing the fluid path through the second opening when pivoted to a second position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the connector comprises an electrical connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electrical connector is releasably couplable to a battery disposable entirely within the cavity for supplying power to the second device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electrical connector is releasably couplable to a control device disposable entirely within the cavity for supplying control signals to the second device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the connector is releasably couplable to the second opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the connector comprises an electrical connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cover further comprises an electrical connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The medical device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cover further comprises a display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A method of obtaining percutaneous access to the interior of a patient, comprising: 
<claim-text>making a straight incision in the patient; </claim-text>
<claim-text>implanting in the patient through the straight incision a medical device comprising a housing defining a cavity, a first opening into the cavity, and a second opening into the cavity, the housing being implantable in a patient to dispose the cavity subcutaneously within the patient, the first opening being substantially flush with the surface of the skin of the patient and creating a percutaneous passageway from the exterior of the skin of the patient into the cavity, the second opening creating a passageway from the cavity into the interior of the patient; </claim-text>
<claim-text>mating a connector to a proximal end of a catheter; </claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting a distal end of the catheter through the second opening; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sliding the catheter through the second opening into the interior of the patient and coupling the proximal end of the catheter and the connector to the second opening thereby disposing the connector substantially within the cavity and sealing the second opening and creating a fluid path from the interior of the patient to the connector; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting a first device external to the patient to the connector through the first opening. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising anchoring the housing within the patient with sutures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sutures comprise subcutaneous sutures </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising anchoring the housing within the patient with subcutaneous hooks.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030004520A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
