<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002025A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002025A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002025A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002025A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002025A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002025A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002025A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002025A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002025A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002025A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002025A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002025A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002025</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894482</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03B027/62</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>355</class>
<subclass>075000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>355</class>
<subclass>072000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>414</class>
<subclass>225000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>414</class>
<subclass>321000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>355</class>
<subclass>053000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Reticle stop block apparatus and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Daniel</given-name>
<middle-name>Lawson</middle-name>
<family-name>Greene</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Worcestor</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ron</given-name>
<family-name>Sinicki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Newberg</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kurt</given-name>
<family-name>Woolley</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>South Jordan</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Intel Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SCHWEGMAN, LUNDBERG, WOESSNER &amp; KLUTH, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 2938</address-1>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Methods and apparatus for ensuring the proper handling of reticles in the manufacturing of microdevices are disclosed. The methods and apparatus employ one or more reticle stop blocks fixed to a reticle handling arm. The one or more reticle stop blocks are designed and arranged to engage an edge of the reticle in order to place the reticle in a desired position on the reticle handling arm should the reticle be improperly arranged in a cassette in which the reticle is stored. By ensuring proper placement of the reticle on the reticle handling arm when the reticle is removed from the cassette, the likelihood of a subsequent fault in handling the reticle is greatly reduced. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to photolithography, and in particular to methods and apparatus for ensuring proper handling of reticles in photolithography systems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The manufacture of certain types of microdevices, such as semiconductor integrated circuits, flat-panel displays, ink-jet heads and the like, involves the process of photolithography and hence the use of photolithography systems, also called &ldquo;photolithography tools.&rdquo; Photolithography tools are designed to project an image of a finely patterned mask (&ldquo;reticle&rdquo;) onto a photosensitive substrate. The reticle typically includes a pellicle, which is a thin membrane displaced from the patterned side of the reticle by a frame. The pellicle serves to keep dust and other particulates off of the patterned surface that would otherwise be imaged onto the substrate. After the substrate is exposed, it is processed to create a desired structure based on the imaged pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The manufacturing process typically involves repeating the photolithography and process steps using different reticles in order to build up the device. Accordingly, photolithography tools typically include (or are operatively coupled with) an automatic reticle handling system to facilitate the rapid loading and unloading of reticles to and from the tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Reticles are fragile and thus are always contained inside a protective plastic case called a &ldquo;cassette&rdquo; until extracted by the reticle handling system. In the reticle handling operation, multiple reticles in their respective cassettes are manually loaded into a reticle library within the photolithography tool. A first reticle handler then inserts a reticle handling arm into a particular cassette to engage the reticle therein. Once engaged, the reticle is then transferred to a second reticle handler, which aligns and delivers the reticle to another location, such as a reticle stage or a pellicle inspection station (e.g., a pellicle particle detector or &ldquo;PPD&rdquo;) within the photolithography tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In many photolithography tools, successful transfer of a reticle from the cassette into its proper position in the tool requires that the reticle be properly positioned on the first reticle handler. Otherwise, the transfer (&ldquo;handoff&rdquo;) between the first and second reticle handlers can be faulty. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a prior art reticle handling system that includes a reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> that is part of a first reticle handler. The reticle handling arm is in communication with a reticle carrier <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> that is part of a second reticle handler. Reticle carrier <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> includes translatable lifting brackets <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> that are adapted to engage a reticle <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> residing on reticle arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and to lift the reticle from the reticle handling arm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> If the reticle is not properly positioned on the reticle handling arm, the lifting brackets can jam against the reticle, as shown, when attempting to engage the reticle. This can damage the reticle and/or the reticle handling arm, and/or can jam the reticle handling system, thereby causing a system failure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The consequences of faulty reticle handling can be financially serious. A jammed reticle stops production, requires expert man-hours to repair, and can damage the reticle handling system and/or the reticle itself. Reticles are relatively expensive, so that having to replace a reticle damaged by faulty handling adds cost to the manufacturing process. Accordingly, it is important in microdevice manufacturing to take appropriate steps to ensure that the likelihood of reticle handling faults is minimized.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a prior art reticle handling system having a first reticle handling arm and a reticle carrier with translatable lifting brackets, illustrating how incorrect positioning of the reticle on the reticle handling arm can result in a reticle handling fault, such as a jammed reticle as shown; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a schematic block diagram of a photolithography tool in combination with a reticle handling system according to the present invention that includes a reticle library, a first reticle handler, and a second reticle handler; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a close-up cut-away side view of the reticle library of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> showing two of the plurality of cassettes stored in the library, with a reticle in each of the shown cassettes; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a plan view of an exemplary two-support-arm reticle handling arm as part of the first reticle handler of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, showing a reticle supported by the two support arms and a reticle stop block on each support arm, wherein the reticle stop blocks serve to place the reticle at a desired position on the support arms; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> taken along the line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>B-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>B; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is a plan view similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, but showing another example embodiment of the present invention comprising a single reticle stop block attached to the base portion of the reticle handling arm; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a plan view of a reticle stop block as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> illustrating an example embodiment of a reticle stop block that slides over a support arm of the reticle handling arm and that can be fixed to the support arm using a set screw; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the reticle stop block of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a side view of the reticle handling arm and the exemplary reticle stop block of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference> prior to the reticle being engaged by the translatable lifting brackets of a reticle carrier; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is the same side view as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> subsequent to the reticle being successfully engaged and lifted by the translatable lifting brackets of the reticle carrier, in contrast to the prior art faulty reticle transfer due to reticle misplacement on the reticle handling arm as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to photolithography, and in particular to methods and apparatus for ensuring proper handling of reticles in photolithography systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In the following detailed description of the embodiments of the invention, reference is made to the accompanying drawings that form a part hereof, and in which is shown by way of illustration specific embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. These embodiments are described in sufficient detail to enable those skilled in the art to practice the invention, and it is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized and that changes may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention. The following detailed description is, therefore, not to be taken in a limiting sense, and the scope of the present invention is defined only by the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, there is shown a photolithography tool <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> that includes, in order along an axis A, an illumination system <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a reticle stage <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> adapted to support a reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so that it can receive illumination from the illumination system. Reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes an upper surface <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, a lower surface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> with a pattern <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> formed thereon, and edges <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is, in an example embodiment, made of glass, such as quartz or fused silica. Pattern <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, in exemplary embodiments, is opaque and made of chrome, a transparent dielectric, or a combination of the two. Reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> typically includes a pellicle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> arranged adjacent lower surface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and covering (but displaced from) pattern <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Pellicle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is typically formed by stretching an optically neutral polymer over a frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Further included in photolithography tool <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> along axis A is a projection lens <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and a substrate stage <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> that supports a substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to be processed. Substrate stage <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> supports substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> such that an image of pattern <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is formed on the the substrate during illumination of the reticle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> With continuing reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A and also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, operatively coupled to photolithography tool <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is a reticle handing system <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> that includes a reticle library <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> that is capable of containing a plurality of cassettes <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> each of which contains a reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment of the present invention, reticle library <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is within photolithography tool <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Reticle library <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> includes an open (or openable) side <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> that allows access to cassettes <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and reticles <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Reticle handling system <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> also includes a first reticle handler <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> in operative communication with reticle library <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> to engage and receive reticles stored therein, and a second reticle handler <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> in operative communication with the first reticle handler and reticle stage <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to engage and receive reticles on the first reticle handler and deliver them to the reticle stage or another location. For example, in addition to reticle handling system <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, an inspection station <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> may be provided so that reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be transferred thereto by second reticle handler <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and inspected prior to being transferred to photolithography tool <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and reticle stage <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Inspection station <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> may be, for example, a pellicle inspection device such as a pellicle particle detector (&ldquo;PPD&rdquo;). Further, second reticle handler <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> may include two or more reticle handling arms (not shown) that are in operate communication with a reticle carrier (described below) to facilitate the transfer of reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to inspection station <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> or reticle stage <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference>, first reticle handler <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> includes, in an example embodiment, a reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> having two spaced apart elongate support arms (&ldquo;arms&rdquo;) <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> each having an upper surface <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>. Arms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> extend horizontally outwardly from a base portion <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and are preferably parallel and spaced apart by a distance sufficient to accommodate pellicle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> between them when reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is engaged, recieved and supported. In an exemplary embodiment, arms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and base portion <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> are flat so that reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> can be easily inserted into cassette <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in reticle library <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and other areas of reticle handling system <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Base portion <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is connectable to a motor assembly (not shown) included as part of first reticle handler <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and that provides the necessary movement of arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for reticle handling. Vacuum lands <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, connected to respective vacuum lines (not shown), are included on upper surface <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> of each arm <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and are used to secure reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> by providing a vacuum seal to select areas of reticle lower surface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> once the reticle is arranged in a desired position on the handling arm. In an exemplary embodiment of the present invention, handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is made of aluminum and vacuum lands <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> are made of teflon or conductive plastic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> With continuing reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference>, reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> also includes one or more reticle stop blocks <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> each having a side edge <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>. In an example embodiment, two reticle stop blocks <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> are used, with one stop block fixed to each arm <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> near base portion <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. Reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is, in an example embodiment, made of an electrostatic dissipative material such as a polymer, e.g., polypropylene, polystyrene, polysilicon, polytetrafluoroetylene (&ldquo;TEFLON&rdquo;), etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>C, in another example embodiment of the present invention, a single reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be attached to base portion <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> between arms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, with a portion of the block extending outward to a fixed distance in the direction parallel to arms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. Reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> in this example embodiment may be formed from a block of material, such as a block of polymer, or machined from stock, such as polymer stock. Reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is then affixed to base portion <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> by a set screw, adhesive or other known affixing techniques so that side edge <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> engages reticle edge <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to define a desired position of the reticle on reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference>, an exemplary reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> of the present invention is shown. A preferred method of forming reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference> involves slicing a section (e.g., about 0.5&Prime;) of 3/8&Prime; polymer (&ldquo;poly&rdquo;) rod stock and forming a threaded bore <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> through the centerline <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. The method further includings forming a through bore <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> through side edge <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, the bore being sized to accommodate arm <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and vacuum lands <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, if present. A set screw <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> is then used to fix the position of reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> on arm <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> once the block is slid over the arm and positioned in the desired location along the arm. The desired location is that which results in the reticle residing in a desired position on arms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> after being engaged by reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, as discussed further below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> It will be apparent to one skilled in the art that any number of techniques, such as the use of adhesives, can be used to fix reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> to arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Moreover, reticle stop block can be essentially any geometrical shape. In an example embodiment, reticle stop block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> has a height H that is less than the thickness of reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so that the reticle stop block does not protrude above upper surface <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, to ensure proper clearance when loading and unloading reticles to and from cassette <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in reticle library <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> With reference again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference> and also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference>, when a particular reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> needs to be loaded onto reticle stage <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of photolithography tool <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is inserted into open side <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of library <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and into cassette <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to engage and receive the reticle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In the absence of reticle stop block(s) <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, the x-position of reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> on reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may, in some reticle handling systems, be dictated by the position of reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in cassette <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. Thus, if a reticle is not fully inserted into cassette <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> or is otherwise not properly arranged therein, the x-position of the reticle on the reticle handling arm will not be correct, i.e., will not be located at the desired position. The desired position, as mentioned above, is one that allows for the successful transfer of the reticle from first reticle handling system <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to second reticle handling system <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Arrangement of the reticle in a position other than the desired position can result in a faulty transfer of the reticle from first reticle handling system <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to second reticle handling system <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, with the negative consequences mentioned above and illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> with respect to the prior art reticle handling system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, in the present invention one or more reticle stop blocks <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> are positioned on reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> such that when the reticle handling arm is inserted into cassette <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to engage reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, reticle edge <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> makes contact with side edge <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> of the one or more stop blocks. This moves (e.g., pushes) the reticle to a desired x-position on arms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, the desired position being selected to ensure successful transfer of the reticle to second reticle handler <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, as described below. If reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is properly positioned in cassette <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, then reticle edge <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> will not touch side edge <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> of the one or more reticle stop blocks <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> during reticle engagement as the reticle adopts the desired position without the assistance of the one or more reticle stop blocks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</cross-reference>, once reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is properly loaded onto reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, the arm transports the reticle to second reticle handler <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The latter includes a reticle carrier <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> having a platen <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> that is connectable to a motor assembly (not shown) included as part of second reticle handler <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and that provides the necessary movement of reticle carrier <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> for reticle transfer. Platen <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> has a lower surface <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> from which extends opposing translatable lifting brackets <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> (also called &ldquo;fingers&rdquo;). Lifting brackets <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> are designed to separate (open) to capture reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and then close to engage the captured reticle so that it can be lifted from reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Again, in the absence of reticle stop blocks <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, there is a chance that a misalignment of the reticle on reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> relative to the desired position will cause fingers <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> to forceably contact the reticle, (e.g., jam into upper surface <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG.1</cross-reference>) and damage the reticle and/or cause a reticle jam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Once reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is properly transferred to reticle carrier <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, the reticle is then carried by the reticle carrier over to a second location. The second location may be, for example, reticle stage <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in photolithography <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the second location may be inspection station <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, such as a pellicle inspection device (e.g., a PPD), and then moved to reticle stage <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> after inspection. The reticle, once positioned in reticle stage <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, is then exposed by photolithography tool <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to pattern substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in the formation of a microdevice, as described above in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment, reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> transports reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to inspection station <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. This is accomplished by reticle arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> delivering reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to reticle carrier <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. The vacuum applied via vacuum lands <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is then released so that reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is free to move relative to arms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. Fingers <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> of reticle carrier <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> are then positioned about reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and closed. This accurately positions reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> on reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> prior to the reticle being delivered to the inspection station by the reticle handling arm. Again, if proper initial alignment of reticle <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> on reticle handling arm <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is not achieved prior to the fine alignment performed by reticle carrier <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, then there is the aforementioned risk of damage to the reticle when engaged by the reticle carrier. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Conclusion </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The present invention includes apparatus and methods that utilizes one or more reticle stop blocks in the automated handling of reticles. The one or more reticle stop blocks are positioned on a reticle handling arm for ensuring the proper positioning of a reticle thereon. Such positioning ensures the successful transfer of the reticle from the reticle handling arm to a reticle carrier so that the reticle can be successfully loaded into a photolithography tool. The use of reticle stop blocks will, for certain reticle handling systems, result in a reduced likelihood of reticle handling faults, which can damage the reticle and/or jam the reticle handling system or phototool, and which can also stop the manufacturing process. The present invention offers a simple and elegant solution to the problem of faulty reticle handling in certain reticle handling systems used in conjunction with photolithography tools. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> While the present invention has been described in connection with preferred embodiments, it will be understood that it is not so limited. On the contrary, it is intended to cover all alternatives, modifications and equivalents as may be included within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for facilitating the positioning of a reticle to a desired position on a reticle handling arm, comprising: 
<claim-text>one or more reticle stop blocks fixed to the reticle handling arm and positioned to engage an edge of the reticle being positioned on the reticle handling arm to place the reticle in the desired position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reticle handling arm has two spaced apart support arms and a reticle stop block is fixed to at least one of the support arms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the support arms include one or more vacuum lands for securing the reticle to the reticle handling arm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the support arms are spaced apart so as to accommodate a pellicle attached to the reticle when the reticle is engaged. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the one or more reticle stop blocks are formed from an electrostatic dissipative material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the one or more reticle stop blocks are fixed to the reticle handling arm using one or more set screws. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A reticle handling arm apparatus for handling a reticle, comprising: 
<claim-text>a base portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>two spaced apart support arms extending outwardly from the base portion for engaging a lower surface of the reticle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more reticle stop blocks fixed relative to the handling arm and positioned to engage an edge of the reticle so as to assure accurate placement of the reticle in a desired position on the support arms. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, including two reticle stop blocks, with one reticle stop block fixed to each support arm near the base portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, including a single reticle stop block attached to the base portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the one or more reticle stop blocks do not extend beyond an upper surface of the reticle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the support arms are spaced apart so as to accommodate a pellicle attached to the reticle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A reticle handling system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first reticle handler having a reticle handling arm that includes a base portion, two spaced apart support arms extending outwardly from the base portion for engaging a lower surface of the reticle, and one or more reticle stop blocks fixed relative to the handling arm and positioned to engage an edge of the reticle so as to assure accurate placement of the reticle in a desired position on the support arms; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second reticle handler in operative communication with the first reticle handler to engage and receive a reticle from the first reticle handler. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second reticle handler includes a reticle carrier having translatable lifting brackets adapted to engage the reticle when the reticle resides on the reticle handling arm of the first reticle handler. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a reticle library capable of containing a plurality of reticles to be engaged and received by the reticle handling arm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method of receiving a reticle in a desired position on a reticle handling arm of a reticle handler, comprising: 
<claim-text>coupling at least one reticle stop block to the reticle handling arm so as to engage an edge of the reticle to define a desired position on the reticle handling arm. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reticle handling arm has two spaced apart support arms, and including: 
<claim-text>fixing one reticle stop block to each support arm. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, further including: 
<claim-text>engaging the reticle with a second reticle handler. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, further including: 
<claim-text>transferring the reticle to a reticle stage of a photolithography tool with either the reticle handling arm or the second reticle handler. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, including: 
<claim-text>transferring the reticle to an inspection station. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, further including: 
<claim-text>forming an image of the reticle onto a substrate using the photolithography tool. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method of handling a reticle stored in a cassette, comprising: 
<claim-text>inserting a reticle handling arm into the cassette to engage and receive the reticle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting the position of the reticle on the reticle handling arm by engaging an edge of the reticle with one or more reticle stop blocks arranged on the reticle arm so as to place the reticle in a desired position relative to the reticle arm if the reticle is not properly arranged in the cassette. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reticle handling arm has two spaced apart support arms, and including: 
<claim-text>arranging at least one reticle stop block on the support arms. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, including: 
<claim-text>securing the reticle to the reticle handling arm via vacuum once the desired position is attained. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, including: 
<claim-text>engaging the reticle with a reticle carrier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, including: 
<claim-text>transferring the reticle to a second location. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second location is an inspection station. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second location is a reticle stage of a photolithography tool.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002025A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002025A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002025A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002025A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002025A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002025A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
