<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002427A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002427A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002427</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10128530</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020424</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-61041</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010929</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-23747</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010502</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11B007/24</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>369</class>
<subclass>120000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>369</class>
<subclass>275300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Optical disc having uniform structure</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kyung-Geun</given-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>In-sik</given-name>
<family-name>Park</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Du-seop</given-name>
<family-name>Yoon</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>STAAS &amp; HALSEY LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>700 11TH STREET, NW</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 500</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An optical disc is manufactured under a uniform condition by forming grooves and lands on the entire surface of the disc. The optical disc is configured to obtain a reliable reproduction signal, and the grooves and lands are formed on a lead-in area, a user data area and a lead-out area of the optical disc. Since the same manufacturing condition can be adopted in mastering discs, the yield can be enhanced and the manufacturing cost can be reduced. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of Korean Application Nos. 2001-61041, filed Sep. 29, 2001 and 2001-23747, filed May 2, 2001, in the Korean Industrial Property Office, the disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an optical disc which can be manufactured under uniform conditions by forming grooves and lands on the entire surface of the disc having a lead-in area, a user data area and a lead-out area, and which is configured to obtain a highly reliable recording/reproduced signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In general, optical discs are widely employed as information recording media for an optical pickup device which records/reproduces information in a non-contact manner. They are classified into compact discs (CDs) and digital versatile discs (DVDs) according to information recording capacity. Furthermore, a DVD disc capable of writing, erasing and reading information can be sub-divided into a digital versatile disc-random access memory (DVD-RAM) disc and a digital versatile disc-rewritable (DVD-RW) disc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a conventional DVD-RAM or DVD-RW disc having a lead-in area <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a user data area <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a lead-out area <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The lead-in area <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> contains read only data, such as the disc size, number of track layers on a readable plane or illegal copy preventing information. The user data area <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> contains user data that can be repeatedly read and/or written. The lead-out area <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> contains other disc-related information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> further shows a partially enlarged view of the lead-in area <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (a portion A), the user data area <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (a portion C) and the lead-out area <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (a portion B). In the lead-in area <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the lead-out area <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, pits <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are used to record read only data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In the user data area <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, grooves <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and lands <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are alternatively formed to accommodate recording and/or reproducing information marks <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> along a predetermined track. Here, a reference numeral <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> denotes a reproduction beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A noticeable difference between a DVD-RAM and a DVD-RW is a physical area provided for recording. In other words, the DVD-RAM performs recording on both the lands <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the grooves <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, while the DVD-RW performs recording only on the grooves <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Application of these two standard formats results in the following problems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> First, while a DVD-RW having the same physical recording structure as a DVD-ROM (read only disc) has an excellent reproduction compatibility in DVD-ROM drives or DVD players, a DVD-RAM having a phase difference corresponding to depths of a land and a groove requires hardware modification to suitably track lands and grooves. Therefore, a conventional DVD-RAM has a poor reproduction compatibility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Second, in the context of recording/reproduction characteristics or injection-molding characteristics in recording data on a groove, the grooves formed in a DVD-RW are two or more times shallower than that in a DVD-RAM. Here, if necessary, read only data is formed on the lead-in area <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a form of pits <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a graph illustrating an amplitude ratio of a reproduced signal with respect to a pit depth represented in &lgr;/n unit for a wavelength (&lgr;) of a reproduced beam to a refractive index (n) of a disc. In cases where the lengths of a recording mark for the minimum recording mark length T are 3T and 14T, the amplitude ratios denoted by m<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and m<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>are in a range of between 0.2 and 0.3 where the pit depth (corresponding to a groove depth of a DVD-RW) is approximately 0.06 in &lgr;/n unit. The amplitude ratio is approximately 1 where the pit depth is approximately 0.25. Accordingly, the signal level at the pit depth of &lgr;/12n is approximately 30% (1:0.3) as compared to the case where the pit depth is &lgr;/4n. Therefore, a reliable pit signal cannot be obtained where read only data as shallow as a groove depth of a DVD-RW is formed in a DVD-RAM. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Third, there is a demand for a multi-layered optical disc having a plurality of recording layers, looking from the direction of an incident beam, to enhance the recording capacity. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a dual recording layer disc having a first recording layer L<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and a second recording layer L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A recording laser passes through the first recording layer L<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> where a recording is performed on the second recording layer L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In this case, there is a difference in light power between a pit portion and a groove portion. Also, where a physical header representing a basic recording unit in a data area is used, there is a difference in light transmittance because unlike the recording area, the physical header area always remains crystallized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a graph illustrating light power for each of a mirror portion, pit portion, groove portion and a groove portion with marks. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the physical geometry of the first recording layer L<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> affects the light power. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Table 1 below lists conditions used in the light power experiments.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="133PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Parameter</entry>
<entry>Condition</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Wavelength (nm)</entry>
<entry>400</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Numerical aperture (NA)</entry>
<entry>0.65/0.85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Minimum mark length (&mgr;m)</entry>
<entry>0.275/0.194</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Modulation</entry>
<entry>EFM &plus; (Eight-to-Fourteen Modulation-plus)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Track pitch (&mgr;m)</entry>
<entry>0.30, 0.34, 0.38</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Reflectivity (%)</entry>
<entry>Rc &equals; 25, Ra &equals; 5</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In Table 1, Rc represents the reflectivity of a crystallized portion of a recording layer and Ra represents the reflectivity of an amorphous portion of a recording layer. According to the experimental results, the smallest decrease in the light power was found in the mirror portion. The light power gradually decreased, in order, with the physical geometry of a pit portion, a groove portion and a groove portion with marks. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows that a recording/ reproducing beam <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is trapped over a boundary of the lead-in area <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the first recording layer L<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and the data area <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> having grooves. Accordingly, the amount of the light beam irradiated onto the second recording layer L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is different from the case where a recording/reproducing beam <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extends over only to the grooves. Therefore, the groove portion with marks adversely affects the recording power as the data is written on the second recording layer L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the dual-layered optical disc, resulting in a poor recording/reproduction efficiency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Fourth, in order to reduce a spot size of a reproducing beam to attain high-density, a numerical aperture (NA) should be increased. However, the problem with a dual recording layer disc is that a difference in light power becomes more serious as the NA increases. Factors causing the difference in the light power with increased NA are listed in Table 2 below.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="105PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center">TABLE 2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Item</entry>
<entry>Parameter</entry>
<entry>Example</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Dual recording</entry>
<entry>Structure of first recording layer</entry>
<entry>Grooves, pits, etc.,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>layers</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>High NA</entry>
<entry>Number of tracks trapped by beam</entry>
<entry>85 for NA 0.65</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>160 for NA 0.85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Incident angle of beam</entry>
<entry>40.5&deg; for NA 0.65</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>58.2&deg; for NA 0.85</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> As shown in Table 2, with the grooves and pits formed on the first recording layer of a dual recording layer disc, the number of tracks trapped by a beam and the incident beam angle increase as the NA is increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Finally, the manufacturing conditions of the disc mastering may vary depending on different structures of the disc in a lead-in area (pits), a data area (grooves) and a lead-out area (pits). This makes the manufacturing process complex, resulting in a poor yield and an increased manufacturing cost. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to provide an optical disc with an improved yield, a reduced manufacturing cost and an improved recording/reproducing capacity, by forming grooves in both a lead-in area and a lead-out area so as to have the same manufacturing conditions for discs during mastering. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide an optical disc having an improved structure of multiple recording layers such that light power is uniformly irradiated to the multi-layered disc during recording/reproducing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Additional objects and advantages of the invention will be set forth in part in the description which follows, and, in part, will be obvious from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> To achieve the above and other objects of the present invention, there is provided an optical disc for recording and/or reproduction, wherein grooves and lands are provided to a lead-in area, a user data area and a lead-out area of the optical disc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the present invention wobbles are formed on at least one side of the grooves and lands as read only data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, the wobbles in the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area may be modulated by the same modulation technique or by different modulation techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The wobbles may be modulated by a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) technique or by a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique in which a wobbled portion of a single frequency having a predetermined period and a non-wobbled portion having a predetermined period are merged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the wobbles may be modulated by a frequency modulation technique, an amplitude modulation technique, a phase modulation technique, a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique or a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the wobbles in the user data area may be modulated by at least one selected from a QPSK modulation, a frequency modulation, an amplitude modulation, a MAM modulation, a phase modulation, a MSK modulation and a STW modulation, and the wobbles in the lead-in area and the lead-out area are modulated by a modulation technique different from that of the wobbles in the user data area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The optical disc according to the present invention comprises at least one recording layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> An optical disc for recording and/or reproduction according to another embodiment of the present invention comprises a lead-in area, a user data area and a lead-out area, wherein each have grooves and lands formed thereon, and data in the user data area is recorded on at least one side of the lands and grooves. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> An optical disc for recording and/or reproduction according to yet another embodiment of the present invention comprises a lead-in area, a user data area and a lead-out area, wherein each have grooves and lands formed thereon, and the lead-in area further includes a read only data area and a write/read data area.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> These and other objects and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent and more readily appreciated from the following description of the preferred embodiment, taken in conjunction with the accompanying attached drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagram of a conventional optical disc with enlarged views illustrating portions A, B and C; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a graph illustrating the amplitude ratio of a reproduced signal with respect to a pit depth; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a diagram of a partial cross-sectional view illustrating a conventional optical disc; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a graph illustrating light power with respect to a mirror portion, a pit portion, a groove portion and a groove portion with marks; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a diagram of an optical disc according to an embodiment of the present invention with enlarged views illustrating portions D, E and F; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating a one-side wobbling method adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating a wobble-and-land prepit combination method adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</cross-reference> is a diagram of waveforms obtained from wobbles based on a frequency modulation technique adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</cross-reference> is a diagram of waveforms obtained from wobbles based on a phase modulation technique adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8C</cross-reference> is a diagram of waveforms obtained from wobbles based on an amplitude modulation technique adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8D</cross-reference> is a diagram of waveforms obtained from wobbles based on a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a diagram of wobbles based on a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) technique adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a diagram of waveforms obtained from wobbles based on a Minimum Shift Keying (MSK) modulation technique adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a diagram of waveforms obtained from wobbles based on a Surface Transverse Wave (STW) modulation technique adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating wobbles with different track pitches adopted by an optical disc according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating a lead-in area of an optical disc according to yet another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating a header field and a read only data field of the optical disc of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating an example of an optical recording/reproducing system which records and/or reproduces data from an optical disc of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows an optical disc according to an embodiment of the present invention. The optical disc includes a lead-in area <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a user data area <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and a lead-out area <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, and grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> that are formed on the entire surface thereof. User data can be recorded on only the grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> or on both the grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and the lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. Where read only data is recorded, waveforms of wobble signals <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> are consecutively recorded on at least one side of the grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, instead of pits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> An enlarged view of portions D and E shows that the grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and the lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> are alternately formed in the lead-in and lead-out areas <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, and waveform wobble signals <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> are formed on both the grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and the lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. A portion F shows that the grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and the lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> are alternately formed in the user data area <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and the wobble signals <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> are formed on both the grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and the lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. Recording and/or reproduction are performed while a recording/reproduction beam <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> travels along groove and/or land tracks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a one-side wobbling method in which wobbles <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>&prime; are formed on at least one side of the lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>&prime; and grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>&prime;. Alternatively, wobbles may be formed on both sides of the grooves <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>&prime; and lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows that an optical disc according to another embodiment of the present invention may record read only data by a combination of wobbles <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> and land prepits <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> formed on lands <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> at predetermined intervals. The land prepits <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> are formed on a predetermined area during the manufacture of a disc substrate. A pickup device provided in a recording/reproducing apparatus (not shown) can easily move to a desired location using the information recorded in the land prepits <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. Also, the pickup device can identify a sector number or type, a land/groove or the like, and perform a servo control using the information recorded in forms of land prepits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As described above, the optical disc of the present invention has read only data recorded as wobble signals rather than pits, and the physical geometry of the recording layer is the same throughout the entire surface of the optical disc. Therefore, the optical disc of the present invention having multiple layers has less reduction in light power than a conventional optical disc having multiple layers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</cross-reference> shows an example of a wobble signal modulation adopted by an optical disc of the present invention. Specifically, a frequency modulation technique is used, and data is memorized by changing frequencies of wobble signals <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>&prime;. For example, data is recorded in combinations of bits of logic &ldquo;0&rdquo; or &ldquo;1&rdquo;. Data is recorded in such a manner that the frequencies of the wobble signals <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>&prime; are made different in cases of the bits of logic &ldquo;0&rdquo; and logic &ldquo;1&rdquo;, respectively. For example, the frequency of the wobble signal of the logic &ldquo;0&rdquo; is greater than that of the logic &ldquo;1&rdquo;, so as to distinguish the bits having logic values &ldquo;0&rdquo; and &ldquo;1&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</cross-reference> shows that a phase modulation technique may be used in recording data, whereby phases of wobble signals <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>&prime; are shifted. That is, data is recorded in such a manner that the phases of the wobble signals in cases of bits of logic &ldquo;0&rdquo; and bits of logic &ldquo;1&rdquo; are made different. For example, a phase difference of 180&deg; is made between the wobble signal of the logic &ldquo;0&rdquo; and the wobble signal of the logic &ldquo;1&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8C</cross-reference> shows that wobble signals can also be modulated by an amplitude modulation technique. That is, data is recorded in such a manner that amplitudes of wobble signals of bits of logic &ldquo;0&rdquo; and &ldquo;1&rdquo; are made different. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8D</cross-reference> shows that data may be recorded by a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique, in which a wobbled portion <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> of a single frequency having a predetermined period and/or a non-wobbled portion <highlight><bold>137</bold></highlight> having a predetermined period, are merged. For example, the lengths of neighboring wobbled portions or the lengths of neighboring non-wobbled portions are made different, thereby recording data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> In addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows that data can be recorded by a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation, whereby the phases of the respective wobble signals <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> are different from each other at 90&deg;. Here, a reference numeral <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> denotes a recording mark corresponding to user data. As described above, where read only data is recorded as wobble signals, both the user data and the read only data are stored in the groove and/or land tracks, thereby enhancing the utilization efficiency of a recording area of a disc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> shows that data can be recorded by a Minimum Shift Keying (MSK) modulation, whereby only the frequencies in a predetermined period comprising consecutive wobble signals <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> are varied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows that a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation may be employed, whereby saw tooth wobbles <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are formed. The logic states &ldquo;0&rdquo; or &ldquo;1&rdquo; of the saw tooth wobbles <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are determined by the shapes of a relatively sharply sloping portion <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a relatively gently sloping portion <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> shows that a crosstalk between tracks can be reduced by making track pitches TP<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and TP<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of wobbles different. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> shows a lead-in area of an optical disc according to yet another embodiment of the present invention. That is, a read only data area <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and a write/read data area <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> are provided in the lead-in area (i.e., <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>) of the optical disc. In the read only data area <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, data is recorded by first wobbles. In the write/read data area <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, second wobbles are formed. The first and second wobbles may be modulated by different modulation techniques or indicated by different specifications. In other words, the first wobbles are modulated by at least one selected from a QPSK modulation, a frequency modulation, an amplitude modulation, a phase modulation a MAM modulation, a MSK modulation and an STW modulation, and the second wobbles are modulated by a modulation technique different from that for the first wobbles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, shows an example of a header field <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and a read only data field <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the optical disc shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. That is, address information is contained in the entire area of the grooves in the write/read area <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, and the header field <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, indicating the address information, and the read only data field <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are provided in the read only data area <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. The header field <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may be positioned at the front or rear of an error correction code (ECC) recording unit or at the interface of ECC recording units. Here, the specification of wobbles in the header field <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may be identical with or different from that of wobbles in the write/read data area <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> or read only data area <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. In particular, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, wobbles formed in the read only data field <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the read only data area <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> are high-frequency wobbles and wobbles formed in the header field <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and the write/read data area <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> are low-frequency wobbles. This arrangement prevents a reproduction signal from deteriorating as the address information contained in the header field <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is recorded at high frequency. Also, to reduce the crosstalk between the tracks, track pitches from the write/read data area <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and the read only data area <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> may be set differently from each other. For example, the track pitch for the read only data area <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> may be greater than that of the write/read data area <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The optical disc of the present invention may further include a predetermined area formed for a specific purpose in addition to the lead-in area <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the data area <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the lead-out area <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. For example, the predetermined area may be a burst cutting area (BCA) for copy protection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating an example of an optical disc recording/reproducing system which records and/or reproduces data from an optical disc of the present invention. The system includes a laser diode <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> which radiates light, a collimating lens <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> which collimates the light radiated from the laser diode <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, a polarizing beam splitter <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> which changes the traveling path of incident light according to the polarization direction of the incident light, a &frac14; wavelength plate <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and an objective lens <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> which focuses the incident light onto an optical disc <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. The light reflected from the optical disc <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is reflected by the polarizing beam splitter <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and received by a photodetector, e.g., a quadrant photodetector <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. The light received in the quadrant photodetector <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> is converted into an electrical signal and output to a channel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, in which the electrical signal is detected as an RF signal, and to a channel <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, in which the electrical signal is detected as a wobble signal by a push-pull method. Here, H<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, H<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, H<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and H<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> denote DC amplifiers, and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>denote first through fourth current signals output from the quadrant photodetector <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> According to an optical disc of the present invention, read only data can be formed by various modulation schemes described above. In particular, wobble signals can be formed on the lead-in area <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the lead-out area <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and the user data area <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> by the same modulation technique. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, wobbles can be formed by different modulation techniques according to the disc area, that is, the lead-in area <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the user data area <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> or the lead-out area <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. For example, at least one selected from a frequency modulation, a phase modulation, an amplitude modulation, a MAM modulation, a QPSK modulation, a MSK modulation and an STW modulation can be employed in the user data area <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Then, a modulation technique different from that employed in the user data area <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, may be employed in the lead-in area <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and the lead-out area <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> To increase the storage capacity, the present invention provides a disc having at least one recording layer. For example, a dual recording-layer disc of the present invention comprises grooves and lands which are formed on the entire surface of the dual recording-layer disc, and read only data which is formed uniformly as wobble signals. Thus, there is no difference in the light power at the boundary between the lead-in area or lead-out area and the user data area. Furthermore, efficiency of a recording area is enhanced because the read only data is recorded as wobble signals, allowing both the user data and the read only data to be stored in the groove and/or land tracks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In the optical disc according to the present invention, grooves are consecutively formed throughout the entire surface of the disc, which eases the manufacturability and provides advantages from the viewpoint of controllability of mastering parameters. Also, since the same manufacturing condition can be adopted in mastering discs, the yield can be enhanced and the manufacturing cost can be reduced. Furthermore, the light power can be uniformly adjusted while recording/reproducing data on/from a multiple-layered disc, by forming read only data as wobbles rather than pits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Although a few embodiments of the present invention have been shown and described, it would be appreciated by those skilled in the art that changes may be made in this embodiment without departing from the principles and spirit of the invention, the scope of which is defined in the claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An optical disc for recording and/or reproduction, comprising: 
<claim-text>a lead-in area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a user data area; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lead-out area, wherein each of the lead-in area, the user area and the lead-out area includes grooves and lands formed thereon. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the grooves and lands include wobbles which are formed on at least one side of the grooves and lands as read only data. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area are modulated by the same modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area are modulated by different modulation techniques. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique in which a wobbled portion of a single frequency having a period and a non-wobbled portion having a period are merged. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a frequency modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by an amplitude modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a phase modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique in which only frequencies in a period having consecutive wobbles are varied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the user data area are modulated by one of a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation technique, a frequency modulation technique, an amplitude modulation technique, a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique, a phase modulation technique, a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique and a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique, and the wobbles in the lead-in area and the lead-out area are modulated by at least one different modulation technique from that for the wobbles in the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes at least one recording layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a specific purpose area in addition to the lead-in area, the lead-out area and the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes at least one recording layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a specific purpose area in addition to the lead-in area, the lead-out area and the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique in which a wobbled portion of a single frequency having a period and a non-wobbled portion having a period are merged. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a frequency modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by an amplitude modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a phase modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique in which only frequencies in a period having consecutive wobbles are varied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes at least one recording layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a specific purpose area in addition to the lead-in area, the lead-out area and the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An optical disc for recording and/or reproduction, comprising: 
<claim-text>a lead-in area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a user data area; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lead-out area, wherein 
<claim-text>each of the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area includes grooves and lands formed thereon, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the user data area further includes data which is recorded on at least one side of the lands and the grooves. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the grooves and/or the lands include wobbles which are formed as read only data. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area are modulated by the same modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area are modulated by different modulation techniques. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique in which a wobbled portion of a single frequency having a period and a non-wobbled portion having a period are merged. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a frequency modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by an amplitude modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a phase modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique in which only frequencies in a period having consecutive wobbles are varied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the user data area are modulated by one of a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation technique, a frequency modulation technique, an amplitude modulation technique, a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique, a phase modulation technique, a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique and a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique, and the wobbles in the lead-in area and the lead-out area are modulated by at least one different modulation technique from that for the wobbles in the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a specific purpose area in addition to the lead-in area, the lead-out area and the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes at least one recording layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a specific purpose area in addition to the lead-in area, the lead-out area and the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes at least one recording layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. An optical disc for recording and/or reproduction, comprising: 
<claim-text>a lead-in area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a user data area; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lead-out area, wherein 
<claim-text>each of the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area includes grooves and lands formed thereon, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the lead-in area further includes a read only data area and a write/read data area. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the grooves and/or the lands include wobbles which are formed as read only data. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area are modulated by the same modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the lead-in area, the user data area and the lead-out area are modulated by different modulation techniques. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique in which a wobbled portion of a single frequency having a period and a non-wobbled portion having a period are merged. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a frequency modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by an amplitude modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a phase modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique in which only frequencies in a period having consecutive wobbles are varied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles are modulated by a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles in the user data area are modulated by one of a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation technique, a frequency modulation technique, an amplitude modulation technique, a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique, a phase modulation technique, a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique and a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique, and the wobbles in the lead-in area and the lead-out area are modulated by at least one different modulation technique from that for the wobbles in the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a specific purpose area in addition to the lead-in area, the lead-out area and the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes at least one recording layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the read only data area includes first wobbles; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the write/read data area includes second wobbles, wherein the second wobbles are modulated by a modulation technique different from that for the first wobbles. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first wobbles are modulated by one of a Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) modulation technique, a frequency modulation technique, an amplitude modulation technique, a Modified Amplitude Modulation (MAM) technique, a phase modulation technique, a minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation technique and a saw tooth wobble (STW) modulation technique, and the second wobbles are modulated by a different modulation technique from that for the first wobbles. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first wobbles are high-frequency wobbles with respect to the second wobbles and the second wobbles are low-frequency wobbles with respect to the first wobbles. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 58</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the read only data area further includes a header field which is positioned at a front or a rear of an error correction code (ECC) recording unit or at the interface of ECC recording units, and indicates address information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 59</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wobbles formed at the header field are the low-frequency wobbles. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the read only data area further includes a header field which is positioned at a front or a rear of an error correction code (ECC) recording unit or at the interface of ECC recording units, and indicates address information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the write/read data area has a track pitch different from that of the read only data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the track pitch for the read only data area is greater than that of the write/read data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the write/read data area has a track pitch different from that of the read only data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 64</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the track pitch for the read only data area is greater than that of the write/read data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes multiple recording layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00067">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes multiple recording layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00068">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical disc includes multiple recording layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00069">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. An optical disc for recording and/or reproduction, comprising recording layers having a lead-in, user data and lead-out areas, wherein each of the lead-in, user data and lead-out areas includes grooves and lands formed thereon so as to prevent a light power difference at a boundary between the lead-in area or lead-out area, and the user data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00070">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. An optical recording and/or reproducing apparatus which records and/or reproduces data from an optical disc which includes recording layers having a lead-in, user data and lead-out areas, wherein each of the lead-in, user data and lead-out areas includes grooves and lands formed thereon, comprising: 
<claim-text>a laser diode which radiates light; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a collimating lens which collimates the light radiated from the laser diode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a polarizing beam splitter which changes a path of the light according to a polarization direction of the light; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an objective lens which focuses the light onto the optical disc; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a photodetector which receives the light uniformly irradiated and reflected from the lead-in, user and lead-out areas having the grooves and the lands formed thereon. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00071">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The optical recording and/or reproducing apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 70</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the user data area of the optical disc further includes information which is recorded on at least one side of the lands and the grooves. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00072">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The optical recording and/or reproducing apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 70</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lead-in area of the optical disc further includes a read only data area and a write/read data area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00073">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the specific purpose area is a burst cutting area (BCA). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00074">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the specific purpose area is a burst cutting area (BCA). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00075">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the specific purpose area is a burst cutting area (BCA). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00076">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the specific purpose area is a burst cutting area (BCA). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00077">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. The optical disc according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the specific purpose area is a burst cutting area (BCA).</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002427A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
