<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002030A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002030A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002030A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002030A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002030A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002030A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002030</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894169</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01N021/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>356</class>
<subclass>073100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>OPTICAL CROSS-SWITCH SIGNAL MONITORING METHOD AND SYSTEM THEREFOR</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dale</given-name>
<family-name>Schroeder</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Scotts Valley</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>AGILENT TECHNOLOGIES, INC.</name-1>
<name-2>Legal Department, DL429</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Intellectual Property Administration</address-1>
<address-2>P.O. Box 7599</address-2>
<city>Loveland</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80537-0599</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method and device are provided for monitoring a light signal in an optical switch having a first waveguide and a second waveguide that intersect a first trench such that optical coupling is dependent upon a fluid being at the first trench, and having a test waveguide that intersects a second trench such that optical coupling is dependent upon the fluid being at the second trench. By changing the fluid at the first trench to switch the optical switch to cause a light signal to be reflected from the first waveguide into the second waveguide and by partially changing the fluid at the second trench to switch the optical switch to cause a portion of the light signal to be reflected from the first waveguide into the test waveguide. The portion of the light signal in the test waveguide can be monitored using a light. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates generally to optical cross-switches and more particularly to a detector for monitoring signals in optical cross-switches. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In the past, telecommunications and data communications networks have traditionally relied on electrical signals transmitted electrically on conductive lines. As higher and higher data exchange rates are required, conductive lines are no longer sufficient and increasingly the data is transmitted through the use of optical signals through optical fibers. Equipment for efficiently generating and transmitting the optical signals has been designed and implemented, but the manufacturability of optical switches for use in telecommunications and data communications networks is problematic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Fouquet et al. (U.S. Pat. No. 5,699,462), which is assigned to the assignee of the present invention, describes a switching matrix that is used for routing optical signals from any one of a number of parallel input optical fibers to any one of a number of parallel output optical fibers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> (PRIOR ART), therein is shown an isolated optical switching element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> formed on a substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is of silicon or silica. The optical switching element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes planar waveguides defined by a lower cladding layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a core <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and an upper cladding layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The core <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is primarily silicon dioxide, but other materials that affect the index of refraction of the core may be used. The cladding layers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are formed of a material having a refractive index that is substantially different from the refractive index of the core material, so that optical signals are guided along the core material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In the manufacturing process, the core <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is patterned to define an input waveguide <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and an output waveguide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of a first waveguide path and to define an input waveguide <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and an output waveguide <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of a second waveguide path. The upper cladding layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is then deposited over the core <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A trench <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is etched through the core <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> at the intersection of the first and second waveguide paths and the two cladding layers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to the substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The waveguide paths intersect the trench <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> at an angle of incidence greater than the critical angle of total internal reflection (TIR) when the trench <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is filled with a fluid, which can be a liquid, plasma, or a gas, having a refractive index which closely matches the refractive index of the waveguides; thus, light is transmitted to a &ldquo;through&rdquo; path to the output waveguide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> when fluid is present in the trench <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Thus, TIR diverts light from the input waveguide <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at a region <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to a &ldquo;reflected&rdquo; path to the output waveguide <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, unless an index-matching fluid is located within the gap between the aligned waveguides <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The trench <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is positioned in a &ldquo;forward&rdquo; position with respect to the four waveguides <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> such that one sidewall of the trench <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> passes through or is slightly offset from the intersection of the axes of the waveguide paths on the side away from the input of the input waveguide <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> (PRIOR ART), therein is shown a plurality of the optical switching elements <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a 4 times 4 matrix <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In the 4 times 4 matrix <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, any one of four input waveguides <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may be optically coupled to any one of four output waveguides <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The switching arrangement is referred to as &ldquo;non-blocking,&rdquo; since any free input waveguide can be connected to any free output waveguide regardless of which connections have already been made through the switching arrangement. Each of the sixteen optical switches has a trench that causes TIR in the absence of an index-matching fluid at the gap between collinear waveguides, but collinear waveguides of a particular waveguide path are optically coupled when the gaps between the collinear waveguides are filled with the refractive index-matching fluid. Trenches in which the waveguide gaps are filled with fluid are represented by fine lines that extend at an angle through the intersections of optical waveguides in the array. On the other hand, trenches in which the index-matching fluid is absent at the gaps are represented by broad lines through a point of intersection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> For example, the input waveguide <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> (PRIOR ART) is in optical communication with the output waveguide <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as a result of reflection at the empty gap of the trench <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Since all other cross points for allowing the input waveguide <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to communicate with the output waveguide <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are in a transmissive state, a signal that is generated at the input waveguide <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> will be received at output waveguide <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. In like manner, the input waveguide <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is optically coupled to the first output waveguide <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the third input waveguide <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is optically coupled to the fourth output waveguide <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and the fourth input waveguide <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is coupled to the third output waveguide <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> There are a number of available techniques for changing an optical switch of the type shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> from a transmissive state to a reflective state and back to the transmissive state. One method of changing states involves forming and eliminating the gap by forming and removing vapor bubbles in a refractive index-matching fluid. A plurality of heating elements are used where the application of heat to a trench forms the vapor bubble to remove the fluid and the removal of the heat causes the vapor bubble to collapse and return the fluid. The heating elements and their control are well known in the art and are used in ink jet printers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The refractive index-matching fluid is supplied from a reservoir under the trench and resides within the trench in the waveguide paths until a vapor bubble is formed to create an index mismatch and cause light to be reflected at the sidewall of a trench. Collapsing the vapor bubble returns the switch to the transmissive state. A bubble forms in less than 1 ms when heat is applied and collapses in less than 1 ms when heat is removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the optical switching element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, light coming in is from an independent outside source and the light going out goes to an independent outside receiver, neither of which can be tapped for information. Unlike an electrical circuit where it is possible to make a parallel test connection, in optical circuits, parallel connections cause losses in the signal. Further, an external coupler is required for each waveguide and must be attached for each monitoring operation, which makes uninterrupted monitoring of the optical switching element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> costly and time consuming. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art have long sought, with little success, a way to be able to perform inexpensive uninterrupted monitoring of optical switches. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a method of monitoring a light signal in an optical switch having a first waveguide and a second waveguide that intersect a first trench such that optical coupling is dependent upon a fluid being at the first trench, and having a test waveguide that intersects a second trench such that optical coupling is dependent upon the fluid being at the second trench. By changing the fluid at the first trench to switch the optical switch to cause a light signal to be reflected from the first waveguide into the second waveguide and by partially changing the fluid at the second trench to switch the optical switch to cause a portion of the light signal to be reflected from the first waveguide into the test waveguide. The portion of the light signal in the test waveguide can be monitored using a light monitor for inexpensive uninterrupted monitoring of the optical switch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention further provides an optical switch for a light signal monitoring system. The system includes a support structure having a first waveguide and a second waveguide that intersect a first trench such that optical coupling is dependent upon a fluid being at the first trench, and a test waveguide that intersects a second trench such that optical coupling is dependent upon the fluid being at the second trench. A mechanism is provided for changing the fluid at the first trench to switch the optical switch to cause a light signal to be reflected from the first waveguide into the second waveguide and a mechanism for partially changing the fluid at the second trench to switch the optical switch to cause a portion of the light signal to be reflected from the first waveguide into the test waveguide which can be monitored using a light monitor for inexpensive uninterrupted monitoring of the optical switch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The above and additional advantages of the present invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art from a reading of the following detailed description when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> (PRIOR ART) is a top view of an optical switching element that utilizes total internal reflection in accordance with the prior art; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> (PRIOR ART) is a 4 times 4 matrix of switching elements of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to allow connection of any one of a number of input waveguides to any one of a number of output waveguides in accordance with the prior art; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a 4 times 4 matrix of switching elements having a test column and test row waveguides, which allow monitoring an optical cross-connect switch in a system in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, therein are shown a plurality of optical switching elements <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> in a 4 times 4 matrix <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> on a support structure (not shown). In the 4 times 4 matrix <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, any one of four input waveguides <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may be optically coupled to any one of four output waveguides <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. The switching arrangement is referred to as &ldquo;non-blocking,&rdquo; since any free input waveguide can be connected to any free output waveguide regardless of which connections have already been made through the switching arrangement. Each of the sixteen optical switches has a trench that causes Total Internal Reflection (TIR) in the absence of an index-matching fluid at the gap between collinear waveguides, but collinear waveguides of a particular waveguide path are optically coupled when the gaps between the collinear waveguides are filled with the refractive index-matching fluid. The trenches in which the waveguide gaps are filled with fluid are represented by fine lines that extend at an angle through the intersections of optical waveguides in the array. On the other hand, broad lines through a point of intersection represent trenches in which the index-matching fluid is absent at the gaps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> For example, the input waveguide <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is in optical communication with the output waveguide <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> as a result of reflection at the empty gap of a trench <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> in the optical switching element <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Since all other cross points for allowing the input waveguide <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> to communicate with the output waveguide <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> are in a transmissive state, a signal that is generated for the input waveguide <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> will be output only at the output waveguide <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In the present invention, monitoring waveguides are present in the 4 times 4 matrix <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> in the form of a test column <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> and a test row <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> having associated trenches in the same manner as the other waveguides. The test column <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> can have all &ldquo;forward&rdquo; positioned trenches except for the trench at the intersection with the test row <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> or can have all &ldquo;reversed&rdquo; position trenches where the trenches pass through or are slightly offset from the intersection of the axes of the waveguide paths toward the input side of the input waveguides. The test row <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> has all &ldquo;reversed&rdquo; position trenches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In developing the present invention, it was unexpectedly discovered that by using a heater resistor for heating the fluid in a trench caused a change in its index of refraction, which caused a partial mirroring effect. Further, it was observed that, when a bubble begins to form, it forms as a sphere and moves up into the trench as more vapor is formed as the fluid is brought to its boiling point by applying more power to the heater resistor. The bubble squeezes against the front edge of the trench and it has a rounded top on it. The rounded top first scatters light from the input waveguide into the output waveguide. As the bubble grows, it starts to flatten in the trench and to mirror the light. As the bubble grows fully, a full mirror effect is established and the light from the input waveguide is fully reflected into the output waveguide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Using the test column <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> and the test row <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, it is has been found to be possible to monitor any signal input by heating the fluid in a trench using the same resistor used to form the switching bubble but by applying a much lower power. When the fluid is heated, its index of refraction changes causing some of the signal to take a &ldquo;switched&rdquo; path while the majority of the signal continues on the through path. Similarly, the heating can also be controlled to produce a partial bubble, which also causes some of the signal to take the switched path. The ability to control the heating to change the refractive index and control the formation of the bubble allows control of the degree of the TIR mirror effect. As a result, the signal may be &ldquo;tapped&rdquo; without a significant signal loss. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A light receiver can monitor the tapped signal or monitor by being connected to either the output of the test column <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> or of the test row <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> For example, in unmonitored operation, the light signal is transmitted along the input waveguide <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> where a bubble in the trench <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> causes reflection into the output waveguide <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. To monitor the light signal in the input waveguide <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> and the output waveguide <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, a bubble is formed at low power in a trench of a switching element such as a trench <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> of the optical switching element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to direct a tapped signal (shown as a dotted line) to a monitor <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As would be evident, monitoring could also be performed of any input waveguide by forming a bubble at low power an appropriately positioned trench in the test column <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> to provide the tapped signal to an alternate monitor <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Also, more than one trench in the column <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> could be turned on at low power to monitor any activity into the 4 times 4 matrix <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> without requiring scanning. Similarly, monitoring could also be performed of any output waveguide using an appropriately positioned trench in the test row <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> to provide the tapped signal to the monitor <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in conjunction with a specific best mode, it is to be understood that many alternatives, modifications, and variations will be apparent to those skilled in the art in light of the aforegoing description. Accordingly, it is intended to embrace all such alternatives, modifications, and variations that fall within the spirit and scope of the included claims. All matters hither-to-fore set forth or shown in the accompanying drawings are to be interpreted in an illustrative and non-limiting sense. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">The invention claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of monitoring a light signal in a fluid containing device comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a fluid containing device having a plurality of optical waveguides and a plurality of trenches provided therein, including: 
<claim-text>a first waveguide and a second waveguide that intersect a first trench such that optical coupling between the first and second waveguides is dependent upon a fluid being at the first trench, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a test waveguide that intersects a second trench such that optical coupling between the test and first waveguides is dependent upon the fluid being at the second trench; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>changing the fluid at the first trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause a light signal to be reflected between the first and second waveguides; </claim-text>
<claim-text>partially changing the fluid at the second trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause a portion of the light signal to be reflected between the test and first waveguides; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring the portion of the light signal in the test waveguide using a light monitor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fluid containing device includes a second test waveguide that intersects a third trench such that optical coupling between the test waveguides is dependent upon the fluid being at the third trench including: 
<claim-text>changing the fluid at the third trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected from the test waveguide into the second test waveguide; and wherein: 
<claim-text>monitoring the portion of the light signal in the test waveguide is performed through the second test waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fluid containing device includes a third waveguide that intersects a third trench such that optical coupling between the first and third waveguides is dependent upon the fluid being at the second trench and a second test waveguide intersects a fourth trench such that such that optical coupling between the second test and third waveguides is dependent upon the fluid being at the fourth trench including: 
<claim-text>partially changing the fluid at the third trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the first and third waveguides; </claim-text>
<claim-text>changing the fluid at the fourth trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the second test and third waveguides; and wherein: 
<claim-text>monitoring the portion of the light signal in the third waveguide is performed through the second test waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein partially changing the fluid at the second trench changes the index of refraction thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein partially changing the fluid at the second trench causes the beginning of bubble formation thereat. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method of monitoring a light signal in a fluid containing device comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a fluid containing device having a plurality of optical waveguides and a plurality of trenches provided therein, including: 
<claim-text>a first waveguide and a second waveguide that intersect a forward positioned first trench such that optical coupling between the first and second waveguides is dependent upon a refractive index-matching fluid being at the first trench, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a test waveguide that intersects a reverse positioned second trench such that optical coupling between the first and test waveguides is dependent upon the refractive index-matching fluid being at the second trench; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the refractive index-matching fluid at a first power level at the first trench to switch the refractive index-matching fluid containing device to cause a light signal to be reflected between the first and second waveguides; </claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the refractive index-matching fluid at a second power level lower than the first power level at the second trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause a portion of the light signal to be reflected between the test and first waveguides; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring the portion of the light signal in the test waveguide using a light monitor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fluid containing device includes a second test waveguide that intersects a reverse positioned third trench such that optical coupling between the test waveguides is dependent upon the refractive index-matching fluid being at the third trench including: 
<claim-text>heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the second power level at the third trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the second test and test waveguides; and wherein: 
<claim-text>monitoring the portion of the light signal in the test waveguide is performed through the second test waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the refractive index-matching fluid containing device includes a third waveguide that intersects a forward positioned third trench such that optical coupling between the first and third waveguides is dependent upon the refractive index-matching fluid being at the second trench and a second test waveguide intersects a reverse positioned fourth trench such that such that optical coupling between the third and second test waveguides is dependent upon the refractive index-matching fluid being at the fourth trench including: 
<claim-text>heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the second power level at the third trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the first and third waveguides; </claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the first power level at the fourth trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the second test and third waveguides; and wherein: 
<claim-text>monitoring the portion of the light signal in the third waveguide is performed through the second test waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the second power level at the second trench changes the index of refraction thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the second power level at the second trench causes the beginning of bubble formation thereat. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A fluid containing device for a light signal monitoring system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a support structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of optical waveguides and a plurality of trenches provided in the support structure, including: 
<claim-text>a first waveguide and a second waveguide that intersect a first trench such that optical coupling between the first and second waveguides is dependent upon a fluid being at the first trench, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a test waveguide that intersects a second trench such that optical coupling between the first and test waveguides is dependent upon the fluid being at the second trench; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mechanism for changing the fluid at the first trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause a light signal to be reflected between the first and second waveguides; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mechanism for partially changing the fluid at the second trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause a portion of the light signal to be reflected between the test and first waveguides. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The fluid containing device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> including a second test waveguide that intersects a third trench such that optical coupling between the test waveguides is dependent upon the fluid being at the third trench including: 
<claim-text>a mechanism for partially changing the fluid at the third trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the test and second waveguides. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The fluid containing device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> including a third waveguide that intersects a third trench such that optical coupling between the first and third waveguides is dependent upon the fluid being at the second trench and a second test waveguide intersects a fourth trench such that such that optical coupling between the third and second test waveguides is dependent upon the fluid being at the fourth trench including: 
<claim-text>a mechanism for partially changing the fluid at the third trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the first and third waveguides; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mechanism changing the fluid at the fourth trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the second test and third waveguides. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The fluid containing device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mechanism for partially changing the fluid at the second trench changes the index of refraction thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The fluid containing device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mechanism for partially changing the fluid at the second trench causes the beginning of bubble formation thereat. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A system for monitoring light signals in a fluid containing device comprising: 
<claim-text>a fluid containing device having a plurality of optical waveguides and a plurality of trenches provided therein, including: 
<claim-text>a first waveguide and a second waveguide that intersect a forward positioned first trench such that optical coupling between the first and second waveguides is dependent upon a refractive index-matching fluid being at the first trench, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a test waveguide that intersects a reverse positioned second trench such that optical coupling between the first and test waveguides is dependent upon the refractive index-matching fluid being at the second trench; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heater for heating the refractive index-matching fluid at a first power level at the first trench to switch the refractive index-matching fluid containing device to cause a light signal to be reflected between the first and second waveguides; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a heater for heating the refractive index-matching fluid at a second power level lower than the first power level at the second trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause a portion of the light signal to be reflected between the test and first waveguides; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a light monitor for monitoring the portion of the light signal in the test waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fluid containing device includes a second test waveguide that intersects a reverse positioned third trench such that optical coupling between the test waveguides is dependent upon the refractive index-matching fluid being at the third trench including: 
<claim-text>a heater for heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the second power level at the third trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the second test and test waveguides; and wherein: 
<claim-text>the light monitor monitors the portion of the light signal in the test waveguide through the second test waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the refractive index-matching fluid containing device includes a third waveguide that intersects a forward positioned third trench such that optical coupling between the first and third waveguides is dependent upon the refractive index-matching fluid being at the second trench and a second test waveguide intersects a reverse positioned fourth trench such that such that optical coupling between the third and second test waveguides is dependent upon the refractive index-matching fluid being at the fourth trench including: 
<claim-text>a heater for heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the second power level at the third trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the first and third waveguides; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a heater for heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the first power level at the fourth trench to switch the fluid containing device to cause the portion of the light signal to be reflected between the second test and third waveguides; and wherein: 
<claim-text>the light monitor monitors the portion of the light signal in the third waveguide through the second test waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the heater for heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the second power level at the second trench changes the index of refraction thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the heater for heating the refractive index-matching fluid at the second power level at the second trench causes the beginning of bubble formation thereat.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002030A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002030A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002030A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
