<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002912A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002912A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002912A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002912A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002912A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002912A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002912A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002912A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002912A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002912A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002912A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002912A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002912A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002912A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002912</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10159986</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020603</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>512166</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010601</filing-date>
<country-code>NZ</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B05C021/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>401</class>
<subclass>220000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>401</class>
<subclass>208000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Wax applicator</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<family-name>Morpeth</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Auckland</city>
<country-code>NZ</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JACOBSON HOLMAN PLLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>400 SEVENTH STREET, N.W.</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A wax applicator having a first container to contain wax and an applicator head for receiving the wax from the first container, and a roller for transferring the wax to a surface which may include a lid. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a wax applicator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> It is well known in the art that one effective way of removing hair from the body is to apply a warm wax or other wax like substance to the skin using a spatula or other similar means. The wax is then removed from the skin by using a cotton strip or other piece of cotton that has been placed on the wax. The cotton strip is then pulled back. At the time as the wax is being removed it also removes the hair from the roots, as the hairs are now embedded in the wax. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The disadvantage of using a warm or cold wax using a spatula is that the wax can get messy. This is because the wax is a thick liquid and becomes tacky and stringy on delivering it from the pot to the body. There is also the difficulty of spreading the wax to an ideal thickness on the body which again can get messy. The wax also has a tendency of getting stuck to the clothes and hands of the person applying the wax. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, means have been devised to contain the wax within a container that can be heated, either internally or externally. The application of the wax is then made via an attachment to the container that holds the wax. This ensures that the application of the wax does not have to be handled outside of the container in which the wax was heated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Reference is made to U.S. Pat. No. 6,076,984, which incorporates a container and application means via a roller to transfer heated wax from the container to the surface of the skin. The full content of U.S. Pat. No. 6,076,984 is herein incorporated by way of reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> However, a disadvantage of using a roller to apply wax to the skin is that as the contours of the body can be uneven, and in some places concave, the wax is not evenly distributed nor does the wax reach these concave areas of the body. Such as for example the arm pit, where the edges surrounding the arm pit become coated with the wax. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A further disadvantage of a roller is that the area to which the roller applies wax cannot be reduced to an area smaller than the area of the roller. Therefore to apply wax to these small areas the roller must be carefully manoeuvred to apply wax to the area in question. Generally in such circumstances there is a wastage of wax and wax being applied to inappropriate areas. Such as for example facial hair along the top lip of a person where the wax can inadvertently be applied to the lip. Also where wax is being applied to the eye lid area, care must be taken to ensure no wax is also applied to the eye or eye lashes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Other problems with wax roller applicators is the build-up of wax around the sides of the roller and in between the space between the roller and edge of the applicator. Another problem is that the edges of a flat sided roller can catch on the skin&apos;s surface and prevents the roller from turning rendering the process of applying the wax as ineffectual. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Further problems with wax roller applicators is that they are often badly designed in terms of the ergonomics of the container. An example of bad ergonomic design is that when an ordinary applicator is used for applying wax to the leg, where the user is sitting, the applicator must be placed at right angles to the leg, especially around the base of the leg. Thus the user needs to have a very long arm or has to manoeuvre the applicator in such a way to ensure the wax is applied which can be very uncomfortable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> It is therefore an object of the present invention to provide an ergonomically designed wax applicator that allows wax to be applied, whether the surface of the skin is uneven or not, to aid in the removal of body hair and/or at least to provide the public with a useful choice. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In a first aspect the present invention consists in a wax applicator comprising or including </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> a first container to contain wax or similar substance, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> an applicator head for receiving said wax from said first container, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> a roller for transferring said wax from said applicator head to apply the wax to a surface, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> optionally a lid, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> wherein said roller is rotatably mounted, whether removable or not, with said applicator head, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> wherein said applicator head is able to be attached to said first container either by screw or snap engagement, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> wherein said applicator head has at least one longitudinal edge the said edge extending parallel with the surface of the roller on at least one side of the applicator head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Preferably said first container is provided with snap engagement features or is screw threaded at one end, for attachment of said applicator head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Preferably said applicator head is provided with receiving means for receiving said roller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Preferably said receiving means is provided with shoulders configured to the shape of said roller head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Preferably said applicator head has mounts to receive said roller, said mounts being recesses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Preferably said roller is provided with an axle defining upstands capable of engaging with said mounts that are snap engageable with said axle defining upstand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Preferably said applicator head is provided with a hole in which to receive said wax from said first container. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Preferably said applicator head is provided with a second containment region for receiving said wax from said first container immediately prior to being applied to said surface via said roller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In a further aspect the present invention consists in an applicator assembly (&ldquo;applicator&rdquo;) suitable for applying a liquid to a surface, said applicator comprising or including </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> a container containing or to contain the liquid, said container having an outlet, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> an applicator head engaged or engageable with said container to receive liquid from said container via said outlet, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> a roller at least in part in or rotatably locatable in said applicator head to both receive liquid received by the applicator head from the container and to transfer the liquid onto a surface on which the liquid coated roller is to be rolled, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> wherein the applicator head and the roller subassembly has such asymmetry such that the rolling direction is better in one sense than the other when the container of the applicator, as a result of the applicator disposition relative to the surface, is proximate to said surface to which the liquid is to be applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Preferably said applicator head is engaged to said container about said outlet by a screw or snap interengagement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Preferably said roller has its rolling surface substantially cylindrically formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Preferably said roller includes convex ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Preferably the ends of the roller are closely associated with the applicator head so as to prefer uptake of the liquid from within the applicator head on the rolling surface of the roller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Preferably the rolling surface of the roller is in close proximity of an edge, lip or other defined periphery of the applicator head within which said roller is located so as to restrict presentation of liquid on the rolling surface to a desired amount. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Preferably said applicator head is asymmetric about an axis transverse to the rolling axis of said roller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Preferably said applicator is assembled and includes said liquid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Preferably said outlet has a removable seal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Preferably said applicator and roller subassembly has a closure cap. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Preferably said liquid (whether liquid at ambient temperatures or not) is a depilatory composition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In yet a further aspect the present invention consists in an applicator head suitable for applying a liquid to a skin surface, said head comprising or including </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> an attachment part capable of fitting to a container, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> a receiving opening for receiving a roller, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> a containment region having a hole into said attachment part to receive a liquid from a container and a surface substantially corresponding to the application area of said roller, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> a roller located at least in part in said receiving opening to receive liquid received by said containment region and by rotation of said roller transfers the liquid onto a skin surface, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> wherein said roller when rolled in one direction, rather than the other, better enables substantially more of the head to be in contact with the skin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Preferably said attachment part is engaged to said container by snap or screw engagement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In another aspect the present invention relates to any part of the applicator substantially as hereinafter described with or without reference to any one or more of the accompanying drawings and/or which includes apparatus as previously defined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As used herein the term &ldquo;first container&rdquo; refers to and includes any container capable of acting as a wax reservoir such as for example a container, bottle, flask or other similar container. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> As used herein the terms &ldquo;wax&rdquo; or &ldquo;liquid&rdquo; refers to and includes any depilatory substance, gel, gel like fluids or creams that can be applied to the skin to remove the hair, this includes such depilatory substances based on sugars, resins and beeswaxes.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> One preferred form of the present invention will now be described with reference to the accompanying drawings in which; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a preferred form of the wax hair removal applicator with the lid on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the wax hair removal applicator with the lid off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of the applicator head with the roller removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross section of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> through BB, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a view of the wax hair removal applicator in use and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side view illustrating the position of the edge of the applicator head relative to the axis of the roller.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Preferably one form of the wax applicator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The lid <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can easily be removed from the applicator head <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> by simply applying pressure along the top of the lid and uplifting the lid by the hand. The roller <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is then exposed and ready for use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The roller <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> has a main surface area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> which can receive the wax from a containment region <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and is located into the receiving area <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the applicator head. The roller <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> also has regions <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> located at either end of the roller which receives a greatly reduced amount of wax due to the shoulders <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and partitions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> preventing a substantial amount of wax moving into the area between the shoulders <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the regions <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The amount being approximately 50%. The shoulders <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the applicator head are configured to a shape to receive the roller. Due to region <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> being of a smaller area than the main surface area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and receiving a greatly reduced amount of wax, enables the provision of a narrow strip of wax to be applied to these sensitive areas of the body for hair removal. Such areas include the underarm or upper lip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The applicator head is also provided with an opening <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> that allows the heated wax to flow from the container <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into the containment region. Once the wax is in the containment region it can be applied to a surface via the roller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The roller is preferably mounted inside the applicator head about the rollers stub axis <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to allow free rotation. This rotation is achieved by the stub axis fitting into the recesses <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the receiving region of the applicator head and this allows the stub axis to rotate freely. The roller can be pushed into the recesses and alternatively popped out again for easy cleaning if required, however generally the roller can not be popped out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> An opening space <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is provided between the roller and the top lip <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the applicator head. This opening space provides the opening through which the wax can be applied onto a surface. This opening space allows the wax to be applied in an even continuous strip as the top lip causes excess wax to be retained and the opening space determines the amount of wax that can be applied. The advantage of this is that through the opening <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> which is useful for such body areas as the leg. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows the wax applicator in use where a person holds the container either at an angle to the surface as shown or alternatively the applicator head can be flush with the surface. This will depend on how the user wishes to use the applicator. The wax is then applied to the surface, usually over hairs that become coated, a cotton strip is then placed on the wax covered area pressed down and as the cotton strip is removed this removes the cold wax which now has the hair embedded into surface allowing the hair to be lifted out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> which is a side view of the applicator it can be seen that the edge <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the opening of the applicator head <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is located on the body side of the applicator to the position at which the rotational axis of the roller is located relative to the body. Such a displacement may be by, for example, a distance &ldquo;D&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The point at which the skin can first make contact with the surface of the roller as the roller rotates, is at the edge <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the opening. By having the axis <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> placed above the edge <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, as the roller rotates, this allows the surface of the roller at the edge <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to advance in a direction with a component of movement outwardly. When the surface &ldquo;S&rdquo; of the applicator is placed flush against the skin, and the device is moved along the skin, an application of wax can occur to the skin which provides a thin but continuous stream of wax. In the most preferred form the surface &ldquo;S&rdquo;, is of a shape which, for example, in side view as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, angles towards the surface of the roller in the direction approaching the edge of the opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A wax applicator comprising or including 
<claim-text>a first container to contain wax or similar substance, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an applicator head for receiving said wax from said first container, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a roller for transferring said wax from said applicator head to apply the wax to a surface, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>optionally a lid, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said roller is rotatably mounted, whether removable or not, with said applicator head, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said applicator head is able to be attached to said first container either by screw or snap engagement, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said applicator head has at least one longitudinal edge the said edge extending parallel with the surface of the roller on at least one side of the applicator head. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A wax applicator as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first container is provided with snap engagement features or is screw threaded at one end, for attachment of said applicator head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A wax applicator as claimed in claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> wherein said applicator head is provided with receiving means for receiving said roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A wax applicator as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said receiving means is provided with shoulders configured to the shape of said roller head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A wax applicator as claimed in any one of claims <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> wherein said applicator head has mounts to receive said roller, said mounts being recesses. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A wax applicator as claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said roller is provided with an axle defining upstands capable of engaging with said mounts that are snap engageable with said axle defining upstand. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A wax applicator as claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said applicator head is provided with a hole in which to receive said wax from said first container. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A wax applicator as claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said applicator head is provided with a second containment region for receiving said wax from said first container immediately prior to being applied to said surface via said roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An applicator assembly (&ldquo;applicator&rdquo;) suitable for applying a liquid to a surface, said applicator comprising or including 
<claim-text>a container containing or to contain the liquid, said container having an outlet, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an applicator head engaged or engageable with said container to receive liquid from said container via said outlet, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a roller at least in part in or rotatably locatable in said applicator head to both receive liquid received by the applicator head from the container and to transfer the liquid onto a surface on which the liquid coated roller is to be rolled, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the applicator head and the roller subassembly has such asymmetry such that the rolling direction is better in one sense than the other when the container of the applicator, as a result of the applicator disposition relative to the surface, is proximate to said surface to which the liquid is to be applied. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An applicator as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said applicator head is engaged to said container about said outlet by a screw or snap interengagement. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An applicator as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> wherein said roller has its rolling surface substantially cylindrically formed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An applicator as claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claims 9</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said roller includes convex ends. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An applicator as claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claims 9</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00012">12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ends of the roller are closely associated with the applicator head so as to prefer uptake of the liquid from within the applicator head on the rolling surface of the roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An applicator as claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claims 9</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00013">13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the rolling surface of the roller is in close proximity of an edge, lip or other defined periphery of the applicator head within which said roller is located so as to restrict presentation of liquid on the rolling surface to a desired amount. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An applicator as claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claims 9</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00014">14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said applicator head is asymmetric about an axis transverse to the rolling axis of said roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An applicator of any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claims 9</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00015">15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said applicator is assembled and includes said liquid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An applicator of any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claims 9</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00016">16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said outlet has a removable seal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An applicator of any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claims 9</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00017">17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said applicator and roller subassembly has a closure cap. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An applicator of any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claims 9</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00018">18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said liquid (whether liquid at ambient temperatures or not) is a depilatory composition. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An applicator head suitable for applying a liquid to a skin surface, said head comprising or including 
<claim-text>an attachment part capable of fitting to a container, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a receiving opening for receiving a roller, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a containment region having a hole into said attachment part to receive a liquid from a container and a surface substantially corresponding to the application area of said roller, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a roller located at least in part in said receiving opening to receive liquid received by said containment region and by rotation of said roller transfers the liquid onto a skin surface, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said roller when rolled in one direction, rather than the other, better enables substantially more of the head to be in contact with the skin. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An applicator head as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said attachment part is engaged to said container by snap or screw engagement. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Any part of the applicator substantially as hereinbefore described with or without reference to any one or more of the accompanying drawings and/or which includes apparatus as previously defined.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002912A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002912A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002912A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002912A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002912A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002912A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002912A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
