<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000314A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000314A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000314A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000314A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000314A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000314A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000314A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000314A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000314A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000314A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000314A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000314A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000314</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09897003</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01N003/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>073</class>
<subclass>849000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>System and method for measuring bending in a pin member</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Douglas</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Smith</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>North Ogden</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Totman</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ogden</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Randy</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Everton</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Brigham City</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Paul</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Jean</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Layton</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Marvin</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Bunderson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Brigham City</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mark</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Eggett</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Brigham City</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Randy</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Borgstrom</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>South Weber</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SULLIVAN LAW GROUP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1850 NORTH CENTRAL AVENUE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1140</address-2>
<city>PHOENIX</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<postalcode>85004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An instrumented pin member is provided that is capable of measuring bending moments, and optionally of measuring bending and axial strain in real or near real time. The instrumented pin member includes a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis, wherein the pin member body includes a bending portion. A sensing device is positioned at the pin member body within the bending portion for sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain, and for outputting a sensor measurement signal representative of the bending strain. A sensor measurement signal output device is provided for outputting the sensor measurement signal from the sensor device. A related system includes a plurality of pin members, among other things. Related methods also are disclosed. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to instrumented coupling devices and methods and, more specifically, to apparatus and methods for measuring or predicting bending in a pin member used to couple a joint. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A common means of joining two mechanical bodies together involves the use of one or more pin members disposed through aligned and mating apertures. A &ldquo;pin member&rdquo; as the term is used herein may be interpreted broadly to include such devices as bolts, screws, pins, axles, and the like. The joint may take any one of a number of forms. It may, for example, comprise a flanged joint between two pipes, pressure vessel housings, a flanged joint between two solid rocket motor casings, clevis and yoke assemblies, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Under operating conditions, a variety of forces act on the pin member. These forces include tension and compression forces along the longitudinal axis of the pin member, or with force components along that axis, shear forces normal to the longitudinal axis of the pin member, torsional forces, and bending moments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Apparatus and methods have been known for instrumenting a pin member to measure tension, compression shear, and/or torsion. For example, the use of various types of strain gages to measure such forces are well known. Sensing devices also are known in which such strain gages are used in combination with bridge circuitry such as a Wheatstone bridge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The effective measurement of bending forces, however, has eluded effective measurement. Bending forces in many mechanical system is a particularly incideous force, e.g., because it typically isolates a relatively large stress in a localized area. It is often highly desirable to design a component or system so that bending forces and their detrimental effects can be minimized. The direction of bending can be important in some applications, for example, because pin member through-hole radial translation with respect to the pin member shaft often can result in unobvious bending directions with respect to the ideal. The measurement of bending forces or moments often is particularly difficult, however, because the direction of the force can change, sometimes rapidly, over time. In the case of solid rocket motor joints, for example, when the rocket motor is fired, bending moments can be vary substantial and their direction can vary widely. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, an object of the present invention according to one aspect is to provide an instrumented pin member that can effectively measure bending stresses within the pin member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Additional objects and advantages of the invention will be set forth in the description which follows, and in part will be apparent from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The objects and advantages of the invention may be realized and obtained by means of the instrumentalities and combinations pointed out in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> To achieve the foregoing objects, and in accordance with the purposes of the invention as embodied and broadly described in this document, an instrumented pin member is provided. The instrumented pin member comprises a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis. The pin member body comprises a bending portion. The instrumented pin member further comprises a sensing device positioned at the pin member body within the bending portion for sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain, and for outputting a sensor measurement signal representative of the bending strain. In addition, the instrumented pin member comprises a sensor measurement signal output device for outputting the sensor measurement signal from the sensor device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Preferably but optionally, the sensing device senses components of the bending strain in the bending portion along an x axis and a y axis, wherein the x axis and the y axis are orthogonal to the pin member axis and to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The pin member body may comprises a bolt, a pin, a screw, an axle, and the like. Preferably but optionally, the pin member body has a cylindrical shape about the pin member axis. The pin member head preferably includes a head, and the bending portion is adjacent to the head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The sensing device preferably comprises first and second x-axis sensor elements for measuring the bending strain along the x axis, and first and second y-axis sensor elements for measuring the bending strain along the y axis. Each of the first and second x axis sensor elements preferably comprises an axial sensor for sensing strain in a pin member axial direction corresponding to the pin member axis. The pin member body preferably comprises a shank including a shank perimeter lying in a plane orthogonal to the pin member axis. Each of the first and second x axis sensor elements preferably comprises a tangential sensor for sensing strain in a tangential direction tangential to the shank perimeter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In the presently preferred embodiments, each of the first and second y axis sensor elements comprises an axial sensor for sensing strain in a pin member axial direction corresponding to the pin member axis. The pin member body preferably comprises a shank including a shank perimeter lying in a plane orthogonal to the pin member axis, and each of the first and second y axis sensor elements comprises a tangential sensor for sensing strain in a tangential direction tangential to the shank perimeter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Each of the first and second x axis sensor elements and each of the first and second y axis sensor elements preferably comprises an axial sensor for sensing strain in a pin member axial direction corresponding to the pin member axis. Each of the first and second x axis sensor elements and each of the first and second y axis sensor elements preferably comprises a tangential sensor for sensing strain in a tangential direction tangential to the shank perimeter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The sensing device preferably comprises an x axis bridge having a left side and a right side, wherein the left x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right x axis bridge side comprise first and second positions. The first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right x axis bridge side are in a first aligned x axis configuration, and the second position of the left x axis bridge side and the second position of the right x axis bridge side are in a second aligned x axis configuration. In the preferred embodiments, the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. The sensing device of the preferred embodiments comprises an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration. The sensing device is in the bending stress measurement mode when the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. The sensing device is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. Similarly, the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements preferably are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration for measurement of bending. Where the sensing device can assume an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration, the sensing device preferably is in the bending stress measurement mode when the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. It is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The sensing device according to presently preferred embodiments similarly comprises a y axis bridge having a left side and a right side, wherein the left y axis bridge side comprises first and second positions and the right y axis bridge side comprises first and second positions. The first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right y axis bridge side being in a first aligned y axis configuration, and the second position of the left y axis bridge side and the second position of the right y axis bridge side are in a second aligned y axis configuration. The axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements preferably are in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration for measurement of bending. Where the sensing device can assume axial and bending measurement configurations or modes, the sensing device preferably is in the bending stress measurement mode when the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration, and the sensing device is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned opposed y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. Similarly, the tangential sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements preferably are in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. The sensing device preferably is in the bending stress measurement mode when the axial sensor of the first and second y axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration, and it is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The instrumented pin member preferably but optionally also comprises a switching device operatively coupled to the sensing device for switching between an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration. The switching device may comprises a solid state switching circuit. The switching device may be and preferably is positioned at the pin member head. In a presently preferred embodiment, the pin member head includes an external surface and a notch disposed in the external surface, and the switching device is mounted to the external surface. The pin member head also may comprises a head including a head cavity, and the switching device may be positioned at the pin member head cavity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The switching device preferably comprises a periodic switching signal source for providing a periodic switching signal. In the presently preferred embodiments, the periodic signal comprises a square wave signal that alternately switches between a high and low state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Where the sensing device comprises a pair of bridges each having an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration, the switching device preferably comprises a switch operatively coupled to the pair of bridges for switching the pair of bridges between the axial stress measurement configuration and the bending stress measurement configuration. Preferably but optionally, the switching device switches the pair of bridges to the bending stress measurement configuration substantially simultaneously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the invention, a system is provided for measuring bending at a joint. The system according to this aspect of the invention comprises an instrumented pin member disposed at the joint, wherein the instrumented pin member comprises a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis. The pin member body comprises a bending portion. The pin member further includes a sensing device positioned at the pin member body within the bending portion for sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain, and for outputting a sensor measurement signal representative of the bending strain. The pin member further includes a sensor measurement signal output device for outputting the sensor measurement signal from the sensor device. The system also includes a data receiving device operatively coupled to the sensor measurement signal output device for receiving the sensor output signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Preferably but optionally, the system comprises a switching device operatively coupled to the sensing device for switching the sensing device in and out of a bending stress mode. The system preferably but optionally comprises a plurality of the instrumented pin members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The data receiving device may comprise a data processor, a data display, and/or other data receiving and/or data handling/processing components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In accordance with still another aspect of the invention, a method is provided for measuring bending at a joint. The method comprises disposing an instrumented pin member at the joint. The instrumented pin member comprises a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis, and the pin member body comprising a bending portion. The method further includes sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain during a bending stress measurement mode and outputting a sensor measurement signal, and communicating the sensor measurement signal to a data receiving device. The disposing of the instrumented pin member preferably comprises disposing a plurality of the instrumented pin members at the joint so that the instrumented pin members are substantially equally spaced about the joint. The sensing preferably includes switching in and out of the bending stress measurement mode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> With the presently preferred embodiments of the invention, it is possible to reliably and accurately measure the magnitude and direction of bending moments in a pin member, in real or near real time, and under actual operating conditions. Using, among other things, an arrangement in which net axial strain, i.e., net tension and compression measurements, are canceled out, and optionally in which the measurement device switches between tension/compression measurements and bending measurements, it is possible to obtain highly accurate bending moment information, including not only the presence of bending forces and their magnitude, but also direction as a function of time. With the embodiments disclosed herein, it is possible to automatically switch in periodic fashion from measuring axial strain or preload while disregarding or isolating out bending and torsional stress, and independently or alternately measure bending magnitude and direction while disregarding or isolating out axial and torsional stresses. This permits the essentially simultaneous measurement of bending moments and axial loads.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of the specification, illustrate presently preferred embodiments and methods of the invention and, together with the general description given above and the detailed description of the preferred embodiments and methods given below, serve to explain the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective elevational view of a bolted joint between two vessels, in which joint instrumented bolts according to a presently preferred embodiment of the present invention have been incorporated to illustrate the principles and possible applications of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a system according to a presently preferred system embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of an instrumented pin member according to a first preferred embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top axial view of the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an expanded side view of the head and upper shank portion of the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side cut-away view of the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, taken along cut-away lines <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a axial or top cut-away view of the head and upper shank portion of the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, taken along lines <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an electrical schematic diagram of a bridge assembly according to a bending stress measurement configuration used in the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an electrical schematic diagram of a bridge assembly according to an axial stress measurement configuration used in the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an electrical schematic diagram of a switching circuit used in the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows an end view of a connector used in the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a side view of an instrumented pin member according to a second preferred embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a top axial view of the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is an expanded side view of the head and upper shank portion of the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is an axial cut-away view of the instrumented pin member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, taken along cut-away lines <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight></paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS AND METHODS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made in detail to the presently preferred embodiments and methods of the invention as illustrated in the accompanying drawings, in which like reference characters designate like or corresponding parts throughout the drawings. It should be noted, however, that the invention in its broader aspects is not limited to the specific details, representative devices and methods, and illustrative examples shown and described in this section in connection with the preferred embodiments and methods. The invention according to its various aspects is particularly pointed out and distinctly claimed in the attached claims read in view of this specification, and appropriate equivalents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one aspect of the invention, an instrumented pin member is provided. The instrumented pin member according to this aspect may take the form of or comprise a bolt, a screw, a pin, or the like. In many applications the pin member will have a round or substantially round shank, although this is not necessarily limiting. It is possible, for example, to have an oval, square, rectangular or like shape for the shank portion of the pin member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a related aspect of the invention, one or more such pin members may be used as part of a system for measuring bending stresses at a joint. In any case, the instrumented pin member or members preferably will take the general form, at least in size, shape, etc., of the actual, normally non-instrumented pin members used to secure a joint. This will generally be true at least where the objectives of the use include predicting the stresses and related performance of the non-instrumented pin member, although it is not necessarily limiting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> To illustrate these principles, a solid rocket motor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> having first and second casing members <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Casing members <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are joined and mate to one another at a circular joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. First and second casing members <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> include respective circular flanges <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for mating and securing the casing members to one another. These flanges <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, which form or comprise joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, include a plurality of mated flange apertures <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Under normal operating conditions, a pin member in the form of a non-instrumented bolt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> would be placed in each of the apertures <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to collectively secure the flanges <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and thus the casing members <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, together. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Optionally but preferably, one or more instrumented pin members, e.g., as described more fully herein, can be substituted at joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for selected ones of non-instrumented pin members <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> so that when motor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is fired, the instrumentation, again, for example, as described herein, can measure bending stresses within these instrumented pin members, i.e., at joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A plurality of these instrumented pin members may be disposed, for example, by uniformly distributing them around joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, or in other predetermined arrangements. The bending stress data, and in some instances other data as well, from the instrumented pin member or pin members can be used to simulate, estimate or otherwise predict the same stresses that are occurring in the normal operational, non-instrumented pin members and at the joint itself. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a functional block diagram of a system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> according to a presently preferred system embodiment of the invention, which would be suitable, for example, for predicting bending stresses in the pin members <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> comprises a plurality of instrumented pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> according to a presently preferred embodiment. Each pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> may be assumed, for purposes of reference and illustration, to be disposed about a longitudinal pin member axis <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are uniformly distributed about joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> among the non-instrumented pin members <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> System <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> also comprises a control box <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, a preamplifier or data conditioner <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, a storage device <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, e.g., a hard drive on a computer, a processor <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, e.g., such as the processor of a commercially-available personal computer or small business computer, and a display monitor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. A data recording <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> device such as a strip chart recorder or other device useful for recording data from the instrumented pin members may be used as well. In presently preferred embodiments, the system comprises a computer, preferably a 12 bit range or above, and a control box <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Control box <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is positioned between the pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and preamp <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, and preferably is located as close to the pin members as is practicable under the circumstances with respect to the electrical connections. Control box <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is electrically coupled to the sensors as described below, and receives signals, e.g., analog sensor measurement output signals, from them. It includes an oscillator as described further below, an opto-isolator for assisting in isolating the digital signals from the analog. Control box <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is capable of operating in three modes, i.e., a pure axial measurement mode, a pure bending mode, and a switching mode in which it alternates between an axial stress measurement mode and a bending stress measurement mode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> An instrumented pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> according to a first presently preferred embodiment of this aspect of the invention is shown in side view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and in top or plan view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> comprises a pin member body <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, which for purposes of illustration may be assumed to be disposed about pin member axis <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. To aid in illustration, a conventional three-axis rectilinear coordinate system may be assumed to exist at the pin member. Pin member longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is assumed herein to correspond to the z axis, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The mutually orthogonal x and y axes are assumed to lie in a plane normal to the z axis, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The instrumented pin members as described herein below use a sensing device to measure components of the bending strain in the bending portion along the x and y axes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The instrumented pin member optionally may be constructed from an operational pin member of the type normally used at the joint. In the illustrative embodiments described herein, for example, a bolt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) is used as a starting component and is modified as described herein below to obtain each instrumented pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> With reference to the first preferred but merely illustrative embodiment, pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> comprises a bolt having a pin member body <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> in the form of a shank <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. This is not necessarily limiting, however. The instrumented pin member may comprise forms other than a bolt, such as those pin member types noted above. In many applications, the pin member body may have a cylindrical shape about the pin member axis, at least within the shank portion. In this illustrative embodiment, bolt <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is a steel bolt having a length along longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of about 3 inches. Shank <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> includes threads <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> having a major or outside diameter of about 0.75 inches. Shank <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> has a shank perimeter <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> lying in a plane <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> orthogonal to pin member axis <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Plane <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of course is a theoretical or geometric construct used for illustrative and reference purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Pin member head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> comprises a top portion <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, a base portion <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, and a cylindrical wall portion <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. Pin member head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is sized and configured to secure pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the flange aperture <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> has an outside or radial diameter of about 1.1 to 1.2 inches. Where the pin member comprises a bolt, screw, or other device in which it would be appropriate to turn or torque the head to control the pin member, e.g., to tighten or loosen it, pin member head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> may comprise an appropriate means for turning or wrenching the pin member. Examples of such means would include a hex or octal head, a star configuration, a broach for use with an allen wrench or similar device, etc. In pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> according to the presently preferred embodiment, pin member head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> includes a broach <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> for mating with an allen wrench. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The pin member body according to this aspect of the invention also comprises a bending portion. This portion of the pin member body undergoes bending stresses and experiences associated strains under normal operating conditions for the joint and the device of which it forms a part, e.g., the rocket motor. The bending portion as referred to herein need not constitute the entire portion of the pin member that is subject to bending stresses or strains. It does, however, comprise at least a portion of the pin member body that is subject to bending stress which in many cases will include the entire member. The bending portion as the term is used herein refers to any area or portion of the pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> that is suitable for measurement of bending moments under the application and circumstances. Preferably the bending portion is selected to be a region of the pin member that experiences substantial strain relative to other parts of the pin member during normal operating conditions, and which is representative of the strain occurring in the entire portion of the pin member that is subject to such bending forces. The bending portion in many instances will comprise the area immediately adjacent to the pin member head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As implemented in the preferred embodiment, pin member body <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> includes a bending portion <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> disposed in the upper portion of shank <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, just below base <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Bending portion <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> in this specific embodiment may be assumed to extend from base <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> downward in the axial direction <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> along shank <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> approximately 0.2 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> includes a radially chamfered groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> in bending portion <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. It preferably is positioned on shank <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> below the base <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The positioning of the groove preferably is selected to that unwanted contributions from localized effects at and around the base <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> are avoided, and so that there is no unwanted interference with the head during installation, maintenance, etc. This groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> may be disposed in the shank portion, for example, by lathing pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The depth of groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> radially with respect to shank perimeter <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> of shank <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and the length along the axial dimension <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> (z-axis) may be selected to house and accommodate sensors and associated circuitry, as will be described herein below. In the presently preferred embodiments and using the sensors as described herein below, the depth of groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> is approximately equal to the depth of the minor thread diameter of the shank threads. Preferably it is no smaller than the thread root, e.g., to avoid adverse effects on the strength of the pin member. Groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> is shown in highly exaggerated depth in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> to better illustrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Further in accordance with this aspect of the invention, the instrumented pin member includes a sensing device positioned at the pin member body within the bending portion for sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain, and for outputting a sensor measurement signal representative of the bending strain. The sensing device senses the bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain in the sense that it is capable of sensing bending strains, and thus bending moments, in the bending portion of the pin member, without the measurement being adversely affected by a net axial strain, i.e., without adverse interference or effects of a net tension or compression of the pin member. This may be done, and in the presently preferred embodiments is done, using among other things a sensing device wherein such net axial strain components are canceled out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The sensing device may comprise essentially any sensor or measuring device, or any collection of sensors or measuring devices, capable of sensing strain within the portion of the instrumented pin member to which the sensor or sensors are applied. The specific sensor or sensors used in a particular application may depend upon a number of factors, for example, such as the size of the pin member, the available size and geometry for groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, the material from which the pin member is constructed, the nature and extent of the anticipated forces on the pin member and sensor, the durability and requirements of the sensor or sensors with respect to the specific application and operational environment, other equipment with which the device is to be used, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The sensing device according to this aspect of the invention preferably comprises first and second x-axis sensor elements for measuring the bending strain in along the x axis, and first and second y-axis sensor elements for measuring the bending strain along the y axis. The sensor elements preferably lie in a plane orthogonal with respect to the pin member longitudinal axis, for example, such as plane <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. In presently preferred embodiments, each of the first and second x and y axis sensor elements comprises an axial sensor for sensing strain in a pin member axial direction corresponding to the pin member axis, and a tangential sensor for sensing strain in a tangential direction tangential to the shank perimeter. The tangential direction in these embodiments involves a tangent to shank perimeter, or more accurately to the slightly smaller perimeter of groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> in planes orthogonal to pin member axis <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> where the sensors reside, for example, as identified in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> by reference number <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. Tangential direction <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> thus represents tangent vectors to shank perimeter <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, or to the perimeter of groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, and thus constitutes a circumferential tangent to the shank or groove circumference. Given that radial depth of groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> in many applications will be quite small relative to the shank diameter, the groove perimeter for groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and the shank perimeter at a given radial location will be essentially the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The sensing device according to the preferred embodiments will now be described. In these illustrative embodiments, a sensing device is provided which comprises first and second x axis sensor elements BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and BX<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, respectively, and first and second y axis sensor elements BY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and BY<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, respectively. Each of the sensor elements lies on the perimeter of groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, and thus essentially at shank perimeter <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, all within plane <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Sensor elements BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and BX<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> lie along the x axis on opposite sides of shank perimeter <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, and sensor elements BY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and BY<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> lie on the y axis on opposite sides of shank perimeter <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The x axis sensor elements thus are disposed at 90 degrees with respect to the y axis sensor elements. Each of the sensor elements BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BX<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, BY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and BY<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises a pair of sensors including an axial or &ldquo;tension&rdquo; sensor, denoted by a &ldquo;T,&rdquo; and a tangential or &ldquo;compression&rdquo; sensor, denoted by a &ldquo;C&rdquo; after the sensor element designation, e.g., BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(T) or BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(C). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The sensors may comprise any sensor or measuring device that can be affixed to the bending portion of the pin member and can sense or measure strain in the appropriate directions as generally described herein. Strain gages are preferred. In the presently preferred embodiments, each of the sensors comprises a strain gage, such as Model EA-06-062TZ-350, commercially available from Micro-Measurements, Measurement Group, Inc. of Wendell, N.C. The sensors of each sensor element, e.g., sensors BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(T) and BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(C), are positioned immediately adjacent to one another, as close as is reasonably practicable without interfering with one another, and so that installation, servicing or repair, and possibly removal of one sensor can be undertaken without interfering with or damaging the other sensor of that sensor element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The sensors and sensor elements are positioned and affixed to pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> by attaching or fastening them to the appropriate locations, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 5</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, using appropriate fastening means. Such fastening means may include bonding the sensors using a suitable bonding agent, for example, such as an epoxy or other adhesive. In the presently preferred embodiments, the sensors are bonded to shank <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> within groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> using an epoxy, such as M-BOND 200 or M-BOND 600, commercially available from Micro-Measurements. Where protection of the sensors is necessary or appropriate, e.g., from vibration, thermal loads, etc., it may be desirable to provide a suitable insulator between the shank and sensor. An example would include a tape such as Kapton tape with a silicon adhesive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Each sensor (strain gage) outputs a sensor measurement signal comprising strain measurements taken by that sensor. Each of the sensors has electrically coupled to it a pair of wire or conductor leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for providing power to the sensor and for communicating the sensor measure signal from the sensor. Leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in the presently preferred embodiments comprise, for example, polyimide Kapton insulated wire having a diameter of 0.005 inches. Leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> run from the respective sensors to a pair of axial notches <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, in this embodiment one axial notch <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> per side of the shank, i.e., two axial notches. The top of notches <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, i.e., at base <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, leads to an angled channel <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> extending through the lower portion of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and ending at an aperture <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. A vertical channel <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> extends vertically within head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, having an opening at its bottom portion into aperture <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and having an aperture <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> at top portion <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> extend from the sensors, along groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to the appropriate or nearest one of notches <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, through angled notch <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, into and up vertical notch <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and out the top of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> at aperture <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. A strain relief means, such as rubber surgical tubing <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> or the like, is disposed at aperture <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> to facilitate the exit of leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> without damaging them. A shielded cable <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be used to contain leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are electrically coupled to a connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, as will be described in greater detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The sensing device according to presently preferred embodiments of the invention comprises a bridge assembly for receiving the sensor measurement signals and making necessary or appropriate conversions to measure bending stress. In these embodiments, the bridge assembly can assume an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration. The bridge assembly may comprise a single bridge, but preferably and optionally comprises a pair of bridges, which still further preferably comprise an x axis bridge and a y axis bridge. The use of only a single bridge can be useful in detecting bending strains, but typically will not include directional information, or will measure only components of strain along a single plane. It will In accordance with the presently preferred embodiments, the sensing device comprises a pair of bridges, specifically an x axis bridge <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and a y axis bridge <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, for example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. In these embodiments, each of the bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> comprises a full active Wheatstone strain gage bridge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The x axis bridge in preferred embodiments comprises a left side and a right side. The left x axis bridge side comprises first and second positions and the right x axis bridge side comprises first and second positions. The first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right x axis bridge side comprise what may be termed a first aligned x axis configuration, and the second position of the left x axis bridge side and the second position of the right x axis bridge side comprise what may be termed a second aligned x axis configuration. Similarly, the y axis bridge in preferred embodiments comprises a left side and a right side. The left y axis bridge side comprises first and second positions and the right y axis bridge side comprises first and second positions. The first position of the left y axis bridge side and the first position of the right y axis bridge side comprise what may be termed a first aligned y axis configuration, and the second position of the left y axis bridge side and the second position of the right y axis bridge side comprise what may be termed a second aligned configuration. The first aligned x axis configuration corresponds to the first aligned y axis configuration, and the second aligned x axis configuration corresponds to the second aligned y axis configuration, as will be illustrated further herein below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> As specifically implemented in the presently preferred embodiments, x axis bridge <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> comprises a left side <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> and a right side <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. Y axis bridge similarly comprises a left side <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and a right side <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>. X axis bridge <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> at its left side <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> includes a first position <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and a second position <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>, and at its right side <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> includes a first position <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and a second position <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. Similarly, y axis bridge <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> at its left side <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> includes a first position <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and a second position <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>, and at its right side <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> includes a first position <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> and a second position <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>. In these embodiments, first x axis potions <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> are aligned, and second positions <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> are aligned. Positions <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> are opposed, as are positions <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Similarly with respect to the y axis bridge, first y axis potions <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> are aligned, and second positions <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> are aligned. Positions <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> are opposed, as are positions <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>, x axis bridge <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> has a power source at its left side comprising a positive voltage &plus;EX(<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) at a top terminal, electrically coupled to position <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, and a negative voltage &minus;EX(<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) electrically coupled to position <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. The &ldquo;EX&rdquo; portion refers to an excitation voltage, which terminology is common in the field. The numeral in parenthesis represents the pin number of connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> corresponding to that voltage level or signal. Bridge <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> also has a power source at its right side comprising positive voltage &plus;XF coupled to position <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and a negative voltage &minus;XF coupled to position <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. The y axis bridge <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is similarly configured. Bridge <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> has a power source at its left side comprising a positive voltage &plus;EX(<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) coupled to position <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, and a negative voltage &minus;EX(<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) coupled to position <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>. Bridge <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> also has a power source at its right side comprising positive voltage &plus;XF coupled to position <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> and a negative voltage &minus;XF coupled at position <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>. Aligned configurations as the term is used herein refers to positions in a given bridge wherein two of the positions are aligned as noted above, i.e., first position to first position or second position to second position within a given bridge, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. Opposed configurations as the term is used herein refers to positions in a given bridge wherein two of the positions are opposite one another as described above, and as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> When measuring bending stresses with embodiments comprising the x and y bridges as heretofore described, either the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned configuration and the second aligned configuration, or the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned configuration and the second aligned configuration, or preferably both are so configured. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, for example, a first aligned configuration involves aligned resistances from top left to top right as shown in the figure, e.g., positions <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. The second aligned configuration involves aligned resistances from bottom left to bottom right, e.g., positions <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. The same applies to bridge <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> With respect to the presently preferred embodiments, in x axis bridge <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, sensor BX<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>(C) comprises the resistance at position <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. By reversing the polarity of the right side of the bridge with respect to that of an axial strain measurement configuration, sensor BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(C) comprises the resistance at position <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. With this reversed polarity configuration, sensor BX<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>(T) comprises the resistance at position <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>, and sensor BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(T) comprises the resistance at position <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. Similarly with y axis bridge <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, sensor BY<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>(C) comprises the resistance at first left position <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, sensor BY<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>(T) comprises the resistance at second left position <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>, sensor BY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(C) comprises the resistance at first right position <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, and sensor BY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(T) comprises the resistance at second right position <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>. With this configuration, the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration, and the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. Similarly, the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration, and the tangential sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In operation, the sensor configuration shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> serves to cancel net axial strains (net tension or compression) and measures bending moments. Because separate x and y axis sensors and corresponding separate x axis and y axis bridges are used, it is possible to obtain x and y components, so that the direction of the bending moments can be determined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The system comprising instrumented pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> with sensors as described and with bridges as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> cancel net axial strains, and therefore measure bending moments. In presently preferred embodiments, however, it is desired and preferred that each instrumented pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> also be configured to operate in an axial stress measurement mode, in which net axial stress is measure exclusive of bending moments, and a bending stress measurement mode, in which bending stress is measured exclusive of net axial stresses, and preferably exclusive of torsional stresses as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> To implement this feature, the sensing device preferably comprises an axial stress measurement configuration, a bending stress measurement configuration, and a switching device operatively coupled to the sensing device for switching between them. The pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, when placed in the axial stress measurement configuration and operated as described herein, is in the axial measurement mode. When pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is placed in the bending stress measurement configuration and operated, it is in the bending stress measurement mode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The sensing device according to the presently preferred embodiments as disclosed herein is in the bending stress measurement mode when the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration, and the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. Similarly, the sensing device is in the bending stress measurement configuration when the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration, and the tangential sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The sensing device of the preferred embodiments is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration, e.g., when they are in an opposed configuration, and when the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration, e.g., when they are in the opposed configuration. Similarly, the preferred sensing device is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration, and the tangential sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration, e.g., they are in the opposed configuration. Thus, by effectively reversing the polarity or arrangement of the sensors (effective resistances) in the bridge, the sensing device can be converted or switched between measuring bending strains and axial strains. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The switching device enables the instrumented pin member to switch between the axial strain measurement configuration and the bending strain measurement configuration, as noted above. This preferably is accomplished in the presently preferred embodiments by using the switching device to adapt and control the configuration of bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> In the presently preferred embodiments, alternate readings of tension/compression on the one hand and bending stresses may be obtained by switching the configuration of the sensors on the right side of the bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the switching device for these instrumented pin members may be any device that is capable of operating with the sensors and switching states to alternate the configuration of the respective sensors. Examples of suitable switching devices, therefore, may include a solid state switching circuit, using such components transistors or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> A switching device <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> according to the presently preferred embodiments for this aspect of the invention comprises a pair of identical switching circuits <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>, one of which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. Switching circuit <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> comprises a pair of 4-ohm complimentary metal oxide semiconductor (CMOS) SPDT switches <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, each of which comprises a pair of field effect transistor (FET). In these preferred embodiments, switches <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> comprise an Advanced Micro Devices Model ADG719BRM switch, commercial available from Advanced Micro Devices of Sunnyvale, Calif. Switches <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> function to reverse the polarity of the right side of bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, thereby effectively reversing the positions of the sensors at the first and second positions of the right sides of the respective bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, i.e., between the bridge assembly configurations shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. Switch <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> provides the switched coupling of the bridge line providing voltage &plus;XF, and switch <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> provides the switched coupling of the bridge line providing voltage &minus;XF, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. The switches selected for switching circuits <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> preferably have a very low impedance when in the &ldquo;ON&rdquo; state, and have an extremely high impedance when in the &ldquo;OFF&rdquo; state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Switch <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> comprises switch terminals <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, at which it receives voltage lines &plus;EX and &minus;EX, respectively. Switch <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> receives as an input at <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> a BSIG signal line <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight>. The BSIG signal in these embodiments comprises a 0 volt or 5 volt signal that can be used to switch the transistors. Switch <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> under the control of the BSIG signal controls a two-pole switch handle <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, which closes the line between either terminal <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> or terminal <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Switch handle <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> is coupled at its output to a line <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> providing voltage &plus;XF to the sensors on the right side of bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. FET <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> also provides as outputs lines <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> to provide voltages &plus;EX and &minus;EX, which are provided to the sensors on the left side of bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Switch <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is identical to switch <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. It comprises switch terminals <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>, at which it receives voltage lines &plus;EX and &minus;EX, respectively. Switch <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> receives BSIG signal line <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> as an input at <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Switch <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> under the control of the BSIG signal controls a two-pole switch handle <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>, which closes the line between either terminal <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> or terminal <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>. Switch handle <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> is coupled at its output to a line <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> providing voltage &minus;XF to the sensors on the right side of bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. Switch <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> also provides as outputs lines <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> to provide voltages &plus;EX and &minus;EX, which are provided to the sensors on the left side of bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> A resistor <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> is located between the input line providing signal BSIG and the line providing voltage &minus;EX at terminals <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>. Resistor <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> in the preferred embodiments comprises a 100 ohm, 0.1 watt metal film chip resistor. This configuration functions to protect the transistors by bleeding off any static energy or voltage buildup on the inputs to the transistors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> A switching signal source <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> is coupled to the line providing signal BSIG for generating the switching signal thereby provided. Preferably the switching signal comprises a periodic signal that causes the switching circuitry to switch states periodically. It should be noted, however, that this is not necessarily limiting, and that other switch timing relationships are possible. Switching signal source <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> in the preferred embodiments comprises an oscillator <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight> that provides a conditioned, periodic square wave for selectively and periodically triggering switches <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. Oscillator <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight> according to the presently preferred embodiment is physically located in control box <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. Switching signal source <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> also may include circuitry for shaping the signal as is appropriate for the particular switches used. A frequency divider, for example, may be used to better insure that the switching transistor is precise, e.g., by building up the leading or trailing edge of the square wave. In the presently preferred embodiments, switching circuits <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>, under the control of the switching signal BSIG, cause each pin member to switch states between the axial stress measurement configuration and the bending stress configuration at a desired rate, depending upon the application. This switching rate may vary from 0 Hz (steady axial or bending mode) to 40 to 50 KHz and possibly higher. Preferred ranges include 10 Hz to 2 KHz, and more preferably about 110 to 500 Hz. Higher frequencies such as 30 to 40 KHz may be useful, for example, when investigating mechanical shock or shock wave phenomena. Natural physical limits on the switching frequency may occur, depending on the circumstance, as will be understood by persons of ordinary skill in the art. Physical limits may be placed, for example, by the line impedance of lines coupled to the switches, or by the frequency of the phenomena to be measured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Preferably the switching circuits cause switching between modes to occur substantially simultaneously among all of the sensors. With an appropriate repetition rate, this can yield an essentially real time or near real time measurement of both axial and bending stresses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> In the presently preferred embodiments, the switching device comprises two sets of the switching circuitry shown in schematic form in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. One of the switching circuitry sets is coupled to and operates the sensors on one side of the pin member, and the other circuitry set is coupled to and operates the sensors on the other side of the pin member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The switching device is preferably physically located on the instrumented pin member. In the preferred embodiments, the switching circuitry sets are disposed on printed circuit (PC) boards or solder tabs that are affixed to or within the head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, affixed to its exterior or within it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 5</cross-reference>, for example, a flat <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> is disposed on each side of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> within wall <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The flats preferably are opposite one another with respect to the head diameter. Each flat <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> comprises a substantially planar surface disposed in the side of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, for example, by machining, so that the switching circuit sets (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) and their supporting solder tabs can be affixed to the surface. The solder tab and switching set circuit are bonded to the flat, for example, using a suitable bonding agent, such as M-BOND 200 or M-BOND 600, commercially available from Micro-Measurements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> A notch <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight> is provided along wall <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> for passage of leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> from the sensors to switching circuits <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>. Notch <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> again may be made in wall <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> by machining. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Still further in accordance with this aspect of the invention, the instrumented pin member includes a sensor measurement signal output device for communicating the sensor measurement output signal. The sensor signal output device may comprise any means for communicating the sensor measurement signal to the environment outside the instrumented pin member itself. This device, for example, may comprise leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> housed in shielded cable <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, and connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The sensor measurement signal output device may, however, take other forms, depending upon the application, etc. Examples would include a remote transmission means such as electromagnetic (e.g., radio frequency, infrared, optical), acoustic, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the preferred embodiments, the sensor signal output device comprises connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and shield cable <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> coupled to it for communicating the signals generated by the respective sensors. The number of leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> contained within the cable can depend upon the number of sensors employed in the instrumented pin member, depending upon such things as whether or not a multiplexing technique is used. In the presently preferred embodiment, each sensor element BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BX<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, BY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BY<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> will have associated with it at least one lead <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, which will constitute a part of the output device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> A second preferred embodiment <highlight><bold>1052</bold></highlight> of this aspect of the invention will now be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 through 15</cross-reference>. This embodiment is essentially identically with pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, except that it uses a different pin member head configuration, and it locates the switching circuitry in a broach within the top portion of the head, rather than at the cylindrical or side wall of the head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> It was noted with respect to the previous embodiment that head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> may include a broach <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> in top portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of pin member head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and that switching circuits <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> were affixed to the exterior wall <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> of head <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, on flats <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the broach <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> includes an extended cavity <highlight><bold>1089</bold></highlight>, extending relatively further into the head <highlight><bold>1074</bold></highlight>, and the switching circuitry is affixed to an interior wall of the head cavity. In this preferred embodiment, switching circuits <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>, which are mounted on solder tabs as described above, are bonded directly to the interior wall of cavity <highlight><bold>1089</bold></highlight>, e.g., by a suitable bonding agent. A presently preferred bonding agent is M-BOND 200 or M-BOND 600, noted above. Tape or other insulating material may be used to protect the sensing circuitry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The cavity <highlight><bold>1089</bold></highlight> itself may be made in known fashion, i.e., by machining. With referenced to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, an angled notch <highlight><bold>1116</bold></highlight> is provided in head <highlight><bold>1074</bold></highlight>, extending from notch <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight> as previously described and extending to the cavity <highlight><bold>1089</bold></highlight> of broach <highlight><bold>1088</bold></highlight>. Notch <highlight><bold>1116</bold></highlight> is sized so that leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can pass through it and into the cavity. A notch <highlight><bold>1115</bold></highlight> extends from aperture <highlight><bold>1114</bold></highlight> into extended portion <highlight><bold>1089</bold></highlight> of the broach. This notch can be useful in gaining access to the cavity <highlight><bold>1089</bold></highlight>, e.g., for placing switching device components, inspecting them, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the system aspect of the invention, the system is provided for measuring bending at a joint. The system comprises an instrumented pin member disposed at the joint. The instrumented pin member comprises a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis. The pin member body comprises a bending portion. The pin member further includes a sensing device positioned on the pin member body within the bending portion for sensing an axial strain and an axially orthogonal strain in the bending portion and for outputting a sensor output signal. The system also preferably includes a switching device operatively coupled to the sensing device for switching between an axial sensing mode and an axially orthogonal sensing mode. The system according to this aspect of the invention also includes a sensor signal output device for communicating the sensor output signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> In a presently preferred embodiment according to this system aspect, the pin member comprises instrumented pin member <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, member <highlight><bold>1052</bold></highlight>, or both, as previously described herein. In the preferred system embodiment, a plurality of such pin members are employed, e.g., as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> and described with reference to that figure herein above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The instrumented pin member according to this system embodiment preferably comprises a switching device operatively coupled to the sensing device for switching the sensing device in and out of a bending stress mode. The preferred switching device according to the system embodiment comprises the switching device <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> as described herein above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The system further includes a data receiving device operatively coupled to the sensor signal output device for receiving the sensor output signal. Preferably but optionally, the data receiving device comprises a data processor. It also may comprise a data display, a data recorder, a strip chart recorder, or any other device or collection of devices suitable for receiving, storing, processing and/or displaying or presenting the data embodied in the sensor signal. As implemented in the presently preferred embodiments, the data receiving device comprises the components illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, and as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the invention, a method is provided for measuring bending at a joint. The method includes disposing an instrumented pin member at the joint, wherein the instrumented pin member comprises a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis, and wherein the pin member body comprising a bending portion. The method also comprises sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain during a bending stress measurement mode and outputting a sensor measurement signal. The method further includes communicating the sensor measurement signal to a data receiving device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> The aforementioned disposition of the instrumented pin member preferably comprises disposing a plurality of the instrumented pin members at the joint so that the instrumented pin members are substantially equally spaced about the joint. The sensing preferably includes switching in and out of the bending stress measurement mode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Although not necessarily limited to applications involving the presently preferred system and embodiments disclosed herein above, a preferred version of the method according to this aspect of the invention will be described and illustrated with reference to them. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the presently preferred implementation of the method includes disposing a plurality of pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, or pin members <highlight><bold>1052</bold></highlight>, about joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, in a uniform and symmetric pattern. For ease of description, it will be assumed below that pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are used, although this is not limiting. Each of pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is preloaded by torquing it down a predetermined amount in known fashion, and according to the specifications for like non-instrumented pin members, e.g., pin members <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Each pin member is given a predetermined orientation, which serves as a reference point or calibration point to determine any later rotation of the pin member. The pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> then are coupled using connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to control box <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, preamplifier <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, processor <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and the other components of the system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Pin members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> then are calibrated by adjusting the processor to set the axial and bending stresses at preload, and the directions of rotation or bending, to be zero under the preload conditions. The specific manner in which this is done will depend upon the specific processor and other equipment that comprises system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, but will be readily understood by those of ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Assuming the alternating axial and bending stress measurement modes are desired, control box <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is switched to this setting. The vessel or joint to which system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is attached, for example, joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of rocket motor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, is then actuated, or placed in an operational mode, during which axial and bending stresses are placed on joint <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. As this occurs, oscillator <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight> provides a periodic square wave to switching circuitry <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>, which causes the sensing device <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> to alternate between the axial stress measurement configuration and the bending stress measurement configuration. As this is done, a periodic sensor measurement signal is created at the output of bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, and is communicated via leads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to preamp <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and processor <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The sensor measurement signal is segregated into an axial stress component and a bending stress component, the latter of which comprises x axis and y axis bending information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Once the sensor measurement signal is obtained from the sensors and from the bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> in the bending stress measurement configuration and mode, the bending moments can be determined as follows, preferably in processor <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> or its equivalent. The root sum square of the outputs from bridges <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> yields the magnitude (lbf*ft) of bending moment in the pin member. The arctangent (degrees) of the quotient of the outputs from these bridges in bending mode yields the direction of bending moment (i.e., the orientation of the plane containing the bending moment), e.g., in degrees counterclockwise from the positive x-axis strain gage grouping (axial-circumferential half bridge pair, BX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> It may be preferred in some applications to include fillers, adhesives, coatings and/or the like to secure and protect the components. In the presently preferred embodiments, for example, fillers such as M-BOND GA2 and adhesives such as those identified herein above are used to encase the electrical components, secure wiring, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> The invention, as noted, is not necessarily limited to the specific embodiments and illustrations shown and described here. The description above in terms of a rectilinear coordinate system (x, y, z), for example, has been used merely to better illustrate the preferred embodiments and the related principles of the invention. It of course will be understood and appreciated by persons skilled in the art that other coordinate systems also could be used, and that translations of such coordinate systems to and from a rectilinear coordinate system are possible. Instead of x and y sensors as described above, for example, the sensing device may be configured to operate in radial or polar coordinate system. Embodiments of the invention in that case would operate in the same manner as herein described, although a translation of coordinate systems from one system to the other likely would be required. Such coordinate system translations are well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Additional advantages and modifications will readily occur to those skilled in the art. Therefore, the invention in its broader aspects is not limited to the specific details, representative devices and methods, and illustrative examples shown and described. Accordingly, departures may be made from such details without departing from the spirit or scope of the general inventive concept as defined by the appended claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member, comprising: 
<claim-text>a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis, the pin member body comprising a bending portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing device positioned at the pin member body within the bending portion for sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain, and for outputting a sensor measurement signal representative of the bending strain; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor measurement signal output device for outputting the sensor measurement signal from the sensor device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device senses components of the bending strain in the bending portion along an x axis and a y axis, the x axis and the y axis being orthogonal to the pin member axis and to each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pin member body comprises a bolt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pin member body has a cylindrical shape about the pin member axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the pin member body comprises a head; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the bending portion is adjacent to the head. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device comprises: 
<claim-text>first and second x-axis sensor elements for measuring the bending strain along the x axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second y-axis sensor elements for measuring the bending strain along the y axis. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the first and second x axis sensor elements comprises an axial sensor for sensing strain in a pin member axial direction corresponding to the pin member axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the pin member body comprises a shank including a shank perimeter lying in a plane orthogonal to the pin member axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the first and second x axis sensor elements comprises a tangential sensor for sensing strain in a tangential direction tangential to the shank perimeter. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the first and second y axis sensor elements comprises an axial sensor for sensing strain in a pin member axial direction corresponding to the pin member axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the pin member body comprises a shank including a shank perimeter lying in a plane orthogonal to the pin member axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the first and second y axis sensor elements comprises a tangential sensor for sensing strain in a tangential direction tangential to the shank perimeter. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>each of the first and second x axis sensor elements and each of the first and second y axis sensor elements comprises an axial sensor for sensing strain in a pin member axial direction corresponding to the pin member axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the pin member body comprises a shank including a shank perimeter lying in a plane orthogonal to the pin member axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the first and second x axis sensor elements and each of the first and second y axis sensor elements comprises a tangential sensor for sensing strain in a tangential direction tangential to the shank perimeter. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the sensing device comprises 
<claim-text>an x axis bridge having a left side and a right side, the left x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right x axis bridge side being in a first aligned x axis configuration, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second position of the left x axis bridge side and the second position of the right x axis bridge side being in a second aligned x axis configuration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements being in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device comprises: 
<claim-text>an x axis bridge having a left side and a right side, the left x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right x axis bridge side being in a first aligned x axis configuration, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second position of the left x axis bridge side and the second position of the right x axis bridge side being in a second aligned x axis configuration; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the sensing device being in the bending stress measurement mode when the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the sensing device comprises 
<claim-text>an x axis bridge having a left side and a right side, the left x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right x axis bridge side being in a first aligned x axis configuration, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second position of the left x axis bridge side and the second position of the right x axis bridge side being in a second aligned x axis configuration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements being in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device comprises: 
<claim-text>an x axis bridge having a left side and a right side, the left x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right x axis bridge side being in a first aligned x axis configuration, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second position of the left x axis bridge side and the second position of the right x axis bridge side being in a second aligned x axis configuration; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the sensing device being in the bending stress measurement mode when the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the sensing device comprises 
<claim-text>a y axis bridge having a left side and a right side, the left y axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right y axis bridge side comprising first and second positions, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right y axis bridge side being in a first aligned y axis configuration, and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second position of the left y axis bridge side and the second position of the right y axis bridge side being in a second aligned y axis configuration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements being in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device comprises an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration, 
<claim-text>the sensing device being in the bending stress measurement mode when the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned opposed y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the sensing device comprises 
<claim-text>a y axis bridge having a left side and a right side, the left y axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right y axis bridge side comprising first and second positions, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right y axis bridge side being in a first aligned y axis configuration, and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second position of the left y axis bridge side and the first position of the right y axis bridge side being in a second aligned y axis configuration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the tangential sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements being in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device comprises an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration, 
<claim-text>the sensing device being in the bending stress measurement mode when the axial sensor of the first and second y axis sensor elements are in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the sensing device is in the axial stress measurement configuration when the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements are not in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the sensing device comprises 
<claim-text>an x axis bridge having a left side and a right side, the left x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right x axis bridge side comprising first and second positions, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right x axis bridge side being in a first aligned configuration, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second position of the left x axis bridge side and the second position of the right x axis bridge side being in a second opposed configuration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the axial sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements being in one of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration, and the tangential sensors of the first and second x axis sensor elements being in the other of the first aligned x axis configuration and the second aligned x axis configuration; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the sensing device further comprises 
<claim-text>a y axis bridge having a left side and a right side, the left y axis bridge side comprising first and second positions and the right y axis bridge side comprising first and second positions, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first position of the left x axis bridge side and the first position of the right y axis bridge side being in a first aligned configuration, and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second position of the left y axis bridge side and the second position of the right y axis bridge side being in a second aligned configuration, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the axial sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements being in one of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration, and the tangential sensors of the first and second y axis sensor elements being in the other of the first aligned y axis configuration and the second aligned y axis configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing device comprises a bridge assembly having an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a switching device operatively coupled to the sensing device for switching between an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switching device comprises a solid state switching circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the pin member comprises a head; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the switching device is positioned at the pin member head. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the pin member head includes an external surface and a notch disposed in the external surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the switching device is mounted to the external surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the pin member comprises a head including a head cavity; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the switching device is positioned at the pin member head cavity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switching device comprises a periodic switching signal source for providing a periodic switching signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the instrumented pin member further comprises a switching device operatively coupled to the bridge assembly for switching between the axial stress measurement configuration and the bending stress measurement configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the sensing device comprises a pair of bridges each having an axial stress measurement configuration and a bending stress measurement configuration; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the switching device comprises a switch operatively coupled to the pair of bridges for switching the pair of bridges between the axial stress measurement configuration and the bending stress measurement configuration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switching device switches the pair of bridges to the bending stress measurement configuration substantially simultaneously. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. An instrumented pin member, comprising: 
<claim-text>a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis, the pin member body comprising a bending portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing device positioned on the pin member body within the bending portion for sensing a bending stress in the bending portion during a bending stress measurement mode and for outputting a sensor measurement signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switching device operatively coupled to the sensing device for switching the sensing device in and out of the bending stress measurement mode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor signal output device for communicating the sensor measurement signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A system for measuring bending at a joint, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>an instrumented pin member disposed at the joint, the instrumented pin member comprising 
<claim-text>a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis, the pin member body comprising a bending portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing device positioned at the pin member body within the bending portion for sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain, and for outputting a sensor measurement signal representative of the bending strain, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor measurement signal output device for outputting the sensor measurement signal from the sensor device; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a data receiving device operatively coupled to the sensor measurement signal output device for receiving the sensor output signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the instrumented pin member further comprises a switching device operatively coupled to the sensing device for switching the sensing device in and out of a bending stress mode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the system comprises a plurality of the instrumented pin members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the data receiving device comprises a data processor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the data receiving device comprises a data display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A method for measuring bending at a joint, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>disposing an instrumented pin member at the joint, the instrumented pin member comprising a pin member body disposed about a pin member axis, the pin member body comprising a bending portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>sensing a bending strain in the bending portion exclusive of a net axial strain during a bending stress measurement mode and outputting a sensor measurement signal, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>communicating the sensor measurement signal to a data receiving device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in claim <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, wherein the disposing of the instrumented pin member comprises disposing a plurality of the instrumented pin members at the joint so that the instrumented pin members are substantially equally spaced about the joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in claim <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, wherein the sensing includes switching in and out of the bending stress measurement mode.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000314A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000314A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000314A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000314A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000314A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000314A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
