<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000358A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000358A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000358A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000358A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000358A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000358A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000358A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000358A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000358A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000358A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000358A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000358A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000358A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000358A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000358A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000358A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000358</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09885176</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010621</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B26D005/42</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>083</class>
<subclass>247000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>083</class>
<subclass>277000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>083</class>
<subclass>282000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>083</class>
<subclass>210000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>083</class>
<subclass>212000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>083</class>
<subclass>230000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>083</class>
<subclass>727000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>083</class>
<subclass>728000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Adjustable shuttle stop apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gerald</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Harris</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Pryor</city>
<state>OK</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Timothy</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Neall</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Pryor</city>
<state>OK</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MCAFEE &amp; TAFT</name-1>
<name-2>TENTH FLOOR, TWO LEADERSHIP SQUARE</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>211 NORTH ROBINSON</address-1>
<city>OKLAHOMA CITY</city>
<state>OK</state>
<postalcode>73102</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A adjustable shuttle stop apparatus for use in controlling feeding of material to a machining operation on a machine tool, such as a band saw. The apparatus comprises a feed conveyor, a band saw adjacent to the feed conveyor, a shuttle vise movably disposed on the feed conveyor, and an adjustable stop on the feed conveyor for adjusting a distance between the stop and the shuttle vise and for stopping the shuttle vise at the cutting position. The adjustable stop compensates for undesired movement of the shuttle vise caused by clamping the workpiece such that the distance between the stop and the shuttle vise remains substantially constant. This allows for a consistent cut length of the workpiece on subsequent cutting cycles. Different embodiments of the adjustable stop are disclosed along with a method of use of the apparatus. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to stops used in controlling the feeding of material as a workpiece to a machining operation, such as cutting a length of the material on a band saw, and more particularly, to an adjustable stop which compensates for undesired movement of the workpiece. The stop is illustrated in conjunction with a shuttle vise on a band saw, but the stop may be used in other applications, such as the feeding of material to a punch press, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Machines for cutting material, such as large band saws which are used to cut workpieces formed of elongated materials, are well known in the art. The workpiece material is positioned on a feed conveyor adjacent to the saw blade and moved into a cutting position under the saw blade by a shuttle vise which is moved to a clamping position to initially clamp the material and then move in a direction toward the saw blade and to a cutting position. A stop is sometimes used to limit movement of the shuttle vise and to insure it stops at the desired cutting position. As the material is moved, it extends beyond the saw blade onto a receiving conveyor where it is clamped by a fixed vise adjacent to the saw blade. At this point, the material is cut by the saw blade. While the saw blade is cutting, the shuttle vise is released from the material and moved back to the desired clamping position to clamp the material again and move it to the cutting position for the next cutting operation. This type of saw works well for many applications where the cut length of the material is not particularly critical. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> However, in cases where the cut length of the material may be critical this prior art saw may not be able to position the material in the cutting position accurately enough to insure that the cut length is within the desired tolerances. Closer tolerance requirements are becoming more common. The problem has to do with the straightness of the material, surface imperfections, and/or flexibility of the material and the deflection thereof when clamped by the shuttle vise. When the vise clamps the material, the clamping action may actually cause the shuttle vise to move slightly due to these variations in the material. This means that the shuttle vise is moved away from or toward the stop with the result that the cut length of the material may be correspondingly longer or shorter than desired. Obviously, if the movement of the shuttle vise can be greater than the cut length tolerances on the workpiece, this is very undesirable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention solves this problem by providing an adjustable stop to compensate for the amount of undesired movement of the shuttle vise and transmitting a signal to a controller which adjusts the position of the stop. Thus, when the shuttle vise moves to the cutting position and engages the adjusted stop, the cut length of the material will be at the proper length. That is, the adjustment of the stop compensates for the undesired movement of the shuttle vise so that the cut length of the material stays within the desired tolerances. Also, the encoder will detect the incorrect position of the shuttle vise and will adjust the front stop to compensate for the positional error in the shuttle vise. In addition to this positional adjustment, when the shuttle vise clamps the material to be cut, the encoder will detect variances which occur while clamping and will make an adjustment for that error also. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It will be understood by those skilled in the art, that this adjustable stop apparatus is useful in any application in which material is clamped and moved. Accordingly, the invention is not intended to be limited to a band saw application. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention may be described as a material cutting apparatus comprising a feed conveyor, a band saw adjacent to the feed conveyor, a shuttle vise movably disposed on the feed conveyor and an adjustable stop on the feed conveyor for adjusting a distance between the stop and the shuttle vise. The shuttle vise is adapted for clamping a workpiece on the feed conveyor when in a clamping position and moving the workpiece to a cutting position adjacent to the band saw. The stop is also adapted for stopping the shuttle vise at the cutting position. Preferably, the stop is adapted for adjusting the distance between the stop and shuttle vise in an amount equal to movement of the shuttle vise caused by clamping the workpiece or errors in the initial positioning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The apparatus may further comprise an encoder adapted for generating a signal in response to the movement of the shuttle vise and an actuator for moving the adjustable stop in response to the signal. The apparatus may further comprise a controller for receiving the signal and transmitting this signal to the actuator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The apparatus may additionally comprise a positional sensor for sensing a position of the adjustable stop and transmitting a positional signal in response thereto to the controller. The positional sensor may a transducer, switch or other type of sensor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the adjustable stop comprises a wedge having an angled face opposite the shuttle vise and an actuator for moving the wedge transversely with respect to the feed conveyor. The actuator is characterized by any linear motion device, such as a pneumatic or hydraulic cylinder. In this first embodiment, the apparatus may further comprise a bumper disposed on the shuttle vise. The bumper has an angled face corresponding to the angled face on the wedge, and movement of the wedge results in varying the distance between the face on the bumper and the face on the wedge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In a second embodiment, the adjustable stop comprises a stepped member having a plurality of faces directed toward the shuttle vise and an actuator for moving the stepped member transversely with respect to the feed conveyor. The actuator may be the same or similar to that described for the first embodiment. In the second embodiment, the apparatus may further comprise a bumper attached to the vise and having a face thereon. The actuator is adapted for moving the stepped member such that a selected one of the plurality of faces is aligned with the face on the bumper. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In a third embodiment, the adjustable stop comprises a sleeve, a shaft threadingly connected to the sleeve, and a prime mover for rotating the shaft. The shaft has an end with a face thereon directed toward the shuttle vise. Rotation of the shaft varies the distance between the face and the shuttle vise. The third embodiment may further comprise a bumper attached to the shuttle vise and adapted for engaging the face on the end of the shaft. The prime mover may be directly connected to the shaft or may be connected to the shaft by a drive train such as a first pulley connected to the shaft, a second pulley connected to the prime mover, and a belt interconnecting the first and second pulleys. It will be understood that the adjustable stop mechanism could be mounted on the shuttle vise and the fixed bumper attached to the saw frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Preferably, in the third embodiment, the apparatus further comprises a spring engaging the shaft and biasing the shaft longitudinally with respect to the sleeve for eliminating play in the threaded connection between the shaft and sleeve. The third embodiment may also comprise a switch and a cam rotatable by the prime mover and having a cam lobe thereon for engaging the switch when the cam is in a predetermined position. This predetermined position preferably corresponds to a longitudinal mid-point of the shaft. The switch is connected to the controller for the shuttle vise so the system can be reset with the location of the shaft known. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In a fourth embodiment, the adjustable stop comprises an eccentric cam and a prime mover for rotating the cam. Rotation of the cam varies the distance between the cam surface and the shuttle vise. A bumper may be attached to the shuttle vise and adapted for engaging the cam surface. The prime mover may be directly connected to the cam, such as by a shaft, or may be connected to the cam by a drive train, such as a belt-and-pulley assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The present invention may also be described as a method of cutting a workpiece comprising the step of (a) providing a material cutting apparatus comprising a feed conveyor, a band saw adjacent to the feed conveyor, a shuttle vise movably disposed on the feed conveyor, an adapter for clamping a workpiece on the feed conveyor when in a clamping position and moving the workpiece to a cutting position adjacent to the band saw, and a stop on the feed conveyor for stopping the shuttle vise at the cutting position. The method further comprises the steps of (b) detecting movement of the shuttle vise resulting from clamping the workpiece and (c) adjusting the stop on the feed conveyor for compensating for the movement of the shuttle vise such that a distance between the shuttle vise and the stop remains substantially constant. Step (c) may also comprise adjusting the stop for compensating for initial inaccurate positioning of the shuttle vise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Step (c) may comprise generating a signal in response to the movement of the shuttle device and transmitting the signal to an actuator for moving the adjustable stop in response to the signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, step (c) comprises moving a wedge on the stop transversely with respect to the feed conveyor. In another embodiment, step (c) comprises moving a stepped member having a plurality of faces thereon transversely with respect to the feed conveyor. In still another embodiment, step (c) comprises rotating a shaft connected to the stop. In an additional embodiment, step(c) comprises rotating an eccentric cam to vary the distance between a cam surface on the cam and the shuttle vise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Numerous objects and advantages of the invention will become apparent as the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments is read in conjunction with the drawings which illustrate such embodiments.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a side view of the band saw apparatus with adjustable shuttle stop of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a plan view of the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an end view as seen from the feed side of the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a schematic of the control circuit for the adjustable stop used in the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> schematically illustrates a first embodiment of the adjustable stop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic of a second embodiment of the adjustable stop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a third embodiment of the adjustable stop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a view of the adjustable stop as seen from the bottom of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates a fourth embodiment of the adjustable stop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a plan view of the fourth embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows a variation of the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates another variation of the first embodiment.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the drawings and more particularly to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the band saw apparatus with adjustable shuttle stop of the present invention is shown and generally designated by the numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a horizontally disposed feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a horizontally disposed receiving conveyor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is disposed between feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and receiving conveyor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and is adapted for cutting workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> formed of elongated material. Workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> includes a single piece or multiple pieces bundled and/or stacked together. Band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> will normally be connected to receiving conveyor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> generally comprises a pair of side rail supports <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> interconnected by a plurality of cross members <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Side rail supports <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are supported on a plurality of legs <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> above a ground surface <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> also has a plurality of longitudinally spaced, transversely extending rollers <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> rotatably mounted on a pair of longitudinally extending roller supports <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Roller supports <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are attached to, or integral with, side rail supports <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> A shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is mounted on feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and may be moved longitudinally therealong as will be hereinafter described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> comprises an outer housing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> formed by a pair of upright members <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> interconnected by a horizontal member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Upright members <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are slidably mounted on side rail supports <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by a pair of linear guide rail bearings <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Each linear bearing <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> includes a rail <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and a rail bushing <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> movably disposed on the rails. Linear bearings <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are of a kind known in the art and provide substantially free longitudinal movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> with respect to feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with relatively little friction. Linear bearings <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> also are designed to resist both horizontal and vertical forces applied by rail bushings <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> on rails <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Thus, linear bearings <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> provide a guide for longitudinal movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and support to resist forces applied to the shuttle vise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment, shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> also comprises a stationary vise plate <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> attached to upright member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and a movable vise plate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> attached to upright member <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> by a vise actuator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Vise actuator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> may be of any kind known in the art, such as a hydraulic or pneumatic cylinder or other device capable of providing the desired motion. By energizing actuator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in a manner known in the art, movable vise plate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may be moved in a transverse direction toward or away from stationary vise plate <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, vise plate <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> may also be movable by an actuator (not shown) similar to actuator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. It is not intended that the invention be limited only to a shuttle vise having a movable plate and a stationary plate. Movable vise plate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is adapted to engage workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and clamp it against stationary vise plate <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> in a manner hereinafter described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> A drive mechanism is utilized to move shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> along rails <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of linear bearings <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, this drive mechanism comprises a driven sprocket <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> mounted at one end of feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a drive sprocket <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> mounted at an opposite end of feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and a chain <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> wrapped around, and engaged with, the sprockets. As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, chain <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is connected to one side of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> at an attachment point <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and the other end of the chain is attached to the shuttle vise at another attachment point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> on the opposite side of the shuttle vise. It will be seen by those skilled in the art that rotation of drive sprocket <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> in a clockwise direction as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> will result in a corresponding movement of chain <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> around sprockets <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> which causes shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to move to the right toward band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Similarly, counterclockwise rotation of driven sprocket <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> will cause the shuttle vise to move away from the band saw. Drive sprocket <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is actuated by a prime mover <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of a kind known in the art, such as a reversible electric motor, a servomotor, a hydraulic motor, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Other drive mechanisms could also be used. For example, shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> could be driven using a rack and pinion system, a hydraulic or pneumatic cylinder, a rotating screw device, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> An encoder strip <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is attached to one of side rail supports <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> adjacent to one of rails <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. An encoder reader <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is attached to shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and adapted to read encoder strip <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> as the shuttle vise is moved along feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. As will be further described herein, encoder reader <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> generates an encoder signal in response to the movement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment, also shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> as well as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</cross-reference>, a belt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is attached to shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and the belt engages belt pulleys <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. An encoder <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>&prime; is used to measure the rotation of belt pulley <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> corresponding to the movement of belt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, and thus of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. As will be further described herein in this embodiment, encoder <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>&prime; generates an encoder signal in response to the movement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, other methods of measuring the movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be used. For example, measurement could be by use of a laser, using an encoder to measure rotation of a pinion gear on a rack attached to the shuttle vise, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Receiving conveyor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> comprises a pair of side supports <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> interconnected by cross members <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. Side supports <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are supported on ground surface <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> by a plurality of legs <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Receiving conveyor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> also includes a plurality of longitudinally spaced transverse rollers <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> rotatably mounted on a pair of longitudinally extending roller supports <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. Roller supports <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> are attached to, or integral with, the corresponding cross members <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> comprises an outer housing <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> which contains a rotating band saw blade <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and band saw driver <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> therein. Band saw driver <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is of a kind known in the art, such as an electric motor. Band saw portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is mounted such that band saw blade <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> may be moved downwardly so that it cuts through workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> when the workpiece is at the cutting position thereof. Again, the invention is not intended to be limited to the particular band saw embodiment shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> A fixed vise <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is positioned adjacent to the inlet side of band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and is of construction similar to shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> except that the fixed vise does not move. Fixed vise <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> has an outer housing <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> with a stationary vise plate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> attached to the housing and a movable vise plate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> connected to the housing by a vise actuator <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Vise actuator <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is similar to previously described vise actuator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and, when energized, may be used to position movable vise plate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> toward and away from stationary vise plate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Alternately, two movable vise plates could be utilized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Similarly, another fixed vise <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> may be located adjacent to the discharge side of band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Fixed vise <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> has an outer housing <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> with a stationary vise plate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> attached to the housing and a movable vise plate <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> connected to the housing by a vise actuator <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Vise actuator <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is similar to previously described vise actuator <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and, when energized, may be used to position movable vise plate <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> toward and away from stationary vise plate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. Optionally, two moveable vise plates could be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as previously described is of a kind generally known in the art, such as that disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,353,910, a copy of which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further comprises an adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> for limiting the movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> toward band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> when moving workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to the cutting position. Shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> stops moving toward band saw portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> when bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> on the shuttle vise engages adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> control circuit for adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is shown. Shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is driven as previously described by prime mover <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and the corresponding movement of encoder strip <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, results in encoder <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> precisely locating the position of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and sending a signal in response to that position to a controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> sends a signal to a stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> which controls movement of adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> toward and away from shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> As will be further described herein, adjusting stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to compensate for errors in positioning and/or movement caused by clamping, speeds up positioning time for shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> makes fine adjustments easier than the more coarse general positioning of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> as well as providing adjustment after clamping workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In operation, workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is positioned on feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> such that it may be engaged by shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. As previously stated, workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may include a plurality of elongated items, such as pieces of steel bar stock. Shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> moves away from band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> until it reaches the desired clamping position which is predetermined, based upon the desired cut length of workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Vise actuator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is energized so that movable vise plate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is moved toward stationary vise plate <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to clampingly engage workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> between the vise plates. As previously mentioned, the action of clamping workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may cause shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to move somewhat from its original, predetermined clamping position. Because the material of workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may not be straight, may have surface imperfections, or may compress or flex during clamping, the reaction forces thus applied to shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and the tolerances of all of the components, can result in the shuttle vise moving from the optimum position thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> After clamping, shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is moved toward band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> until it engages stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> at the cutting position. If stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is fixed, any movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> caused by the clamping on workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> will result in the overall movement of the shuttle vise to be something other than what is desired. This is a particular problem, if the undesired movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> during the clamping operation results in a change which is outside the tolerance of the cut length of workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. That is, if shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is moved away from band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and away from a fixed stop, the cut length of the material will be greater than desired. Similarly, if shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is moved toward band saw portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> during clamping, the resulting movement toward a fixed stop would cause the workpiece to be cut shorter than desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Because of the nature of the materials clamped, it is virtually impossible to prevent this type of movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> eliminates this problem. When shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is moved to its clamping position in a direction away from band saw portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, this movement is measured by encoder <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. After clamping, the additional movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is also detected by encoder <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. Encoder <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> sends a signal to controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> which in turn energizes stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> to move adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to a distance equal to, and in the same direction as, the movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> during clamping. That is, if the clamping causes shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to be moved back from its desired position by 0.060 inches, stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> will move adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> away from band saw <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and toward shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by the same distance. Thus, when shuttle <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is then moved from the clamping position to the cutting position, it will move the original, predetermined distance. Thus, there has been compensation for the undesired movement during clamping. This compensation by adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> provides that the cut lengths of workpiece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are substantially the same for each cycle. In this way, much more precise cut length tolerances can be met using apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> than with previously known band saws. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Also, controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> receives a positional signal from a positional sensor <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> in response to the current position of stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and/or adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Sensor <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> may be a transducer or other sensor if a kind known in the art. It can even be a switch triggered by movement of adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Sensor <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> and the positional signal therefrom are used to control movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in order to maximize the available adjustable movement of adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. For example, if adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> were in an extended position, controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> would control the initial movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to stop the shuttle vise such that it requires adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to retract for the correct length, and vice versa. Alternatively, adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can automatically be reset to a mid-position whenever shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is moved to its clamping position. The various embodiments discussed herein explain this further. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, specific embodiments of adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are shown and generally designated by the numerals <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>C and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>D. While four embodiments of adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are shown, the invention is not intended to be limited only to these four. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> first embodiment adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A is shown. In this embodiment, shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a first embodiment bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>A thereon. Bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>A has a face <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> which is angled from a transverse plane with respect to apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A comprises a wedge supported for transverse movement on a support <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is connected to a first embodiment stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A. Stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A is illustrated as a pressure-actuated hydraulic or pneumatic cylinder, but any other linear motion device providing linear movement of stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A would be acceptable, as will be further described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> has a face <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> which is angled to correspond to face <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> on bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Undesired movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> upon clamping is detected by encoder <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> which sends a signal to stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A to move wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> transversely with respect to feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> along support <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. By moving wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to the left as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the point of contact on face <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is moved closer to face <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, and conversely, moving wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to the right in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> will move face <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> away from face <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The amount of movement of stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is determined by controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> so that the distance between faces <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is moved by the same amount, and in the same direction as, the undesired movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> during clamping. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Sensor <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>A sends a positional signal to controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to control movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in order to maximize the available adjustable movement of adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A as previously described generally in the discussion of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a second embodiment adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B which is somewhat similar to first embodiment <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A. In second embodiment <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B, shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a second embodiment bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>B having a transversely extending face <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> thereon. Adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B includes a stepped member <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> supported on a support <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and actuated by a second embodiment stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B. Stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B is essentially the same as first embodiment stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A and may comprise a hydraulic or pneumatic cylinder or other linear movement device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Stepped member <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> has a plurality of stepped surfaces, such as <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> thereon. While three such stepped surfaces are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that more or less stepped surfaces could be utilized depending on circumstances. When stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B is actuated to locate face <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> opposite bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>B, the distance between faces <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> will be less than between faces <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the distance between faces <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> will be less than between faces <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. By energizing stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>B in response to a signal from controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, the desired face <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is positioned opposite face <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to compensate for movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> when clamping. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Sensor <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>B sends a positional signal to controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to control movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in order to maximize the available adjustable movement of adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>B as previously described generally in the discussion of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, a third embodiment adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>C is illustrated in which shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>C thereon with a face <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> extending transversely. Third embodiment stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>C comprises a mount <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> with an internally threaded sleeve <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, such as an Acme nut, attached thereto. Mount <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may be attached to fixed object such as one of side rail supports <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of feed conveyor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>). A shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is threadingly engaged with sleeve <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and has an end face <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> thereon generally opposite face <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> on bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>C. As illustrated, third embodiment stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>C comprises a pulley assembly with a pulley <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> which is connected to another pulley <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> by a drive belt <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. Pulley <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is attached to a shaft <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> of a prime mover <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, also part of stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>C, and driven by shaft <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> in response to a signal from controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Thus, when shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> moves undesirably during clamping, prime mover <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> is actuated in response to that movement. Prime mover <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> is of a type which is reversible, such as a reversible electric motor, a servomotor, hydraulic pump, etc. Actuation of prime mover <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> results in corresponding rotation of pulleys <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> through drive belt <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. This rotates shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> within sleeve <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> which in turn causes longitudinal movement of shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and end face <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> toward or away from face <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. In this way, the distance between faces <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> may be adjusted to correspond with the clamping movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The total longitudinal movement of shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is on the order of about 0.1 inches which is not enough to cause any significant alignment problems of pulley <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> with respect to pulley <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> A spring <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> is attached to mount <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> by any means know in the art. Spring <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> has a cantilevered spring arm <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> which engages a groove <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> in a distal end of shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. Spring arm <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is preloaded to always bias shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> in a direction indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> regardless of the longitudinal position of the shaft. This biasing of shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> insures that any slack or &ldquo;play&rdquo; in the threaded engagement of the shaft with sleeve <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> is eliminated and therefore does not affect the longitudinal positioning of shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> A cam <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> is connected to shaft <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> of prime mover <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> on the outside of pulley <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Cam <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> has a cam lobe <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> thereon adapted for engaging sensor <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>C, such as a switch <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Switch <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is of a kind known the art and is connected to controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, but other types of sensors could be used. Preferably, cam lobe <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> engages switch <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, when shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is approximately at its mid-point longitudinally. In this way, controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> can easily be reset and recalibrated when shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is not positioned too far in either longitudinal direction thereof. Thus, switch <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> acts as another embodiment of sensor <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> as generally illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, shaft <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> could be directly coupled to the shaft of a prime mover which may be any type of device which provides reversible rotational movement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Finally, referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>, a fourth embodiment adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>D is shown in which shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>D thereon with a face <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> extending transversely. Fourth embodiment stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>D comprises an eccentric cam <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> driven by fourth embodiment stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D through a shaft <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. Stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D could also be connected to cam <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> by a belt-and-pulley assembly in a manner known in the art. Fourth embodiment stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>D is preferably a prime mover, such as a reversible step motor which allows rotation of cam <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> in either direction in variable increments, although other rotatable devices could also be used. Cam <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> has an outer cam surface <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> thereon which is adapted for contacting face <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> on bumper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>D. By rotation of cam <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight>, it will be seen by those skilled in the art that the distance between the center of shaft <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> and the point of contact of cam surface <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> with face <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> may be varied to adjust the position of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Sensor <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>D sends a positional signal to controller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> related to the rotational position of shaft <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> and/or cam <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> to control movement of shuttle vise <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in order to maximize the available adjustable movement of adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>D as previously described generally in the discussion of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference>, two variations of first embodiment adjustable stop <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>A are shown. It will be seen by those skilled in the art that these variations may be incorporated in other embodiments in addition to the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11, a</cross-reference> stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A&prime; is shown as a reversible step motor or the like connected to wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> by a screw member which results in linear movement of the wedge as the motor is rotated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, linear motion of wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is provided by a rack and pinion gear system. A pinion gear <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> is connected to a stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A&Prime; by a shaft <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. Pinion gear <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> engages a gear rack <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> which is connected to wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. This, of course, results in linear movement of rack <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> and wedge <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> in response to rotation of pinion gear <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>. Stop actuator <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A&Prime; is shown as a prime mover, such as a reversible step motor, but other rotatable devices could also be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> It will be seen, therefore, that the band saw with adjustable shuttle stop of the present invention is well adapted to carry out the ends and advantages mentioned, as well as those inherent therein. While presently preferred embodiments of the apparatus have been shown for the purposes of this disclosure, numerous changes in the arrangement and construction of parts may be made by those skilled in the art. All such changes are encompassed within the scope and spirit of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A material cutting apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a feed conveyor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a machine tool adjacent to said feed conveyor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shuttle vise movably disposed on said feed conveyor, said shuttle vise being adapted for clamping a workpiece on said feed conveyor when in a clamping position and moving the workpiece to a cutting position adjacent to the machine tool; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustable stop on said feed conveyor for adjusting a distance between said stop and said shuttle vise and stopping said shuttle vise at said cutting position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>said adjustable stop is adapted for adjusting said distance in an amount approximately equal to movement of said shuttle vise caused by clamping the workpiece. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>an encoder adapted for generating a signal in response to said movement of said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for moving said adjustable stop in response to said signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a controller for receiving said signal and transmitting said signal to said actuator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a positional sensor for sensing a position of said adjustable stop and transmitting a positional signal in response thereto to said controller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said controller transmits a signal for varying said cutting position of said shuttle vise in response to said positional signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a positional sensor adapted for sensing a position of said adjustable stop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said positional sensor is a transducer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said positional sensor is a switch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said adjustable stop comprises: 
<claim-text>a wedge having an angled face opposite said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for moving said wedge transversely with respect to said feed conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is characterized by a linear motion device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said apparatus further comprises a bumper disposed on said shuttle vise, said bumper having an angled face corresponding to the angled face on said wedge, wherein movement of said wedge results in varying the distance between the face on said bumper and the face on said wedge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said adjustable stop comprises: 
<claim-text>a stepped member having a plurality of faces directed toward said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for moving said stepped member transversely with respect to said feed conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is characterized by a linear motion device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said apparatus her comprises a bumper attached to said shuttle vise and having a face thereon; 
<claim-text>wherein, said actuator is adapted for moving said stepped member such that a selected one of said faces is aligned with said face on said bumper. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said adjustable stop comprises: 
<claim-text>a sleeve; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shaft having an end with a face thereon directed toward said shuttle vise, said shaft being threadedly connected to said sleeve such that rotation of said shaft varies the distance between said face and said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a prime mover for rotating said shaft. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>a bumper attached to said shuttle vise and adapted for engaging said face on said end of said shaft. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pulley connected to said shaft; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pulley connected to said prime mover; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a belt interconnecting said first and second pulleys. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a spring engaging said shaft and biasing said shaft longitudinally with respect to said sleeve for eliminating play in a threaded connection between said shaft and sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>a switch; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cam rotatable by said prime mover and having a cam lobe thereon for engaging said switch when said cam is in a predetermined position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said predetermined position corresponds to a longitudinal mid-point position of said shaft. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said adjustable stop comprises: 
<claim-text>an eccentric cam having a cam surface thereon directed toward said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for rotating said cam. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is a reversible step motor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said apparatus further comprises a bumper attached to said shuttle vise and having a face thereon; 
<claim-text>wherein, said cam surface is adapted for engagement by said face. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said machine tool is a band saw. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an actuator for moving said adjustable stop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is linear motion device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is a pressure-actuated cylinder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is connected to said stop by a screw device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is connected to said stop by a rack and pinion gear system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. On a machine of the type comprising a feed conveyor, a material cutting device adjacent to the feed conveyor, a shuttle vise longitudinally movably disposed on said feed conveyor and adapted for clamping a workpiece when in a clamping position and moving the workpiece to a cutting position under the material cutting device, the improvement comprising: 
<claim-text>a stop disposed on said feed conveyor for limiting movement of said shuttle vise toward said material cutting device, the distance between said stop and said shuttle vise being adjustable in response to movement of said shuttle vise when clamping the workpiece. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>an encoder adapted for generating a signal in response to said movement of said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for moving said stop in response to said signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a positional sensor adapted for sensing a position of said stop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said positional sensor is a transducer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said positional sensor is a switch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>said stop comprises a wedge having an angled face opposite said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator adapted for moving said wedge transversely with respect to said feed conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a bumper disposed on said shuttle vise, said bumper having an angled face corresponding to the angled face on said wedge, wherein movement of said wedge results in a variation of the distance between the face on said bumper and the face on said wedge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>said stop comprises a stepped member having a plurality of faces directed toward said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator adapted for moving said stepped member transversely with respect to said feed conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a bumper attached to said shuttle vise and having a face thereon; 
<claim-text>wherein, said actuator is adapted for moving said stepped member such that a selected one of said plurality of faces is aligned with said face on said bumper. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>an actuator comprising: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sleeve; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shaft threadingly engaged with said sleeve and rotatable therein; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a prime mover for rotating said shaft; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein: 
<claim-text>said stop comprises an end of said shaft directed toward said shuttle vise. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a bumper attached to said shuttle vise and adapted for engaging said end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator further comprises: 
<claim-text>a first pulley connected to said screw; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pulley connected to said prime mover, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a belt interconnecting said first and second pulleys. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a spring engaging said shaft and baising said shaft longitudinally with respect to said sleeve for eliminating play in a threaded connection between said shaft and sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising; 
<claim-text>a switch; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cam rotatable by said prime mover and having a cam lobe thereon for engaging said switch when said cam is in a predetermined position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference> wherein, said predetermined position corresponds to a longitudinal mid-point positon of said shaft. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>said stop comprises an eccentric cam having a cam surface directed toward said shuttle vise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for rotating said cam. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is a reversible step motor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said apparatus further comprises a bumper attached to said vise and having a face thereon; 
<claim-text>wherein, said cam surface is adapted for engagement by said face. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The improvement of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>said machine tool is a band saw; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said material cutting device is a band saw blade. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an actuator for moving said adjustable stop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is linear motion device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is a pressure-actuated cylinder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is connected to said stop by a screw device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said actuator is connected to said stop by a rack and pinion gear system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. A method of cutting a workpiece comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>(a) providing a cutting apparatus comprising a feed conveyor, a machine tool adjacent to said feed conveyor, a shuttle vise movably disposed on said feed conveyor and adapted for clamping the workpiece when in a clamping position and moving the workpiece to a cutting position adjacent to the machine tool, and a stop for stopping the shuttle vise at the cutting position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) detecting movement of said shuttle vise resulting from clamping the workpiece; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) adjusting said stop on said feed conveyor for compensating for said movement of said shuttle vise such that a distance between said shuttle vise and said stop remains substantially constant. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein step (c) comprises: 
<claim-text>generating a signal in response to said movement of said shuttle device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting said signal to an actuator for moving said adjustable stop in response to said signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein step (c) comprises moving a wedge on said stop transversely with respect to said feed conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein step (c) comprises moving a stepped member having a plurality of faces thereon transversely with respect to said feed conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein step (c) comprises rotating a shaft connected to said stop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein step (c) comprises rotating a cam such that a cam surface on said cam is moved with respect to said feed conveyor.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000358A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000358A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000358A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000358A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000358A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000358A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000358A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000358A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
