<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001025A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001025A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001025A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001025A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001025</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895460</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B67D005/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B05B001/30</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B05B001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>071000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>589000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>548000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>581100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Showerhead leak detector and shutoff</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<family-name>Quintana</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Westminster</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KLEIN, O&apos;NEILL &amp; SINGH</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2 PARK PLAZA</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 510</address-2>
<city>IRVINE</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>92614</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A microprocessor-operated valve is held in a showerhead to shut off flow of water if a leak detector measures any water leakage. The valve is mounted in a conduit in the showerhead and operated to shut off water flow if the water leak detector senses leakage from the showerhead. An electric motor is held in the showerhead and actuated to drive a gear train to close the normally-open valve and shut off water flow through the conduit. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to fluid control devices, and more particularly, to a showerhead, having a sensor for detecting any leaks and automatically shutting off the flow of water through the showerhead to avoid wastage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> As homeowners and others are well aware, if appliances, sinks, showerheads, and the like, that use water are not connected properly, or as they get older, they may leak. Such leakage, if not stopped, can cause unsightly stains, waste large amounts of water, or cause flooding, which may result in unwanted cost and/or serious problems. Furthermore, with the increase in population and use of water, water is becoming scarce and conservation is becoming increasingly more important. Therefore, the detecting and prevention of water leaks to save water when using showerheads and other devices has become a priority. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention incorporates a leak detecting sensor that is secured in a desired location in a showerhead. The sensor is programmed to transmit a signal to a control device connected to a low-voltage, rechargeable battery or other type power source for energizing a motor to operate a valve to cut off water flow through the showerhead. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention further includes a reset button that indicates that the showerhead has been shut off, and which must be reset before the showerhead may be used further. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is a general object of the present invention to provide an improved and simplified showerhead flow control and leak detector device. It is a particular object of the present invention to provide an improved and simplified showerhead water flow control and leak detector device, including a sensor that is mounted in a desired location in the showerhead. It is yet another particular object of the present invention to provide an improved and simplified showerhead water flow control and leak detector system, having a separate leak detecting portion, and a motor operated shutoff valve. It is still another particular object of the present invention to provide an improved and simplified microprocessor controlled showerhead shutoff device having a leak sensing member mounted adjacent a flow conduit therethrough. It is a further particular object of the present invention to provide an improved and simplified showerhead water flow control device having a microprocessor-operated drive motor connected to a power source held in the showerhead for operating a shutoff valve means when a leak detector mounted in the showerhead determines that there is a water leak. And, it is a still further object of the present invention to provide a showerhead leak detector and shutoff means having an accoustical detector and an indicating means therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> These and other objects and advantages of the present invention are achieved by providing a showerhead having a built-in leak detecting means mounted in a pre-selected location and electrically connected, between a power source and an electric motor for activating a gear-operated valve held in the showerhead.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The objects and features of the present invention, which are believed to be novel, are set forth with particularity in the appended claims. The present invention, both as to its organization and manner of operation, together with further objects and advantages, may best be understood by reference to the following description, taken in connection with the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side elevational view, partially in cross-section, showing a showerhead of the present invention having a gear-operated valve means mounted in a conduit to control water flow through the showerhead, together with a leak detector mounted on the conduit and electrically connected between a power source, a mircoprocessor and a motor for actuating the valve means; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a partial diagramatic perspective view of the interior of the showerhead of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a partial cross-sectional view of the conduit, with shutoff valve in the open position; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a further partial cross-sectional view of the conduit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, with the shutoff valve in the closed position.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The following description is provided to enable any person skilled in the art to make and use the invention and sets forth the best modes contemplated by the inventor of carrying out his invention. Various modifications, however, will remain readily apparent to those skilled in the art, since the generic principles of the present invention have been defined herein specifically to provide for an improved and simplified showerhead water leak detector and shutoff valve. A showerhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown having a body <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with an internal flow conduit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> connected between an inlet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a massage or other type head <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A gear-actuated valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, such as a ball valve, is held in the conduit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Shower water will normally enter inlet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, pass through internal flow conduit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and through a passage <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the normally open valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to exit through the massage head <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> However, if a water leak is detected from or in the showerhead <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, as explained more fully below, a motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> will be actuated to drive a gear <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to turn valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> ninety degrees (90&deg;) to the closed position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, so as to cut off water flow through the showerhead. The gear <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may drive a single gear <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, connected to a drive shaft <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> connected to valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, or may be connected to a drive train having a plurality of gears to operate the valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The number and size of gears used in the drive train will depend on the size of the showerhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and the motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and how fast it is desired to close and open valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A leak detector <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which may be of any type, but which is preferably of the acoustical type, such as a microphone, is secured in a pre-selected area to the exterior of the conduit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The leak detector <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is directly connected to a microprocessor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by a lead <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The microprocessor is connected to a self-contained internal power source, such as a battery <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> held in a watertight compartment <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. When a leak is detected by detector <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> a signal is sent to the microprocessor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is actuated by the power source <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to rotate and close the normally open valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, approximately 90&deg;, by means of the gear drive system <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in the body <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Upon closing of valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, water flow in conduit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> will be shut off. When the motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> turns gears <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to the water shutoff position, it actuates a lever <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to actuate a switch <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, such as a microswitch. When switch <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is actuated, a button <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, preferably colored red or some other bright color, is actuated or released to indicate that valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is closed and that water flow through the showerhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has been interrupted. The leak may then be repaired and the button <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> reset to operate the motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to return the valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to the open position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The leak detector <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> mounted on the conduit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> must be calibrated or set so as to only operate motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to close the valve when it senses a slow leak or drip from the showerhead, and not when there is a continuous flow of water through conduit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, during normal use of the showerhead. This calibration can be programmed into the microprocessor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art will appreciate that various adaptations and modifications of the just-described preferred embodiments can be configured without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention. Therefore, it is to be understood that, within the scope of the appended claims, the invention may be practiced other than as specifically described herein. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A showerhead having a combination water flow control and leak detecting device therein, comprising: 
<claim-text>a body having an inlet, an outlet and a through conduit connected therebetween; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a leak detector sensor held in the body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a power source held in the body and connected to the leak detector sensor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for connecting the leak detector sensor to a motor-actuated, normally-open valve held in the conduit, to control the flow of water through the conduit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The showerhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a motor connected to the valve; the motor being secured within the body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The showerhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a switch, actuated by the motor-actuated, normally-open valve, when the valve is in the closed position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The showerhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a plurality of gears connected between the motor and the valve. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The showerhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a button on the switch to indicate that the normally-open valve is closed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The showerhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the leak detector sensor is secured to an exterior surface of the conduit, the motor-actuated, normally-open valve has a gear drive mounted between an electrical motor held in the body and a rotary valve element held in the conduit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The showerhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a microprocessor held in the body and connected between the power source, the leak detector sensor and a motor for actuating the rotary valve element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A combination water flow control and water leak detecting device held in a showerhead, comprising: 
<claim-text>a body having an inlet, an outlet and a through conduit connected therebetween; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a leak detector sensor secured to an exterior surface of the conduit within the body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a microprocessor motor-operated, normally-open valve, including a gear drive and an electrical power source held in the body to control the flow of water through the conduit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for connecting the leak detector sensor to the microprocessor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and water leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the leak detector sensor is a microphone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and water leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a switch held in the body, which switch is actuated when the normally-open valve is closed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and water leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the switch includes a reset button that is in an extended position, outside of the body, when the normally-open valve is closed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and water leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the normally-open valve is a ball valve and the gear drive includes a plurality of gears connected to a shaft secured to the ball valve. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and water leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the power source is at least one battery held in a housing formed in the body </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and water leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the motor-actuated, normally-open valve has a gear drive mounted between an electrical motor held in the body and a ball valve element held in the conduit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and water leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the power source is at least one battery held in the body, and the body has a reset switch mounted therein, operatively connected to the gear drive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A combination water flow control and leak detecting device for a showerhead, comprising: 
<claim-text>a leak detector mounted on a conduit passing between an inlet and an outlet of the showerhead; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gear-driven, motor-actuated, normally-open valve, held in the conduit to control flow of water therethrough; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a microprocessor and a power source held in the showerhead and operatively connected between the leak detector and an electric motor to control the flow of water through the conduit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and leak detecting device for a showerhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the leak detector includes a microphone to transmit a signal to the microprocessor to close the normally-open valve if a leak is detected. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and leak detecting device for a showerhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein there are a plurality of gears held between the electric motor and the normally-open valve, and a switch is operated by at least one of the plurality of gears when the normally-open valve is closed, and, the switch includes an indicating means thereon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the indicating means is a reset button that extends from an outer surface of a body of the showerhead. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The combination water flow control and leak detecting device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the normally-open valve is actuated approximately 90&deg;, between the normally-open position and a closed position, by a gear drive held between an electric motor and a ball valve element; and the electric motor is connected to the microprocessor and a battery held in the showerhead.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001025A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001025A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
