<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002965A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002965A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002965A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002965A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002965A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002965A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002965A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002965A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002965A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002965A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002965A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002965A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002965A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002965A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002965A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002965A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002965</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10186325</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B65F003/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>414</class>
<subclass>408000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Automatic refuse container latch</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10186325</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020628</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09824128</doc-number>
<document-date>20010402</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6413031</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bruce</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Yakley</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Neenah</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>White</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Oshkosh</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mark</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Wittak</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Oshkosh</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Andrew</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Desotell</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Appleton</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>COOK, ALEX, MCFARRON, MANZO, CUMMINGS &amp; MEHLER LTD</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>SUITE 2850</address-1>
<address-2>200 WEST ADAMS STREET</address-2>
<city>CHICAGO</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60606</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An automatic refuse container latch that is adapted to receive one of the opposed, outwardly-extending portions of a trunnion for a refuse container in order to secure the refuse container to a refuse collection vehicle. The latch comprises a forward stop that is adapted to be secured to the refuse collection vehicle and which forms a part of a channel for slidingly receiving one of the outwardly extending portions of the trunnion. An elongated locking arm is provided that has first and second ends with a pivot connection intermediate the first and second ends. The pivot connection is slidingly secured to an elongated track. A piston actuator is provided comprising a cylinder and a rod, with the rod being movable between a retracted and an extended position. A locking ear is provided for capturing the second end of the locking arm. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This Application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. application Ser. No. 09/824,128, filed Apr. 2, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to refuse collection vehicles and, more particularly, to an improved automatic refuse container latch for securing a refuse container to the refuse collection vehicle during the emptying of the contents of the container into the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Large refuse collection containers are commonly used in commercial and high density residential settings. Refuse collected in a container is typically transferred to a refuse collection vehicle by placing an upper edge of the container adjacent a loading edge or sill of the hopper of the refuse collection vehicle. The upper edge of the container includes a trunnion structure, about which the container is pivoted to tip the container so that the contents are discharged into the hopper. The tipping of the container is commonly accomplished with the aid of a lift mechanism, such as a push bar, winch/cable/hook combination, or reeving cylinder, which are well known. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> For safety reasons, a pair of latch mechanisms is typically used to secure the container to the truck hopper adjacent the sill, each latch mechanism defining an enclosed slot that captures an outwardly-extending portion of the trunnion. Many latch mechanisms require that the container be positioned with respect to the truck so that the trunnion bar extensions are within the slot area to be closed by the latch. It can be difficult to so position the container, due to its weight and/or the unevenness of the surface supporting the container. These difficulties are exacerbated if the latch must be manually closed by the truck operator, as the operator may not have sufficient strength to close the latch and move the trunnion bar into the desired area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is the principle object of the present invention to provide an improved refuse container latch for use with a refuse collection truck. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> More specifically, it is an object of the present invention to provide an automatic refuse container latch that safely and securely locks a container to the refuse collection vehicle and that is relatively simple in design and reliable in operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is a further object to provide an automatic refuse container latch that is durable and able to withstand heavy use and abuse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is a still further object to provide an automatic refuse container latch that retracts to an out-of-the-way position when not in use. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> These objects, as well as others that will become apparent upon reference to the following detailed description and the accompanying drawings, are accomplished by a refuse container latch that is adapted to receive one of the opposed, outwardly-extending portions of a trunnion for a refuse container in order to secure the refuse container to a refuse collection vehicle. The latch comprises a forward stop that is adapted to be secured to the refuse collection vehicle and which forms a part of a channel for slidingly receiving one of the outwardly-extending portions of the trunnion. An elongated track is provided which is secured to the refuse collection vehicle. An elongated locking arm is provided that has first and second ends, with a pivot connection intermediate the first and second ends. This pivot connection is slidingly secured to the elongated track. A piston actuator is provided comprising a hydraulic cylinder and a rod, with the rod being moved between a retracted and an extended position, one of the cylinder and the rod being adapted to be pivotally connected to the refuse collection vehicle and the other of the cylinder and rod being pivotally connected to the first end of the locking arm. A locking ear is provided for capturing the second end of the locking arm. Thus, when the rod moves from its retracted position to its extended position, the pivot connection first slides along the elongated track, the latching arm rotates about the pivot connection to capture one of the outwardly-extending portions of the trunnion and draw the trunnion into the channel. Simultaneously, the locking ear captures the second end of the latching arm to secure the trunnion and the channel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, the track comprises a pair of spaced-apart plates, each having a substantially identical elongated slot for receiving the pivot connection of the latching arm. The latching arm is located between the plates and the pivot connection comprises a transverse shaft that is captured in the slots of the two plates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Additionally, a major portion of the slot or track, beginning with the first end, is generally horizontal, while a minor portion of the slot or track at the second end is generally vertical. Accordingly, the latching arm moves horizontally as the pivot connection travels from the first end of the slot along the major portion of the slot, then rotates about the pivot connection and moves vertically as the pivot connection travels along the minor portion of the slot to the second end of the slot, with the second end of the latching part simultaneously being captured by the locking ear as the pivot connection reaches the end of the minor portion of the slot.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a rear hopper refuse collection truck and a refuse container. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an enlarged fragmentary perspective view of a portion of the refuse collection truck of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing an automated refuse container latch according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of the automated refuse container latch of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, showing the latch in its retracted position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a side view of the automated refuse container latch of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, showing the latch in the extended or locked position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> an enlarged fragmentary perspective view of an alternate embodiment of an automated refuse container latch according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side view of the automated refuse container latch of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, showing the latch in its retracted position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a side view of the automated refuse container latch of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, showing the latch in the extended or locked position.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Turning to the figures of the drawings, there is seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1 a</cross-reference> perspective view of a rear hopper refuse collection truck, generally indicated by <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, with which an automated refuse container latch according to the present invention may be advantageously used. The truck <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a hopper portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> depending from the truck generally rearward of the rear wheels <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into which refuse is dumped for compaction. The hopper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a rearward-facing opening generally defined by sidewalls <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a lower loading edge or sill <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and an upper edge <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Each sidewall <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes an extension or ear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> adjacent the loading sill <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> that cooperates with the container latch to be described in detailed below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Also shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a rollable refuse container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> having an open end including, on one side, a trunnion bar <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> that has a portion that laterally extends beyond each sidewall of the container, referred to herein as the container arms <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The trunnion bar <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the container is typically between 1&frac14;, inches to 1&frac34; inches in diameter and between 77&frac12; inches and 78 inches from end-to-end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> As is well known, to empty the container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of its contents, the container is positioned with the trunnion bar <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> adjacent the loading edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the hopper, with the container arms <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> between the sidewall extensions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The container arms <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are then secured to the hopper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is then pivoted about the trunnion <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> by means of e.g., a hydraulically-actuated container push bar <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (also called a tipper bar or kick bar), a drum winch <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> having a cable and hook (not shown) , or a reeving cylinder <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The container push bar <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes support arms <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> that are pivotally connected to the hopper sidewall <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> by means of posts <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The push bar <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may include lift pads <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to prevent damage to the container when engaged by the push bar. A dumping cylinder <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> moves the push bar <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to dump the contents of the refuse container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In keeping with the invention, a hydraulically-actuated refuse container latch, generally designated <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, is provided at each side of the hopper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to form a pocket or channel that securely captures the container arms <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. As best seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the refuse container latch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> includes a forward stop <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> made of, e.g., forged steel which is secured by welding to the loading sill <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and sidewall extension <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. (While only one container latch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is shown, it is understood that a container latch is located at each end of the loading sill <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> so that both container arms <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are securely held prior to tipping the container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>.) The forward stop <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be provided with a reinforcing member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of, e.g., square bar stock, on its aft side. Forward stop <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> limits the forward movement of the container arms <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and thus the container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, into the hopper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, while the sidewall extensions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> prevent excessive movement of a container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in a direction lateral to the refuse collection truck <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> An elongated locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is provided that cooperates with the forward stop <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and sidewall extension <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to close the pocket or channel after the container arm <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is located therein. The locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is movable by means of an hydraulically-actuated piston cylinder <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and piston rod <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> between a retracted position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) that is substantially out-of-the-way under the loading sill <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to an extended, locking position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). To this end, the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is mounted for both pivoting and sliding motion to a generally elongated track <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> secured to the bottom of the hopper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and/or loading sill <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, the track <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> includes two substantially-identical, spaced-apart plate members <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, each having an elongated slot <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Each slot <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> includes a generally horizontal major portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a shorter, minor portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that is at an angle with respect to the major portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is disposed between the two plates <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and includes a transverse shaft <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> intermediate its two ends that is sized to be captured in the slots <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of the plate members <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The shaft <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is able to both pivot with respect to the plate members <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and travel along the length of the slot <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, thus providing for both linear and rotatory motion of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A guide member <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, preferably in the form of a roller, is secured to the track <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> aft of the elongated slot <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The guide member <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> underlies the free end of the retracted locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. As the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> moves along the track, the guide member <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> engages an angled portion <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to move the free end of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> upward to capture the end of the container arm <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> To move the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> from the retracted position to the extended position, one end of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is pivotally secured by a clevis <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to the piston rod <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the piston cylinder <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> being pivotally mounted to a bracket <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> secured to the underside of the hopper <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. When in the extended or locked position, the other end of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is received in a locking ear <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, the locking ear <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is formed integrally with the forwarded stop <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and includes an aperture for receiving the end of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. To facilitate the entry of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> into the aperture, the end of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> may be beveled, as shown at <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The locking ear <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> may also include a reinforcing member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, which can be positioned to guide the beveled end <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> toward the aperture in the locking ear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The track <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is designed so that the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> moves first generally horizontally as the pivot connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> moves along the major portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the slot <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> from its retracted position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) to an intermediate position. In this intermediate position, the beveled end <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is aft of the locking ear <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and the container arms <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of a container <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. When the pivot connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> reaches the intersection of the major portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the minor portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the slot, the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> then pivots about the pivot connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in a clockwise direction (as illustrated) to capture the container arm <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and draw it toward the forward stop <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> then moves generally vertically as the pivot connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> moves along the minor portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the slot so that the beveled end <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> passes through the aperture in the locking ear <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to close the channel, thus capturing the arm <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the trunnion bar <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). This action is reversed to release the container arms <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> upon retraction of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Turning to FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, there is seen an alternate embodiment of an automatic container latch according to the present invention. To the extent that the structure of FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> corresponds to that shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, identical reference numerals are used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment of FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the guide roller <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> has been eliminated. Instead, the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> includes two spacedapart pivot connections <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In addition, the minor portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the slot <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> has been lengthened. Thus, as the two pivot connections <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>move along the track from the retracted position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) to the extended position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>), pivot connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>first reaches the intersection of the major portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and minor portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the slot <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> then rotates clockwise about the pivot connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to capture the container arm and draw it toward the forward stop <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The pivot connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>then travels up the minor portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the slot <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> followed by the second pivot connection <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, thus moving the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> generally vertically so that the free end of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is captured by the locking ear <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to close the channel. To this end, the free end of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> includes a notch <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> that engages a lip <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> on the locking ear <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. This action is reversed to release the container arms upon retraction of the locking arm <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As can be appreciated, the hydraulic pistons for the locking arms can be controlled in a manner well known in the art, with the extension and retraction of both locking arms preferably occurring simultaneously. To further enhance operator safety, the controls for the push bar or winch <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can also be configured so that the locking arms must first be in their extended, latched position capturing the trunnion bar before the push bar or winch can be operated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Thus, an automated refuse container latch achieving all the objects of the present invention has been provided. While the latch has been described in terms of a preferred embodiment, there is no intention to limit the invention to the same. Instead, the invention is defined by the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A refuse container latch for securing a refuse container having an trunnion with opposed, outwardly-extending portions to a refuse collection vehicle, the latch comprising: 
<claim-text>a forward stop adapted to be secured to the refuse collection vehicle and forming a part of a channel for slidingly receiving one of the outwardly-extending portions of the trunnion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated track having a first and second end adapted to be secured to the refuse collection vehicle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated locking arm having first and second ends with first and second spaced-apart pivot connections intermediate the first and second ends slidingly secured to the elongated track; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston actuator comprising a cylinder and a rod, the rod being movable between a retracted and an extended position, one of the cylinder and the rod being adapted to be pivotally connected to the refuse collection vehicle and the other of the cylinder and rod being pivotally connected to the first end of the locking arm; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a locking ear for capturing the second end of the locking arm, </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby, when the rod moves from the retracted to the extended position, the pivot connections first slide along the elongated track from the first end to the second end and, upon the first pivot connection reaching the second end of the track, the locking arm rotates about the first pivot connection to capture one of the outwardly-extending portions of the trunnion to draw the refuse container trunnion into the channel and, upon the second pivot connection reaching the second end of the track, the locking ear capturing the second end of the locking arm to secure the trunnion in the channel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The refuse container latch of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the track comprises a pair of spaced-apart plates, each having substantially identical elongated slots for receiving the pivot connection of the locking arm, the locking arm being located between the plates and the pivot connections each comprising a transverse shaft that is captured in the slots of the plates. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The refuse container latch of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a major portion of the track beginning with the first end is generally horizontal and a minor portion of the track at the second end is generally vertical so that, as the rod moves from the retracted to the extended position, the locking arm moves first linearly as the pivot connections travel from the first end of the track along a major portion thereof, the locking arm then rotating about the first pivot connection and then moving linearly as the second pivot connection travels along the minor portion of the track, the second end of the locking arm being captured by the locking ear as the pivot connections move along the minor portion of the track. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The refuse container latch of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a major portion of the slots, beginning with the first end, is generally horizontal and a minor portion of the slots, at the second end, is generally vertical, so that, as the rod moves from the retracted to the extended position, the locking arm moves linearly as the pivot connections travel from the first end of the slots along the major portion of the slots, then rotates about the first pivot connection, and then moves linearly as the second pivot connection moves along the minor portion of the slots, the second end of the locking arm being captured by the locking ear as the pivot connections move along the minor portion of the slots. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A refuse container latch for securing a refuse container having a trunnion with opposed outwardly-extending portions, to a refuse collection vehicle, the latch comprising: 
<claim-text>a forward stop adapted to be secured to the refuse collection vehicle and forming a part of a channel for slidingly receiving one of the outwardly-extending portions of the trunnion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated track having a first and second end adapted to be secured to the refuse collection vehicle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated locking arm having first and second ends with a pivot connection intermediate the first and second ends slidingly secured to the elongated track; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a guide member adjacent the second end of the elongated track; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piston actuator comprising a cylinder and a rod, the rod being movable between a retracted and extended position, one of the cylinder and rod being adapted to be pivotally connected to the refuse collection vehicle and the other of the cylinder and the rod being pivotally connected to the first end of the locking arm; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a locking ear for capturing a second end of the locking arm; 
<claim-text>whereby, when the rod moves from the retracted to the extended position, the pivot connection first slides along the elongated track from the first end to the second end, the locking arm riding on the guide member so that as the pivot connection reaches a location adjacent the second end of the track, the locking arm moves upward and rotates about the pivot connection to capture one of the outwardly-extending portions of the trunnion and to draw the refuse container trunnion into the channel, the locking ear capturing the second end of the locking arm to secure the trunnion in the channel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The refuse container latch of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the locking arm has a first angled portion constituting the first end, a first straight portion connected to the first angled portion, a second straight portion constituting the second end, and a second angled portion connecting the second straight portion to the first straight portion, each of the straight and angled portions having a longitudinal axis, with the longitudinal axes of the angled portions being substantially parallel and the longitudinal axes of the straight portions being substantially parallel, the pivot connection being at the transition between the first angled portion and the first straight portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The refuse container latch of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising sidewall extensions secured to the refuse collection vehicle adjacent the forward stop for limiting the lateral movement of the refuse container with respect to the refuse collection vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The refuse container of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the forward stop includes a reinforcing bar on its aft side.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002965A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002965A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002965A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002965A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002965A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002965A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002965A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002965A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
