<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000195A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000195A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000195A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000195A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000195A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000195A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000195</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895032</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A01D067/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>056</class>
<subclass>320100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Lawn mower guard device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<family-name>Watkins</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ft. Worth</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Myers &amp; Associates</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Law, P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Building 3, Suite 200</address-1>
<address-2>1827 Powers Ferry Road</address-2>
<city>Atlanta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<postalcode>30339</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A protective mulching device capable of quickly and interchangeably mounting to a lawn mower housing, wherein a magnetic mounting plate having exposed hook and loop fastener is easily and removably installed on the metal deck of a lawn mower proximate to the discharge opening, and wherein a broom-like strip having an arrangement of bristles on one side and hook and loop fastener on the other side is removably attached to the mounted plate on the lawn mower and is positioned so that the bristles at least partially obstruct the mower discharge opening, thereby encouraging grass clippings to remain within the cutting area for an extended time period, enhancing mulching effectiveness, and discouraging the passage of potentially dangerous projectiles therethrough. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to mower safety devices and, more specifically, to a protective mulch enhancing device capable of mounting to a lawn mower, thereby enabling the shielding of people and property from mower generated projectiles, while at the same time mulching grass. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Proper maintenance of a lawn requires routine mowing and edging. Completion of these tasks can be dangerous. Stones and other objects are often picked up and thrown by mower blades, becoming high-speed projectiles. In addition, razor sharp blade edges have been responsible for countless accidental foot and hand injuries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> As a result, protective guards have been designed to inhibit the ejection of projectiles from the base of the housing and to prevent the accidental entry of feet and hands into the cutting area. Utilization of these protective shields requires semi-permanent installation, such as bolting through the mower housing. This disadvantageously complex installation process typically necessitates disassembly of mower components to provide access to inner housing surfaces. In addition to being time consuming and tedious, such disassembly and reassembly can also be dangerous, wherein the handling of sharp mower blades is required. Thus, installation and use of such shielding devices can be effectively discouraged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Safety issues notwithstanding, routine lawn maintenance and mowing can be problematic. For instance, environmental concerns about landfills have led most to cease acceptance of grass and lawn clippings. Composting is one alternative, however, remains realistically unavailable to many. Direct mulching of grass clippings is an environmentally attractive alternative, wherein cut grass is mulched within the mower housing and then reintroduced onto the lawn. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Mulching devices have been designed for installation on existing mowers. Unfortunately, like the protective shields described above, utilization of these mulching devices requires semi-permanent installation, such as bolting through the mower housing. This disadvantageously complex installation process necessitates disassembly of mower components to provide access to inner blade housing and ejection chute surfaces. Moreover, mulching devices can be inherently dangerous, having their own sharp edges in addition to those of mower blades. Not only can these installation and safety issues discourage initial users, but as the blades and tines incorporated into these mulching devices become worn, the entire complicated process must be revisited to either sharpen or replace the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Another disadvantage of the complicated attachment methods for mower shields and mulching plates is that a user must purchase a separate device for each mower to be utilized, since they are not readily interchangeable. Thus, an individual or lawn service needing more than one size mower to accomplish mowing of a variety of landscape terrains would require more than one mower shield or mulching plate, necessitating increased expenditures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is readily apparent that there is a need for a mower guard capable of quickly and interchangeably mounting to any metal lawn mower housing, wherein a row of extended bristles are removably secured thereto, thereby enabling efficient mulching and quick replacement of worn parts, thus preventing the above-discussed disadvantages. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Briefly described, in a preferred embodiment, the present invention overcomes the above-mentioned disadvantages, and meets the recognized need for such a device, by providing a mower guard capable of quickly and interchangeably mounting to a lawn mower housing, wherein a row of bristles are removably secured thereto and extended therefrom, thereby enabling efficient mulching and interchangeability of parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to its major aspects and broadly stated, the present invention is a protective mulching device capable of magnetically mounting to a lawn mower, thereby enabling the shielding of people and property from mower generated projectiles, while at the same time utilizing a row of bristles to contain and mulch grass cuttings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> More specifically, the present invention is an elongated, magnetic mounting plate for removably securing to the metal deck of a lawn mower, wherein the outer surface of the positioned mounting plate has hook and loop fastener exposed thereon. A correspondingly elongated strip of hook and loop fastener with a broom-like arrangement of bristles affixed thereto is removably secured to the positioned mounting plate. The broom-like strip is positioned to enable the extended, closely spaced bristles to partially obstruct the mower discharge opening, thereby encouraging grass clippings to remain within the cutting area for an extended time period, enhancing mulching effectiveness, and discouraging the passage of potentially dangerous projectiles therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to provide a lawn mower guard device that is simpler in construction than prior art devices and thus less expensive to manufacture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to provide a lawn mower guard device that is easily and removably mounted to a lawn mower deck. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to provide a lawn mower guard device that limits the discharge opening of a mower, thereby increasing the retention time of grass clippings within the blade area and thus maximizing cutting and mulching thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to protect individuals and property from potentially dangerous projectiles while also enhancing mulching effectiveness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to increase the speed and safety of installation of lawn mower protective guards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to increase the speed and safety of installation of lawn mower mulching attachments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to provide an easily removable magnetic mount for a lawn mower mulching guard, thereby enabling quickly interchangeable use on a variety of mowers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to provide an easily removable broom-like strip, thereby enabling quick replacement of worn elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> A feature and advantage of the present invention is the ability of such a device to be inexpensively manufactured, thereby reducing the required material and labor costs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> These and other objects, features and advantages of the invention will become more apparent to one skilled in the art from the following description and claims when read in light of the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be better understood by reading the Detailed Description of the Preferred and Alternate Embodiments with reference to the accompanying drawing figures, in which like reference numerals denote similar structure and refer to like elements throughout, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top view of a mounting plate component of a lawn mower guard device according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention, showing exposed hook and loop fastener thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a bristle strip component of a lawn mower guard device according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention, showing an overturned corner having exposed hook and loop fastener thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a lawn mower guard device according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention, showing the mounting plate component of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> magnetically mounted on a lawn mower deck proximate to a discharge opening, and showing the bristle strip component of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> fastened to said mounting plate, partially blocking the discharge opening. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED AND ALTERNATE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In describing the preferred and alternate embodiments of the present invention, as illustrated in the figures, specific terminology is employed for the sake of clarity. The invention, however, is not intended to be limited to the specific terminology so selected, and it is to be understood that each specific element includes all technical equivalents that operate in a similar manner to accomplish similar functions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the present invention is a lawn mower guard device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprising mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Preferably, mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is substantially rectangular shaped with first surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, second surface <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, first end <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and second end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. In the preferred form, mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has magnetic characteristics, thereby enabling secure, removable placement on a metal surface. However, while it is preferred that mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is magnetic, the novel lawn mower guard device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> herein described could be utilized and configured wherein mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is not magnetic, but has a magnet mounted thereon thereby providing the intended result, specified features and advantages encompassed within the concept of the invention herein presented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Preferably, first surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is substantially flat and magnetized, whereby first surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can be removably secured to a metal deck of a lawn mower housing. Preferably, second surface <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is substantially flat with hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> affixed thereto. Hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> preferably extends substantially from first end <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to second end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Preferably, mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is approximately four inches wide, however, while four inches is the preferred width, other widths ranging from approximately one to eight inches could be used depending upon the intended mower housing dimensions, thereby enabling utilization of lawn mower guard device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> on a variety of personal and commercial mowers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is preferably substantially rectangular shaped with first surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, second surface <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, first end <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and second end <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Preferably, first surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is substantially flat with hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> affixed thereto. Hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> preferably extends substantially from first end <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to second end <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> thereof, whereby first surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is removably affixed to second surface <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Preferably, bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is approximately three and one-half inches wide, however, while three and one-half inches is the preferred width, other widths ranging from approximately one-half to seven and one-half inches could be used, thereby corresponding to the dimensions of mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> A plurality of narrowly spaced, substantially fine diameter bristles <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is preferably sewn to second surface <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Preferably, each bristle <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is elongated straw. However, while straw is the preferred bristle material, other appropriately strong and flexible alternatives could be used, such as, for exemplary purposes only, nylon, metal, rubber or plastic. Each bristle <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is preferably dimensioned to extend substantially across the width of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, protruding therefrom in a broom-like arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment, mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> could be metal, plastic or other formed material with a magnet or magnets mounted thereon, thereby enabling secure, removable placement on a metal surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment, mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> could be substantially arcuately shaped, thereby enabling placement on curved housing surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment, the width of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> could be decreased, thereby enabling placement of two bristle strips on mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, wherein two bristle extension lengths would be provided for increased mulching action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment, bristles <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> could be glued, welded, melded or otherwise affixed to second surface <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In use, first magnetic surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is removably positioned on a metal deck of a lawn mower, proximate to the mower discharge opening. Hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is thereby exposed on second surface <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Corresponding hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, exposed on first surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, is secured to hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, thereby affixing bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> at a user selectable position relative to the mower discharge opening. The broom-like arrangement of bristles <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> affixed thereto extend, partially obstructing the mower discharge opening. The degree of obstruction is determined by user placement of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Once in place, the bristles <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of lawn mower guard device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> restrict the ejection of potentially dangerous projectiles, such as stones, and also restrict the discharge of grass clippings, thereby causing increased retention thereof within the cutting area, enhancing mulching effectiveness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> If bristles <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> become worn, or if positioning adjustment is desired, bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is easily removed and replaced or repositioned by separating hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> on first surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of bristle strip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> from hook and loop fastener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on second surface <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of mounting plate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> If removal of lawn mower guard device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is desired, first magnetic surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is easily separated from the metal housing of the lawn mower without the use of any tools, wherein thereafter lawn mower guard device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can easily be placed onto another mower for further utilization. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Having thus described exemplary embodiments of the present invention, it should be noted by those skilled in the art that the within disclosures are exemplary only, and that various other alternatives, adaptations, and modifications may be made within the scope of the present invention. Accordingly, the present invention is not limited to the specific embodiments illustrated herein, but is limited only by the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A lawn mower guard device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a mounting plate having an outer surface and an inner surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bristled member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first hook and loop fastener carried by said outer surface of said mounting plate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hook and loop fastener having an exposed surface and a rear surface, said bristled member carried by said rear surface and said exposed surface removably secured to said outer surface of said mounting plate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one magnet carried on said inner surface of said mounting plate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The lawn mower guard device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bristled member is straw bristles sewn onto said rear surface of said second hook and loop fastener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The lawn mower guard device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bristled member is plastic bristles sewn onto said rear surface of said second hook and loop fastener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The lawn mower guard device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bristled member is plastic bristles fused onto said rear surface of said second hook and loop fastener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The lawn mower guard device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said bristled member is metal bristles extending from a substantially flat, substantially elongated plate, and wherein said plate is carried by said rear surface of said second hook and loop fastener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The lawn mower guard device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said mounting plate is substantially arcuately shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A mulch enhancing protective device for mounting on a lawn mower comprising: 
<claim-text>an elongated mounting plate having a magnetic inner surface and an outer surface, said outer surface having hook and loop fastener carried thereby; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elongated brush having an inner surface, said inner surface having hook and loop fastener carried thereby for removably securing said elongated brush to said outer surface of said magnetic mounting plate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The mulch enhancing protective device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elongated brush has straw bristles sewn thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The mulch enhancing protective device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elongated brush has plastic bristles affixed thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The mulch enhancing protective device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elongated brush has metal bristles carried thereby. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A mulch enhancing protective shield device for limiting lawn mower discharge comprising: 
<claim-text>a substantially rectangular, substantially flat magnetic plate having an outer surface, said outer surface having hook and loop fastener carried thereby; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a substantially rectangular shield having an upper edge, a lower edge, an outer surface, said outer surface substantially covered with semi-flexible, closely spaced tines, said tines secured proximate to said upper edge and said tines extending past said lower edge, and an inner surface, said inner surface having hook and loop fastener carried thereby for removably securing said shield to said plate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The mulch enhancing protective shield device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said semi-flexible, closely spaced tines are straw. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The mulch enhancing protective shield device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said semi-flexible, closely spaced tines are plastic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The mulch enhancing protective shield device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said semi-flexible, closely spaced tines are metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000195A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000195A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000195A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
