<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000940A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000940A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000940A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000940A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000940A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000940A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000940A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000940A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000940A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000940A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000940A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000940A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000940</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09962824</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010925</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05B003/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>219</class>
<subclass>540000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>219</class>
<subclass>541000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Heat dissipation devices for heater elements</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60302472</doc-number>
<document-date>20010702</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sidney</given-name>
<family-name>Furlong</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ogden</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Edward</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Zelazny</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>N. Ogden</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Joey</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Anderson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Taylorsville</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Thomas V. Miller</name-1>
<name-2>Howrey Simon Arnold &amp; White, LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO Box 4433</address-1>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>77210-4433</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A heat dissipation device for a heater. The heater having a heater element portion, cold pin portions, and connectors. The cold pin portions are connected between the heater element portion and the connectors. The heat dissipation device is connected to the cold pin portions of the heater element to dissipate conducted heat from the heater element portion. This is done through convection to the surrounding air before the conducted heat reaches the connectors. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present application claims priority from Provisional Application Serial No. 60/302,472 entitled &ldquo;Heat Dissipation Devices for Heater Elements&rdquo; filed Jul. 2, 2001, commonly owned by the assignee of the present invention and incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to heaters, and more particularly, to devices that dissipate heat that conducts from the heat generating element to its associated electrical connectors. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The use of heaters is a common industrial practice that has many applications. Such heaters may be required to heat an environment to maintain a desired temperature. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</cross-reference> show a conventional heater <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that may be used to heat an environment. The heater <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a heater element portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, cold pin portions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and connectors <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. When power is provided to the heater <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the heater element portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is the portion of the heater <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that generates heat. The cold pin portions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> extend between the heater element portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the connectors <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> but do not actively generate heat when power is applied to the heater <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Each connector <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has a base <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and an electrical terminal <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The base <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are used for mechanically attaching the heater to a wiring enclosure or other housing <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The terminals <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are used for electrically connecting the heater to a power source and controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A problem with conventional heaters is that heat generated from the heater element portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will conduct through the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and to the connectors <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. This may cause failure to sensitive wiring or controller components due to excessive temperatures. To overcome this problem, it has been known to use high temperature resistant wiring and components. Such wiring and components, however, are generally more expensive. It has also been known to locate the controller a sufficient distance away from the heater <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. This also has its inefficiencies. For example, the wiring that connects the heater to the controller may still be subject to excessive temperatures. Additionally, such a connection will result in less compact assemblies. It has further been known to use a secondary-cooling source such as fans or refrigeration. These methods are typically more expensive and require additional labor to manufacture or install. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to overcoming, or at least reducing the effects of, one or more of the problems set forth above. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> To that end, the present invention includes a heat dissipation device for a heater. The heater having a heater element portion, cold pin portions and connectors. The heat dissipation device includes a body portion that is attached to the at least one of the cold pin portions to dissipate heat conducted to the cold pin portion from the heater element portion. In one embodiment, the body portion of the heat dissipation device is in the shape of a strip that extends between the cold pin portions. In another embodiment, the body portion of the heat dissipation device is in the shape of a disc. In a further embodiment, the heat dissipation device has a plurality of fins. The plurality of fins extends from the body portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the present invention includes a heater having a heater element portion, a first and second cold pin portion, a first and second connector, and at least one heat dissipation device. The heater element portion has a first and second end. The first cold pin portion is connected to the first end of the heater element portion. The second cold pin portion is connected to the second end of the heater element portion. The first connector is attached to the first cold pin portion and the second connector is attached to the second cold pin portion. The at least one heat dissipation device is attached to the first cold pin portion and the second cold pin portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In a further embodiment, the present invention includes a heater having a heater element portion, a first and second cold pin portion, a first and second connector, and a first and second heat dissipation device. The heater element portion has a first and second end. The first cold pin portion is connected to the first end of the heater element portion. The second cold pin portion is connected to the second end of the heater element portion. The first connector is attached to the first cold pin portion and the second connector is attached to the second cold pin portion. The first dissipation device is attached to the first cold pin portion and the second dissipation device is connected to the second cold pin portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The above summary of the present invention is not intended to represent each embodiment, or every aspect of the present invention. This is the purpose of the figures and detailed description that follows.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Other objects and advantages of the invention will become apparent upon reading the following detailed description and upon reference to the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The foregoing and other aspects of the present invention will be best understood with reference to a detailed description of specific embodiments of the invention, which follows, when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>B are side views of a conventional, prior art heater that may be used to heat an environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is perspective view of one embodiment of a heater having a heat dissipation device according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of the heater in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>A-B are side and plan views of a strip of the heat dissipation device in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of another embodiment of a heater having a heat dissipation device according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A-B are side and plan views of the heat dissipation device for the heater in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a side view of another embodiment of a heater having a heat dissipation device according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>A-B are side and plan views of the heat dissipation device for the heater in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> While the invention is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments have been shown by way of example in the drawings and will be described in detail herein. However, it should be understood that the invention is not intended to be limited to the particular forms disclosed. Rather, the invention is to cover all modification, equivalents and alternatives falling within the scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF ILLUSTRATIVE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Illustrative embodiments will now be described with reference to the accompanying figures. Turning to the drawings, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference> show a heater <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> according to the present invention. In one embodiment, the heater <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has a heater element portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, cold pin portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and at least one heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> have a base <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and an electrical terminal <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The bases <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are used for mechanically attaching the heater to a wiring enclosure or other housing (not shown). The terminals <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are used for electrically connecting the heater <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to a power source and controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The terminals <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the connector <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to the heater element portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the heater element portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is a tubular heater element that has one turn so that the terminals <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are located in close proximity to each other. The present invention, however, is not limited to this specific design of a heater element portion and is applicable to other shapes and sizes. When power is provided to the heater <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> via the electrical terminals <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the heater element portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> will generate heat. The heater <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has two cold pin portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> that extend between the heater element portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and the connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> but do not actively generate heat when power is applied to the heater <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is preferably attached to each of the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the heater <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> has at least one strip <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> that extends between the two cold pin portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference>, each strip <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> has a body portion <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and holes or slots <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. The holes or slots <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> are used to attach the strip <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The attachment may be made by crimping, staking, welding or brazing the strip <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. What is important is that the attachment provide a good contact surface between the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the strip <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. To provide a better conducting surface, each hole or slot <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> may have a ridge <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. The body portion <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is used to conduct and convect heat that has transferred to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> from the heater element portion <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is made of a heat conducting material. Suitable materials may include brass, aluminum, steel or Monel&reg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The use of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> lowers the temperatures of the connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and any attached wiring, wiring enclosure or controller. This is accomplished by dissipating conducted heat through convection to the surrounding air before the conducted heat reaches the connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Peripheral temperatures are reduced by the use of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to the point where standard wiring may be used to connect power to the heater <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The number and size of the strips <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> for the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is implementation specific. Increasing the number of strips or size will enhance the heat dissipating abilities of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows another embodiment of a heater <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> according to the present invention. In this embodiment, the heater <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> has a heater element portion <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, cold pin portions <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, connectors <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, and at least one heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The connectors <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> have a base <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and an electrical terminal <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The bases <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> are used for mechanically attaching the heater to a wiring enclosure or other housing (not shown). The terminals <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> are used for electrically connecting the heater <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to a power source and controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Similar to the previous embodiment, the terminals <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to the heater element portion <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. The heater element portion <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may be a tubular heater element that has at least one turn so that the terminals <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> are located in close proximity to each other. When power is provided to the heater <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> via the electrical terminals <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, the heater element portion <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> will generate heat. The heater <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> has two cold pin portions <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> that extend between the heater element portion <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the connectors <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> but do not actively generate heat when power is applied to the heater <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is preferably attached to each of the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> of the heater <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, however, the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> has a plurality of discs <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> that surround each cold pin portion <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A and 6B</cross-reference>, each disc <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> has a body portion <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> and holes or slots <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. The holes or slots <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> are used to attach the disc <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. The attachment may be made by crimping, staking, welding or brazing the disc <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. As with the previous embodiment, what is important is that the attachment provides a good contact surface between the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and the discs <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. To provide a better conducting surface, each hole or slot <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> may have a ridge <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. The body portion <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> is used to conduct and convect heat that has transferred to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> from the heater element portion <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The heat dissipation devices <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A and 6B</cross-reference> are made of a heat conducting material. Suitable materials may include brass, aluminum, steel or Monel&reg;. The heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may comprise of individual discs <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> or formed from a single strip of metallic material wrapped around the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The use of the heat dissipation devices <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> lowers the temperatures of the connectors <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> and any attached wiring, wiring enclosure or controller. This is accomplished by dissipating conducted heat through convection to the surrounding air before the conducted heat reaches the connectors <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. Peripheral temperatures are reduced by the use of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to the point where standard wiring may be used to connect power to the heater <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. The number and size of the discs <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> for the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is implementation specific. Increasing the number of discs or size will enhance the heat dissipating abilities of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows another embodiment of a heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> according to the present invention. In this embodiment, the heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> has a heater element portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, cold pin portions <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, connectors <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, and at least one heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The connectors <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> have a base <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> and an electrical terminal <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. The bases <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> are used for mechanically attaching the heater to a wiring enclosure or other housing (not shown). The terminals <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> are used for electrically connecting the heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> to a power source and controller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Similar to the previous embodiments, the terminals <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to the heater element portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. The heater element portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may be a tubular heater element that has at least one turn so that the terminals <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> are located in close proximity to each other. When power is provided to the heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> via the electrical terminals <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, the heater element portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> will generate heat. The heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> has two cold pin portions <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> that extend between the heater element portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> and the connectors <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> but do not actively generate heat when power is applied to the heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> A heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is preferably attached to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> of the heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, however, the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> has a tubular body portion <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> and a plurality of fins <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>. The plurality of fins <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> are attached to the body portion <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A and 8B</cross-reference>, the body portion <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> has a hole or slot <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>. The hole or slot <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> is used to slide over the cold pin portion <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> of the heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. The heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is then attached to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> by crimping, staking, welding or brazing the body portion <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. As with the previous embodiments, what is important is that the attachment provides a good contact surface between the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> and the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. The fins <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> are used to conduct and convect heat that has transferred to the cold pin portions <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> from the heater element portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The heat dissipation devices <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A and 8B</cross-reference> are made of a heat conducting material. Suitable materials may include brass, aluminum, steel or Monel&reg;. The heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may formed from a single piece of metallic material. Alternatively, the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may be formed from separate components. For example, the body portion <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> may be a tube and individual fins <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> would be welded or otherwise attached to the body portion <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Like the previous embodiments, the use of the heat dissipation devices <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> lowers the temperatures of the connectors <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and any attached wiring, wiring enclosure or controller. This is accomplished by dissipating conducted heat through convection to the surrounding air before the conducted heat reaches the connectors <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. Peripheral temperatures are reduced by the use of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> to the point where standard wiring may be used to connect power to the heater <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. The number and size of the fins <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> for the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is implementation specific. Increasing the number of fins or size will enhance the heat dissipating abilities of the heat dissipation device <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> What has been described are heat dissipation devices that may be used with heaters to dissipate heat and protect sensitive wiring and components attached to the electrical connector of the heater. The heat dissipation devices described herein reduce the temperature of the electrical connector and attached wiring and components. This reduces the need for more expensive temperature resistant wiring and components. It also reduces the need for use of secondary cooling methods such as fans or refrigeration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described with reference to the preferred embodiments, obvious modifications and alterations are possible by those skilled in the related art. Therefore, it is intended that the invention include all such modifications and alterations to the full extent that they come within the scope of the following claims or the equivalents thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A heat dissipation device for a heater, the heater having a heater element portion, cold pin portions and connectors, the heat dissipation device comprising a body portion, the body portion of the heat dissipation device attached to at least one of the cold pin portions to dissipate heat conducted to the cold pin portion from the heater element portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The heat dissipation device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the body portion is in the shape of a strip, the strip extending between the cold pin portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The heat dissipation device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the body portion is in the shape of a disc. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The heat dissipation device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein heat dissipation device further has a plurality of fins, the plurality of fins extending from the body portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A heater comprising: 
<claim-text>a heater element portion having a first and second end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cold pin portion connected to the first end of the heater element portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cold pin portion connected to the second end of the heater element portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first connector attached to the first cold pin portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connector attached to the second cold pin portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one heat dissipation device attached to the first cold pin portion and the second cold pin portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one heat dissipation device is a metallic strip that extends between the first cold pin portion and the second cold pin portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one heat dissipation device is made of brass. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one heat dissipation device is made of steel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one heat dissipation device is attached to the first cold pin portion and the second cold pin portion by crimping. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A heater comprising: 
<claim-text>a heater element portion having a first and second end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cold pin portion connected to the first end of the heater element portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cold pin portion connected to the second end of the heater element portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first connector attached to the first cold pin portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connector attached to the second cold pin portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first heat dissipation device attached to the first cold pin portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second heat dissipation device attached to the second cold pin portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the first or second heat dissipation devices has a body portion in the shape of a disc. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one of the first or second heat dissipation devices is made of a metallic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the first or second heat dissipation devices has a body portion and a plurality of fins. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one of the first or second heat dissipation devices is made of a metallic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A heater comprising: 
<claim-text>a heater element portion having a first and second end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cold pin portion connected to the first end of the heater element portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cold pin portion connected to the second end of the heater element portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first connector attached to the first cold pin portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connector attached to the second cold pin portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a means attached to the first and second cold pin portions for dissipating the heat from the heater element portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the dissipation means includes a metallic strip that extends between the first cold pin portion and the second cold pin portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the metallic strip has at least one hole and a ridge protruding from an outer edge of the hole for attachment to the first and second cold pin portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the dissipation means includes a series of circular discs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein dissipation means includes a body portion and a plurality of fins, the plurality of fins extending from the body portion, the body portion attached to the first and second cold pin portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The heater of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein dissipation means is made of a metallic material.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000940A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000940A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000940A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000940A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000940A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000940A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
