<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002176A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002176A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002176A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002176A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002176A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002176A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002176A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002176A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002176A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002176A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002176</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10164694</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020610</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-31970</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010608</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B007/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>822000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Actuator for optical pickup</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dae-Jong</given-name>
<family-name>Jang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>STAAS &amp; HALSEY LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>700 11TH STREET, NW</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 500</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An actuator for an optical pickup includes a magnetic circuit having a structure in which coils to drive an objective lens in one direction selected from a focusing, tilting, or tracking directions, and magnets to drive the objective lens in the other directions. The coils and magnets are installed on the bobbin. The actuator for an optical pickup reduces the number of wires required for 6-axis direction driving, thereby making assembly easy. The actuator includes magnets, yokes, and coils in the bobbin, thereby reducing the mass of the bobbin, improving sensitivity, and increasing the efficiency of magnetic force. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of Korean Application No. 2001-31970, filed Jun. 8, 2001, in the Korean Intellectual Property Office, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an actuator for an optical pickup, and more particularly, to an actuator for an optical pickup having an improved structure in which assembly is easier and sensitivity is increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> An actuator for an optical pickup drives an objective lens in a focusing direction, in a tracking direction and/or in a tilting direction. Actuators for optical pickups include moving coil type actuators, which have a coil installed on a bobbin, and moving magnet type actuators, which have a magnet installed on a bobbin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> conventional moving coil type actuator for an optical pickup includes a pair of focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> installed at opposite ends of first sides of a bobbin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> on which an objective lens <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is installed. A pair of tracking coils <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are installed at opposite ends of second sides of the bobbin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Tracking magnets <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, which are opposite the corresponding tracking coils <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, are installed on a base <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are fixed and installed on external yokes <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, which are installed on the base <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Internal yokes <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> are installed on the base <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. One end of each of four wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which support the bobbin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and one end of each of two wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>which are used to drive the bobbin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in a tilting direction, are coupled to the bobbin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The other end of each of the four wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and the two wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are coupled to a mount <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The mount <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is fixed to the base <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The four wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and the two wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are paths used to apply current to the pair of focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In the conventional moving coil type actuator for an optical pickup shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, since the pair of focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the pair of tracking coils <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> drive the objective lens <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> in focusing and tracking directions using a synchronous driving method, and the pair of focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> drive the objective lens <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> in a tilting direction using an asynchronous driving method, the two wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as well as the four wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which are used as paths for applying current to the pair of focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, are required. That is, six wires (four wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and two wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) are required for the conventional moving coil type actuator for an optical pickup shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Since the bobbin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is light in weight, the conventional moving coil type actuator has a high sensitivity. However, since six wires (four wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and two wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) are required to drive the bobbin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in focusing, tracking, and tilting directions, the conventional moving coil type actuator has a complicated and cluttered structure and is difficult to assemble. That is, it is very difficult to attach six wires (four wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and two wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) to the narrow sides of the bobbin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, resulting in an increase in defects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> conventional moving magnet type actuator for optical pickup includes four magnets <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, pairs of which are installed at corresponding opposite sides of a bobbin <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. At the center of the bobbin <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is installed an objective lens <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. Two pairs of focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and two pairs of tracking coils <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are installed on corresponding sides of a base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> opposite corresponding pairs of the magnets <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Four holders <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, which support the bobbin <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, are installed in a mount <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which is fixed to the base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The four holders <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> only support the bobbin <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and are thus unlike the wires <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the conventional moving coil type actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, in the conventional moving magnet type actuator, the four magnets <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are installed on the bobbin <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and thus increase the mass of the bobbin <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. This increase in mass results in a decrease in a sensitivity of the actuator. Also, since the conventional moving magnet type actuator does not include yokes, it is difficult to obtain a path for a magnetic field. This difficulty decreases the efficiency of magnetic force in affecting the coils <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> To solve the above and other problems, it is an object of the present invention to provide an actuator for an optical pickup having an improved structure which is easier to assemble than a conventional moving coil type actuator for an optical pickup, and is more sensitive and uses magnetic force more efficiently than a conventional moving magnet type actuator for an optical pickup. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Additional objects and advantages of the invention will be set forth in part in the description which follows and, in part, will be obvious from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, to achieve the above and other objects, there is provided an actuator for an optical pickup according to an embodiment of the invention that includes a bobbin on which an objective lens is installed, holders coupled between a mount installed on a base and the bobbin to support the bobbin such that the bobbin is movable with respect to the base, and a magnetic circuit installed in the bobbin and in the base to drive the objective lens in focusing, tracking, and tilting directions, wherein the magnetic circuit includes coils installed on the bobbin and which drive the objective lens in one direction selected from focusing, tilting, and tracking directions, and magnets installed on the bobbin to drive the objective lens in another direction selected from the focusing, the tilting, and the tracking directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the invention, the magnetic circuit includes first and second coils installed at opposite first sides of the bobbin and are used to drive the objective lens in the focusing and the tilting directions, first and second magnets installed on the base opposite the corresponding first and second coils, tracking magnets installed at opposite second sides of the bobbin and are used to drive the objective lens in the tracking direction, and tracking coils installed on the base opposite the corresponding tracking magnets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, the magnetic circuit includes first and second magnets installed at opposite first sides of the bobbin and are used to drive the objective lens in the focusing and the tilting directions, first and second coils installed on the base opposite the corresponding first and second magnets, tracking coils installed at opposite second sides of the bobbin and are used to drive the objective lens in a tracking direction, and tracking magnets installed on the base opposite the tracking coils. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> According to yet another aspect of the invention, the holders comprise wires or leaf springs and are used as paths to apply current to the tracking or first and second coils installed on the bobbin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> According to still another aspect of the invention, the actuator further includes yokes to improve the efficiency of a magnetic force of the magnetic circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> According to still yet another aspect of the invention, the actuator further includes internal yokes installed on the base opposite the corresponding first and second coils, or external yokes installed on the base opposite the corresponding first and second magnets installed opposite the first and second coils. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> According to a further aspect of the invention, the actuator further includes internal yokes installed on the base opposite the corresponding tracking coils, or external yokes installed on the base opposite the corresponding tracking magnets installed opposite the tracking coils. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> According to a yet further aspect of the invention, the first, second, and tracking coils comprise fine pattern coils (FPCs). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> According to a still further aspect of the invention, the actuator includes less than 6 wires connected to the bobbin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> According to a still yet further aspect of the invention, fewer than 4 magnets are on the bobbin having the fewer than 6 wires.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent and more readily appreciated by describing in detail embodiments thereof with reference to the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a conventional moving coil type actuator for an optical pickup; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a conventional moving magnet type actuator for an optical pickup; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic view of an actuator for an optical pickup according to an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a plan view of the actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic perspective view of an actuator for an optical pickup according to another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view of the actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates the arrangement of tracking coils and magnets of the actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates the arrangement of focusing and tilting coils and magnets of the actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Hereinafter, embodiments of the present invention will be described in detail the invention with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein like reference numerals refer to the like elements throughout. The embodiments are described below in order to explain the present invention by referring to the figures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, an actuator for an optical pickup according to an embodiment of the present invention includes first and second coils (i.e., focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) installed at opposite first sides of a bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Tracking magnets <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> are installed at opposite second sides of the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. First and second magnets (i.e., focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) are installed on a base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Tracking coils <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> are installed on the base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding tracking magnets <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Internal yokes <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> are installed on the base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. External yokes <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> are installed on the base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> are installed on the external yokes <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the invention, but need not be so installed in all aspects of the invention. Four holders <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> movably support the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with respect to the base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. One end of the holder <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is coupled to the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and the other end of the holders <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is coupled to a mount <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> installed on the base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The holders <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> are used as paths to apply current to the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> installed on the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. According to embodiments of the invention, the holder <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> comprises wires and/or leaf springs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> An objective lens <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is installed on the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is driven in a focusing and/or tilting direction by the interaction of current flowing through the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> with the magnetic field of the focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. When force is simultaneously applied to the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in a same direction by a synchronous driving method, the objective lens <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is driven in a focusing direction. When force is applied to the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in different directions by an asynchronous driving method (i.e., force is applied upward to a focusing and/or tilting coil <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and force is applied downward to the other focusing and/or tilting coil <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>), the objective lens <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is rotated in a tilting direction. When force is simultaneously applied to the tracking magnets <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and the tracking coils <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> in a same direction by a synchronous driving method, the objective lens <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is driven in a tracking direction. In this way, the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is driven in three degrees of freedom. However, it is understood that the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> could be driven in additional ones of the degrees of freedom using other combinations of applied forces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Since the present invention includes coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and magnets <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> on the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, 6-axis direction driving is possible using only four holders <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. Further, when the holder <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is a leaf spring instead of a wire, the leaf spring can be integrated into the base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> A neodymium (Nd) magnet, which is quite appropriate for a small size, is used as one of the magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> according to another embodiment of the invention. Also, a multiple magnet is used as one of the magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> so as to increase magnetic flux density in an air gap according to a further embodiment of the invention. However, other types and forms of magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprise conventional wound coils and/or fine pattern coils (FPCs) according to embodiments of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, in the actuator for an optical pickup according to another embodiment of the present invention, the position of focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is exchanged with the position of focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, and the position of tracking magnets <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is exchanged with the position of tracking coils <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> as compared to the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Thus, in the actuator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and the tracking coils <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> are installed on a bobbin <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> are installed on a base <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The tracking magnets <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> are installed on the base <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding tracking coils <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Internal yokes <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> are further installed on the base <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> opposite the corresponding tracking coils <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. External yokes <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> are further installed on the base <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> opposite the tracking magnets <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The tracking magnets <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> are installed on the external yokes <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> in the shown embodiment, but it is understood that the tracking magnets <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> need not be so installed in all aspects of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The principle of driving in a focusing and/or tilting direction and in a tracking direction is the same as in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Specifically, the actuator for an optical pickup that includes the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the tracking magnets <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> installed on the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is included in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The internal yokes <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> are included opposite the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, and the external yokes <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> are included opposite the focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, resulting in obtaining paths for magnetic flux. The yokes <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> need not be used in all aspects of the invention. The actuator for an optical pickup that includes the tracking coils <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and the focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> installed in the bobbin <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are included in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The internal yokes <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> are included opposite the tracking coils <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, and the external yokes <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> are included opposite the tracking magnets <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, resulting in obtaining paths for magnetic flux. The yokes <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> need not be used in all aspects of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The arrangement of magnets <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and coils <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the actuator will be explained with reference to the embodiment of the present invention shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> using <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>. The principle of force applied in a tracking direction can be known from the arrangement of the tracking coils <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and the tracking magnets <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. In accordance with Fleming&apos;s law, when magnetic flux flows from the left sides of the tracking coils <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to the ground and current flows upward, force is applied to the left sides of the tracking coils <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. When current flows downward, force is applied to the right sides of the tracking coils <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, and thus, the tracking coils <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> can be driven in the tracking direction. This same principle is applied to force applied in the tracking direction in the arrangement of the tracking coils <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and the tracking magnets <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> according to the embodiment of the present invention shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the principle of force applied in a focusing and/or tilting direction can be known from the arrangement of the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. Also, in accordance with Fleming&apos;s law, when magnetic flux flows from upper portions of the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> to the ground and current flows from left to right, force is applied upward to the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. When current flows from right to left, force is applied downward to the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. When force is applied to the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in the same direction, the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is driven in the focusing direction, which is roughly parallel with the optical axis of the objective lens <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. When force is applied to the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in different directions, the bobbin <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is driven to rotate in the tilting direction. This principle is also applied to force applied in the focusing and tilting directions in the arrangement of the focusing and/or tilting coils <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the focusing and/or tilting magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> according to the embodiment of the present invention shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The middle portion of each of the magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is a neutral zone that a magnetic force does not affect. Higher magnetic flux is distributed at both ends of each of the magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. According to an embodiment of the invention the magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> are multiplied at opposite ends of each of the magnets <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, resulting in higher magnetic flux density in an air gap and thus a greater effect on the coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, coils and magnets are on the bobbin, thereby reducing the number of wires compared with the conventional moving coil type actuator for an optical pickup having only coils on a bobbin, and making assembly easy. Further, the mass of the bobbin is reduced compared to the conventional moving magnet type actuator for an optical pickup, thereby improving sensitivity, and further includes yokes on the base, thereby increasing the efficiency of magnetic force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In the actuator for an optical pickup according to the present invention, assembly of the actuator is simpler than the assembly of the conventional moving coil type actuator for an optical pickup, and the mass of the bobbin is reduced compared with the mass of the conventional moving magnet type actuator for an optical pickup, thereby improving sensitivity of the actuator for an optical pickup. And if the actuator further includes yokes, magnetic force is used more efficiently. It is further understood that the actuator could be used in devices other then optical pickup assemblies, and that the bobbin could be made to move in others of the six degrees of freedom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> While this invention has been particularly shown and described with reference to preferred embodiments thereof, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes in form and details may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the accompanying claims and equivalents thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An actuator usable in an optical pickup, the actuator comprising: 
<claim-text>a bobbin to hold an objective lens; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a base including a mount; </claim-text>
<claim-text>holders coupled between the mount and said bobbin to support said bobbin such that said bobbin is movable with respect to said base; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a magnetic circuit installed at said bobbin and at said base to drive the objective lens in focusing, tracking, and tilting directions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said magnetic circuit comprises bobbin coils to drive the objective lens in one direction selected from focusing, tilting, and tracking directions, bobbin magnets to drive the objective lens in the other directions selected from the focusing, the tilting, and the tracking directions, and the bobbin coils and the bobbin magnets are installed on said bobbin. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the bobbin coils comprise first and second coils installed at opposite first sides of said bobbin and are used to drive the objective lens in the focusing and the tilting directions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the bobbin magnets comprise tracking magnets installed at corresponding opposite second sides of said bobbin and are used to drive the objective lens in the tracking direction; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said magnetic circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>first and second magnets installed on said base opposite the corresponding first and second coils, </claim-text>
<claim-text>tracking coils installed on said base opposite the corresponding tracking magnets. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the bobbin magnets comprise first and second magnets installed at corresponding opposite first sides of said bobbin and are used to drive the objective lens in the focusing and the tilting directions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the bobbin coils comprise tracking coils installed at corresponding opposite second sides of said bobbin and are used to drive the objective lens in the tracking direction; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said magnetic circuit further comprises 
<claim-text>first and second coils installed on said base opposite the corresponding first and second magnets, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>tracking magnets installed on said base opposite the corresponding tracking coils. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said holders comprise wires and/or leaf springs and provide paths to apply current to the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said holders comprise wires and/or leaf springs and provide paths to apply current to the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said holders comprise wires and/or leaf springs and provide paths to apply current to the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin comprise fine pattern coils (FPCs). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin comprise fine pattern coils (FPCs). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin comprise fine pattern coils (FPCs). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin comprise fine pattern coils (FPCs). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin comprise fine pattern coils (FPCs). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin coils installed at said bobbin comprise fine pattern coils (FPCs). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising yokes to improve an efficiency of a magnetic force of said magnetic circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising yokes to improve an efficiency of a magnetic force of said magnetic circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising yokes to improve an efficiency of a magnetic force of said magnetic circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said yokes comprise: 
<claim-text>internal yokes disposed on said base between the objective lens and the corresponding bobbin coils, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>external yokes disposed on said base and adjacent the corresponding base magnets. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin magnets comprise neodymium magnets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said holders comprise less than six wires and provide current to the bobbin coils, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said bobbin holds less than four bobbin magnets. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the focusing direction is substantially parallel with an optical axis of the objective lens, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the tracking direction is perpendicular to the focusing direction, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the tilting direction rotates about a rotational axis perpendicular to both the focusing and tracking directions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An actuator to hold a lens, comprising: 
<claim-text>a bobbin to hold the lens; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a base including a mount; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a magnetic circuit formed at said bobbin and at said base, said magnetic circuit comprising bobbin coils and bobbin magnets on said bobbin and which use corresponding base magnets and base coils on said base to selectively move and/or rotate said bobbin along ones of six degrees of freedom; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>holders coupled between the mount and said bobbin to support said bobbin such that said bobbin moves relative to said base and to provide current to the bobbin coils. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin coils and the base magnets drive said bobbin to rotate about a rotational axis and to move along an axis substantially parallel with an optical axis of the lens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin magnets and the base coils drive said bobbin to move along an axis substantially perpendicular with the optical axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin magnets and the base coils drive said bobbin to rotate about a rotational axis and to move along an axis substantially parallel with an optical axis of the lens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin coils and the base magnets drive said bobbin to move along an axis substantially perpendicular with the optical axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one of the bobbin magnets comprises a multiple magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one of the base magnets comprises a multiple magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bobbin magnets each comprise a neutral area between opposite ends of the bobbin magnet, and a higher magnetic flux is distributed at the opposite ends of the bobbin magnet than at the neutral area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the neutral area extends in a direction substantially parallel with an optical axis of the lens such that the bobbin magnets provide a force in a direction substantially perpendicular to the optical axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The actuator of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the neutral area extends in a direction substantially perpendicular to an optical axis of the lens such that the bobbin magnets provide a force in a direction substantially parallel with the optical axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002176A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002176A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002176A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002176A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002176A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
