<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003538A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003538A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003538A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003538A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003538A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003538A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003538</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10147026</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020515</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A01K067/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C07H021/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12N009/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12N005/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12P021/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>069100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>320100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>325000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>196000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>366000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>800</class>
<subclass>008000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>536</class>
<subclass>023200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Neuropathic pain genes; compositions thereof; related reagents</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10147026</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020515</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09666067</doc-number>
<document-date>20000919</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60155702</doc-number>
<document-date>19990923</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60198931</doc-number>
<document-date>20000421</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Paul</given-name>
<middle-name>Shartzer</middle-name>
<family-name>Dietrich</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Palo Alto</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chiao-Chain</given-name>
<family-name>Huang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Los Altos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Carl</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Johnson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Burlingame</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lakshmi</given-name>
<family-name>Sangameswaran</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BOZICEVIC, FIELD &amp; FRANCIS LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>200 MIDDLEFIELD RD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 200</address-2>
<city>MENLO PARK</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94025</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The invention provides NPGs from rat and human, reagents related thereto including polynucleotides encoding NPGs, purified polypeptides, and specific antibodies. Methods of making and using these reagents, in particular, methods for screening compounds which modulate NPGs activity are provided. Also provided are methods of diagnosis, kits, and transgenic animals. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This U.S. Patent Application claims benefit, under 35 U.S.C. 119(e), to U.S. Provisional Application Serial Nos. 60/155,702, filed Sep. 23, 1999, and 60/198,931, filed Apr. 4, 2000, both of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entirety.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to nucleic acid and amino acid sequences associated with neuorpathic pain and the use of these sequences in diagnosis of various disease states associated with neuropathic pain and cognition and for use as targets for screening compounds useful in the treatment of these disease states. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Pain is the most common reason that patients visit a physician, and such complaints account for millions of visits annually. Nearly 64 million people suffer from trauma-related pain each year. Chronic pain is responsible for billions of dollars in lost workdays. As much as $65 million a year is lost as a result of diminished work productivity. (Bonica, et al. (eds.) (1980) Pain, Discomfort and Humanitarian Care, Elsevier, NY.) Several physiologic types of pain have been defined: somatic, visceral, neuropathic, and complex regional pain syndrome. (Doyle, et al. (eds.) (1997) Textbook of Palliative Medicine, 2<highlight><superscript>nd </superscript></highlight>ed., Oxford University Press, Oxford, England; and Stanton-Hicks, et al. (1995) Pain 63:127.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Neuropathic pain can be described as pain associated with damage or permanent alteration of the peripheral or central nervous system. Clinical manifestations of neuropathic pain include a sensation of burning or electric shock, feelings of bodily distortion, allodynia and hyperpathia. Peripheral nervous system (PNS) associated neuropathic pain can be divided into two categories: pain affecting single nerves (mononeuropathies); and pain involving the PNS diffusely (polyneuropathies). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Several molecular mechanisms have been implicated in PNS associated neuropathic pain, including activation of certain receptors and ion channels. (Besson (1999) Lancet 353:11610-1615.) With respect to receptors, several G protein coupled receptors (GPCRs) associated with neuropathic pain have been isolated. (Halazy (1999) Exp. Opin. Ther. Patents 9:431-446.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Similarly, several ion channels associated with nociception, the sensation of pain, have been isolated including, the vanilloid receptor (VR1); ATP-gated ion channels such as the P2X receptors; acid-sensing ion channels such as the ASIC receptors; and sodium channels such as the SNS/PN channels. (See, e.g., McCleskey and Gold (1999) Annu. Rev. Physiol. 61:835-856.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> GPCRs posses unique structure and activities, including seven hydrophobic domains which span the plasma membrane and form a bundle of antiparallel &agr;-helices. Stimulation of these receptors by agonists activates the receptor and allows it to interact with an intracellular G-protein complex. The G-protein complex activates a variety of second messenger molecules which regulate signaling pathways and modulate cellular responses (Lee, M. J. et al (1996) J. Biol. Chem. 271:11272-11279). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Other molecules involved in the physiology of neuropathic pain have yet to be elucidated. The discovery of genes differentially expressed in an animal model of neuropathic pain, presents the opportunity to investigate the mechanisms of this and other neuropathic disorders. Discovery of these molecules satisfies a need in the art by providing new compositions and methods useful in the diagnosis of pain and neurological disease states, and screening of compounds useful in treatment of these disease states. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>C show the deduced amino acid sequence for NPG-8 (SEQ ID NO:16). The potential signal peptide is within the dotted line box. The cleavage site is marked by a vertical arrow and a gap. The Na/Ca exchanger Ca<highlight><superscript>&plus;&plus;</superscript></highlight> binding domain repeats are in bold with the two acidic amino acid rich segments of each domain underlined. The cystein-rich box just N-terminal of the 7TM region is underlined and the potential cleavage site marked with an arrow. The individual transmembrane domains are underlined.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The invention is based on the discovery of new neuropathic pain genes (NPG1, NPG2, NPG3, NPG4, NPG5, NPG6, NPG7, and NPG8, hereinafter NPG) the polynucleotides encoding NPG1-8, and the use of these compositions in screening for compounds effective in treating disease states associated with the nervous system, in particular, neuropathic pain, perphipheral neuropathies, post-traumatic pain, post-surgical pain, pain associated with cancer, pain associated with chemotheraphy; and neurological disease states including, but not limited to, cognitive disease states, such as Alzheimer&apos;s disease and dementia, and the use of these compositions for diagnosis of these disease states. In particular, the present invention provides expression vectors, host cells, antibodies, diagnostic kits, and transgenic/knockout animals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The invention features an isolated polynucleotide encoding a neuropathic pain gene (NPG) polypeptide. The invention further provides an isolated polynucleotide, encoding an NPG polypeptide wherein the polynucleotide encodes an NPG polypeptide comprising the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14 or 16. In certain embodiments, the polynucleotide is detectably labeled or is complementary to the polynucleotide encoding an NPG polypeptide. The complementary polynucleotide can also be detectably labeled. In another embodiment, the polynucleotide comprises the nucleic acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, or 15. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The present invention encompasses an expression vector comprising the polynucleotide encoding an NPG polypeptide. Also contemplated is a host cell comprising the polynucleotide encoding an NPG polypeptide. The host cell can be a prokaryotic or eukaryotic cell. The invention further comprises a method of producing an NPG polypeptide comprising the steps of: culturing the host cell comprising the expression vector comprising the polynucleotide encoding an NPG polypeptide under conditions suitable for expression of the NPG polypeptide; and recovering the polypeptide from the host cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The present invention also contemplates a method of detecting a polynucleotide encoding an NPG polypeptide in a sample containing nucleic acid material, comprising: contacting the sample with a polynucleotide which is the complement of the polynucleotide encoding an NPG polypeptide, wherein the complement is detectably labeled, under conditions suitable for formation of a hybridization complex; and detecting the complex, wherein the presence of the complex is indicative of the presence of the polynucleotide encoding the polypeptide in the sample. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a diagnostic test kit comprising: the polynucleotide comprising SEQ ID NO:1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, or 15; and instructions for conducting the diagnostic test. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The present invention encompasses a method of screening for a compound that modulates NPG activity comprising contacting an NPG, or fragment thereof with the compound and detecting modulation of NPG activity. In certain embodiments, the NPG is expressed on a cell or tissue or immobilized on a solid support. The compound can be an antagonist of NPG activity or an agonist of activity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides an isolated NPG polypeptide comprising the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, or 16. The polypeptide is recombinantly produced or synthetically produced. The present invention also provides an isolated antibody which specifically binds to the polypeptide of SEQ ID NO:2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, or 16. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The present invention encompasses a transgenic nonhuman mammal comprising the polynucleotide encoding an NPG polypeptide. The transgenic nonhuman mammal can also comprise the polynucleotide which is the complement of the polynucleotide encoding NPG which is capable of hybridizing to a polynucleotide encoding NPG, thereby reducing expression of NPG. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Before the present proteins, nucleotide sequences, and methods are described, it is to be understood that the present invention is not limited to the particular methodologies, protocols, cell lines, vectors, and reagents described, as these may vary. It is also understood that the terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing particular embodiments only, and is not to limit the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The singular forms &ldquo;a,&rdquo; &ldquo;an,&rdquo; and &ldquo;the&rdquo; include plural reference unless the context clearly dictates otherwise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> All technical and scientific terms used herein have the same meanings as commonly understood by one of ordinary skill in the art to which this invention pertains. The practice of the present invention will employ, unless otherwise indicated, conventional techniques of protein chemistry and biochemistry, molecular biology, microbiology and recombinant DNA technology, which are within the skill of the art. Such techniques are explained fully in the literature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Although any machines, materials, and methods similar or equivalent to those described herein can be used to practice or test the present invention, the preferred machines, materials, and methods are now described. All patents, patent applications, and publications mentioned herein, whether supra or infra, are each incorporated by reference in its entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Definitions </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;NPG&rdquo; refers to the amino acid sequences of substantially purified NPG obtained from any species particularly mammalian species, including bovine, ovine, porcine, murine, equine, and preferably the human species, from any source, whether natural, synthetic, semi-synthetic, or recombinant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Agonist&rdquo; refers to a molecule which, when bound to NPG, or is within proximity of NPG, modulates the activity of NPG by increasing or prolonging the duration of the effect of NPG. Agonists can include proteins, nucleic acids, carbohydrates, organic compounds, inorganic compounds, or any other molecules which modulate the effect of NPG. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> An &ldquo;allelic variant&rdquo; is an alternative form of the gene encoding NPG. Allelic variants may result from at least one mutation in the nucleic acid sequence and may result in altered mRNAs or in a polypeptide whose structure or function may or may not be altered. Any given recombinant gene may have none, one, or many allelic forms. Common mutational changes which give rise to allelic variants are generally ascribed to natural deletions, additions, or substitutions of nucleotides. Each of these types of changes may occur alone, or in combination with the others, one or more times in a given sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Amplification&rdquo; relates to the production of additional copies of a nucleic acid sequence. Amplification can be carried out using polymerase chain reaction (PCR) technologies or other methods well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Antagonist&rdquo; refers to a molecule which, when bound to NPG or within close proximity, decreases the amount or the duration of the biological or immunological activity of NPG. Antagonists may include proteins, nucleic acids, carbohydrates, antibodies, organic compounds, inorganic compounds, or any other molecules which exert an effect on NPG activity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Antibody&rdquo; can be an intact molecule or fragments thereof, such as Fab, F(ab)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and Fv fragments, which are capable of binding an epitopic determinant. The antibody can be polyclonal, monoclonal, or recombinantly produced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The terms &ldquo;antigenic determinant&rdquo; or &ldquo;epitopic determinant&rdquo; refer to the fragment of a molecule that makes contact with a particular antibody. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;antisense&rdquo; refers to any composition containing nucleic acids which is complementary to the &ldquo;sense&rdquo; strand of a specific nucleic acid molecule. Antisense molecules may be produced by any method including synthesis or transcription. Once introduced into a cell, the complementary nucleotides combine with natural sequences produced by the cell to form duplexes and to block either transcription or translation. The designation &ldquo;negative&rdquo; can refer to the antisense strand, and the designation &ldquo;positive&rdquo; can refer to the sense strand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;coding sequence&rdquo; is a polynucleotide sequence that is transcribed into mRNA and translated into a polypeptide. The boundaries of the coding sequence are determined by a translation start codon at the 5&prime;-terminus and a translation stop codon at the 3&prime;-terminus. A coding sequence can include, but is not limited to, mRNA, cDNA, synthetic DNA, and recombinant polynucleotide sequences. Also included is genomic DNA where the coding sequence is interrupted by introns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Complementary&rdquo; and &ldquo;complementarity&rdquo; refer to the natural binding of polynucleotides to other polynucleotides by base pairing. For example, the sequence &ldquo;5&prime; A-C-G-T 3&prime;&rdquo; will bind to the complementary sequence &ldquo;3&prime; T-G-C-A 5&prime;.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Complementarity between two single stranded molecules may be &ldquo;partial,&rdquo; such that only some of the nucleic acids bind, or it may be &ldquo;complete,&rdquo; such that total complementarity exists between the single stranded molecules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;composition comprising a given polynucleotide sequence&rdquo; and a &ldquo;composition comprising a given amino acid sequence&rdquo; refer broadly to any composition containing the given polynucleotide or amino acid sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;control elements&rdquo; refers collectively to promoters, ribosome binding sites, polyadenylation signals, transcription termination sequences, upstream regulatory domains, enhancers, and the like, which collectively provide for the transcription and translation of a coding sequence in a host cell. Not all of these control sequences need always be present in a recombinant vector so long as the desired gene is capable of being transcribed and translated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The phrase &ldquo;correlates with expression of a polynucleotide&rdquo; indicates that the detection of the presence of nucleic acids, the same or related to a nucleic acid sequence encoding NPG, e.g., by northern analysis, dot blot, or RT-PCR, is indicative of the presence of nucleic acids encoding NPG in a sample, and thereby correlates with expression of the transcript from the polynucleotide encoding NPG. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The phrase &ldquo;detectably labeled&rdquo; as used herein means joining, either covalently or non-covalently to the polynucleotides, polypeptides, or antibodies of the present invention, a substance which provides for a detectable signal. A wide variety of labels and conjugation techniques are well known in the art. Suitable labels include radionuclides, e.g., <highlight><superscript>32</superscript></highlight>P, <highlight><superscript>35</superscript></highlight>S, <highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>H, enzymes, substrates, cofactors, inhibitors, fluorescent moieties, chemiluminescent moieties, magnetic particles, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The phrase &ldquo;disease state&rdquo; means any disease, condition, disorder, symptom, or indication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;expression&rdquo; as used herein intends both transcriptional and translational processes, i.e., the production of messenger RNA and/or the production of protein therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;hybridization complex&rdquo; refers to a complex formed between two nucleic acid sequences by virtue of the formation of hydrogen bonds between complementary bases. A hybridization complex may be formed in solution (conditions calculated by performing, e.g., Cot or Rot) or formed between one nucleic acid sequence present in solution and another nucleic acid sequence immobilized on a solid support (e.g., paper, membranes, filters, chips, pins, glass slides, or any other appropriate substrate to which cells or their nucleic acids have been fixed.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> An &ldquo;isolated polynucleotide&rdquo; that encodes a particular polypeptide refers to a polynucleotide that is substantially free of other nucleic acid molecules that do not encode the subject polypeptide; however, the molecule may include functionally and/or structurally conservative mutations as defined herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;modulate&rdquo; refers to a change in the activity of NPG. For example, modulation may cause an increase or a decrease in protein activity, binding characteristics, or any other biological, functional, or immunological properties of NPG. The ability to modulate the activity of NPG can be exploited in assays to screen for organic, inorganic, or biological compounds which affect the above properties of NPG. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;neuropathy&rdquo; refers to a functional disturbance or pathological change in the peripheral nervous system. Known etiologies include complications of other diseases, e.g., diabetes, cancer, etc., or of toxic states, e.g., arsenic, isoniazid, lead, nitrofurantoin, etc. poisoning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Nucleic acid&rdquo; and &ldquo;nucleic acid sequence&rdquo; refer to a nucleotide, oligonucleotide, polynucleotide, or any fragment thereof. These phrases also refer to DNA or RNA of genomic or synthetic origin which may be single stranded or double stranded and may represent the sense of the antisense strand, a peptide nucleic acid (PNA), or any DNA-like or RNA-like material. In this context, &ldquo;fragments&rdquo; refer to those nucleic acids which, when translated, would produce polypeptides retaining some functional characteristic, e.g., antigenicity, or structural domain, e.g., ion channel domain, characteristic of the full-length polypeptide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The terms &ldquo;operably associated&rdquo; and &ldquo;operably linked&rdquo; refer to functionally related but heterologous nucleic acid sequences. A promoter is operably associated or operably linked with a coding sequence if the promoter controls the translation or expression of the encoded polypeptide. While operably associated or operably linked nucleic acid sequences can be contiguous and in the same reading frame, certain genetic elements, e.g., repressor genes, are not contiguously linked to the sequence encoding the polypeptide but still bind to operator sequences that control expression of the polypeptide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> An &ldquo;oligonucleotide&rdquo; refers to a nucleic acid molecule of at least about 6 to nucleotides, preferably about 15 to 30 nucleotides, and most preferably 20 to 25 nucleotides, which can be used in PCR amplification or in a hybridization assay. &ldquo;Oligonucleotide&rdquo; is substantially equivalent to the terms &ldquo;amplimer,&rdquo; &ldquo;primer,&rdquo; &ldquo;oligomer,&rdquo; and &ldquo;probe&rdquo; as these terms are commonly defined in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Peptide nucleic acid&rdquo; (PNA) refers to an antisense molecule or anti-gene agent which comprises an oligonucleotide of at least 5 nucleotides in length linked to a peptide backbone of amino acid residues ending in lysine. The terminal lysine confers solubility to the composition. PNAs preferentially bind complementary single stranded DNA or RNA and stop transcript elongation, and may be pegylated to extend their lifespan in the cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The phrases &ldquo;percent identity&rdquo; and &ldquo;% identity&rdquo; refer to the percentage of sequence similarity found by a comparison or alignment of two or more amino acid or nucleic acid sequences. Percent identity can be determined by a direct comparison of the sequence information between two molecules by aligning the sequences, counting the exact number of matches between the two aligned sequences, dividing by the length of the shorter sequence, and multiplying the result by 100. Readily available computer programs can be used to aid in the analysis, such as ALIGN, Dayhoff, M. O. in <highlight><italic>Atlas of Protein Sequence and Structure </italic></highlight>M. O. Dayhoff ed., 5 Suppl. 3:353-358, National Biomedical Research Foundation, Washington, D.C., which adapts the local homology algorithm of Smith and Waterman (1981) <highlight><italic>Advances in Appl. Math. </italic></highlight>2:482-489, for peptide analysis. Programs for determining nucleotide sequence identity are available in the Wisconsin Sequence Analysis Package, Version 8 (Genetics Computer Group, Madison, Wis.) for example, the BLAST, BESTFIT, FASTA, and GAP programs, which also rely on the Smith and Waterman algorithm. These programs are readily utilized with the default parameters recommended by the manufacturer and described in the Wisconsin Sequence Analysis Package referred to above. Other programs for calculating identity or similarity between sequences are known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Recombinant host cells,&rdquo; &ldquo;host cells,&rdquo; &ldquo;cells,&rdquo; &ldquo;cell lines,&rdquo; &ldquo;cell cultures,&rdquo; and other such terms denoting cell lines cultured as unicellular entities refer to cells which can be, or have been, used as recipients for recombinant vectors or other transfer DNA, immaterial of the method by which the DNA is introduced into the cell or the subsequent disposition of the cell. The terms include the progeny of the original cell which has been transfected. Cells in primary culture as well as cells such as oocytes also can be used as recipients. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;reporter gene&rdquo; is a gene that, upon expression, confers a phenotype on a cell expressing the reporter gene, such that the cell can be identified under appropriate conditions. For example, the reporter gene may produce a polypeptide product that can be easily detected or measured in a routine assay. Suitable reporter genes known in the art which confer this characteristic include those that encode chloramphenicol acetyl transferase (CAT activity), &bgr;-galactosidase, luciferase, alkaline phosphatase, human growth hormone, fluorescent proteins, such as green fluorescent protein (GFP), and others. Indeed, any gene that encodes a protein or enzyme that can readily be measured, for example, by an immunoassay such as an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) or by the enzymatic conversion of a substrate into a detectable product, and that is substantially not expressed in the host cells (specific expression with no background) can be used as a reporter gene to test for promoter activity. Other reporter genes for use herein include genes that allow selection of cells based on their ability to thrive in the presence or absence of a chemical or other agent that inhibits an essential cell function. Suitable markers, therefore, include genes coding for proteins which confer drug resistance or sensitivity thereto, or change the antigenic characteristics of those cells expressing the reporter gene when the cells are grown in an appropriate selective medium. For example, reporter genes include: cytotoxic and drug resistance markers, whereby cells are selected by their ability to grow on media containing one or more of the cytotoxins or drugs; auxotrophic markers by which cells are selected by their ability to grow on defined media with or without particular nutrients or supplements; and metabolic markers by which cells are selected for, e.g., their ability to grow on defined media containing the appropriate sugar as the sole carbon source. These and other reporter genes are well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;change in the level of reporter gene product&rdquo; is shown by comparing expression levels of the reporter gene product in a cell exposed to a candidate compound relative to the levels of reporter gene product expressed in a cell that is not exposed to the test compound and/or to a cell that is exposed to a control compound. The change in level can be determined quantitatively for example, by measurement using a spectrophotometer, spectrofluorometer, luminometer, and the like, and will generally represent a statistically significant increase or decrease in the level from background. However, such a change may also be noted without quantitative measurement simply by, e.g., visualization, such as when the reporter gene is one that confers the ability on cells to form colored colonies on chromogenic substrates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;sample&rdquo; is used in its broadest sense. A sample suspected of containing nucleic acids encoding NPG, or fragments thereof, or NPG polypeptide may comprise a bodily fluid; an extract from a cell chromosome, organelle, or membrane isolated from a cell; an intact cell; genomic DNA, RNA, or cDNA, in solution or bound to a substrate; a tissue; a tissue print; etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Stringent conditions&rdquo; refers to conditions which permit hybridization between polynucleotides and the claimed polynucleotides. Stringent conditions can be defined by salt concentration, the concentration of organic solvent, e.g., formamide, temperature, and other conditions well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Subject&rdquo; means mammals and non-mammals. Mammals means any member of the Mammalia class including, but not limited to, humans, non-human primates such as chimpanzees and other apes and monkey species; farm animals such as cattle, horses, sheep, goats, and swine; domestic animals such as rabbits, dogs, and cats; laboratory animals including rodents, such as rats, mice, and guinea pigs; and the like. Examples of non-mammals include, but are not limited to, birds, and the like. The term &ldquo;subject&rdquo; does not denote a particular age or sex. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;substantially purified,&rdquo; when referring to a polypeptide, indicates that the polypeptide is present in the substantial absence of other similar biological macromolecules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;transfection&rdquo; refers to the insertion of an exogenous polynucleotide into a host cell, irrespective of the method used for the insertion, or the molecular form of the polynucleotide that is inserted. The insertion of a polynucleotide per se and the insertion of a plasmid or vector comprised of the exogenous polynucleotide are included. The exogenous polynucleotide may be directly transcribed and translated by the cell, maintained as a nonintegrated vector, for example, a plasmid, or alternatively, may be stably integrated into the host genome. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;transformed&rdquo; refers to any known method for the insertion of foreign DNA or RNA sequences into a host prokaryotic cell. The term &ldquo;transfected&rdquo; refers to any known method for the insertion of foreign DNA or RNA sequences into a host eukaryotic cell. Such transformed or transfected cells include stably transformed or transfected cells in which the inserted DNA is rendered capable of replication in the host cell. They also include transiently expressing cells which express the inserted DNA or RNA for limited periods of time. The transformation or transfection procedure depends on the host cell being transformed. It can include packaging the polynucleotide in a virus as well as direct uptake of the polynucleotide, such as, for example, lipofection or microinjection. Transformation and transfection can result in incorporation of the inserted DNA into the genome of the host cell or the maintenance of the inserted DNA within the host cell in plasmid form. Methods of transformation are well known in the art and include, but are not limited to, viral infection, electroporation, lipofection, and calcium phosphate mediated direct uptake. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Treating&rdquo; or &ldquo;treatment&rdquo; of a disease state includes: 1) preventing the disease state, i.e. causing the clinical symptoms of the disease state not to develop in a subject that may be exposed to or predisposed to the disease state, but does not yet experience or display symptoms of the disease state; 2) inhibiting the disease state, i.e., arresting the development of the disease state or its clinical symptoms; 3) or relieving the disease state, i.e., causing temporary or permanent regression of the disease state or its clinical symptoms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;variant&rdquo; of NPG polypeptides refers to an amino acid sequence that is altered by one or more amino acid residues. The variant may have &ldquo;conservative&rdquo; changes, wherein a substituted amino acid has similar structural or chemical properties (e.g., replacement of leucine with isoleucine.) More rarely, a variant may have &ldquo;nonconservative&rdquo; changes (e.g., replacement of glycine with tryptophan.) Analogous minor variations may also include amino acid deletion or insertions, or both. Guidance in determining which amino acid variations may be substituted, inserted, or deleted without abolishing biological function may be found using programs well known in the art, for example, LASERGENE software (DNASTAR). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;variant&rdquo; when used in the context of a polynucleotide sequence, may encompass a polynucleotide sequence related to NPG. This definition may include, for example &ldquo;allelic&rdquo; (as defined above), &ldquo;splice,&rdquo; &ldquo;species,&rdquo; &ldquo;polymorphic,&rdquo; or &ldquo;degenerate&rdquo; variants. A splice variant may have significant identity to a reference molecule, but will generally have a greater of less number polynucleotides due to alternate splicing of exons during mRNA processing. The corresponding polypeptide may possess additional functional domains or an absence of domains. Species variants are polynucleotide sequences that vary from one species to another. The resulting polypeptides generally will have significant amino acid identity to each other. A polymorphic variant is a variation in the polynucleotide sequence of a particular gene between individuals within a given species. Polymorphic variants may also encompass &ldquo;single nucleotide polymorphisms&rdquo; (SNPs) in which the polynucleotide sequence varies by one base. The presence of SNPs may be indicative of, for example, a certain population, a disease state, or a propensity for a disease state. A degenerate variant encompasses a multitude of polynucleotides which encode NPG polypeptides. The degenerate variants may occur naturally or may be produced synthetically. Synthetic degenerate variants are made in accordance with the standard triplet genetic code as applied to the polynucleotide sequence of naturally occurring NPG, and all such variations are to be considered as being specifically disclosed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;vector&rdquo; is a replicon in which another polynucleotide segment is attached, such as to bring about the replication and/or expression of the attached segment. The term includes expression vectors, cloning vectors, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The present invention is based on the discovery of a new NPG, the polynucleotides encoding NPG, and the use of these compositions for screening compounds useful in the treatment or prevention of disease states associated with neuropathic pain, including, but not limited to, peripheral neuropathies, post-traumatic pain, post-surgical pain, diabetic neuropathy, cancer neuropathy, pain associated with chemotherapy, toxic neuropathy, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Table 1 describes the clone number, homologue, tissue distribution, domains of particular interest, and the corresponding sequence identifier.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Neuropathic pain genes</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="6">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="42PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Molecule</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Name</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Homolog</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(Clone</entry>
<entry>Type of</entry>
<entry>(Accession</entry>
<entry>Percent</entry>
<entry>Tissue</entry>
<entry>Sequence</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>number)</entry>
<entry>Sequence</entry>
<entry>number)</entry>
<entry>Identity</entry>
<entry>Distribution</entry>
<entry>Identifier</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="6">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="42PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>NPG-1</entry>
<entry>Nucleic</entry>
<entry>Thioredoxin</entry>
<entry>65%</entry>
<entry>Highest in</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(IV-33)</entry>
<entry>and</entry>
<entry>Domain</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>brain, heart,</entry>
<entry>NO: 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>amino</entry>
<entry>(AL021396)</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>liver, and</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>acid</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>testis</entry>
<entry>NO: 2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NPG-2</entry>
<entry>Nucleic</entry>
<entry>LIM domain</entry>
<entry>63%</entry>
<entry>Highest in</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(IV-56)</entry>
<entry>and</entry>
<entry>(U49957),</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>heart, liver,</entry>
<entry>NO: 3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>amino</entry>
<entry>ajuba,</entry>
<entry>30%</entry>
<entry>and spleen</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>acid</entry>
<entry>CE15,</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NO: 4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>zyxin</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(AF097511)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NPG-3</entry>
<entry>Nucleic</entry>
<entry>TPR domain</entry>
<entry>28%</entry>
<entry>Brain</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(IV-63)</entry>
<entry>and</entry>
<entry>(AF016427)</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NO: 5</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>amino</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>acid</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NO: 6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NPG-4</entry>
<entry>Nucleic</entry>
<entry>VT4</entry>
<entry>54%</entry>
<entry>Highest in</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(IV-65)</entry>
<entry>and</entry>
<entry>(U19346),</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>brain, spinal</entry>
<entry>NO: 7</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>amino</entry>
<entry>yemanuclein</entry>
<entry>44%</entry>
<entry>cord, heart,</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>acid</entry>
<entry>(X63503)</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>kidney,</entry>
<entry>NO: 8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>skeletal</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>muscle, and</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>testis</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NPG-5</entry>
<entry>Nucleic</entry>
<entry>GS2</entry>
<entry>41%</entry>
<entry>Spinal cord,</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(IV-69)</entry>
<entry>and</entry>
<entry>(Z97055)</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>kidney</entry>
<entry>NO: 9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>amino</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>acid</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NO: 10</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NPG-6</entry>
<entry>Nucleic</entry>
<entry>KIAA0686</entry>
<entry>81%</entry>
<entry>Spinal cord</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(IV-71)</entry>
<entry>and</entry>
<entry>(AB014586),</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NO: 11</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>amino</entry>
<entry>Na&plus;/Ca&plus;&plus;</entry>
<entry>26%</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>acid</entry>
<entry>Exchanger</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NO: 12</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(P70414),</entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>latrotoxin</entry>
<entry>20%</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>receptor</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(G3766207)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NPG-7</entry>
<entry>Nucleic</entry>
<entry>KIAA0871</entry>
<entry>96%</entry>
<entry>Brain, spinal</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(IV-75)</entry>
<entry>and</entry>
<entry>protein</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>cord</entry>
<entry>NO: 13</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>amino</entry>
<entry>(AB020678),</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>acid</entry>
<entry>rap2</entry>
<entry>36%</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NO: 14</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Interacting-</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>protein 8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(AC002457)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NPG-8</entry>
<entry>Nucleic</entry>
<entry>Very Large</entry>
<entry>100%&ensp;</entry>
<entry>Brain,</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(human</entry>
<entry>and</entry>
<entry>G Protein</entry>
<entry>over 3&prime;</entry>
<entry>pituitary</entry>
<entry>NO: 15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>ortholog</entry>
<entry>amino</entry>
<entry>Receptor</entry>
<entry>6 kb</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SEQ ID</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>of</entry>
<entry>acid</entry>
<entry>(AF055084)</entry>
<entry>portion</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NO: 16</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>NPG-6)</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The sequence of NPG-6 (SEQ ID Nos:11 and 12) was analyzed by computer algorithms, e.g., PHD (Rost and Burhard (1996) Meth. Enzymol. 266:525-539), BLAST, etc. Computer analysis revealed seven transmembrane domains (TM) characteristic of G protein coupled receptors (GPCR). Further analysis showed NPG-6 to be most closely related to Family B, Group 4 GPCRs, which includes the latrophilin-1 receptor, the EMR1 hormone receptor, and CD97. GenBank Accession number AB014586, corresponding to KIAA0686, shows high identity to a fragment of NPG-6. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The N-terminal region of Family B, Group 4 GPCR are characteristically longer than Family B, Groups 1-3. Additional BLAST analysis of the the N-terminal region of NPG-6 showed identity to the NCX class of Na<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>/Ca<highlight><superscript>&plus;&plus;</superscript></highlight> exchangers (e.g., GenBank Accesion No. P70414), which are found in a variety of organisms. One characteristic of this class of ion exchangers is the presence of highly conserved NIbeta domains. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Structurally, NPG-6 contains at least six NI&bgr; domains in the extracellular NH-terminus and 7 transmembrane domains proximal to the COOH-terminus. The NI&bgr; domains encompass residues from: 89 through about 189; about 209 through about 309; about 569 through about 669; about 805 through about 905; and about 1060 through about 1160, each of SEQ ID NO:12. The transmembrane domains encompass residues from: about 1481 through about 1501; about 1513 through about 1533; about 1543 through about 1563; about 1585 through about 1605; about 1634 through about 1654; about 1678 through about 1698; and 1704 through about 1724, each of SEQ ID NO:12. An extracellular fragment runs from about amino acid residue 1 through about residue 1478. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> In situ hybridization performed on rat brain sections showed that NPG-6 prominently localized in the ventrocaudal striatum, an area known to have extensive connections with lateral mesocortical regions. NPG-8 also localized in the parafascicular nucleus, a part of the intralaminar nuclear complex of the thalamus, as well as within the ependyma lining of the ventricles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> NPG-8 is the human ortholog of NPG-6. BLAST analysis with the amino acid sequence (SEQ ID NO:16) revealed strong homology to the latrotoxin and related GPCR family B receptors comprising approximately the last 500 amino acids at the carboxy end of the sequence. Seven potential transmembrane domains were identified as well as a conserved cysteine-rich sequence, proximal to the first TM, which is a potential proteolytic processing site in the latrotoxin receptor family. Searches using portions of NPG-8 revealed identity to various publicly available genomic sequences (e.g., GenBank Accession No. AC027323), some of which mapped to human chromosome 5. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The cytoplasmic amino terminal domain of NPG-8 contains several domains with homology to the high affinity calcium-binding domain of the NCX class of Na<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>/Ca<highlight><superscript>2&plus;</superscript></highlight> exchangers. (See, e.g., Levitsky, D. O. et al (1994) <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>269:22847-22852; and Dyck, C. et al (1998) <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>273:12981-12987.) Within each domain, the strongest homology was to two acidic amino acid rich stretches of 12 to 16 amino acids, separated by approximately 15 to 40 amino acids, that are thought to play a critical role in calcium binding (See <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). Homology was also found to an aggregation protein from a marine sponge (GenBank Accession No. AF020903), which also contains multiple calcium-binding domain homologous regions. GenBank Accession No. AF055084 (Very Large G-protein Receptor; VLGR) was found to have high sequence identity to a portion of NPG-8, with large differences noted in the 5&prime; end of VRL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The invention also encompasses nucleic or amino acid variants of NPG. A preferred variant is one which has at least about 80%, more preferably at least about 90%, and most preferably at least about 95% amino acid or nucleic acid identity to the corresponding NPG sequence, and which contains at least one functional or structural characteristic of NPG. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Polynucleotides </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Although nucleotide sequences which encode NPG and its variants are preferably capable of hybridizing to the nucleotide sequence of the naturally occurring NPG under appropriately selected conditions of stringency, it may be advantageous to produce nucleotide sequence encoding NPG or its derivatives possessing a substantially different codon usage, e.g., inclusion of non-naturally occurring codons. Codons may be selected to increase the rate at which expression of the peptide occurs in a particular prokaryotic or eukaryotic host in accordance with the frequency with which particular codons are utilized by the host. Other reasons for substantially altering the nucleotide sequence encoding NPG and its derivatives without altering the encoded amino acid include the production of RNA transcripts having more desirable properties, such as greater half-life or stability for improved translation, than transcripts produced from the naturally occurring sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Also encompassed by the invention are polynucleotides that are capable of hybridizing to the claimed polynucleotide sequences, and, in particular, to those shown in SEQ ID NO:1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, or 15, under various conditions of stringency. (See, e.g., Wahl, G. M. and S. L. Berger (1987) Methods Enzymol. 152:399-401; Kimmel, A. R. (1987) Methods Enzymol. 152:507-511.) For example, stringent salt concentration will ordinarily be less that about 750 mM NaCl and 75 mM trisodium citrate, preferably less than about 500 mM NaCl and 50 mM trisodium citrate, and more preferably less than about 250 mM NaCl and 25 mM trisodium citrate. Low stringency hybridization can be obtained in the absence of organic solvent, e.g., formamide, while high stringency hybridization can be obtained in the presence of at least about 35% formamide, and more preferably at least about 50% formamide. Stringent temperature conditions will ordinarily include temperatures of at least about 30&deg; C., preferably at least about 37&deg; C., and more preferably 42&deg; C. Varying additional parameters such as hybridization time, the concentration of detergent, e.g., sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS), and the inclusion or exclusion of carrier DNA, are well known to those skilled in the art. Various levels of stringency are accomplished by combining these various conditions as needed. In a preferred embodiment, hybridization will occur at 30&deg; C. in 750 mM NaCl, 75 mM trisodium citrate, and 1% SDS. In a preferred embodiment, hybridization will occur at 37&deg; C. in 500 mM NaCl, 50 mM trisodium citrate, 1% SDS, 35% formamide, and 100 &mgr;g/ml denatured salmon sperm DNA (ssDNA). In a more preferred embodiment, hybridization will occur at 42&deg; C. in 250 mM NaCl, 25 mM trisodium citrate, 1% SDS, 50% formamide, and 200 &mgr;g/ml denatured ssDNA. Useful variations of these conditions will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The washing steps which follow hybridization can also vary in stringency. Wash stringency conditions can be defined by salt concentration and by temperature. As above, wash stringency can be increased by decreasing salt concentration or by increasing temperature. For example, stringent salt concentration for the wash steps will preferably be less than about 30 mM NaCl and 3 mM trisodium citrate, and more preferably less than about 15 mM NaCl and 1.5 mM trisodium citrate. Stringent temperature conditions for the wash step will ordinarily include temperature of at least about 25&deg; C., preferably of at least about 42&deg; C., and more preferably of at least about 68&deg; C. Generally the wash step will occur at 25&deg; C. in 30 mM NaCl, 3 mM trisodium citrate, and 0.1% SDS. Preferably, the wash step will occur at 42&deg; C. in 15 mM NaCl, 1.5 mM trisodium citrate, and 0.1% SDS. More preferably, the wash step will occur at 68&deg; C., in 15 mM NaCl, 1.5 mM trisodium citrate, and 0.1% SDS. Additional variations on these conditions will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, polynucleotide sequences encoding all or part of NPG may be synthesized using chemical methods well known in the art. (See, e.g., Caruthers, M. H. et al. (1980) Nucl. Acids Res. Symp. Ser. 7:215-223, Horn, T. et al. (1980) Nucl. Acids Res. Symp. Ser. 7:225-232.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The present invention further covers recombinant polynucleotides and fragments having a DNA sequence identical to or highly homologous to the isolated polynucleotides of NPG. In particular, the sequences will often be operably linked to DNA segments which control transcription, translation, and DNA replication. Alternatively, recombinant clones derived from the genomic sequences, e.g., containing introns, will be useful for transgenic and knock-out studies, including transgenic cells, organisms, and knock-out animals, and for gene therapy. (See, e.g., Goodnow (1992) &ldquo;Transgenic Animals&rdquo; in Roitt (ed.) Encyclopedia of Immunology, Academic Press, San Diego, Calif., pp. 1502-1504; Travis (1992) Science 254:707-710; Capecchi (1989) Science 244:1288-1292; Robertson (ed.) (1987) Teratocarcinomas and Embryonic Stem Cells: A Practical Approach, IRL Press, Oxford; Rosenberg (1992) J. Clinical Oncology 10:180-199; Hogan, et al. (eds.) (1994) Manipulating the Mouse Embryo: A Laboratory Manual, 2<highlight><superscript>nd </superscript></highlight>edition, Cold Spring Harbor Press, NY; Wei (1997) Ann. Rev. Pharmacol. Toxicol. 37:119-141; and Rajewsky, et al. (1996) J. Clin. Inves. 98:S51-S53.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Examples of these techniques include: 1) Insertion of normal or mutant versions of DNA encoding NPG or homologous animal versions of these genes, by microinjection, retroviral infection, or other means well known to those skilled in the art, into appropriate fertilized embryos in order to produce a transgenic animal (see, e.g., Hogan, supra); and 2) homologous recombination (see, e.g., Capecchi, supra; and Zimmer and Gruss (1989) Nature 338:150-153) of mutant or normal, human or animal versions of these genes with the native gene locus in transgenic animals to alter the regulation of expression or the structure of NPG. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> The technique of homologous recombination is well known in the art. It replaces the native gene with the inserted gene and is thus useful for producing an animal that cannot express native receptor but does express, for example, an inserted mutant receptor, which has replaced the native receptor in the animal&apos;s genome by recombination, resulting in underexpression of the receptor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Microinjection adds genes to the genome, but does not remove them, and so is useful for producing an animal which expresses its own and added receptors, resulting in overexpression of the receptor. One means available for producing a transgenic animal, with a mouse as an example, is as follows: Female mice are mated, and the resulting fertilized eggs are dissected out of their oviducts. The eggs are stored in an appropriate medium such as M2 medium (see, e.g., Hogan, supra). DNA or cDNA encoding NPG is purified from an appropriate vector by methods well known in the art. Inducible promoters may be fused with the coding region of the DNA to provide an experimental means to regulate expression of the trans-gene. Alternatively, or in addition, tissue specific regulatory elements may be fused with the coding region to permit tissue-specific expression of the trans-gene. The DNA, in an appropriately buffered solution, is put into a microinjection needle (which may be made from capillary tubing using a pipet puller) and the egg to be injected is put in a depression slide. The needle is inserted into the pronucleus of the egg, and the DNA solution is injected. The injected egg is then transferred into the oviduct of a pseudopregnant mouse (a mouse stimulated by the appropriate hormones to maintain pregnancy but which is not actually pregnant), where it proceeds to the uterus, implants, and develops to term. As noted above, microinjection is not the only method for inserting DNA into the egg cell, and is used here only for exemplary purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Since the normal action of receptor-specific drugs is to activate or to inhibit the receptor, the transgenic animal model systems described above are useful for testing the biological activity of drugs directed against NPG even before such drugs become available. These animal model systems are useful for predicting or evaluating possible therapeutic applications of drugs which activate or inhibit NPG by inducing or inhibiting expression of the native or trans-gene and thus increasing or decreasing expression of normal or mutant NPG in the living animal. Thus, a model system is produced in which the biological activity of drugs directed against NPG are evaluated before such drugs become available. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The transgenic animals which over- or under-produce NPG indicate, by their physiological state, whether over- or underproduction of NPG is therapeutically useful. It is therefore useful to evaluate drug action based on the transgenic model system. One use is based on the fact that it is well known in the art that a drug such as an antidepressant acts by blocking neurotransmitter uptake, and thereby increases the amount of neurotransmitter in the synaptic cleft. The physiological result of this action is to stimulate the production of less receptor by the affected cells, leading eventually to underexpression. Therefore, an animal which underexpresses receptor is useful as a test system to investigate whether the actions of such drugs which result in under expression are in fact therapeutic. Another use is that if overexpression is found to lead to abnormalities, then a drug which down-regulates or acts as an antagonist to NPG is indicated as worth developing, and if a promising therapeutic application is uncovered by these animal model systems, activation or inhibition of NPG is achieved therapeutically either by producing agonist or antagonist drugs directed against NPG or by any method which increases or decreases the expression of NPG in man. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Polypeptides </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> The predicted sequence NPG amino acid sequence is shown in SEQ ID NO:2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, or 16. The peptide sequences allow preparation of peptides to generate antibodies to recognize such segments, and various different methods may be used to prepare such peptides. As used herein NPG shall encompass, when used in a protein context, a protein having an amino acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, or 16, or a significant fragment of such a protein. It also refers to a vertebrate, e.g., mammal, including human, derived polypeptide which exhibits similar biological function, e.g., antigenic, or interacts with NPG specific binding components, e.g., specific antibodies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The term polypeptide, as used herein, includes a significant fragment or segment, and encompasses a stretch of amino acid residues of at least about 8 amino acids, generally at least 10 amino acids, more generally at least 12 amino acids, often at least 14 amino acids, more often at least 16 amino acids, typically at least 18 amino acids, more typically at least 20 amino acids, usually at least 22 amino acids, more usually at least 24 amino acids, preferably at least 26 amino acids, more preferably at least 28 amino acids, and, in particularly preferred embodiments, at least about 30 or more amino acids. The segments may have lengths of at least 37, 45, 53, 61, 70, 80, 90, etc., and often will encompass a plurality of such matching sequences. The specific ends of such a segment will be at any combinations within the protein. Preferably the fragment will encompass structural domains, as described above, or unique regions useful in generation of binding compositions with specificity for NPG. In another embodiment of the invention, natural, modified, or recombinant nucleic acid sequences encoding NPG may be ligated to a heterologous sequence to encode a fusion protein. For example, to screen peptide libraries for inhibitors of NPG activity, it may be useful to encode a chimeric NPG protein that can be recognized by a commercially available antibody. A fusion protein may also be engineered to contain a cleavage site located between the NPG encoding sequence and the heterologous protein sequence, so that NPG may be cleaved and purified away from the heterologous moiety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The protein may be produced using chemical methods to synthesize the amino acid sequence of NPG, or a fragment thereof. For example, peptide synthesis can be performed using various solid-phase techniques. (See, e.g., Roberge, J. Y. et al. (1995) Science 269:202-204.) Automated synthesis may be achieved, for example, using the ABI 431A peptide synthesizer (Perkin Elmer). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> The newly synthesized peptide may be substantially purified by preparative high performance liquid chromatography. (See, e.g., Creighton, T. (1983) Proteins, Structures and Molecular Principles, W H Freeman and Co., New York, N.Y.) The composition of the synthetic peptides may be confirmed by amino acid analysis or sequencing (e.g., the Edman degradation procedure; Creighton, supra.) Additionally, the amino acid sequence of NPG, or any part thereof, may be altered during direct synthesis and/or combined using chemical methods with sequences from other proteins, or any part thereof, to produce a variant polypeptide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> In order to express a biologically active NPG, the nucleotide sequences encoding NPG or functional equivalents, may be inserted into appropriate expression vector, i.e., a vector which contains the necessary elements for the transcription and translation of the inserted coding sequence. Methods which are well known to those skilled in the art may be used to construct expression vectors containing sequences encoding NPG and appropriate transcriptional and translational control elements. These methods include in vitro recombinant DNA techniques, synthetic techniques, and in vivo genetic recombination. (See, e.g., Sambrook, J. et al. (1989) Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Manual, Cold Spring Harbor Press, Plainview, N.Y.; and Ausubel, F. M. et al. (1989) Current Protocols in Molecular Biology, John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, N.Y.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> A variety of expression vector/host systems may be utilized to contain and express sequences encoding NPG. These include, but are not limited to, microorganisms such as bacteria transformed with recombinant bacteriophage, plasmid, or cosmid DNA expression vectors; yeast transformed with yeast expression vectors; insect cell systems infected with virus expression vectors (e.g., baculovirus) or with bacterial expression vectors (e.g., Ti or pBR322 plasmids); or animal cell systems. The invention is not limited by the host cell employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The &ldquo;control elements&rdquo; or &ldquo;regulatory sequences&rdquo; are those regions of the vector, e.g., enhancers, promoters, 5&prime; and 3&prime; untranslated regions, translated regions, which interact with host cellular proteins to carry out transcription and translation. Such elements may vary in their strength and specificity. Depending on the vector system and host utilized, any number of suitable transcription and translation elements, including constitutive and inducible promoters, may be used. For example, when cloning in bacterial systems, inducible promoters such as the hybrid lacZ promoter of the BLUESCRIPT phagemid (Stratagene, LaJolla, Calif.) or PSPORT1 plasmid (Gibco BRL) and the like may be used. The baculovirus polyhedrin promoter may be used in insect cells. Promoters or enhancers derived from the genomes of plant cells (e.g., heat shock, RUBISCO; and storage protein genes) or from plant viruses (e.g., viral promoters or leader sequences) may be cloned into the vector. In mammalian cell systems, promoters from mammalian genes or from mammalian viruses are preferable. If it is necessary to generate a cell line that contains multiple copies of the sequence encoding NPG, vectors based on SV40 or EBV may be used with an appropriate selectable marker. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In bacterial systems, a number of expression vectors may be selected depending upon the use intended for NPG. For example, when large quantities of NPG are needed for the induction of antibodies, vectors which direct high level expression of fusion proteins that are readily purified may be used. Such vectors include, but are not limited to, the multifunctional <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>cloning and expression vectors such as the BLUESCRIPT phagemid (Stratagene), in which the sequence encoding NPG may be ligated into the vector in frame with sequences for the amino-terminal Met and the subsequent 7 residues of &bgr;-galactosidase so that a hybrid protein is produced; pIN vectors (Van Heeke, G. and S. M. Schuster (1989) J. Biol. Chem. 264:5503-5509); and the like. PGEX vectors (Promega, Madison, Wis.) may also be used to express foreign polypeptides as fusion proteins with glutathione S-transferase (GST). In general, such fusion proteins are soluble and can easily be purified from lysed cells by adsorption to glutathione-agarose beads followed by elution in the presence of free glutathione. Proteins made in such systems may be designed to include heparin, thrombin, or factor XA protease cleavage sites so that the cloned polypeptide of interest can be released from the GST moiety at will. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> In the yeast, <highlight><italic>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</italic></highlight>, a number of vectors containing constitutive or inducible promoters such as alpha factor, alcohol oxidase, and PGH may be used. (See, e.g., Ausubel et al., supra; and Grant et al. (1987) Methods Enzymol. 153:516-544.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> An insect system may also be used to express NPG. For example, in one such system, <highlight><italic>Autographa californica </italic></highlight>nuclear polyhedrosis virus (AcNPV) is used as a vector to express foreign genes in <highlight><italic>Spodoptera frugiperda </italic></highlight>cells or in <highlight><italic>Trichoplusia larvae</italic></highlight>. The sequences encoding NPG may be cloned into a non-essential region of the virus, such as the polyhedrin gene, and placed under control of the polyhedrin promoter. Successful insertion of NPG will render the polyhedrin gene inactive and produce recombinant virus lacking coat protein. The recombinant viruses may then be used to infect, for example, <highlight><italic>S. frugiperda </italic></highlight>cells or <highlight><italic>Trichoplusia larvae </italic></highlight>in which NPG may be expressed (Engelhard, E. K. et al. (1994) Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. 91:3224-3227). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In mammalian host cells, a number of viral-based expression systems may be utilized. In cases where an adenovirus is used as an expression vector, sequences encoding NPG may be ligated into an adenovirus transcription/translation complex consisting of the late promoter and tripartite leader sequence. Insertion in a non-essential E1 or E3 region of the viral genome may be used to obtain a viable virus which is capable of expressing NPG in infected host cells (Logan, J. and Shenk, T. (1984) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 81:3655-3659). In addition, transcription enhancers, such as the Rous sarcoma virus (RSV) enhancer, may be used to increase expression in mammalian host cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Human artificial chromosomes (HACs) may also be employed to deliver larger fragments of DNA than can be contained and expressed in a plasmid. HACs of 6 to 10M are constructed and delivered via conventional delivery methods (liposomes, polycationic amino polymers, or vesicles) for therapeutic purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Specific initiation signals may also be used to achieve more efficient translation of sequences encoding NPG. Such signals include the ATG initiation codon and adjacent sequences. In cases where sequences encoding NPG, its initiation codon, and upstream sequences are inserted into the appropriate expression vector, no additional transcriptional or translational control signals may be needed. However, in cases where only coding sequence, or a fragment thereof, is inserted, exogenous translational control signals including the ATG initiation codon should be provided. Furthermore, the initiation codon should be in the correct reading frame to ensure translation of the entire insert. Exogenous translational elements and initiation codons may be of various origins, both natural and synthetic. The efficiency of expression may be enhanced by the inclusion of enhancers which are appropriate for the particular cell system which is used, such as those described in the literature (Scharf, D. et al. (1994) Results Probl. Cell Differ. 20:125-162). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> In addition, a host cell strain may be chosen for its ability to modulate the expression of the inserted sequences or to process the expressed protein in the desired fashion. Such modifications of the polypeptide include, but are not limited to, acetylation, carboxylation, glycosylation, phosphorylation, lipidation, and acylation. Post-translational processing which cleaves a &ldquo;prepro&rdquo; form of the protein may also be used to facilitate correct insertion, folding and/or function. Different host cells which have specific cellular machinery and characteristic mechanisms for post-translational activities (e.g., CHO, HeLa, MDCK, HEK293, and W138), are available from the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC; Bethesda, Md.) and may be chosen to ensure the correct modification and processing of the foreign protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> For long-term, high-yield production of recombinant proteins, stable expression is preferred. For example, cell lines stably expressing NPG can be transformed using expression vectors containing viral origins of replication and/or endogenous expression elements and a selectable marker gene on the same or on a separate vector. Following the introduction of the vector, cells may be allowed to grow for 1-2 days in an enriched media before they are switched to selective media. The purpose of the selectable marker is to confer resistance to selection, and its presence allows growth and recovery of cells which successfully express the introduced sequences. Resistant clones of stably transformed cells may be proliferated using tissue culture techniques appropriate to the cell type. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Any number of selection systems may be used to recover transformed cell lines. These include, but are not limited to, the herpes simplex virus thymidine kinase (Wigler, M. et al. (1977) Cell 11:223-32) and adenine phosphoribosyltransferase (Lowy, I. et al. (1980) Cell 22:817-23) genes which can be employed in tk<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> or aprt<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> cells, respectively. Also, antimetabolite, antibiotic, or herbicide resistance can be used as the basis for selection; for example, dhfr which confers resistance to methotrexate (Wigler, M. et al. (1980) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 77:3567-70); npt, which confers resistance to the aminoglycosides neomycin and G-418 (Colbere-Garapin, F. et al (1981) J. Mol. Biol. 150:1-14), and genes which confer resistance to hygromycin and puromycin. Additional selectable genes have been described, for example, trpB, which allows cells to utilize indole in place of tryptophan, or hisD, which allows cells to utilize histinol in place of histidine (Hartman, S. C. and R. C. Mulligan (1988) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 85:8047-51). Recently, the use of visible markers has gained popularity with such markers as anthocyanins, and its substrate GUS, and luciferase and its substrate luciferin, being widely used not only to identify transformants, but also to quantify the amount of transient or stable protein expression attributable to a specific vector system (Rhodes, Calif. et al. (1995) Methods Mol. Biol. 55:121-131). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Antibodies </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Antibodies to NPG may be generated using methods that are well known in the art. Such antibodies may include, but are not limited to, polyclonal, monoclonal, chimeric, single chain, Fab fragments, and fragments produced by a Fab expression library. Neutralizing antibodies, (i.e., those which inhibit dimer formation) are especially preferred for therapeutic use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> For the production of antibodies, various hosts including goats, rabbits, rats, mice, humans, and others, may be immunized by injection with NPG or any fragment or oligopeptide thereof which has immunogenic properties. Depending on the host species, various adjuvants may be used to increase immunological response. Such adjuvants include, but are not limited to, Freund&apos;s, mineral gels such as aluminum hydroxide, and surface active substances such as lysolecithin, pluronic polyols, polyanions, peptides, oil emulsions, keyhole limpet hemocyanin, and dinitrophenol. Among adjuvants used in humans, BCG (bacilli Calmette-Guerin) and <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium parvum </italic></highlight>are especially preferable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> It is preferred that the oligopeptides, peptides, or fragments used to induce antibodies to NPG have an amino acid sequence consisting of at least five amino acids and more preferably at least 10 amino acids, and most preferably at least 15 amino acids. It is also preferable that they are identical to a portion of the amino acid sequence of the natural protein, and they may contain the entire amino acid sequence of a small, naturally occurring molecule. Short stretches of NPG amino acids may be fused with those of another protein such as keyhole limpet hemocyanin and antibody produced against the chimeric molecule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Monoclonal antibodies to NPG may be prepared using any technique which provides for the production of antibody molecules by continuous cell lines in culture. These include, but are not limited to, the hybridoma technique, the human B-cell hybridoma technique, and the EBV-hybridoma technique (Kohler, G. et al. (1975) Nature 256:495-497; Kozbor, D. et al. (1985) J. Immunol. Methods 81:31-42; Cote, R. J. et al. (1983) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 80:2026-2030; Cole, S. P. et al. (1984) Mol. Cell Biol. 62:109-120). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> In addition, techniques developed for the production of &ldquo;chimeric antibodies&rdquo;, the splicing of mouse antibody genes to human antibody genes to obtain a molecule with appropriate antigen specificity and biological activity can be used (Morrison, S. L. et al. (1984) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 81:6851-6855; Neuberger, M. S. et al. (1984) Nature 312:604-608; Takeda, S. et al. (1985) Nature 314:452-454). Alternatively, techniques described for the production of single chain antibodies may be adapted, using methods known in the art, to produce NPG-specific single chain antibodies. Antibodies with related specificity, but of distinct idiotypic composition, may be generated by chain shuffling from random combinatorial immunoglobulin libraries (Burton D. R. (1991) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 88:11120-3). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> Antibodies may also be produced by inducing in vivo production in the lymphocyte population or by screening immunoglobulin libraries or panels of highly specific binding reagents as disclosed in the literature (Orlandi, R. et al. (1989) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 86: 3833-3837; Winter, G. et al. (1991) Nature 349:293-299). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Antibody fragments which contain specific binding sites for NPG may also be generated. For example, such fragments include, but are not limited to, the F(ab&prime;)2 fragments which can be produced by pepsin digestion of the antibody molecule and the Fab fragments which can be generated by reducing the disulfide bridges of the F(ab&prime;)2 fragments. Alternatively, Fab expression libraries may be constructed to allow rapid and easy identification of monoclonal Fab fragments with the desired specificity (Huse, W. D. et al. (1989) Science 254:1275-1281). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> Various immunoassays may be used for screening to identify antibodies having the desired specificity. Numerous protocols for competitive binding or immunoradiometric assays using either polyclonal or monoclonal antibodies with established specificities are well known in the art. Such immunoassays typically involve the measurement of complex formation between NPG and its specific antibody. A two-site, monoclonal-based immunoassay utilizing monoclonal antibodies reactive to two non-interfering NPG epitopes is preferred, but a competitive binding assay may also be employed (Maddox, supra). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Uses </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides various methods for determining whether a compound can modulate the activity of NPG. The compound can be a substantially pure compound of synthetic origin combined in an aqueous medium, or the compound can be a naturally occurring material such that the assay medium is an extract of biological origin, such as, for example, a plant, animal, or microbial cell extract. The compound can also be a member of a compound library in which all members of the compound library are screened using the methods described below. The methods essentially entail contacting NPG or fragments thereof, with the compound under suitable conditions and subsequently determining if the compound modulates the activity of NPG. The compounds of interest can function as agonists or antagonists of NPG activity. NPG or fragments thereof, can be expressed on a cell or tissue, naturally or recombinantly, or immobilized by attachment to a solid substrate, e.g., nitrocellulose or nylon membrane, glass, beads, etc. Several high-throughput screening assays are known in the art. (See, e.g., Sittampalam, et al. (1997) Curr. Opin. Chem. Biol. 391; and Silverman, et al. (1998) Curr. Opin. Chem. Biol. 2:397-403.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Transcription based assays that identify signals that modulate the activity of cell surface proteins, e.g., receptors, ion channels, etc., may be used to screen candidate compounds for their ability to stimulate reporter gene product expression and their potential to stimulate the expression of NPG. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> One method tar identifying compounds that stimulate NPG promoter-controlled reporter gene expression comprises introducing into a cell a DNA construct that comprises NPG promoter operably linked to a reporter gene, mixing a test compound with the cell and measuring the level of expression of reporter gene product. A change in the level of expression of the reporter gene product indicates that the compound is capable of modulating the level of NPG expression. The reporter gene construct is preferably stably integrated into the chromosomal DNA of the cell, but is also functional for the purposes disclosed herein in the form of an extra-chromosomal element. The cell may be a eukaryotic cell, or any cell that contains the elements needed to express a structural gene under the regulatory influence of a mammalian gene promoter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> Other transcription based assays are well known in the art. (See, e.g., Zlokamik, et al. (1998) Science 279:84-88; Siverman, supra; and Gonzalez and Negulescu, (1998) Curr. Opin. Biotechnol. 9:624-631.) These transcription based assays asses the intracellular transduction of an extracellular signal using recombinant cells that are modified by introduction of a reporter gene under the control of a regulatable promoter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> A two-hybrid system-based approach can also be employed for compound screening, small molecule identification, and drug discovery. The underlying premise of the two-hybrid system, originally described in yeast by Fields and Song (1989) Nature 340:245-246, provides a connection between a productive protein-protein or protein-compound interaction pair of interest and a measurable phenotypic change in yeast. A reporter cassette containing an up-stream activation sequence which is recognized by a DNA binding domain, is operationally linked to a reporter gene, which when expressed under the correct conditions will generate a phenotypic change. The original two-hybrid system has recently been modified for applicability in high-throughput compound screening. (See, e.g., Ho et al. (1996) Nature 382:822-826; Licitra and Liu (1996) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 93:12817-12821; and Young et al. (1998) Nature Biotech. 16:946-950.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Assays for identifying compounds that modulate ion channel activity are practiced by measuring the ion channel activity when a cell expressing the ion channel of interest, or fragments thereof, is exposed to a solution containing the test compound and a ion channel selective ion and comparing the measured ion channel activity to the native ion channel activity of the same cell or a substantially identical control cell in a solution not containing the test compound. Methods for practicing such assays are known to those of skill in the art. (See, e.g., Mishina et al. (1985) Nature 313:364-369; and Noda, et al. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> Ion channel activity can be measured by methods such as electrophysiology (two electrode voltage clamp or single electrode whole cell patch clamp), guanidinium ion flux assays, toxin-binding assays, and Fluorometric Imaging Plate Reader (FLIPR) assays. (See, e.g., Sullivan, et al. (1999) Methods Mol. Biol. 114:125-133; Siegel and Isacoff (1997) Neuron 19:1-20; and Lopatin, et al. (1998) Trends Pharmacol. Sci. 19:395-398.) An &ldquo;inhibitor&rdquo; is defined generally as a compound, at a given concentration, that results in greater than 50% decrease in ion channel activity, preferably greater than 70% decrease in ion channel activity, more preferably greater than 90% decrease in ion channel activity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> The binding or interaction of the compound with a receptor or fragments thereof, can be measured directly by using radioactively labeled compound of interest (see, e.g., Wainscott et al. (1993) Mol. Pharmacol. 43:419-426; and Loric, et al. (1992) FEBS Lett. 312:203-207) or by the second messenger effect resulting from the interaction or binding of the candidate compound. (See, e.g., Lazereno and Birdsall (1993) Br. J. Pharmacol. 109:1120-1127.) Modulation in receptor signaling can be measured using a detectable assay, e.g., the FLIPR assay. (See, e.g., Coward, P. (1999) Anal. Biochem. 270:242-248; Sittampalam, supra; and Gonzalez and Negulescu, supra.) Activation of certain receptors, in particular, GPCRs, can be measured an <highlight><superscript>35</superscript></highlight>S GTP&ggr;S binding assay. (See, e.g., Lazareno (1999) Methods Mol. Biol. 106:231-245.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the candidate compounds can be subjected to competition screening assays, in which a known ligand, preferably labeled with an analytically detectable reagent, most preferably radioactivity, is introduced with the drug to be tested and the capacity of the compound to inhibit or enhance the binding of the labeled ligand is measured. Compounds are screened for their increased affinity and selectivity for the specific receptor or fragments thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> Candidate compounds are useful in the treatment or prophylaxis of disease states associated with the nervous system, in particular, neuropathic pain, perphipheral neuropathies, post-traumatic pain, post-surgical pain, pain associated with cancer, pain associated with chemotheraphy, and neurological disorders including, but not limited to cognitive disorders, such as Alzheimer&apos;s disease and dementia. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> The polynucleotides of the present invention can be used to design antisense oligonucleotides that inhibit translation of mRNA encoding the NPG of the present invention. Synthetic oligonucleotides, or other antisense chemical structures are designed to bind to mRNA encoding NPG and inhibit translation of mRNA and are useful to inhibit expression of NPG. This invention provides a means to alter levels of expression of NPG by the use of a synthetic antisense oligonucleotide (SAO) which inhibits translation of mRNA encoding these receptors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> The SAO is designed to be capable of passing through cell membranes in order to enter the cytoplasm of the cell by virtue of physical and chemical properties of the SAO which render it capable of passing through cell membranes (e.g. by designing small, hydrophobic SAO chemical structures) or by virtue of specific transport systems in the cell which recognize and transport the SAO into the cell. In addition, the SAO can be designed for administration only to certain selected cell populations by targeting the SAO to be recognized by specific cellular uptake mechanisms which binds and takes up the SAO only within certain selected cell populations. For example, the SAO may be designed to bind to NPG which are found only in certain cell types. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> The SAO is also designed to recognize and selectively bind to the target mRNA sequence, which may correspond to a sequence contained within the sequences of SEQ ID NO:1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, or 15 by virtue of complementary base pairing to the mRNA. Finally, the SAO is designed to inactivate the target mRNA sequence by any of three mechanisms: 1) binding to the target mRNA and thus inducing degradation of the mRNA by intrinsic cellular mechanisms such as RNAse digestion; 2) inhibiting translation of the mRNA target by interfering with the binding of translation-regulating factors or of ribosomes; or 3) inclusion of other chemical structures, such as ribozyme sequences or reactive chemical groups, which either degrade or chemically modify the target mRNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> Synthetic antisense oligonucleotide drugs have been shown to be capable of the properties described above when directed against mRNA targets. (See, e.g., Cohen (1989) Trends in Pharm. Sci. 10:435; and Weintraub (1990) Sci. Am. 262:40-46.) In addition, coupling of ribozymes to antisense oligonucleotides is a promising strategy for inactivating target mRNA. (See, e.g., Sarver et al. (1990) Science 247:1222.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> Diagnostics and Kits </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> The present invention contemplates use NPG polynucleotides, polypeptides, and antibodies in a variety of diagnostic methods kits. Typically the kit will have a compartment containing either a defined NPG polypeptide, polynucleotide, or a reagent which recognizes one or the other, e.g., antigen fragments or antibodies. Additionally the kit will include the reagents needed to carry out the assay in a separate compartment as well as instructions for use and proper disposal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> A variety of protocols including ELISA, RIA, and FACS for measuring NPG are known in the art and provide a basis for diagnosing altered or abnormal levels of NPG expression. Normal or standard values for NPG expression are established by combining body fluids or cell extracts taken from normal mammalian subjects, preferably human, with antibody to NPG under conditions suitable for complex formation. The amount of standard complex formation may be quantified by various methods, but preferably by photometric, means. Quantities of NPG expressed in control and disease samples from biopsied tissues are compared with the standard values. Deviation between standard and subject values establishes the parameters for diagnosing disease. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the invention, the polynucleotides encoding NPG may be used for diagnostic purposes. The polynucleotides which may be used include, oligonucleotide sequences, complementary RNA and DNA molecules, and PNAs. The polynucleotides may be used to detect and quantitate gene expression in biopsied tissues in which expression of NPG may be correlated with disease. The diagnostic assay may be used to distinguish between absence, presence, and excess expression of NPG, and to monitor regulation of NPG levels during therapeutic intervention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, hybridization with PCR probes which are capable of detecting polynucleotide sequences, including genomic sequences, encoding NPG or closely related molecules, may be used to identify nucleic acid sequences which encode NPG. The specificity of the probe, whether it is made from a highly specific region, e.g., 10 unique nucleotides in the 5&prime; regulatory region, or a less specific region, e.g., especially in the 3&prime; coding region, and the stringency of the hybridization or amplification (maximal, high, intermediate, or low) will determine whether the probe identifies only naturally occurring sequences encoding NPG, alleles, or related sequences. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> Probes may also be used for the detection of related sequences, and should preferably contain at least 50% of the nucleotides from any of the NPG encoding sequences. The hybridization probes of the subject invention may be DNA or RNA and derived from the nucleotide sequence of SEQ ID NO:1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, or 15, or from genomic sequence including promoter, enhancer elements, and introns of the naturally occurring NPG. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> Means for producing specific hybridization probes for DNAs encoding NPG include the cloning of nucleic acid sequences encoding NPG or NPG derivatives into vectors for the production of mRNA probes. Such vectors are known in the art, commercially available, and may be used to synthesize RNA probes in vitro by means of the addition of the appropriate RNA polymerases and the appropriate labeled nucleotides. Hybridization probes may be labeled by a variety of reporter groups, for example, radionuclides such as <highlight><superscript>32</superscript></highlight>P or <highlight><superscript>35</superscript></highlight>S, or enzymatic labels, such as alkaline phosphatase coupled to the probe via avidin/biotin coupling systems, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> Polynucleotide sequences encoding NPG may be used for the diagnosis of disease states associated with the nervous system, in particular, neuropathic pain, perphipheral neuropathies, post-traumatic pain, post-surgical pain, pain associated with cancer, pain associated with chemotheraphy; and neurological disease states including, but not limited to cognitive disease states, such as Alzheimer&apos;s disease and dementia. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> In order to provide a basis for the diagnosis of disease states associated with expression of NPG, a normal or standard profile for expression is established. This may be accomplished by combining body fluids or cell extracts taken from normal subjects, either animal or human, with a polynucleotide sequence, or a fragment thereof, which encodes NPG, under conditions suitable for hybridization or amplification. Standard hybridization may be quantified by comparing the values obtained from normal subjects with those from an experiment where a known amount of a substantially purified polynucleotide is used. Standard values obtained from normal samples may be compared with values obtained from samples from subjects who are symptomatic for disease. Deviation between standard and subject values is used to establish the presence of disease. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> Once a disease is established and a treatment protocol is initiated, hybridization assays may be repeated on a regular basis to evaluate whether the level of expression in the subject begins to approximate that which is observed in the normal subject. The results obtained from successive assays may be used to show the efficacy of treatment over a period ranging from several days to months. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> Additional diagnostic uses for oligonucleotides designed from the sequences encoding NPG may involve the use of PCR. Such oligomers may be chemically synthesized, generated enzymatically, or produced in vitro. Oligomers will preferably consist of two nucleotide sequences, one with sense orientation (5&prime; to 3&prime;) and another with antisense (3&prime; to 5&prime;), employed under optimized conditions for identification of a specific gene or condition. The same two oligomers, nested sets of oligomers, or even a degenerate pool of oligomers may be employed under less stringent conditions for detection and/or quantitation of closely related DNA or RNA sequences. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> Methods which may also be used to quantitate the expression of NPG include radiolabeling or biotinylating nucleotides, coamplification of a control nucleic acid, and standard curves onto which the experimental results are interpolated. (See, e.g, Melby, P. C. et al. (1993) J. Immunol. Methods, 159:235-244; and Duplaa, C. et al. (1993) Anal. Biochem. 212:229-236.) The speed of quantitation of multiple samples may be accelerated by running the assay in an ELISA format where the oligomer of interest is presented in various dilutions and a spectrophotometric or calorimetric response gives rapid quantitation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the invention, the nucleic acid sequences which encode NPG may also be used to generate hybridization probes which are useful for mapping the naturally occurring genomic sequence. The sequences may be mapped to a particular chromosome, to a specific region of a chromosome or to artificial chromosome constructions, such as human artificial chromosomes (HACs), yeast artificial chromosomes (YACs), bacterial artificial chromosomes (BACs), bacterial P1 constructions, or single chromosome cDNA libraries. (See, e.g., Price, C. M. (1993) Blood Rev. 7:127-134, and Trask, B. J. (1991) Trends Genet. 7:149-154.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> Fluorescent in situ hybridization (FISH) may be correlated with other physical chromosome mapping techniques and genetic map data. (See, e.g., Verma et al. (1988) Human Chromosomes: A Manual of Basic Techniques, Pergamon Press, New York, N.Y.) Examples of genetic map data can be found in various scientific journals or at Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man (OMIM). Correlation between the location of the gene encoding NPG on a physical chromosomal map and a specific disease, or predisposition to a specific disease, may help delimit the region of DNA associated with that genetic disease. The nucleotide sequences of the subject invention may be used to detect differences in gene sequences between normal, carrier, or affected individuals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> In situ hybridization of chromosomal preparations and physical mapping techniques such as linkage analysis using established chromosomal markers may be used for extending genetic maps. Often the placement of a gene on the chromosome of another mammalian species, such as mouse, may reveal associated markers even if the number or arm of a particular human chromosome is not known. New sequences can be assigned to chromosomal arms, or parts thereof, by physical mapping. This provides valuable information to investigators searching for disease genes using positional cloning or other gene discovery techniques. Once the disease or syndrome has been crudely localized by genetic linkage to a particular genomic region (see, e.g., Gatti, R. A. et al. (1988) Nature 336:577-580), any sequences mapping to that area may represent associated or regulatory genes for further investigation. The nucleotide sequence of the subject invention may also be used to detect differences in the chromosomal location due to translocation, inversion, etc. among normal, carrier, or affected individuals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> All patents, patent applications, and publications mentioned herein, whether supra or infra, are each incorporated by reference in its entirety. The broad scope of this invention is best understood with reference to the following examples, which are not intended to limit the invention to the specific embodiments described below. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> Some of the standard methods are described or referenced, e.g., in Maniatis et al. (1982) Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Manual, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Cold Spring Harbor Press; Sambrook et al. (1989) Molecular Cloning: A Laboratory Manual, (2d ed.), vols. 1-3, CSH Press, N.Y.; or Ausubel et al. (1987 and Supplements) Current Protocols in Molecular Biology, Greene/Wiley, New York; Innis et al. (eds.)(1990) PCR Protocols: A Guide to Methods and Applications Academic Press, N.Y. Methods for protein purification include such methods as ammonium sulfate precipitation, column chromatography, electrophoresis, centrifugation, crystallization, and others. See, e.g., Ausubel et al. (1987 and periodic supplements); Deutscher (1990) &ldquo;Guide to Protein Purification&rdquo; in Methods in Enzymology, vol. 182, and other volumes in this series; and manufacturer&apos;s literature on use of protein purification products, e.g., Pharmacia, Piscataway, N.J., or Bio-Rad, Richmond, Calif. Combination with recombinant techniques allow fusion to appropriate segments, e.g., to a FLAG sequence or an equivalent which can be fused via a protease-removable sequence. See, e.g., Hochuli (1989) Chemische Industrie 12:69-70; Hochuli (1990) &ldquo;Purification of Recombinant Proteins with Metal Chelate Absorbent&rdquo; in Setlow (ed.) Genetic Engineering Principle and Methods 12:87-98, Plenum Press, N.Y.; and Crowe et al. (1992) OIAexpress: The High Level Expression &amp; Protein Purification System QUIAGEN, Inc., Chatsworth, Calif. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example I </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Double-Stranded cDNA Synthesis from Rat Dorsal Root Ganglia (DRG) Poly(A)<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> RNA </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> Dorsal root ganglia from L4-L5 spinal levels of 10 Sprague-Dawley rats were removed from the animals and frozen in liquid nitrogen. Poly(A)<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> RNAs were extracted using MICRO-FASTTRACK RNA isolation kit (Invitrogen, San Diego, Calif., USA) and stored at &minus;80&deg; C. Reverse transcription was carried out with 100 ng of DRG poly(A)&plus;RNA and the SMART PCR cDNA synthesis kit (CLONTECH Laboratories Inc., Palo Alto, Calif., USA). The resulting double-stranded cDNA was used as tester cDNA in the subsequent subtraction. The driver cDNAs were prepared from poly (A<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>) RNA isolated from liver, skeletal muscle, heart, spleen, and kidney (CLONTECH) as described above. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example II </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Isolation of cDNA Clones that are Differentially Expressed in Dorsal Root Ganglia (DRG). </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> A subtracted cDNA library was constructed for dorsal root ganglia isolated 10 days after peripheral nerve injury (Diatchenko et al. (1996) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 93:6025-6030; and Jin et al. (1997) BioTechniques 23:10841086) using the PCR-SELECT cDNA subtraction kit (CLONTECH). The driver cDNAs were made using mRNAs isolated from skeletal muscle, kidney, liver, spleen and heart. Also included was DRG mRNA from Day 0 (i.e. prior to nerve injury) in the preparation of driver cDNAs to enrich genes that are up-regulated in response to the peripheral axotomy. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example III </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">RNA/DNA Dot Blot Analysis </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> Dot blots were prepared using poly(A)<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> RNAs from skeletal muscle, kidney, liver, spleen, heart, and brain, and SMART PCR-generated cDNA (Clontech) from DRG poly(A)<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> RNA. After normalization of each dot to both glyceraldehyde-3phosphate dehydrogenase (G3PDH) and &bgr;-actin, 0.1-0.25 ug of each poly(A)<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>RNA or 0.05 ug of SMART PCR-generated DRG cDNA was mixed with 3% Ficoll and 0.1% bromophenol blue (20 mM NaOH was used for DNA samples or without 20 mM NaOH for RNA samples). Each mixture was then applied to a nylon membrane at 1 ul per dot using a HYDRA-96 automatic dispenser (Robbins Scientific, Sunnyvale, Calif., USA). The membranes were UV cross-linked (Stratagene, La Jolla, Calif., USA) and neutralized in a solution containing 0.1 M Tris (pH 7.4) and 2&times; saline sodium citrate (SSC) before hybridization. Inserts from selected cDNA clones were amplified by PCR, labeled with <highlight><superscript>32</superscript></highlight>P-dCTP (Sambrook, supra) and used as probes in hybridization. Hybridization was carried out using EXPRESSHYB hybridization solution (Clontech) at 65&deg; C. overnight. The next morning the filters were washed twice in 2&times; SSC and 0.1% SDS at 65&deg; C. for 15 min., twice with 0.1&times; SSC and 0.1% SDS at 65&deg; C. for 15 min. and were subsequently exposed to BIOMAX MS autoradiography film (Kodak) for 1-3 days. Eight out of 12 cDNA clones randomly selected from the Day 10 subtracted DRG cDNA library were either DRG-specific or DRG- and/or brain-enriched, indicating a subtraction efficiency of about 67%. Subsequently, 410 random cDNA clones were picked and sequenced using an ABI 373 automatic sequencer (Applied Biosystems, Inc., Foster City, Calif.). The resulting nucleotide sequences were compared with those in the databases of GenBank (Gaithersburg, Md.), EMBL (Heidleberg, Germany) and LIFESEQ (Incyte Pharmaceuticals, inc., Palo Alto, Calif.). Approximately 63.7% of these sequences corresponded to known genes and 37.3% were unknown. To further analyze specific neuropathic pain-related genes, 36 cDNA clones were chosen for differential expression analysis on an array. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example IV </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">cDNA Array Preparation </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> Inserts of selected cDNA clones were amplified using nested primers (Jin, supra) with the PCR protocol. 100 ul of each PCR product was precipitated with ethanol and resuspended at a final concentration of 100 ng/ul in H20. To prepare for arraying, each sample was mixed with an equal volume of 0.6 N NaOH/15% Ficoll/0.5% bromophenol blue. One ul of each denatured DNA sample was transferred onto a nylon membrane using a HYDRA-96 automatic dispenser (Robbins Scientific). The nylon membrane was UV cross-linked (Stratagene) and neutralized in 0.5 M Tris-HCl (pH 7.5). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> Radioactively labeled cDNA probes were prepared as described in Sambrook, supra, with some modifications. In the first strand cDNA synthesis step, a 25 ul reaction contained 0.1-0.2 ug of poly(A)<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> mRNA, oligo (dT) (25-mer), and random primer (6-mer), IX first-strand cDNA synthesis buffer, 2 mM DTT, 200 uM dATP, 200 uM dGTP, 200 uM dTTP, 0.2 uM dCTP, 100 &mgr;Ci <highlight><superscript>32</superscript></highlight>P-dCTP, and 100 units of reverse transcriptase (GIBCO, Gaithersburg, Md.). The reverse transcription was carried out at 42&deg; C. for 1 hour, extracted with phenol:chloroform, precipitated with ethanol, and resuspended in 15 ul of TE. Samples were mixed with 1.5 ul of 2.5 N NaOH, and incubated for 30 minutes at 68&deg; C. to hydrolyze the RNA. After cooling to room temperature, the samples were neutralized by adding of 2 ul of 2M Tris (pH 7.5) and 1.5 ul of 2.5 N HCl. The resulting cDNAs were purified by passing through CHROMA SPIN-200 columns (CLONTECH), co-precipitated with glycogen in ethanol, and resuspended in 100 ul of H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>0. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> <highlight><superscript>32</superscript></highlight>P-labeled cDNA probes were heat-denatured and hybridized to the cDNA arrays in EXPRESSHYB hybridization solution (CLONTECH). The nylon membranes were washed as described above and then scanned by a PHOSPHORIMAGER (Molecular Dynamics, Sunnyvale, Calif., USA). The resulting images were then processed and analyzed using ATLAS VISION software (CLONTECH), which produces a pseudocolor representation of relative gene expression levels. On a single array, the hybridization intensity of each cDNA clone was normalized to that of the internal control clone G5, and the relative expression level of each cDNA clone at different time points was represented in a pseudocolor scale corresponding to the ratio of a normalized readout relative to that at Day 0 (i.e., the readout at Day 0 is arbitrarily set at 1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> Hybridization signals were observed for 85% of the rat cDNA array elements, but not to the negative control, a plasmid DNA, (data not shown). All highly and moderately moderately abundant transcripts, as well as a few rare transcripts were detected. At least 12 cDNA clones that were apparently up-regulated in response to the chronic constriction injury were found. These gene expression levels remained at high levels between 7 to 14 days following the nerve injury, and then subsequently declined towards the normal state. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example V </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Sequence Extension of Differentially Regulated NPG cDNAs </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> Some NPG clones were extended to full length clones using a modified Rapid Amplification of cDNA Ends (RACE) procedure. (See, Ausubel, supra.) Two rounds of PCR were run using EXPAND long range PCR kit (Boeringer-Mannheim, Indianapolis, Ind.) Alternatively, standard library screening using the partial cDNAs described above, was performed. (See, Maniatis, supra; and Ausubel, supra.) </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example VI </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Isolation of NPG-8 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> NPG-8 was isolated using a 5955 bp fragment of NPG-6 to search the LifeSeq database (Incyte Pharmaceuticals, Palo Alto, Calif.). Several clones, including clone id. 3600812) were assembled into a 1.5 kb contiguous sequence. PCR primers designed from this assembled sequence were then used to amplify a MARATHON cDNA library (Clontech) from human brain. Using the SMART RACE cDNA amplification kit (Clontech), larger extension products were isolated. One 3.1 kb product, MT-6, was used for subsequent extensions and sequencing, and has yielded a 19 kb sequence. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example VII </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">In situ Hybridization of NPG-6 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> 3&prime; untranslated sense and anti-sense PCR fragment (253 bp) was labeled with <highlight><superscript>32</superscript></highlight>P was labeled using the RIBOPROBE system (Promega) in vitro transcription reaction. (See, e.g., Lu and Gillet (1994) <highlight><italic>Cell Vision </italic></highlight>1:169-176.) Fresh frozen tissues were cryostat cut at 12 &mgr;m and thaw mounted on aminosilane coated slides. Tissue sections were pretreated as follows (all steps at room temperature unless otherwise noted): 4% paraformaldehyde, 0.05% glutaraldehyde for 5 minutes at 4&deg; C.; PBS for 2 minutes; acetic anhydride in 0.1 M TEA for 5 minutes; PBS for 2 minutes; 2&times; SSC for 2 minutes; and dehydration in ascending concentrations of ethanol. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> Sections were prehybridized for 1 hour at 42&deg; C. in a covered hybridization box lined with moist filter paper saturated with 4&times; SSC and 50% formamide. Probe was applied to slides and allowed to incubate overnight at 60&deg; C. Slides were washed in 2&times; SSC for 5 minutes two times; subjected to RNase digestion (20 &mgr;g/ml RNase A in RNase buffer) for 30 mintues at 37&deg; C.; rinsed two times in RNase buffer for minutes at 37&deg; C.; four changes of 2&times; SSC for 30 minutes each; four changes of 1&times; SSC for 15 minutes each; 0.1&times; SSC fro 1 hour at 65&deg; C.; and 0.1&times; SSC for 10 minutes twice. Washed slides were dehydrated in ascending concentration of ethanol in 0.3M NH<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>OAC, dried and exposed to &bgr;MAX HYPERFILM (Amersham) for 10 days. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> Although the foregoing invention has been described in some detail by way of illustration and example for purposes of clarity and understanding, it will be obvious that certain changes and modifications may be practiced within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<sequence-cwu id="SEQLST-1">
<number>1</number>
<sequence-list-new-rules>
<s100>
<s160>16 </s160>
</s100>
<s200>
<s210>1 </s210>
<s211>5149 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 1 
tcccacttca gagcggccga ggccgagggc ctggagcagg ccgcgctgcc ggccgaggag     60 
agccgtgtgc agcccatgac cgcctccaac tggacgctgg tgatggaggg cgagtggatg    120 
ctgaaatttt atgctccatg gtgtccatcc tgccagcaga ctgattctga atgggagact    180 
tttgcaaaga atggagaaac acttcagatc agtgtgggaa aggtggatgc cattcaagaa    240 
ccaggtttga gtggccgctt ctttgtcacc actctcccag cattttttca tgcaaaagat    300 
gggatattcc gccgttaccg tggtccagga atctatgaag atttacagaa ttacatatta    360 
gagaagaaat ggcaatcagt tgagcctctc actggctgga agtccccagc ctctctaacg    420 
atgtctggaa tggctggtct ttttagtatc tctggcaaga tttggcatct tcacaactat    480 
ttcacagtga ctcttggaat tcctgcatgg tgttcttatg tttttttcgt cattgccact    540 
ttggtctttg gcctgttcat gggtttgatc ctggtggtga tctcagaatg cttctatgtg    600 
cctcttccaa gagcttcctc tgaacgctct gagcaggagc agaggtctga ggaggctcaa    660 
ggagctgagc agctccagga tgcagaggaa gagaaggatg actcaaatga agaagaaaac    720 
aaagacagtc ttgtggatga tgaggaagag aaagaggacc ttggagatga cgatgaagta    780 
gaagaagatg aggaagaaga caacttggca ggcatcatgg atgaggagaa aagtgacagc    840 
aatgagcaag gagttgtgaa ggagggcagt gtgtccccga aggatgaaga agctcgttca    900 
gctgacacac aggacgtggt ggaagactcc ttgaggcagc gcaagagtca gcatgccaag    960 
ggaccatagg ttacattatg ctacttctaa aaatacaggc caaaaaaaaa taagtttgtt   1020 
tccctctggt gtgcagttta agccaaatcc ttagttgttt gttttgtttt gtttctctgg   1080 
atgagcagtg ttcactttta aaagatgatc tctggccctg tggttacgtg gtagtaagct   1140 
cagtgttgta agagtcaggt gcagcactta gccaccatgg tgtcaggatc tttgtgggga   1200 
cttgtgcaga acaagtcgat gtgcttggga actaaggagt aaatcagaag acttctctgc   1260 
agttctcatg agcaccttta gaaatgaggc tgctgcttag tgaagtgaga acaaagccac   1320 
cgcactctgg agcaccttga agtagaggaa gtgtttgccg tcaccgttaa gcatgtcctt   1380 
tagtcatgtc agcaacatag gtgccacagc tccacaacat tatcttgggg ttagaaattg   1440 
tggagacctg gatatagata caacttcaaa atgaagtcat gtaagctctt ggggtctctg   1500 
ttgtcttttg tttcttacct ttaatctcta tgacttttcc tctttgactt gcagactcca   1560 
tttcacagct gctctgtagt gagaagagca ggcagcagtg atctgcatgc gttaccctta   1620 
attgaagtaa agcttgaggt aatcagtaat cacagctgat gatgccaaga ccgccaagtg   1680 
tctcaaagat atgctgtact ctgaaaaagc aaaagagagt agtggattca taggacaggt   1740 
ataaacaaca tcttgcttgg gtccctatag ttacaggatg acttctttaa gtttcttcag   1800 
ccacattctt tgtttttctg aaccgaaagt gctctatatc ttgtcactac aaggtagttt   1860 
tctaaagctg acttcatgtc tgtgatagtt tccatctcca ggaatctctc tggaatcact   1920 
ttaataacca ctgaaaaggc atgtcggctt tgcttttctt gatgtgcttt tggtgaaaaa   1980 
attgatgaaa gtcaatatca agaggtgaaa gatttgattt gtttctatct cccttgatcc   2040 
tctagagaat tgtatgatta taaatctctc cctgctcaat ctaatatcag tgtcaaggaa   2100 
cccaactttc ttaaaaaaat atttccatct cctctcttac cctctcatgt ctgcaaataa   2160 
atgcataaaa tagattttag ctgtatgaaa gatgactaaa gtgaatctta ttacccttgg   2220 
gttgagtcag agtaatgagt ttaggtttgt gaaattcaaa atgtttcgac attttaaaaa   2280 
gggatatgta gtgtaattct ctgtctgctt agataaccct ttgctgccaa caggagagtc   2340 
attggtagtg gaggttcaga attcgccctc ctatactgca caagcctgct acaaactttg   2400 
cacaaaggaa gattttattg tgacaatcca ttctttatca atgtttttat ttcatctttg   2460 
taacttagtt aactatcagt tcaaggctaa ggctatcaca gaactggaga cctacttccc   2520 
ttccatgttt ctgcccttct gatacatcct tactcaaaag tgccatggtt ctgtggtact   2580 
tcctgctata tcttcctact agagctaagc tgcaccttct cttttgcagt gcattttgtt   2640 
tccttgtaat cagatgcatg gagtgtgtaa tagtaaatct atgttcaggg tatggaaaag   2700 
ggaaggcttg tgtctctgtt ctgtgacgta ccctcctcca aattgacata ctgggttcta   2760 
gtgcgataat tgagcagagg aaaacttgaa gacttacagt cagccttagc tttgataaat   2820 
gttttaaaac cacattccag ttggaccaca aatactatct aataatataa tgagataata   2880 
tattttcttt cttaataata cttaaaagat attggaggct gggagaaagg gccacgaaga   2940 
agaggcctaa aattatattt atttgtagga acaaattttt cctagctttt ctctttttaa   3000 
tatcctggta aaaattgggt ttctagtaaa tagtccagga gtatttactt aacttaattt   3060 
cttttgattt aaagccttta ggttaatttt caatactttg ttaatataaa attaaaggga   3120 
aagaccaact tacgattaga tcaacattta atatcacttt atttttgtgt atataataaa   3180 
tttaatccag aagttaagtg catgaaaaca tgattttata aaacaaaact aaccatgctt   3240 
cccctccatt gccatacctg ctatttaatt gtagattgct attttctgta tgttaaaatt   3300 
gggtgaatga gatagcaatt gtggaatgag gatatatagt gctttatgga caggtagtta   3360 
gagaaaggtg ccttgttctt cattggaata tctgaaaatt ccacctcttt ttaatttttc   3420 
ttagcacttc accccttaac catgctgaac catagcagct tgcttagaat ctcatggaag   3480 
caatgcacag gcaaattcac gtttttgttg ttttgattgt tttgattttg aaagctaatc   3540 
gtggaacatg gaagagatgg ctcattcagt gcacaggcca tttcgctggg tgctgtggca   3600 
gtcactgcag tctcatccta tacataggct ctgtacctat tactatagta actagtgcag   3660 
tggaaggcaa acacgcttga caagatcgtc tctgggtagc tgaaaagcta cactctcaca   3720 
ttttagggcc accccatgac tgataattaa gatactgctg tgtagtttga gtatgtgtaa   3780 
acttgaataa gagcaccttg taacatcttt tgacgaggag attaaaatgc tagttaacag   3840 
aatatctacc atgttgcttt ttgcatgatg ggaaacaatg gagttcaaag ggaagtttta   3900 
aaggaatgaa aagggtgaaa gatatttcag cattaaaatc ctaagcatga agtgaaagga   3960 
gagattggta cttctgctgg tgtatacagg ttttctgtgt tcttctctta gtgttccgct   4020 
gttattcctg ccagtattgt acatgcgtga ttgacttgcc tgtcaaatct atcaagtatt   4080 
ggaaagtatt tgtgtaaatc tttgtgccaa caagaattct cccagtgttg tgtatcttta   4140 
cctcatacca ttcattgata tggttcttgt gagattgtag ctcgtctgac agaagccaag   4200 
gtggaatccg atgaaacctg ccgaggcagg aggttcaact gagaaaccta agacagcttc   4260 
agcctagcat gtggacctca gcggcatagt ctctaaagtt ttgtgtaaac tgtgatgttc   4320 
acctgtggct ttgacccatt tctgatgtgg tttaatttta tttctttctg gacagctttg   4380 
tagaaatgga atttttatac taaagacact gttcacttgt aagtcaatac attataaaat   4440 
ggtgtattta ttttttgtaa tagtgtggat tgtttagccc agtgtattta ttttccttta   4500 
cctgtgtatt ctgtgctctc aaatagatgt gtagcaattg aaatgagaac tcagtgcatc   4560 
atttcaagca ctacattgcc tgcattgcaa attctctgag cacaggattg tacagaaccc   4620 
tgagcctgtg tactgccatt tgattgtcag ttccatttgt gtcaaaacct aaaggtggtg   4680 
atgaccaagt gaaacagagt gctgtactgc tttttcatat gaatattttc acataaaagc   4740 
atttgtgaaa gcagttgaaa atattacttt gtttaaaaaa atctttcttc tgtgttyaaa   4800 
aaaararwat tcattctcta cctttcatac ctaaacttgg tgaaattcat gccatgtgcc   4860 
caaggttaat gctgaagatg taaggccttc tgaacacacc acagctcatt agctcactgt   4920 
actctctgta cgagctcgtt ccacttgcca tggccaggtt ggtgcagtta ctaagtaact   4980 
ctgctactcc tccaagattg ctggacttcc gcattcttct aggacttcta gaagaccatc   5040 
tcaacttaac cgttcccacc actgtagcaa taaaaaaagg aaagggcggg ggctcctttg   5100 
aacacactta aaaataaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaa               5149 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>2 </s210>
<s211>322 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 2 
Ser His Phe Arg Ala Ala Glu Ala Glu Gly Leu Glu Gln Ala Ala Leu 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Pro Ala Glu Glu Ser Arg Val Gln Pro Met Thr Ala Ser Asn Trp Thr 
            20                  25                  30 
Leu Val Met Glu Gly Glu Trp Met Leu Lys Phe Tyr Ala Pro Trp Cys 
        35                  40                  45 
Pro Ser Cys Gln Gln Thr Asp Ser Glu Trp Glu Thr Phe Ala Lys Asn 
    50                  55                  60 
Gly Glu Thr Leu Gln Ile Ser Val Gly Lys Val Asp Ala Ile Gln Glu 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Pro Gly Leu Ser Gly Arg Phe Phe Val Thr Thr Leu Pro Ala Phe Phe 
                85                  90                  95 
His Ala Lys Asp Gly Ile Phe Arg Arg Tyr Arg Gly Pro Gly Ile Tyr 
            100                 105                 110 
Glu Asp Leu Gln Asn Tyr Ile Leu Glu Lys Lys Trp Gln Ser Val Glu 
        115                 120                 125 
Pro Leu Thr Gly Trp Lys Ser Pro Ala Ser Leu Thr Met Ser Gly Met 
    130                 135                 140 
Ala Gly Leu Phe Ser Ile Ser Gly Lys Ile Trp His Leu His Asn Tyr 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Phe Thr Val Thr Leu Gly Ile Pro Ala Trp Cys Ser Tyr Val Phe Phe 
                165                 170                 175 
Val Ile Ala Thr Leu Val Phe Gly Leu Phe Met Gly Leu Ile Leu Val 
            180                 185                 190 
Val Ile Ser Glu Cys Phe Tyr Val Pro Leu Pro Arg Ala Ser Ser Glu 
        195                 200                 205 
Arg Ser Glu Gln Glu Gln Arg Ser Glu Glu Ala Gln Gly Ala Glu Gln 
    210                 215                 220 
Leu Gln Asp Ala Glu Glu Glu Lys Asp Asp Ser Asn Glu Glu Glu Asn 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Lys Asp Ser Leu Val Asp Asp Glu Glu Glu Lys Glu Asp Leu Gly Asp 
                245                 250                 255 
Asp Asp Glu Val Glu Glu Asp Glu Glu Glu Asp Asn Leu Ala Gly Ile 
            260                 265                 270 
Met Asp Glu Glu Lys Ser Asp Ser Asn Glu Gln Gly Val Val Lys Glu 
        275                 280                 285 
Gly Ser Val Ser Pro Lys Asp Glu Glu Ala Arg Ser Ala Asp Thr Gln 
    290                 295                 300 
Asp Val Val Glu Asp Ser Leu Arg Gln Arg Lys Ser Gln His Ala Lys 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Gly Pro 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>3 </s210>
<s211>3308 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 3 
tttcgcctgt ttttggtttt gtgacttaga ggagagaact tttctaagca ggccgggcac     60 
gactgaaggc tactctgccc ccacgtggac gctcccctgg ggaaaagaag tctgaaagta    120 
aacttagcct cgccggcctg aaggcctcaa ctttggctgg actgtaagtt tcggagtcat    180 
gaccttctcg ctgggcaggt gggaatcttt atctatcttg ggctggacct gaaacctcag    240 
tcagcaccca aatctccccc accccattca cactttgtac caggggtagg ccccggacac    300 
tgatctacaa catggataaa tatgatgatc tgggccttga ggccagtaag ttcattgagg    360 
acctgaacat gtacgaggcc tccaaggatg ggctcttccg ggtggacaag ggtgctagca    420 
acaaccccga atttgaggaa actcgaaggg tgttcgcgac caagatggcc aaaatccacc    480 
tccagcagca gcaacagcag cagctcctac aggaggaggc cctacctagg gcaggcagaa    540 
gccccatcaa cggtgggaac cgtcagggtg tgagcagcaa gctggctgca gatggggccg    600 
ctaagcctcc tcttgctgtg ccaacagtag cacctggact agctaccacc actatggcgg    660 
tgcagtcctc atacccacct caggagcaga ggaccaggcc atctgcccac ggtgcaaggc    720 
ctggcagtca gaactgtggt tccagggagg ggcctgtgag ttcccagaga cctgctttac    780 
acggtctggg tccctgtgaa gacccttcct gcctcactca cggagactat tacgacaatt    840 
tctctttggc aagcccacag tggggtgata aaccagaaga gtcccctagc atgagtttga    900 
gtgtagggag tggatggcct ggttgcccag gaaatgattc cctgtcgcac agatcctgtg    960 
gggacagtca tccttaccac ccacagctct ccatgtgctc tggcaggtct tttgaaagtg   1020 
gtcaggacag tggcattggt ggccatagca gtgagaagcc aacaggcctt tggtccactg   1080 
cctcctctca gagagtgaac ctgggctttt cttccacggg cttggagaat gggaccccag   1140 
ctcaacccaa gggcacaacc gtttcagcac caatggtccc tagcagcact agccaaggcg   1200 
cttgtctgag aagagattcg agtctgggat atgaggctcc aggcagggtc ttcaaacctc   1260 
ttgtggacac tcagccttgg ctccaggatg ggcccaagtc gtacctctct gtttctgctc   1320 
cactatcctc aacaaccagc aaggacaatg ccaagacagg tatgaccgct ggactggatc   1380 
ctaagcttgg atgtgtggag tctggcacta gtcccaagcc cagccccacc agtaacgtcc   1440 
atccggtaat gtctgctccg tctgagttat cttgtaaaga gagtcctccc agctggtcca   1500 
ctgacagtag cctgggacct gtgctcccag agagccccac cccctccagg gtgaggttgc   1560 
cctgccagac cctcacgcca ggccccgagc ttggaccctc cactgcggaa ttgaagttgg   1620 
aagccctcac ccagcgtctg gagcgagaga tggatgctca ccccaaagca gactacttcg   1680 
gagcctgtgt gaaatgcagc aaaggggtgt ttggagctgg ccaggcctgt caggccatgg   1740 
gggatctcta ccacgatgcc tgcttcacct gtgcagcctg cagcaggaag ttaagaggaa   1800 
aggccttcta ttttgtcaat ggcaaagtat tctgtgagga agactttttg tactctggct   1860 
ttcagcagtc tgcggacaga tgttttcttt gtggacacct gattatggac atgatcctac   1920 
aggccctagg gaagtcctat caccctggct gtttccgctg cgtcatctgc aatgagtgtc   1980 
tagatggggt tcctttcacc gtggactctg agaacaagat ctactgtgtc cgagattatc   2040 
acaaggtgct ggcccccaag tgtgcagcct gtggccttcc cattcttcca ccagagggct   2100 
cagatgagac catcagagtt gtgtccatgg accgagacta ccatgtagag tgctaccact   2160 
gtgaggactg tggtctggag ctcaatgatg aggatggtca ccgctgctat ccactggggg   2220 
accacctgtt ctgtcactcc tgccatgtca agagactgga gaaaggaccc tcacctgcat   2280 
ccctccacca gcaccacttc tagcaaagag acagtgggga tgtggggcca gcctgcccag   2340 
ggaggtgtct gtgtagcact tctgagcttc cccacagctg gggcacagga agaggaggga   2400 
caggaagttg agttcctgtg tgtgtgaagg gtatcattct tttaaccaca gcagtgtgca   2460 
ctccccatcc tgtccgtgtg ttttccaagt gcttttctct attgtcacac tctcgccaaa   2520 
tcactcagga agatgctcca acttgcacat gacacaagat ggggtctgtg taactggaca   2580 
catcctactc cctggaaaca ggttttcaga ttgtgttggg catattccac agtgtcccta   2640 
aagagaaaca atggtggagg tgagcaggag aatgcctgca cccagataac cctcacacag   2700 
cctgtgctgt gacttcacag ttctgtccac ttcagagctt tagttcttct gaggatgctt   2760 
caaaccctta actgcattac agcaggaaag aagtactgca tatatttgct ttgtaccttg   2820 
gagtttgctt ggtgaaagag agccaagctt agacatctgg gaggctgggt ctccctgctg   2880 
tgcctctgca gttcctgctg cacctaaggc agtggagctg gggcagaggc ctgccctgcc   2940 
ctgccctgcc ctgccctgtc ctatatagcc agctcagaga gaactggtgc aggcaccagg   3000 
cttcttgtcc atgcttggtg ctgtgtttca ttgctttcct ccagtctgtg acattggagt   3060 
tgcttcctca aggcgagtct gaggatctca tgcgctcaga tccctgtcaa aggttgggaa   3120 
tcctagtcca tatcctggga gggagctcct tccagaagga aagtgttgtg tgtgagatct   3180 
caaagctagc accagaggga gtgcctgagc ttgtttcaca ggcatctctc tcggccacct   3240 
ctcagcacag acattcgttt ggtttgatga aaccaatata aggtacactg ctttaaaaaa   3300 
aaaaaaaa                                                            3308 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>4 </s210>
<s211>663 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 4 
Met Asp Lys Tyr Asp Asp Leu Gly Leu Glu Ala Ser Lys Phe Ile Glu 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Asp Leu Asn Met Tyr Glu Ala Ser Lys Asp Gly Leu Phe Arg Val Asp 
            20                  25                  30 
Lys Gly Ala Ser Asn Asn Pro Glu Phe Glu Glu Thr Arg Arg Val Phe 
        35                  40                  45 
Ala Thr Lys Met Ala Lys Ile His Leu Gln Gln Gln Gln Gln Gln Gln 
    50                  55                  60 
Leu Leu Gln Glu Glu Ala Leu Pro Arg Ala Gly Arg Ser Pro Ile Asn 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Gly Gly Asn Arg Gln Gly Val Ser Ser Lys Leu Ala Ala Asp Gly Ala 
                85                  90                  95 
Ala Lys Pro Pro Leu Ala Val Pro Thr Val Ala Pro Gly Leu Ala Thr 
            100                 105                 110 
Thr Thr Met Ala Val Gln Ser Ser Tyr Pro Pro Gln Glu Gln Arg Thr 
        115                 120                 125 
Arg Pro Ser Ala His Gly Ala Arg Pro Gly Ser Gln Asn Cys Gly Ser 
    130                 135                 140 
Arg Glu Gly Pro Val Ser Ser Gln Arg Pro Ala Leu His Gly Leu Gly 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Pro Cys Glu Asp Pro Ser Cys Leu Thr His Gly Asp Tyr Tyr Asp Asn 
                165                 170                 175 
Phe Ser Leu Ala Ser Pro Gln Trp Gly Asp Lys Pro Glu Glu Ser Pro 
            180                 185                 190 
Ser Met Ser Leu Ser Val Gly Ser Gly Trp Pro Gly Cys Pro Gly Asn 
        195                 200                 205 
Asp Ser Leu Ser His Arg Ser Cys Gly Asp Ser His Pro Tyr His Pro 
    210                 215                 220 
Gln Leu Ser Met Cys Ser Gly Arg Ser Phe Glu Ser Gly Gln Asp Ser 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Gly Ile Gly Gly His Ser Ser Glu Lys Pro Thr Gly Leu Trp Ser Thr 
                245                 250                 255 
Ala Ser Ser Gln Arg Val Asn Leu Gly Phe Ser Ser Thr Gly Leu Glu 
            260                 265                 270 
Asn Gly Thr Pro Ala Gln Pro Lys Gly Thr Thr Val Ser Ala Pro Met 
        275                 280                 285 
Val Pro Ser Ser Thr Ser Gln Gly Ala Cys Leu Arg Arg Asp Ser Ser 
    290                 295                 300 
Leu Gly Tyr Glu Ala Pro Gly Arg Val Phe Lys Pro Leu Val Asp Thr 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Gln Pro Trp Leu Gln Asp Gly Pro Lys Ser Tyr Leu Ser Val Ser Ala 
                325                 330                 335 
Pro Leu Ser Ser Thr Thr Ser Lys Asp Asn Ala Lys Thr Gly Met Thr 
            340                 345                 350 
Ala Gly Leu Asp Pro Lys Leu Gly Cys Val Glu Ser Gly Thr Ser Pro 
        355                 360                 365 
Lys Pro Ser Pro Thr Ser Asn Val His Pro Val Met Ser Ala Pro Ser 
    370                 375                 380 
Glu Leu Ser Cys Lys Glu Ser Pro Pro Ser Trp Ser Thr Asp Ser Ser 
385                 390                 395                 400 
Leu Gly Pro Val Leu Pro Glu Ser Pro Thr Pro Ser Arg Val Arg Leu 
                405                 410                 415 
Pro Cys Gln Thr Leu Thr Pro Gly Pro Glu Leu Gly Pro Ser Thr Ala 
            420                 425                 430 
Glu Leu Lys Leu Glu Ala Leu Thr Gln Arg Leu Glu Arg Glu Met Asp 
        435                 440                 445 
Ala His Pro Lys Ala Asp Tyr Phe Gly Ala Cys Val Lys Cys Ser Lys 
    450                 455                 460 
Gly Val Phe Gly Ala Gly Gln Ala Cys Gln Ala Met Gly Asp Leu Tyr 
465                 470                 475                 480 
His Asp Ala Cys Phe Thr Cys Ala Ala Cys Ser Arg Lys Leu Arg Gly 
                485                 490                 495 
Lys Ala Phe Tyr Phe Val Asn Gly Lys Val Phe Cys Glu Glu Asp Phe 
            500                 505                 510 
Leu Tyr Ser Gly Phe Gln Gln Ser Ala Asp Arg Cys Phe Leu Cys Gly 
        515                 520                 525 
His Leu Ile Met Asp Met Ile Leu Gln Ala Leu Gly Lys Ser Tyr His 
    530                 535                 540 
Pro Gly Cys Phe Arg Cys Val Ile Cys Asn Glu Cys Leu Asp Gly Val 
545                 550                 555                 560 
Pro Phe Thr Val Asp Ser Glu Asn Lys Ile Tyr Cys Val Arg Asp Tyr 
                565                 570                 575 
His Lys Val Leu Ala Pro Lys Cys Ala Ala Cys Gly Leu Pro Ile Leu 
            580                 585                 590 
Pro Pro Glu Gly Ser Asp Glu Thr Ile Arg Val Val Ser Met Asp Arg 
        595                 600                 605 
Asp Tyr His Val Glu Cys Tyr His Cys Glu Asp Cys Gly Leu Glu Leu 
    610                 615                 620 
Asn Asp Glu Asp Gly His Arg Cys Tyr Pro Leu Gly Asp His Leu Phe 
625                 630                 635                 640 
Cys His Ser Cys His Val Lys Arg Leu Glu Lys Gly Pro Ser Pro Ala 
                645                 650                 655 
Ser Leu His Gln His His Phe 
            660 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>5 </s210>
<s211>6573 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 5 
gctaaatgaa gtgtgcgcgg aaccaagctc aaacacggag gcagaggcac tgcggaaaag     60 
agcgatagaa ggactgggta ggtaggctgc acgctgtccc ccaggattat gaacctgtga    120 
ccgacactaa gctgctccgg ctcacgagaa tccacccacc taaaccaaga cgggcaaaac    180 
agcagcagtc actcatctac agcgatcacg tccgggttcg gccaccgcct gggcctctcg    240 
cttccaatag ctgtcctcgc gcactcaagc tgctcccgcc aactcttccc aaacaagccg    300 
aagcggcgcc ggctgctagg cgacaccact ccccgcccag ccagccaagg ccggaactag    360 
gccccggata ccagggaaga ctacatttca cgactggggg aaaagcttta cggctatgtt    420 
tccccctcca agaccttttt tcactgtgga tgagggaaag ccgtgagaag aggactctac    480 
gtcccagagt gcagttcggc gctgcggctg tgcatactgg gattagaagt tttgggaaga    540 
gcagcgcgtt cccggcgtgc aatgcgagag gctgcggccg ccctggaaga gctggggaag    600 
gatcgggagg cgggaggagc ggctgctaag gtgcggccgc ccaggagccg gagcgtggcg    660 
gactatgaca gtgttttctg cagagtcctt ctccggtcca ccgtctccga agctttcctg    720 
aaccatctct tggcggagcc gccctcagtt tgcctggtta atgatggaag ggaagatggc    780 
tgatattaac ttcaaagaag tgactttgat agtcggcgtg gttgctgcct gctactggaa    840 
cagtctgttc tgtgggtttg tttttgatga tgtttcagca atactggata ccaaagacct    900 
gcacccatct acacctttaa aaactttatt tcagaatgac ttctggggaa ctcctatgtc    960 
tgaggagaga agccacaagt catacaggcc cttaacagtg ttgacatttc gcttaaatta   1020 
cctcctcagt gaactaaagc ccatgtctta ccacctcctg aatacggtgt tccatgctgt   1080 
ggtcagtgtg atctttctca aggtctgcag actttttctg gataagaggg gcagtgtgat   1140 
tgcggctctg ctctttgcag tgcacccaat ccatacggaa gcagtcacag gtgttgtagg   1200 
aagagctgaa ctcttatcct ctgtcttttt cctagctgca ttcctgtcgt atactaaatc   1260 
caaaggacca gacaattcca tagtgtggac tccgattgca ttgacagtgc tcttagtggc   1320 
tgttgcaaca ttgtgtaaag aacaagggat aacagttgtc ggaatctgtt gtgtatatga   1380 
agtatttgtg gcccaagggt acactttgcc attgttatgt gccgttgctg gacagtttct   1440 
ccgcgggaag ggtagcattc cattttctat gctacagaca ttaataaaac tcattgtctt   1500 
gatgttcagt actttactac ttgtcgtgat cagagtccaa gttattcagt cacaacttcc   1560 
agtgtttacg aggtttgata atccagccgc tgtaagccca acccctacaa ggcagctgac   1620 
ttttaactac ctccttcctg tgaatgcttg gcttctattg aatccttcag aactctgctg   1680 
tgattggacc atgggaacaa taccactgat agaatcattt ctagatgttc gaaatcttgc   1740 
cacttttgct ttcttttgct ttctgggtgc tttgggaata ttcagtctca gataccctgg   1800 
tgactcctcc aagactgtcc taatggcgct ttctttaatg gcgttaccat ttattcccgc   1860 
atcaaacctc ttctttcctg ttggatttgt tgttgcagag cgagtactat atgttcctag   1920 
catggggttc tgtattttag tagcccatgg atggcaaaaa atttcaaaca aaagtgtcct   1980 
gaaaaagctc tcctgggttt gtctgtccat ggtgatatta acccatgcct tgaaaacact   2040 
ccatagaaat tgggactggg agtcagaata tacattgttt atgtcagcct taaaggtgaa   2100 
taaaaacaat gccaaattat ggaataatgt gggtcatgct ctggaaaatg agaagaactt   2160 
tgagaaagct ttgaaatact ttttgcaggc tacccatgtt cagccagatg acattggtgc   2220 
ccacatgaat gtaggaagaa cgtataaaaa cttaaacaga actaaagaag ctgaagaatc   2280 
ttacatgttg gctaaatcac taatgcctca gattattcct ggtaaaaaat atgcagccag   2340 
aattgcccct aatcacctaa atgtttatat caatttggcc aacctcattc gagcaaatga   2400 
gtcccgcctg gaggaagckg accagctgta ccgacaggca atcagcatga ggccagactt   2460 
caagcaggct tacattagca ggggagaatt gcttttaaaa atgaataagc ctctcaaagc   2520 
aaaagaagca tatcttaaag cactggagct ggacagaaat aatgcagacc tgtggtacaa   2580 
cttggcaatt gtttatattg aacttaaaga accagatgaa gctctgaaga actttaatcg   2640 
ggctttggaa ctgaactcca gacataagct agcactgttt aattctgcta ttttaatgca   2700 
ggaatcaggt gaagttaaac tcagaccaga agctagaaaa cggcttctaa attacataaa   2760 
tgaggagccg caagatgcta atggctattt caatttgggg atgcttgcca tggatgacaa   2820 
aaaggactct gaagctgaga cttggatgaa gagggctatc aagttacagc ctgacttcag   2880 
aagtgctttg ttcaacctgg cactcctgta ctcacagact gctaaggagt taaaggcatt   2940 
gccaatctta gaagagctgc tcagatacta tcctgatcat accaagggcc tcattttaaa   3000 
aggagatatt ctgatgaacc agaagaagga tatagctgga gctaagaaat gttttgaaaa   3060 
gatcctggaa atggatccaa gcaatgtgca aggaaagcac aatctctgtg tcgtgtactt   3120 
tgaagagaag gacttgctga aagcggagag atgcctagtt gaaaccttgg cattagcacc   3180 
tcatgaggaa tatattcaac gccatttgag tatagtcagg gataaaatcg cctcttctgg   3240 
tattgtggat cagccactgt ccccagttga taagacttca ggtacagaag aaaaagatga   3300 
agtcccttcc gaggatgtaa aagaaatcat cagtgagtcc aggccagcac aaatcataaa   3360 
aacaaatgat aacagaaagt ctcagtctaa caagcagtca acaggaaatg cagaccaaga   3420 
tgccccccat aaaacaacaa aagacatcaa agaaattgag aagaaaagag ttgctgcttt   3480 
gaaaaggcta gaagagattg aacggatttt aaatggagaa taacactaat tctgtatcat   3540 
gtaacaatgt agccaagacc ttcagtctct atcatgtgtt tgcttgtact ggaaactgaa   3600 
aaatgttgag actatatact ggtttttcaa aaactgcata agattctcta tataggatca   3660 
aaatgagatt tttattgaag acctatctgt cccaggatat atgttttata agagaggaca   3720 
caaattttaa tttggaagaa tattggagaa atcacaaatt ccaagtcaca acttgaaacr   3780 
tttattatag aaagagaaag atgtgggttt attatagaaa gaaaagggtg gggaagtact   3840 
gatatgtctt tctactaatc tgaattgaaa taatatgggg catcaaagat gaacccttgg   3900 
agataaatcc agaatgtact ggggtttgtg aattcccatt tattaactgt ttttcatttt   3960 
tcattacctc tttggattca ggaatggact gatactcatt gaagacattc agtaactctt   4020 
ctcataaacc aagggacatt atactgcata gtcatactgt gtttttttaa tgtgttcttt   4080 
gattggaatt tagaaggaat ggtagaaaaa acattttaaa gtaaatcata catcatgtag   4140 
atgacaagtt agcttaggaa tgccttttgt ctttcatgct aatatgtaag cattaagcag   4200 
gtaaagtgtt atgcatatac actagtggtg ctcgctgata ctgtattctc tcacactgag   4260 
gactcccaca taagctacat aaccatgact actcattggc acttgttccc caaagtcttc   4320 
tgcttcttgg cagaaaagtc ccagtcattc ttctttaagc tttagagtaa ttgtagtaat   4380 
ctctttcatc tttaatctct ctggtctgag cttaaaatca gtttcctgtt tycaaactca   4440 
taccttaaca attcttagat acctaaacca ctacagtcag ttttgtttaa ctgaaggcaa   4500 
aacaatgtga catttatttt taaatactag attcctctta tcgtatatat tttattaagt   4560 
atttatttta actactgatc tttcataaaa attttaaact tttagtttaa attgctagtt   4620 
cccttgagtt aactaatctc tatgtcttag aaaccatcct tttctaatgt tttctaagaa   4680 
atcttttata aataggtcat aagaaacatg ttctgcatta aagacccatt ccttttagct   4740 
tcccagagga cctgacatag ttgttttcct tttttttttt cctttttttt ttttttttta   4800 
agataattta actccagcac taaagccaat gggtgttagt tcttgaccca agagatttgt   4860 
taaccatcaa agcagtatct tgtttcagtt cttagrgkgt wtytttgtga cttcagatct   4920 
agagtggaga atacctcatg tactataact tgaagttatt gttctctctg tttatctcta   4980 
gaaaagtttt tgctgataat cactacaatt taaattctaa gtggaggaca gtgcagtaag   5040 
taagtcaaag gaaacctttt atgatagcac acctaataaa agtttgaaga ctattttagt   5100 
aaatttatat agctagtcaa gtgatgagga taaatattaa tatccaataa tttttataca   5160 
agaaatcttt tattagcact cataattatg cctgtcacaa agaaagtact catacttgaa   5220 
ttttaattta tttaaatcaa attcatcttg aatatctatt attaattatt accagtcagt   5280 
gatacccaac ttcatttcgt agtagaatca tatgggagct ttcctgaaat tgagtcatgc   5340 
ttcagtcttt ccaaaacctc ttccagtgag tctcactgta gttagagttc agggcaactg   5400 
ctctaaatta gttcagtaaa ggtccttttc tctcctctgt taaatttgta aattagtaat   5460 
acaacccaat taagttttga tggcttaaat cccactaagg aatatatcct attgaaaata   5520 
taaatagtaa attctatcaa ccttgcttat ggtcaaatta atatttctta agtgcatgaa   5580 
attgtattgg aacgattcag atgagaagct atagtaaata tctccacacc cccagctgcc   5640 
tcagctcttg ttttgaagaa gtgagaacag aaacacttta agcccaggtt actatcttac   5700 
gatttaacac tttggatata tgaattttaa aaaaaaaaag acatatcaca ggattgtgtg   5760 
cagataaaaa gatacaggtt taattttcaa catttaaaaa atctacttgt catgacttct   5820 
agcaaagctt tgacaatctt caaggagcca tgttacattt ccccttcact actcctcaga   5880 
aagtggagtt aaattctaaa ttgctactac agtttttgtt tccctattaa catttgaaat   5940 
tgggaatttt caaattttcc tagtgagtag tcttactcac caaccctcct cttgaggcta   6000 
ggccttgtag tgttgcccat gcaggtcttg aactcaaagg ctcaagtgat cctgtcgcag   6060 
ctccctgtgt gcctgggagt accggcatgt gcatcctcgc ccagtcccag ggtgtgattt   6120 
tccgacacca gtgacgtcaa gaataaaata actagatata tcattttgtt taaccttttg   6180 
tgtatactct tatgtatttg atgtgtgaat tacacagttc taataaaaca tgcctttctt   6240 
taaaaaaaaa aaaaaaactt catgttatag aatgcttcaa agatgcttta atgaaaacta   6300 
ttaagaatat atagatttgt atgtcgattt atacttcaaa aatccatata tttgtcatat   6360 
ttattttttt atttgcatgg ccaaatgata tttaaaatga gtccgtcccc cccccccaaa   6420 
tatctggtaa ctgttaaaac tcttgtcacc tatccatatt cagggttcct taaaaagtag   6480 
tttaaaattg tatgcatttt tatattacta tgctgtttgt gtgtatcaca tttctaaata   6540 
ttcattatta aattgttact ttttaaaact ttc                                6573 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>6 </s210>
<s211>920 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 6 
Met Met Glu Gly Lys Met Ala Asp Ile Asn Phe Lys Glu Val Thr Leu 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Ile Val Gly Val Val Ala Ala Cys Tyr Trp Asn Ser Leu Phe Cys Gly 
            20                  25                  30 
Phe Val Phe Asp Asp Val Ser Ala Ile Leu Asp Thr Lys Asp Leu His 
        35                  40                  45 
Pro Ser Thr Pro Leu Lys Thr Leu Phe Gln Asn Asp Phe Trp Gly Thr 
    50                  55                  60 
Pro Met Ser Glu Glu Arg Ser His Lys Ser Tyr Arg Pro Leu Thr Val 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Leu Thr Phe Arg Leu Asn Tyr Leu Leu Ser Glu Leu Lys Pro Met Ser 
                85                  90                  95 
Tyr His Leu Leu Asn Thr Val Phe His Ala Val Val Ser Val Ile Phe 
            100                 105                 110 
Leu Lys Val Cys Arg Leu Phe Leu Asp Lys Arg Gly Ser Val Ile Ala 
        115                 120                 125 
Ala Leu Leu Phe Ala Val His Pro Ile His Thr Glu Ala Val Thr Gly 
    130                 135                 140 
Val Val Gly Arg Ala Glu Leu Leu Ser Ser Val Phe Phe Leu Ala Ala 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Phe Leu Ser Tyr Thr Lys Ser Lys Gly Pro Asp Asn Ser Ile Val Trp 
                165                 170                 175 
Thr Pro Ile Ala Leu Thr Val Leu Leu Val Ala Val Ala Thr Leu Cys 
            180                 185                 190 
Lys Glu Gln Gly Ile Thr Val Val Gly Ile Cys Cys Val Tyr Glu Val 
        195                 200                 205 
Phe Val Ala Gln Gly Tyr Thr Leu Pro Leu Leu Cys Ala Val Ala Gly 
    210                 215                 220 
Gln Phe Leu Arg Gly Lys Gly Ser Ile Pro Phe Ser Met Leu Gln Thr 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Leu Ile Lys Leu Ile Val Leu Met Phe Ser Thr Leu Leu Leu Val Val 
                245                 250                 255 
Ile Arg Val Gln Val Ile Gln Ser Gln Leu Pro Val Phe Thr Arg Phe 
            260                 265                 270 
Asp Asn Pro Ala Ala Val Ser Pro Thr Pro Thr Arg Gln Leu Thr Phe 
        275                 280                 285 
Asn Tyr Leu Leu Pro Val Asn Ala Trp Leu Leu Leu Asn Pro Ser Glu 
    290                 295                 300 
Leu Cys Cys Asp Trp Thr Met Gly Thr Ile Pro Leu Ile Glu Ser Phe 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Leu Asp Val Arg Asn Leu Ala Thr Phe Ala Phe Phe Cys Phe Leu Gly 
                325                 330                 335 
Ala Leu Gly Ile Phe Ser Leu Arg Tyr Pro Gly Asp Ser Ser Lys Thr 
            340                 345                 350 
Val Leu Met Ala Leu Ser Leu Met Ala Leu Pro Phe Ile Pro Ala Ser 
        355                 360                 365 
Asn Leu Phe Phe Pro Val Gly Phe Val Val Ala Glu Arg Val Leu Tyr 
    370                 375                 380 
Val Pro Ser Met Gly Phe Cys Ile Leu Val Ala His Gly Trp Gln Lys 
385                 390                 395                 400 
Ile Ser Asn Lys Ser Val Leu Lys Lys Leu Ser Trp Val Cys Leu Ser 
                405                 410                 415 
Met Val Ile Leu Thr His Ala Leu Lys Thr Leu His Arg Asn Trp Asp 
            420                 425                 430 
Trp Glu Ser Glu Tyr Thr Leu Phe Met Ser Ala Leu Lys Val Asn Lys 
        435                 440                 445 
Asn Asn Ala Lys Leu Trp Asn Asn Val Gly His Ala Leu Glu Asn Glu 
    450                 455                 460 
Lys Asn Phe Glu Lys Ala Leu Lys Tyr Phe Leu Gln Ala Thr His Val 
465                 470                 475                 480 
Gln Pro Asp Asp Ile Gly Ala His Met Asn Val Gly Arg Thr Tyr Lys 
                485                 490                 495 
Asn Leu Asn Arg Thr Lys Glu Ala Glu Glu Ser Tyr Met Leu Ala Lys 
            500                 505                 510 
Ser Leu Met Pro Gln Ile Ile Pro Gly Lys Lys Tyr Ala Ala Arg Ile 
        515                 520                 525 
Ala Pro Asn His Leu Asn Val Tyr Ile Asn Leu Ala Asn Leu Ile Arg 
    530                 535                 540 
Ala Asn Glu Ser Arg Leu Glu Glu Ala Asp Gln Leu Tyr Arg Gln Ala 
545                 550                 555                 560 
Ile Ser Met Arg Pro Asp Phe Lys Gln Ala Tyr Ile Ser Arg Gly Glu 
                565                 570                 575 
Leu Leu Leu Lys Met Asn Lys Pro Leu Lys Ala Lys Glu Ala Tyr Leu 
            580                 585                 590 
Lys Ala Leu Glu Leu Asp Arg Asn Asn Ala Asp Leu Trp Tyr Asn Leu 
        595                 600                 605 
Ala Ile Val Tyr Ile Glu Leu Lys Glu Pro Asp Glu Ala Leu Lys Asn 
    610                 615                 620 
Phe Asn Arg Ala Leu Glu Leu Asn Ser Arg His Lys Leu Ala Leu Phe 
625                 630                 635                 640 
Asn Ser Ala Ile Leu Met Gln Glu Ser Gly Glu Val Lys Leu Arg Pro 
                645                 650                 655 
Glu Ala Arg Lys Arg Leu Leu Asn Tyr Ile Asn Glu Glu Pro Gln Asp 
            660                 665                 670 
Ala Asn Gly Tyr Phe Asn Leu Gly Met Leu Ala Met Asp Asp Lys Lys 
        675                 680                 685 
Asp Ser Glu Ala Glu Thr Trp Met Lys Arg Ala Ile Lys Leu Gln Pro 
    690                 695                 700 
Asp Phe Arg Ser Ala Leu Phe Asn Leu Ala Leu Leu Tyr Ser Gln Thr 
705                 710                 715                 720 
Ala Lys Glu Leu Lys Ala Leu Pro Ile Leu Glu Glu Leu Leu Arg Tyr 
                725                 730                 735 
Tyr Pro Asp His Thr Lys Gly Leu Ile Leu Lys Gly Asp Ile Leu Met 
            740                 745                 750 
Asn Gln Lys Lys Asp Ile Ala Gly Ala Lys Lys Cys Phe Glu Lys Ile 
        755                 760                 765 
Leu Glu Met Asp Pro Ser Asn Val Gln Gly Lys His Asn Leu Cys Val 
    770                 775                 780 
Val Tyr Phe Glu Glu Lys Asp Leu Leu Lys Ala Glu Arg Cys Leu Val 
785                 790                 795                 800 
Glu Thr Leu Ala Leu Ala Pro His Glu Glu Tyr Ile Gln Arg His Leu 
                805                 810                 815 
Ser Ile Val Arg Asp Lys Ile Ala Ser Ser Gly Ile Val Asp Gln Pro 
            820                 825                 830 
Leu Ser Pro Val Asp Lys Thr Ser Gly Thr Glu Glu Lys Asp Glu Val 
        835                 840                 845 
Pro Ser Glu Asp Val Lys Glu Ile Ile Ser Glu Ser Arg Pro Ala Gln 
    850                 855                 860 
Ile Ile Lys Thr Asn Asp Asn Arg Lys Ser Gln Ser Asn Lys Gln Ser 
865                 870                 875                 880 
Thr Gly Asn Ala Asp Gln Asp Ala Pro His Lys Thr Thr Lys Asp Ile 
                885                 890                 895 
Lys Glu Ile Glu Lys Lys Arg Val Ala Ala Leu Lys Arg Leu Glu Glu 
            900                 905                 910 
Ile Glu Arg Ile Leu Asn Gly Glu 
        915                 920 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>7 </s210>
<s211>3832 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 7 
gaagatccat ttactgatga gcataaggag agacaagaag tggaaatgtt ggctaagaag     60 
tttgaaatga aatacggtgg gaaagcccgt aaacaccgga aggatcggct gcaggattta    120 
attgatatag gctttggcta cgatgagaca gacccgttta ttgataactc agaggcttat    180 
gacgaattag tccctgcttc tctaacaaca aaatatggag gcttctatat caacactggc    240 
actctgcagt ttcgccaagc ttcagatact gaagaagatg attttacaga taaccagaag    300 
cacaagccac ccaaggtttc caaaataaaa gatgatgata ttgaggcaaa gaagcggaag    360 
cggaaagagg aaggggaaaa agaaaagaag ccaaggaaaa aagtacccaa acaactggga    420 
gttgtggctc tcaattcaca caagtctgaa aaaaagaaaa aacgatataa agattccctt    480 
tctttggctg ccatgatacg aaaattccaa aaagagaagg atgccttgaa gaaggagtct    540 
acccctaaag tcccagtgat cccatcaact tcctctctgc ctaagccccc ttgtgctgcc    600 
acaaccctgg gggatgatat cccggactta agtctgaaca gtgctgatcc tgacctccct    660 
atctttgtta gcacaaatga gcatgaacta tttcaggaag ctgaaaatgc cctagagatg    720 
ctggatgatt ttgactttga cagattactg gatgctactt ctgatggaag tcccctctct    780 
gagtcagggg gagaaaatgg aaacaccacc cagcccacct tcgcctctca ggttgtgccc    840 
aaggtggttc ctacacttcc agatggtcta cctgtgcttc tggagaaacg cattgaggac    900 
cttcgtgtag taagtgctgc caaacttttt gatgaagaag gaaggaaaaa attctttaca    960 
caagatatga ataatattct tctagacatc gagttacagc tacaagaact aggtcctgtc   1020 
atccgtagtg gtgtctactc ccatcttgaa gcatttgtgc catgcaataa ggaaacactg   1080 
gtaaaacgtc taaagaagtt acatcttaac gtccaggatg atcgtttaag agaacctctg   1140 
cagaaactga agctggctgt tagcaatgtc atgcctgaac agctgtttaa ataccaggag   1200 
gactgccagg ctcgcagtca agccaaatgt gccaagttgc aagcagatga agaacgagaa   1260 
aaaaatggat ccgatgatga tgatgatgag aaaccaggga agcgagtcat aggcccacga   1320 
aagaagttcc actgggatga caccatcaga actttgttat gtaaccttgt tgaaatcaaa   1380 
ttgggatgct atgaactaga gccaaataaa agccagtctg ctgaggatta tcttaaatcc   1440 
ttcatggaga cagaagtgaa gccactgtgg cctaagggct ggatgcaggc aagaatgctt   1500 
tttaaggaaa gccggagtgt acataatcat cttacttctg ctccggcaaa gaaaaaggtg   1560 
attcctgcat caaagcccaa agtcaaggaa tgtagcccca aaaaagaccc caaagcgcct   1620 
gcatccgtgg tggcttcagg tggttgtcct tgcacgagtt ccagcacatc gatcgttgcc   1680 
tcagccagct ctagctctac accagcccaa gaaaccatct gcctggatga ctccctagat   1740 
gaagaccttt ctctcccctc agcctctctg gatcttgtat ctgaagcttt agctgtcatc   1800 
aacaatggga acaagggccc ctcagtcagt tcaaggctaa atgtgccaac cacaaaacct   1860 
cgtccaggcc tgagagaaga aaagctagca agtatcatga gtaagttacc actggctact   1920 
cccaaaaaac tagattctcc tcagactgct cactcatcaa gtctcattgc tggtcacacg   1980 
gggccagtac caaagaaacc ccaggactta gctcacactg gtatttcttc aggccttatt   2040 
gctggttctt caattcagaa ccctaaagtt tccttagaac ctttgccagc caggctgctc   2100 
cagcaaggac tgcaaaggtc aagccagata catgcttcct cttcacagac tcatgtctcc   2160 
tcctcccaag cccaagctgc tgcctcctct catgctctgg gaacatcaga ggctcaagat   2220 
gcttcttcgt taacacaagt aacaaaggtg caccagcact cagctgtcca gcagaactac   2280 
gtgtctcctt tacaagctac cattagtaaa tcacagacca acccagtggt gaaattaagt   2340 
aataaccccc aactttcctg ttcgtcccag ttactcaaga cttcagagaa gccactgatg   2400 
tatcgcctcc ctttgtctac cccatcacct ggaaatggtt ctcaggggtc tcaccccctg   2460 
gtttctagga cagcaccgag taccactacc tccagtaact atttagccaa ggctatggtg   2520 
tcacaaatct ccacgcaggg tttcaaatct cccttctcaa tggccgcatc tcccaaactt   2580 
gccgcatctc ccaaacctgc cacatctcct aaacctttga cctcacctaa gccttctgtt   2640 
tcacccaagc cctctctatc agctaagcct tcagtatcta ctaaactgat ttctaaatcc   2700 
aacccaactc ccaagcctgc tgtatgcccg agttcttcta gtccaaacac actagtagcc   2760 
cagagtagcc actccacaag taacaaccct gcccataaac agcccagtgg aatgaacatc   2820 
agcagacagt ctcccactct aaatttgttg ccctcaaatc gcacttctgg ccttccgact   2880 
acaaaaactc ttcaggcccc ttctaaacta acaaactcat cgtccgctgg aactgttggg   2940 
aagaacagct tgagtggaat cccagtgaat gtacctgcca gcagaggtag caaccttaac   3000 
tcaagtggag ctaataggac tagtctatct gggggaacag gaagtggaac acagggtgct   3060 
actaaaccgt tgtctactcc acatagacca acctctgcct cagggtcttc agtggtaaca   3120 
gccagtgtgc agtctacagc aggagcatca ttattggcta atgcctcacc tctgactctc   3180 
atgacatcac ctttgtctgt aacaaatcaa actgtgactc cctttgggat gctgggtggc   3240 
cttgttccag tgaccatgcc cttccagttt cccttggagc ttcttggctt tggaacggac   3300 
acagctggag tgacagccac ctcgggatct acctcagcgg ctctccatca tggcctaact   3360 
cagaatttac taaagagttt acagccagga actcagcacg cagcaaccct tccccactca   3420 
cctctgccta cacacttaca gcaagcattt aatgatggag gccaaagtaa aggggacact   3480 
aaattaccac ggaaacctca gtgactttgc agcaagtgag agaggaacca cgtggctggc   3540 
tagctgggag gtggccgacc tgatgggaag tcttggtggt cacagggctg ctgttcctgt   3600 
cgatgtttac attcttgtcc caagcactgt ggagagaagg aaaagaaaga gtatgttact   3660 
tgagcaaagc cagtgcagga ggaagaaatg cttctgtgca aagttagtga cctttggtct   3720 
tttaaaatca aagttcccat gttaacctac ttaaaacaga ctcagctgtc aaacccacag   3780 
aagtataaat ttgactttat agaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aa           3832 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>8 </s210>
<s211>1167 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 8 
Glu Asp Pro Phe Thr Asp Glu His Lys Glu Arg Gln Glu Val Glu Met 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Leu Ala Lys Lys Phe Glu Met Lys Tyr Gly Gly Lys Ala Arg Lys His 
            20                  25                  30 
Arg Lys Asp Arg Leu Gln Asp Leu Ile Asp Ile Gly Phe Gly Tyr Asp 
        35                  40                  45 
Glu Thr Asp Pro Phe Ile Asp Asn Ser Glu Ala Tyr Asp Glu Leu Val 
    50                  55                  60 
Pro Ala Ser Leu Thr Thr Lys Tyr Gly Gly Phe Tyr Ile Asn Thr Gly 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Thr Leu Gln Phe Arg Gln Ala Ser Asp Thr Glu Glu Asp Asp Phe Thr 
                85                  90                  95 
Asp Asn Gln Lys His Lys Pro Pro Lys Val Ser Lys Ile Lys Asp Asp 
            100                 105                 110 
Asp Ile Glu Ala Lys Lys Arg Lys Arg Lys Glu Glu Gly Glu Lys Glu 
        115                 120                 125 
Lys Lys Pro Arg Lys Lys Val Pro Lys Gln Leu Gly Val Val Ala Leu 
    130                 135                 140 
Asn Ser His Lys Ser Glu Lys Lys Lys Lys Arg Tyr Lys Asp Ser Leu 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Ser Leu Ala Ala Met Ile Arg Lys Phe Gln Lys Glu Lys Asp Ala Leu 
                165                 170                 175 
Lys Lys Glu Ser Thr Pro Lys Val Pro Val Ile Pro Ser Thr Ser Ser 
            180                 185                 190 
Leu Pro Lys Pro Pro Cys Ala Ala Thr Thr Leu Gly Asp Asp Ile Pro 
        195                 200                 205 
Asp Leu Ser Leu Asn Ser Ala Asp Pro Asp Leu Pro Ile Phe Val Ser 
    210                 215                 220 
Thr Asn Glu His Glu Leu Phe Gln Glu Ala Glu Asn Ala Leu Glu Met 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Leu Asp Asp Phe Asp Phe Asp Arg Leu Leu Asp Ala Thr Ser Asp Gly 
                245                 250                 255 
Ser Pro Leu Ser Glu Ser Gly Gly Glu Asn Gly Asn Thr Thr Gln Pro 
            260                 265                 270 
Thr Phe Ala Ser Gln Val Val Pro Lys Val Val Pro Thr Leu Pro Asp 
        275                 280                 285 
Gly Leu Pro Val Leu Leu Glu Lys Arg Ile Glu Asp Leu Arg Val Val 
    290                 295                 300 
Ser Ala Ala Lys Leu Phe Asp Glu Glu Gly Arg Lys Lys Phe Phe Thr 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Gln Asp Met Asn Asn Ile Leu Leu Asp Ile Glu Leu Gln Leu Gln Glu 
                325                 330                 335 
Leu Gly Pro Val Ile Arg Ser Gly Val Tyr Ser His Leu Glu Ala Phe 
            340                 345                 350 
Val Pro Cys Asn Lys Glu Thr Leu Val Lys Arg Leu Lys Lys Leu His 
        355                 360                 365 
Leu Asn Val Gln Asp Asp Arg Leu Arg Glu Pro Leu Gln Lys Leu Lys 
    370                 375                 380 
Leu Ala Val Ser Asn Val Met Pro Glu Gln Leu Phe Lys Tyr Gln Glu 
385                 390                 395                 400 
Asp Cys Gln Ala Arg Ser Gln Ala Lys Cys Ala Lys Leu Gln Ala Asp 
                405                 410                 415 
Glu Glu Arg Glu Lys Asn Gly Ser Asp Asp Asp Asp Asp Glu Lys Pro 
            420                 425                 430 
Gly Lys Arg Val Ile Gly Pro Arg Lys Lys Phe His Trp Asp Asp Thr 
        435                 440                 445 
Ile Arg Thr Leu Leu Cys Asn Leu Val Glu Ile Lys Leu Gly Cys Tyr 
    450                 455                 460 
Glu Leu Glu Pro Asn Lys Ser Gln Ser Ala Glu Asp Tyr Leu Lys Ser 
465                 470                 475                 480 
Phe Met Glu Thr Glu Val Lys Pro Leu Trp Pro Lys Gly Trp Met Gln 
                485                 490                 495 
Ala Arg Met Leu Phe Lys Glu Ser Arg Ser Val His Asn His Leu Thr 
            500                 505                 510 
Ser Ala Pro Ala Lys Lys Lys Val Ile Pro Ala Ser Lys Pro Lys Val 
        515                 520                 525 
Lys Glu Cys Ser Pro Lys Lys Asp Pro Lys Ala Pro Ala Ser Val Val 
    530                 535                 540 
Ala Ser Gly Gly Cys Pro Cys Thr Ser Ser Ser Thr Ser Ile Val Ala 
545                 550                 555                 560 
Ser Ala Ser Ser Ser Ser Thr Pro Ala Gln Glu Thr Ile Cys Leu Asp 
                565                 570                 575 
Asp Ser Leu Asp Glu Asp Leu Ser Leu Pro Ser Ala Ser Leu Asp Leu 
            580                 585                 590 
Val Ser Glu Ala Leu Ala Val Ile Asn Asn Gly Asn Lys Gly Pro Ser 
        595                 600                 605 
Val Ser Ser Arg Leu Asn Val Pro Thr Thr Lys Pro Arg Pro Gly Leu 
    610                 615                 620 
Arg Glu Glu Lys Leu Ala Ser Ile Met Ser Lys Leu Pro Leu Ala Thr 
625                 630                 635                 640 
Pro Lys Lys Leu Asp Ser Pro Gln Thr Ala His Ser Ser Ser Leu Ile 
                645                 650                 655 
Ala Gly His Thr Gly Pro Val Pro Lys Lys Pro Gln Asp Leu Ala His 
            660                 665                 670 
Thr Gly Ile Ser Ser Gly Leu Ile Ala Gly Ser Ser Ile Gln Asn Pro 
        675                 680                 685 
Lys Val Ser Leu Glu Pro Leu Pro Ala Arg Leu Leu Gln Gln Gly Leu 
    690                 695                 700 
Gln Arg Ser Ser Gln Ile His Ala Ser Ser Ser Gln Thr His Val Ser 
705                 710                 715                 720 
Ser Ser Gln Ala Gln Ala Ala Ala Ser Ser His Ala Leu Gly Thr Ser 
                725                 730                 735 
Glu Ala Gln Asp Ala Ser Ser Leu Thr Gln Val Thr Lys Val His Gln 
            740                 745                 750 
His Ser Ala Val Gln Gln Asn Tyr Val Ser Pro Leu Gln Ala Thr Ile 
        755                 760                 765 
Ser Lys Ser Gln Thr Asn Pro Val Val Lys Leu Ser Asn Asn Pro Gln 
    770                 775                 780 
Leu Ser Cys Ser Ser Gln Leu Leu Lys Thr Ser Glu Lys Pro Leu Met 
785                 790                 795                 800 
Tyr Arg Leu Pro Leu Ser Thr Pro Ser Pro Gly Asn Gly Ser Gln Gly 
                805                 810                 815 
Ser His Pro Leu Val Ser Arg Thr Ala Pro Ser Thr Thr Thr Ser Ser 
            820                 825                 830 
Asn Tyr Leu Ala Lys Ala Met Val Ser Gln Ile Ser Thr Gln Gly Phe 
        835                 840                 845 
Lys Ser Pro Phe Ser Met Ala Ala Ser Pro Lys Leu Ala Ala Ser Pro 
    850                 855                 860 
Lys Pro Ala Thr Ser Pro Lys Pro Leu Thr Ser Pro Lys Pro Ser Val 
865                 870                 875                 880 
Ser Pro Lys Pro Ser Leu Ser Ala Lys Pro Ser Val Ser Thr Lys Leu 
                885                 890                 895 
Ile Ser Lys Ser Asn Pro Thr Pro Lys Pro Ala Val Cys Pro Ser Ser 
            900                 905                 910 
Ser Ser Pro Asn Thr Leu Val Ala Gln Ser Ser His Ser Thr Ser Asn 
        915                 920                 925 
Asn Pro Ala His Lys Gln Pro Ser Gly Met Asn Ile Ser Arg Gln Ser 
    930                 935                 940 
Pro Thr Leu Asn Leu Leu Pro Ser Asn Arg Thr Ser Gly Leu Pro Thr 
945                 950                 955                 960 
Thr Lys Thr Leu Gln Ala Pro Ser Lys Leu Thr Asn Ser Ser Ser Ala 
                965                 970                 975 
Gly Thr Val Gly Lys Asn Ser Leu Ser Gly Ile Pro Val Asn Val Pro 
            980                 985                 990 
Ala Ser Arg Gly Ser Asn Leu Asn Ser Ser Gly Ala Asn Arg Thr Ser 
        995                 1000                1005 
Leu Ser Gly Gly Thr Gly Ser Gly Thr Gln Gly Ala Thr Lys Pro Leu 
    1010                1015                1020 
Ser Thr Pro His Arg Pro Thr Ser Ala Ser Gly Ser Ser Val Val Thr 
1025                1030                1035                1040 
Ala Ser Val Gln Ser Thr Ala Gly Ala Ser Leu Leu Ala Asn Ala Ser 
                1045                1050                1055 
Pro Leu Thr Leu Met Thr Ser Pro Leu Ser Val Thr Asn Gln Thr Val 
            1060                1065                1070 
Thr Pro Phe Gly Met Leu Gly Gly Leu Val Pro Val Thr Met Pro Phe 
        1075                1080                1085 
Gln Phe Pro Leu Glu Leu Leu Gly Phe Gly Thr Asp Thr Ala Gly Val 
    1090                1095                1100 
Thr Ala Thr Ser Gly Ser Thr Ser Ala Ala Leu His His Gly Leu Thr 
1105                1110                1115                1120 
Gln Asn Leu Leu Lys Ser Leu Gln Pro Gly Thr Gln His Ala Ala Thr 
                1125                1130                1135 
Leu Pro His Ser Pro Leu Pro Thr His Leu Gln Gln Ala Phe Asn Asp 
            1140                1145                1150 
Gly Gly Gln Ser Lys Gly Asp Thr Lys Leu Pro Arg Lys Pro Gln 
        1155                1160                1165 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>9 </s210>
<s211>3089 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 9 
gcagaattga gctgcatcgc cttccggagc ctccagcgcc atgtacgacc cagagcgccg     60 
ctggagcctg tcgttcgcag gctgcggctt cctaggcttc taccacatcg gggctacgct    120 
atgtctgagc gagcgcgctc cgcacatcct ccgcgaagcg cgcactttct tcggctgctc    180 
ggccggtgca ctgcacgcgg tcaccttcgt gtgcagtctc cctctcgatc acatcatgga    240 
gatcctcatg gacctcgtgc ggaaagccag gagccgcaac atcggcaccc tccacccgtt    300 
cttcaacatt aacaagtgcg tcagagacgg ccttcaggag accctcccag acaacgtcca    360 
ccagatcatt tctggcaagg tttacatctc actcaccaga gtgtccgatg gggagaacgt    420 
gctggtgtct gagttccatt ccaaagacga agtggtggat gccctggtgt gctcctgctt    480 
cattcctctc ttctctggcc taatccctcc ttccttccga ggtgagcggt acgtggatgg    540 
aggagtgagt gacaacgtcc ctgtgctgga cgccaaaacc accatcacgg tgtccccttt    600 
ctatggtgag catgacatct gtcccaaagt gaagtccacc aacttcctcc aggtgaatat    660 
caccaacctc agtcttcgtc tctgcactgg gaaccttcat cttctgacca gagcactctt    720 
cccatctgat gtgaaggtga tgggagagct gtgctttcaa gggtacctgg acgccttccg    780 
gttcctggaa gagaacggca tctgtaatgg gccacagcgc agcctgagtc tgtccttgga    840 
gaaggaaatg gcgccagaaa ccatgatacc ctgcttggaa aatggccacc ttgtagcagg    900 
gaacaaggtg ccagtaagct gtgtatgcct tacagctgtg ccgtcggatg agagcatctg    960 
ggagatgctg tcccccaagc tcagcacagc tctgactgaa gcgattaaag acaggggggg   1020 
ctacctgaac aaagtctgca acctcctgcc cattaggatc ctgtcctaca tcttgctgcc   1080 
ctgcactctg cccgtggagt cggccatcgc tgcagtccac aggctggtga tgtggctccc   1140 
tgatatccat gaagatatcc agtggctaca gtgggcaaca tcccaggtgt gtgcccgaat   1200 
gaccatgtgc ctgctcccct ctaccagatc cagagcatcc aaggataacc atcaaacact   1260 
caagcatgga tatcacccat ctctccacaa accccaaggc agctctgccg gtttgtaaat   1320 
tgctggtctc cgtgcttccg atgaacttgg gcattctccc tgtggatggt tccaggagag   1380 
gccatagctg aaggcactct gccttccacc ccaagtccag tttgaccttt atctggagca   1440 
acagtgtcta gatgataggt gggtgggggg tgctgtctct ctgtttccct ctgggaaggg   1500 
ttctgttaac ttttggaggc agctaggaaa tttctctcca ggagctgagc ctgtgcagct   1560 
gcccccttgg tgctgtgtgg taacctcatt gcctgtgacc ctaggatcat aggatctggg   1620 
ctaaataggt agttcataga aaccaaagac aataatttgg tgtttagaaa actacttttg   1680 
gtctgggtga agtctggtgc ttgagagtta gtgcagagag aacagtcaaa ccgtctctca   1740 
gcctgtggat ctatggggat tccaagggct tcagtgtttg gaaacggcaa tccaaacggg   1800 
caatcttgtg caatcttgga aggaaaactg ttcaggaagt gtgatgggat gagctgtggc   1860 
tgtctctgaa aagggcctac catataactt attactttca aggatacctt tggctcttac   1920 
taaaatagtt tataaagcat tttatagaaa cacaccaggg aatgcgtggt gaactacatg   1980 
tatgatcagt gaactgtgac tagaattaac cttaaaatct cttgtatgtg gggccagagc   2040 
aacacaggtg ggaaacgcag cggacctctg cctcctcggc ctcaacatga acttggcttg   2100 
ctttctccac cgtctccaaa tctttgtata gtcatcgacc attaccacct ctcctttccc   2160 
atctactaca gcagccttaa tggggataag tacccccttt tctcaggtgt ccgaataagc   2220 
tgtgggtgtg gcctgtgttt cctgtaattc agaggttaga ttggaacata agcaagcaga   2280 
caaacaagca gacaaacaaa caaggttcta ctcatattcc taagcagtga cagtgaaggc   2340 
atgtgtctcc catgcctgag tctcctaggg tcctagtgag ctctgggttc atgcaagcac   2400 
ttccggagga attgcaccct ccatggaaca cataatctcc actgggttga tcctgattgg   2460 
ataagaaagg atctcgggga gagaatgtgg ttccagaggc aaagtgtcta ggctacacag   2520 
aaaaggtaag actgtcccca agggaagaaa acaaactggg agctggggtc cagctcaatt   2580 
gttaagagtg cttctctagt atgcatgaag cccagagtcc aatctcagta ccagatacac   2640 
ggtacaggca gtgacatatg cctgtaatcc caaccctcaa gcagtagagg caagaggatc   2700 
agaagttcat ggtcatcctt gactacttat acttagggag ttggaggtca gccttggcta   2760 
aatgagaccc tgcctctaaa agaaaagcaa caaacaaaaa atagcagaaa cttctgcctt   2820 
gctttgaact ccccctttct ggaagtttcc caccagcaga gactattcct gttaccctat   2880 
cagacaaaac tcccactggt ttggagtccc tccatcctca ggaacaccgg gtatcaacag   2940 
tgaggagcag ggagcaatgt cttgactggt aagcccttag caaagctggt tcacttgttt   3000 
aaaagcaggt gtgaggggtt ggggatttag ctcagtggta gagcgcttgc ctaggaagcg   3060 
caaggccctg ggttcggtcc ccagctctg                                     3089 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>10 </s210>
<s211>425 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 10 
Met Tyr Asp Pro Glu Arg Arg Trp Ser Leu Ser Phe Ala Gly Cys Gly 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Phe Leu Gly Phe Tyr His Ile Gly Ala Thr Leu Cys Leu Ser Glu Arg 
            20                  25                  30 
Ala Pro His Ile Leu Arg Glu Ala Arg Thr Phe Phe Gly Cys Ser Ala 
        35                  40                  45 
Gly Ala Leu His Ala Val Thr Phe Val Cys Ser Leu Pro Leu Asp His 
    50                  55                  60 
Ile Met Glu Ile Leu Met Asp Leu Val Arg Lys Ala Arg Ser Arg Asn 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Ile Gly Thr Leu His Pro Phe Phe Asn Ile Asn Lys Cys Val Arg Asp 
                85                  90                  95 
Gly Leu Gln Glu Thr Leu Pro Asp Asn Val His Gln Ile Ile Ser Gly 
            100                 105                 110 
Lys Val Tyr Ile Ser Leu Thr Arg Val Ser Asp Gly Glu Asn Val Leu 
        115                 120                 125 
Val Ser Glu Phe His Ser Lys Asp Glu Val Val Asp Ala Leu Val Cys 
    130                 135                 140 
Ser Cys Phe Ile Pro Leu Phe Ser Gly Leu Ile Pro Pro Ser Phe Arg 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Gly Glu Arg Tyr Val Asp Gly Gly Val Ser Asp Asn Val Pro Val Leu 
                165                 170                 175 
Asp Ala Lys Thr Thr Ile Thr Val Ser Pro Phe Tyr Gly Glu His Asp 
            180                 185                 190 
Ile Cys Pro Lys Val Lys Ser Thr Asn Phe Leu Gln Val Asn Ile Thr 
        195                 200                 205 
Asn Leu Ser Leu Arg Leu Cys Thr Gly Asn Leu His Leu Leu Thr Arg 
    210                 215                 220 
Ala Leu Phe Pro Ser Asp Val Lys Val Met Gly Glu Leu Cys Phe Gln 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Gly Tyr Leu Asp Ala Phe Arg Phe Leu Glu Glu Asn Gly Ile Cys Asn 
                245                 250                 255 
Gly Pro Gln Arg Ser Leu Ser Leu Ser Leu Glu Lys Glu Met Ala Pro 
            260                 265                 270 
Glu Thr Met Ile Pro Cys Leu Glu Asn Gly His Leu Val Ala Gly Asn 
        275                 280                 285 
Lys Val Pro Val Ser Cys Val Cys Leu Thr Ala Val Pro Ser Asp Glu 
    290                 295                 300 
Ser Ile Trp Glu Met Leu Ser Pro Lys Leu Ser Thr Ala Leu Thr Glu 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Ala Ile Lys Asp Arg Gly Gly Tyr Leu Asn Lys Val Cys Asn Leu Leu 
                325                 330                 335 
Pro Ile Arg Ile Leu Ser Tyr Ile Leu Leu Pro Cys Thr Leu Pro Val 
            340                 345                 350 
Glu Ser Ala Ile Ala Ala Val His Arg Leu Val Met Trp Leu Pro Asp 
        355                 360                 365 
Ile His Glu Asp Ile Gln Trp Leu Gln Trp Ala Thr Ser Gln Val Cys 
    370                 375                 380 
Ala Arg Met Thr Met Cys Leu Leu Pro Ser Thr Arg Ser Arg Ala Ser 
385                 390                 395                 400 
Lys Asp Asn His Gln Thr Leu Lys His Gly Tyr His Pro Ser Leu His 
                405                 410                 415 
Lys Pro Gln Gly Ser Ser Ala Gly Leu 
            420                 425 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>11 </s210>
<s211>7428 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 11 
ctggaggact ttctgccacc tcatgggatg ctccagtttg ccgatggaca agtcattgca     60 
ccaatacaca taactataat tgatgatact gaatttgaac tctctgaaac attcagcatc    120 
tccttaatga gtgtgactgg tggcggccgc ctgggcgatg atgttttggt gactgttgtc    180 
ataccactga atgactctcc ctttggaata tttggatttg aagagaagac tgtaatggtt    240 
gatagatccc atttgtctga tgaccctgat tcatatgtga aactgacagt tgtccggtcc    300 
ccaggaggaa aaggagctgt ccgacttcac tggactattg aagagaaagc caaagatgac    360 
cttagtcctt tgaacgggac actgtatttt gatgagactg actcccagaa gtccattata    420 
ctgcacatac ttcaaggaca agtgtgctgg ggaagacagg cgcttcacca ttgagctgat    480 
ggatgctggt gaggtagaaa tatctccagg gaaaggtaga gcatcagtca tcattctaga    540 
agagaagagc ccatcagaag ttggaattgt tcatcatcca gacacgtcat tatcggggag    600 
ccctcagcaa catacagtgg cactgccacc atcagcctgg atcgtggccc aggggtttcc    660 
ggggaggtca cagtggactg gaggatattg cctccctcca ggggggagtt tgctgaaaca    720 
tcaggacaac tgaccatgct ggatggacag tctactgcta ctgtagtaat tcaggctttg    780 
gatgatggca tcccagagga gaagtgttcc tacgagtttc agctcactgg aatcagtgag    840 
ggtgcggtgc tgaatgaagc cagcgtcact gccagcatct ccatggtggc cagtgacgct    900 
ccctatggcc agttctcatt ttcacatgag cagcttcaag tttccgaagc agcacagaag    960 
gttaatgtca cagttgctcg ctctggtggt tcctttggac gtgtgcgtgt ctggtatgag   1020 
accggtagca ggacggctga ggcaggctgg gactttgttc ccacttcagg ggagctgatc   1080 
tttgaagccc gagagaagat gaaaagtctg cacattgaaa ttcttgatga caaccttcct   1140 
gaaggccctg aggaattcgt tcttgccatt acaagagtgg acctccaggg aagagggtat   1200 
gatttcacca tccaagagaa tggactccag atagatcagc ctcctgaaat tgggagcatc   1260 
tccgttgttc aaatcataat aatggaaaat gacaatgtag aaggcatcat tgaatttgac   1320 
ccaaagttca ccgacatctc agtggaggaa ggtgctggag tgatcccact ccctgtcatg   1380 
agacttcgag ggacttatgg ccgagtgtca gctgatttca gctcccggga ctcctccgct   1440 
gttccaggag gctatgtact gcatggtggc tcagtcacct ttcagcacgg gcagagccta   1500 
agctttataa atgtctccat cgttgatgac aacgacagtg aatcggagaa gcagcttgaa   1560 
attctgctca ttggagcgac gggtggagca atccttgggc gccacctagt gagcaaaatc   1620 
accattgcca aaagtggctc tccctttggc atcataaggt ttctcaacca aagcaaaatt   1680 
tccgttccta accccaattc cacaatggct ttacacttgg tgttagagcg gactggcgga   1740 
ctcttgggag agattcaggt gagctgggag atagtagggc ccagttctga ggaactgtta   1800 
ctgccacagc acggagactt tgcagaccca gtgagtggca cggtctcatt tggagatggg   1860 
gaaggtggtg tgagaaccat caccctcaca gtttgtcctc atgaagaaac tgaagcggaa   1920 
gagacttttg ttgttcagct taagcctttg aaagaagcca agttagatcc cagagctaaa   1980 
gctgttacgc tgaccataca gaagtttggg gatccaaatg gagtcatcca ttttgctcct   2040 
gagtctttat ctaagaaaat gttctctgag ccaccaccgt cagaaggacc catgcttata   2100 
tccttccttg tcacgagatc caaaggcacc tctggagaga tcacggtgca ctgggagcta   2160 
agcagtgagt ttgaccttac gggagacttc ctttccaccc aaggattttt caccattgct   2220 
gatggagaca gcgaagcaag ctttgatgtc catttgctgc cagatgatgt ccctgagata   2280 
gaggaagaat atgttgtcca gctagtttct gtagagggag gtgcagaact ggacctggag   2340 
aaatgcacct cgaggttctc tgtatctgcc aatgatgacc cgcatggcat atttgccctt   2400 
tattcagatc agcagtcagt actgattggg cagaacctca ttagatccat ccaaattaac   2460 
atcacccggc ttgctggagt gtttggtgct gtggctgtga cacttcaaat actgtctgac   2520 
aataaggaag acccagttgc tactgaaaat gaagagagac aaatggtgat caaggatggg   2580 
gccagatata aagtaggctt ggtgcccttg aaaaatcagg tcttcctatc actgggctcc   2640 
aatttcaccc tgcggctgct gtcagcaagg cttctgagtg gacccttcta tggaatgcca   2700 
acaattcacc aggaagcaaa tcaagctttt ctctctgttc ctgaggaagc tgccaattcc   2760 
caggttggat tcgaatccac tgctttccaa ctcattgaca tcacggccgg cacaagccaa   2820 
gtcacagtct ttaggagagg tacatatggc aggctgtctg tggcctggac cacaggatat   2880 
gctcctggct cagaaatccc tgagcctatt gccatcggca acatgacgcc aactctcggg   2940 
agcctctctt ttctgcatgg agaacagaag aaaggagtcc tcctatggac gtttcccagc   3000 
cctggccagc cagaggcctt tgtccttcat ctgtcaggcc tgaggagcag tgctgcaggt   3060 
ggagctcagc ttagattggc ttttactact gctgaaattg aacccctggg agtcttccag   3120 
ttttccccag gctcaagaaa tatcacagtg tcagaggatg cactgataat ccgaatatgt   3180 
gtgcaaagac tgtttgggtt tcagggtgac ctgattaaag tctcctacaa gacgactgca   3240 
ggaagcgcta agcctctgga ggacttcgaa cctattcaga agggggaaat tttttttcag   3300 
agattccaag ctgaggttga ttttgaaata accattatta acgatcagct tcctgagaga   3360 
gaagaaacat tttacattaa tcttacttca gtagaaacta ggggaccagg aaagggagat   3420 
gtgagttgga gacctcgcct aaatccagat ctcagtgttg caatggtcac catactggac   3480 
aatgatgacc cggctggagt agctgtctct gtccctgtga cagcagggac tgtggcagct   3540 
gacagcactc tccttgccat ggaagctgat tttaccacac accctaacaa aagcaagata   3600 
accaccattc catataccac ggaggtgttt gcccctgtta cagagacagt ggatgtgtct   3660 
gccatccctg agaaacttgt caccattcac agcgccatat ctgaggagcc tgacttggcc   3720 
ccaggaactg ctcaggctgc agtctttggg acactgagtc tcggaccccc cattgtctat   3780 
gtgtcagagg aaatgaagaa taacacaccc agtactgcag atattcaaat ccagaggata   3840 
ggtgggttcg caggcaatgt cagtgtaaca gtgaggactt ttgggggaag atgtgctcag   3900 
aaggaaccca gcgtctggcc ctttcaggat gtttatggaa ttggcaacct aacatgggca   3960 
gttgaagaag aagacttcga agaacaaatg ctaaccctga cgtttctcaa tggggaaaga   4020 
gaacatagaa ttgcagttcg aattctggat gatgatgagc ccgaggggca ggaattcttc   4080 
tatgtgtttc tcactgaccc tcaaggggga gcagagattg tgaggggaaa ggatggctct   4140 
gggttctcag cctttgctct aatccttatc acaggtagtg acctccacga cggcattgtc   4200 
ggcttcagtg aggagtccct gagaggcctg gagctgaggg aaggaactga taagagcagt   4260 
cagcgcctag aggtcacgag gcagcccaac agggcctttg aagaagtcca ggtcttttgg   4320 
cgagtcacac ttaaccaaac agccaccatt ctccaggaga aggggctaaa cctaacagat   4380 
gaactccggt ctgtggcagg ggtcaccact tgcacagtgg gtcaaacaca gtgttttatc   4440 
caccttgaac tcaatcccaa gaaggtgcat caagttgaaa tgcctttctt tgtggagctg   4500 
tatgacgtca ctgctggggc agctataaac aacagtgcca gatttgcccg gattaaagtt   4560 
tccaagagcg gggactctca gagccttgtt ttcttttctg tgggttctcg gctggcagtg   4620 
gctcacaaga aggctacttt gatcagtttg caggtggcca gagattctgg gacaggaatg   4680 
atgatgtctg ttaactttag tacccaggag ctgaggagcg ctgaaacagt tggccggatc   4740 
ctcttatctc cagctgtttc tgggaaggac tttgtgagaa cagaaggcac actggtcttc   4800 
gagcctggcc agaaaagtgc ggtgttggat gttgtcttaa caccagagac agggtcttta   4860 
aataaatttc ctaaacgctt ccagattgtg ctttttgacc caaaaggtgg tgccagaatt   4920 
gataaagtgt acgggactgc caacatcacc cttgtctctg atgtggattc tcaagctgtc   4980 
tgggggcttg aaggcctact acatcagcct ctacatgaag atgttctcaa cagagtgctc   5040 
catagcctca acctgagagt agccacagag agcacagatg agcagctcag tgctgtgatg   5100 
ttcataatgg aaaagataat gatggaagga aaaaaccaag ctttcagtat agaaagccgg   5160 
actcttttct atgaactcct ttgtgctctc attaacccaa agcgcaaaga cactagggga   5220 
ttcagccact ttgcggaggt ggctgagcat tttgcctttt ctcttctgac ggatgttacc   5280 
tgtggatcac ctggtgaaaa aagcaaaacc atccttgaca gttgcccgta tttgtcaatc   5340 
ctggcccttc actggagccc tcagcaaatc aatggacaca ggtttgaagg gaaggaaggt   5400 
gattacattc aaattccaga gaggtttctg gatgctcctg agccggaagt gtcggatggg   5460 
aaaaatgcat gcgcattagt ccagtttgtg gagtacagca gccagcagtg gtttgtagca   5520 
ggagacaacc ttcctgccct gagagacaag gtattgtctt tgaatgtgaa aggtcgggat   5580 
gcacagcccc tgcctaacaa caatgaggtt ctctacagga tttatgcagc cgagcctaga   5640 
attattcctc atacatctct gtgtctcctc tggaatcagg ctgcttccag ytggttgtcc   5700 
gacagccagc tttgcaaagt ggttgaagat gctgcggact atgtggratg cgcctgctca   5760 
cacatgtctg cgtatgctgt ctacgctcag actgacaact tggtgtcgta caacgaagct   5820 
tttttctctg ctggctttat atgcatctca ggtctctgtt tggctgttgt ttcccacgtg   5880 
ttctgtgcta gatactccat gtttgcagct aaacttctga ctcacatgat ggccgccagc   5940 
ttaggagccc aggtttcgtt cctggcatct gcatatgcaa gtccccagct cagcgaggag   6000 
agctgttccg ccgtggctgc tgtggcgcat tacctatacc tttgccagtt tagttggatg   6060 
cttattcagt ctgtgaactt ctggtatgtg ctggtggtga atgatgagca cacggagagg   6120 
cggtgcctgc tcttctgcct tctgagctgg gggcttccat ctttcgtggt gattctcctc   6180 
atagttattt tgagaggaat ctatcatcag agcatgccgc agatctatgg actcattcac   6240 
ggtgacctat gcttcattcc aaacatctat gctgctctgt tcacggctgc tcttgtgcct   6300 
ctaatgtgcc tcgtggtggt atttgtggtg ttcattcatg cctaccagct gaagccacag   6360 
tggaaaggtt acgatgacgt cttcagagga cgaacaaacg ccgcagaaat tcctctgatt   6420 
ttatatctct tcgccctgat ttctctgacg tggctttggg gaggactgca tatggcctac   6480 
cgacacttct ggatgttggt tctctttgtc attttcaata gtctgcaggg actctatgtt   6540 
tttgtggttt atttcatttt acacaatcaa acgtgttgcc ctatgaaggc cagctatacg   6600 
gtggaaatga atggtcaccc aggacccagc acagccttct tcactcctgg gagtggaata   6660 
cctccagctg gagagatgaa caagtctacc cagaacctca tcaatgctat ggaagaggtg   6720 
ccatctgact gggagagagt gtccttccaa cagaccagcc aggcaagccc tgatttgaag   6780 
acaagtcccc agaatggtgc ctcgtttcct tcttctgggg gatatggcca agggtccctg   6840 
atagcagatg aggagtccca ggagtttgat gacctgatat ttgcattaaa aactggtgct   6900 
ggtctcagtg tcagtgacaa cgagtctggt caagggagcc aagagggagg aaccttgact   6960 
gattcccgga ttgtagagct cagaaggata ccaattgctg acacccacct ctgagagtcc   7020 
cactaacact atccattaga aakaggcaag tttcctcgtt gccttggctt ttgtactaaa   7080 
ctctgtaggc atttacagcc atgtagtaat ggcctgtata tcataccaag tgagtaacac   7140 
agaagtgatt gttatgtttg gaatacacat tgctagtgtt tttgcaactt aaaaatgact   7200 
gccacgataa aagatgagat cattcctgta agttacaagg rtgcacattg tccaaaaata   7260 
ttagtcattt tttaatcatc caaactcagc taacattgtt taatgaaaat aatcatcaat   7320 
aaatgcatta gaatgcagrw rrwaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa   7380 
aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaa                7428 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>12 </s210>
<s211>2092 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
<s220>
<s221>UNSURE </s221>
<s222>(1671)...(1671) </s222>
<s223>Xaa&equals;any amino acid </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 12 
Met Leu Asp Gly Gln Ser Thr Ala Thr Val Val Ile Gln Ala Leu Asp 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Asp Gly Ile Pro Glu Glu Lys Cys Ser Tyr Glu Phe Gln Leu Thr Gly 
            20                  25                  30 
Ile Ser Glu Gly Ala Val Leu Asn Glu Ala Ser Val Thr Ala Ser Ile 
        35                  40                  45 
Ser Met Val Ala Ser Asp Ala Pro Tyr Gly Gln Phe Ser Phe Ser His 
    50                  55                  60 
Glu Gln Leu Gln Val Ser Glu Ala Ala Gln Lys Val Asn Val Thr Val 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Ala Arg Ser Gly Gly Ser Phe Gly Arg Val Arg Val Trp Tyr Glu Thr 
                85                  90                  95 
Gly Ser Arg Thr Ala Glu Ala Gly Trp Asp Phe Val Pro Thr Ser Gly 
            100                 105                 110 
Glu Leu Ile Phe Glu Ala Arg Glu Lys Met Lys Ser Leu His Ile Glu 
        115                 120                 125 
Ile Leu Asp Asp Asn Leu Pro Glu Gly Pro Glu Glu Phe Val Leu Ala 
    130                 135                 140 
Ile Thr Arg Val Asp Leu Gln Gly Arg Gly Tyr Asp Phe Thr Ile Gln 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Glu Asn Gly Leu Gln Ile Asp Gln Pro Pro Glu Ile Gly Ser Ile Ser 
                165                 170                 175 
Val Val Gln Ile Ile Ile Met Glu Asn Asp Asn Val Glu Gly Ile Ile 
            180                 185                 190 
Glu Phe Asp Pro Lys Phe Thr Asp Ile Ser Val Glu Glu Gly Ala Gly 
        195                 200                 205 
Val Ile Pro Leu Pro Val Met Arg Leu Arg Gly Thr Tyr Gly Arg Val 
    210                 215                 220 
Ser Ala Asp Phe Ser Ser Arg Asp Ser Ser Ala Val Pro Gly Gly Tyr 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Val Leu His Gly Gly Ser Val Thr Phe Gln His Gly Gln Ser Leu Ser 
                245                 250                 255 
Phe Ile Asn Val Ser Ile Val Asp Asp Asn Asp Ser Glu Ser Glu Lys 
            260                 265                 270 
Gln Leu Glu Ile Leu Leu Ile Gly Ala Thr Gly Gly Ala Ile Leu Gly 
        275                 280                 285 
Arg His Leu Val Ser Lys Ile Thr Ile Ala Lys Ser Gly Ser Pro Phe 
    290                 295                 300 
Gly Ile Ile Arg Phe Leu Asn Gln Ser Lys Ile Ser Val Pro Asn Pro 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Asn Ser Thr Met Ala Leu His Leu Val Leu Glu Arg Thr Gly Gly Leu 
                325                 330                 335 
Leu Gly Glu Ile Gln Val Ser Trp Glu Ile Val Gly Pro Ser Ser Glu 
            340                 345                 350 
Glu Leu Leu Leu Pro Gln His Gly Asp Phe Ala Asp Pro Val Ser Gly 
        355                 360                 365 
Thr Val Ser Phe Gly Asp Gly Glu Gly Gly Val Arg Thr Ile Thr Leu 
    370                 375                 380 
Thr Val Cys Pro His Glu Glu Thr Glu Ala Glu Glu Thr Phe Val Val 
385                 390                 395                 400 
Gln Leu Lys Pro Leu Lys Glu Ala Lys Leu Asp Pro Arg Ala Lys Ala 
                405                 410                 415 
Val Thr Leu Thr Ile Gln Lys Phe Gly Asp Pro Asn Gly Val Ile His 
            420                 425                 430 
Phe Ala Pro Glu Ser Leu Ser Lys Lys Met Phe Ser Glu Pro Pro Pro 
        435                 440                 445 
Ser Glu Gly Pro Met Leu Ile Ser Phe Leu Val Thr Arg Ser Lys Gly 
    450                 455                 460 
Thr Ser Gly Glu Ile Thr Val His Trp Glu Leu Ser Ser Glu Phe Asp 
465                 470                 475                 480 
Leu Thr Gly Asp Phe Leu Ser Thr Gln Gly Phe Phe Thr Ile Ala Asp 
                485                 490                 495 
Gly Asp Ser Glu Ala Ser Phe Asp Val His Leu Leu Pro Asp Asp Val 
            500                 505                 510 
Pro Glu Ile Glu Glu Glu Tyr Val Val Gln Leu Val Ser Val Glu Gly 
        515                 520                 525 
Gly Ala Glu Leu Asp Leu Glu Lys Cys Thr Ser Arg Phe Ser Val Ser 
    530                 535                 540 
Ala Asn Asp Asp Pro His Gly Ile Phe Ala Leu Tyr Ser Asp Gln Gln 
545                 550                 555                 560 
Ser Val Leu Ile Gly Gln Asn Leu Ile Arg Ser Ile Gln Ile Asn Ile 
                565                 570                 575 
Thr Arg Leu Ala Gly Val Phe Gly Ala Val Ala Val Thr Leu Gln Ile 
            580                 585                 590 
Leu Ser Asp Asn Lys Glu Asp Pro Val Ala Thr Glu Asn Glu Glu Arg 
        595                 600                 605 
Gln Met Val Ile Lys Asp Gly Ala Arg Tyr Lys Val Gly Leu Val Pro 
    610                 615                 620 
Leu Lys Asn Gln Val Phe Leu Ser Leu Gly Ser Asn Phe Thr Leu Arg 
625                 630                 635                 640 
Leu Leu Ser Ala Arg Leu Leu Ser Gly Pro Phe Tyr Gly Met Pro Thr 
                645                 650                 655 
Ile His Gln Glu Ala Asn Gln Ala Phe Leu Ser Val Pro Glu Glu Ala 
            660                 665                 670 
Ala Asn Ser Gln Val Gly Phe Glu Ser Thr Ala Phe Gln Leu Ile Asp 
        675                 680                 685 
Ile Thr Ala Gly Thr Ser Gln Val Thr Val Phe Arg Arg Gly Thr Tyr 
    690                 695                 700 
Gly Arg Leu Ser Val Ala Trp Thr Thr Gly Tyr Ala Pro Gly Ser Glu 
705                 710                 715                 720 
Ile Pro Glu Pro Ile Ala Ile Gly Asn Met Thr Pro Thr Leu Gly Ser 
                725                 730                 735 
Leu Ser Phe Leu His Gly Glu Gln Lys Lys Gly Val Leu Leu Trp Thr 
            740                 745                 750 
Phe Pro Ser Pro Gly Gln Pro Glu Ala Phe Val Leu His Leu Ser Gly 
        755                 760                 765 
Leu Arg Ser Ser Ala Ala Gly Gly Ala Gln Leu Arg Leu Ala Phe Thr 
    770                 775                 780 
Thr Ala Glu Ile Glu Pro Leu Gly Val Phe Gln Phe Ser Pro Gly Ser 
785                 790                 795                 800 
Arg Asn Ile Thr Val Ser Glu Asp Ala Leu Ile Ile Arg Ile Cys Val 
                805                 810                 815 
Gln Arg Leu Phe Gly Phe Gln Gly Asp Leu Ile Lys Val Ser Tyr Lys 
            820                 825                 830 
Thr Thr Ala Gly Ser Ala Lys Pro Leu Glu Asp Phe Glu Pro Ile Gln 
        835                 840                 845 
Lys Gly Glu Ile Phe Phe Gln Arg Phe Gln Ala Glu Val Asp Phe Glu 
    850                 855                 860 
Ile Thr Ile Ile Asn Asp Gln Leu Pro Glu Arg Glu Glu Thr Phe Tyr 
865                 870                 875                 880 
Ile Asn Leu Thr Ser Val Glu Thr Arg Gly Pro Gly Lys Gly Asp Val 
                885                 890                 895 
Ser Trp Arg Pro Arg Leu Asn Pro Asp Leu Ser Val Ala Met Val Thr 
            900                 905                 910 
Ile Leu Asp Asn Asp Asp Pro Ala Gly Val Ala Val Ser Val Pro Val 
        915                 920                 925 
Thr Ala Gly Thr Val Ala Ala Asp Ser Thr Leu Leu Ala Met Glu Ala 
    930                 935                 940 
Asp Phe Thr Thr His Pro Asn Lys Ser Lys Ile Thr Thr Ile Pro Tyr 
945                 950                 955                 960 
Thr Thr Glu Val Phe Ala Pro Val Thr Glu Thr Val Asp Val Ser Ala 
                965                 970                 975 
Ile Pro Glu Lys Leu Val Thr Ile His Ser Ala Ile Ser Glu Glu Pro 
            980                 985                 990 
Asp Leu Ala Pro Gly Thr Ala Gln Ala Ala Val Phe Gly Thr Leu Ser 
        995                 1000                1005 
Leu Gly Pro Pro Ile Val Tyr Val Ser Glu Glu Met Lys Asn Asn Thr 
    1010                1015                1020 
Pro Ser Thr Ala Asp Ile Gln Ile Gln Arg Ile Gly Gly Phe Ala Gly 
1025                1030                1035                1040 
Asn Val Ser Val Thr Val Arg Thr Phe Gly Gly Arg Cys Ala Gln Lys 
                1045                1050                1055 
Glu Pro Ser Val Trp Pro Phe Gln Asp Val Tyr Gly Ile Gly Asn Leu 
            1060                1065                1070 
Thr Trp Ala Val Glu Glu Glu Asp Phe Glu Glu Gln Met Leu Thr Leu 
        1075                1080                1085 
Thr Phe Leu Asn Gly Glu Arg Glu His Arg Ile Ala Val Arg Ile Leu 
    1090                1095                1100 
Asp Asp Asp Glu Pro Glu Gly Gln Glu Phe Phe Tyr Val Phe Leu Thr 
1105                1110                1115                1120 
Asp Pro Gln Gly Gly Ala Glu Ile Val Arg Gly Lys Asp Gly Ser Gly 
                1125                1130                1135 
Phe Ser Ala Phe Ala Leu Ile Leu Ile Thr Gly Ser Asp Leu His Asp 
            1140                1145                1150 
Gly Ile Val Gly Phe Ser Glu Glu Ser Leu Arg Gly Leu Glu Leu Arg 
        1155                1160                1165 
Glu Gly Thr Asp Lys Ser Ser Gln Arg Leu Glu Val Thr Arg Gln Pro 
    1170                1175                1180 
Asn Arg Ala Phe Glu Glu Val Gln Val Phe Trp Arg Val Thr Leu Asn 
1185                1190                1195                1200 
Gln Thr Ala Thr Ile Leu Gln Glu Lys Gly Leu Asn Leu Thr Asp Glu 
                1205                1210                1215 
Leu Arg Ser Val Ala Gly Val Thr Thr Cys Thr Val Gly Gln Thr Gln 
            1220                1225                1230 
Cys Phe Ile His Leu Glu Leu Asn Pro Lys Lys Val His Gln Val Glu 
        1235                1240                1245 
Met Pro Phe Phe Val Glu Leu Tyr Asp Val Thr Ala Gly Ala Ala Ile 
    1250                1255                1260 
Asn Asn Ser Ala Arg Phe Ala Arg Ile Lys Val Ser Lys Ser Gly Asp 
1265                1270                1275                1280 
Ser Gln Ser Leu Val Phe Phe Ser Val Gly Ser Arg Leu Ala Val Ala 
                1285                1290                1295 
His Lys Lys Ala Thr Leu Ile Ser Leu Gln Val Ala Arg Asp Ser Gly 
            1300                1305                1310 
Thr Gly Met Met Met Ser Val Asn Phe Ser Thr Gln Glu Leu Arg Ser 
        1315                1320                1325 
Ala Glu Thr Val Gly Arg Ile Leu Leu Ser Pro Ala Val Ser Gly Lys 
    1330                1335                1340 
Asp Phe Val Arg Thr Glu Gly Thr Leu Val Phe Glu Pro Gly Gln Lys 
1345                1350                1355                1360 
Ser Ala Val Leu Asp Val Val Leu Thr Pro Glu Thr Gly Ser Leu Asn 
                1365                1370                1375 
Lys Phe Pro Lys Arg Phe Gln Ile Val Leu Phe Asp Pro Lys Gly Gly 
            1380                1385                1390 
Ala Arg Ile Asp Lys Val Tyr Gly Thr Ala Asn Ile Thr Leu Val Ser 
        1395                1400                1405 
Asp Val Asp Ser Gln Ala Val Trp Gly Leu Glu Gly Leu Leu His Gln 
    1410                1415                1420 
Pro Leu His Glu Asp Val Leu Asn Arg Val Leu His Ser Leu Asn Leu 
1425                1430                1435                1440 
Arg Val Ala Thr Glu Ser Thr Asp Glu Gln Leu Ser Ala Val Met Phe 
                1445                1450                1455 
Ile Met Glu Lys Ile Met Met Glu Gly Lys Asn Gln Ala Phe Ser Ile 
            1460                1465                1470 
Glu Ser Arg Thr Leu Phe Tyr Glu Leu Leu Cys Ala Leu Ile Asn Pro 
        1475                1480                1485 
Lys Arg Lys Asp Thr Arg Gly Phe Ser His Phe Ala Glu Val Ala Glu 
    1490                1495                1500 
His Phe Ala Phe Ser Leu Leu Thr Asp Val Thr Cys Gly Ser Pro Gly 
1505                1510                1515                1520 
Glu Lys Ser Lys Thr Ile Leu Asp Ser Cys Pro Tyr Leu Ser Ile Leu 
                1525                1530                1535 
Ala Leu His Trp Ser Pro Gln Gln Ile Asn Gly His Arg Phe Glu Gly 
            1540                1545                1550 
Lys Glu Gly Asp Tyr Ile Gln Ile Pro Glu Arg Phe Leu Asp Ala Pro 
        1555                1560                1565 
Glu Pro Glu Val Ser Asp Gly Lys Asn Ala Cys Ala Leu Val Gln Phe 
    1570                1575                1580 
Val Glu Tyr Ser Ser Gln Gln Trp Phe Val Ala Gly Asp Asn Leu Pro 
1585                1590                1595                1600 
Ala Leu Arg Asp Lys Val Leu Ser Leu Asn Val Lys Gly Arg Asp Ala 
                1605                1610                1615 
Gln Pro Leu Pro Asn Asn Asn Glu Val Leu Tyr Arg Ile Tyr Ala Ala 
            1620                1625                1630 
Glu Pro Arg Ile Ile Pro His Thr Ser Leu Cys Leu Leu Trp Asn Gln 
        1635                1640                1645 
Ala Ala Ser Ser Trp Leu Ser Asp Ser Gln Leu Cys Lys Val Val Glu 
    1650                1655                1660 
Asp Ala Ala Asp Tyr Val Xaa Cys Ala Cys Ser His Met Ser Ala Tyr 
1665                1670                1675                1680 
Ala Val Tyr Ala Gln Thr Asp Asn Leu Val Ser Tyr Asn Glu Ala Phe 
                1685                1690                1695 
Phe Ser Ala Gly Phe Ile Cys Ile Ser Gly Leu Cys Leu Ala Val Val 
            1700                1705                1710 
Ser His Val Phe Cys Ala Arg Tyr Ser Met Phe Ala Ala Lys Leu Leu 
        1715                1720                1725 
Thr His Met Met Ala Ala Ser Leu Gly Ala Gln Val Ser Phe Leu Ala 
    1730                1735                1740 
Ser Ala Tyr Ala Ser Pro Gln Leu Ser Glu Glu Ser Cys Ser Ala Val 
1745                1750                1755                1760 
Ala Ala Val Ala His Tyr Leu Tyr Leu Cys Gln Phe Ser Trp Met Leu 
                1765                1770                1775 
Ile Gln Ser Val Asn Phe Trp Tyr Val Leu Val Val Asn Asp Glu His 
            1780                1785                1790 
Thr Glu Arg Arg Cys Leu Leu Phe Cys Leu Leu Ser Trp Gly Leu Pro 
        1795                1800                1805 
Ser Phe Val Val Ile Leu Leu Ile Val Ile Leu Arg Gly Ile Tyr His 
    1810                1815                1820 
Gln Ser Met Pro Gln Ile Tyr Gly Leu Ile His Gly Asp Leu Cys Phe 
1825                1830                1835                1840 
Ile Pro Asn Ile Tyr Ala Ala Leu Phe Thr Ala Ala Leu Val Pro Leu 
                1845                1850                1855 
Met Cys Leu Val Val Val Phe Val Val Phe Ile His Ala Tyr Gln Leu 
            1860                1865                1870 
Lys Pro Gln Trp Lys Gly Tyr Asp Asp Val Phe Arg Gly Arg Thr Asn 
        1875                1880                1885 
Ala Ala Glu Ile Pro Leu Ile Leu Tyr Leu Phe Ala Leu Ile Ser Leu 
    1890                1895                1900 
Thr Trp Leu Trp Gly Gly Leu His Met Ala Tyr Arg His Phe Trp Met 
1905                1910                1915                1920 
Leu Val Leu Phe Val Ile Phe Asn Ser Leu Gln Gly Leu Tyr Val Phe 
                1925                1930                1935 
Val Val Tyr Phe Ile Leu His Asn Gln Thr Cys Cys Pro Met Lys Ala 
            1940                1945                1950 
Ser Tyr Thr Val Glu Met Asn Gly His Pro Gly Pro Ser Thr Ala Phe 
        1955                1960                1965 
Phe Thr Pro Gly Ser Gly Ile Pro Pro Ala Gly Glu Met Asn Lys Ser 
    1970                1975                1980 
Thr Gln Asn Leu Ile Asn Ala Met Glu Glu Val Pro Ser Asp Trp Glu 
1985                1990                1995                2000 
Arg Val Ser Phe Gln Gln Thr Ser Gln Ala Ser Pro Asp Leu Lys Thr 
                2005                2010                2015 
Ser Pro Gln Asn Gly Ala Ser Phe Pro Ser Ser Gly Gly Tyr Gly Gln 
            2020                2025                2030 
Gly Ser Leu Ile Ala Asp Glu Glu Ser Gln Glu Phe Asp Asp Leu Ile 
        2035                2040                2045 
Phe Ala Leu Lys Thr Gly Ala Gly Leu Ser Val Ser Asp Asn Glu Ser 
    2050                2055                2060 
Gly Gln Gly Ser Gln Glu Gly Gly Thr Leu Thr Asp Ser Arg Ile Val 
2065                2070                2075                2080 
Glu Leu Arg Arg Ile Pro Ile Ala Asp Thr His Leu 
                2085                2090 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>13 </s210>
<s211>4097 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 13 
attttggtca acaccctgct tactgcgcac aaccaatcct gttagaactc agcatcccgg     60 
ctcatctgag cagatcctct agtgatttct gctggtcaaa attttttaag ataaattgaa    120 
actatagctt aatttttttt atttatattt tttctttttg tatttttttc tgcacaaaga    180 
aggcggattt tttttttcac ttattcatgc caagaccaat ttttgaaagc cagcattggg    240 
tgtgtaggat ttaagcctat agatagcctt gttggaataa aggaaaagga agatcaaagg    300 
agagcacgct ggtggaggac ggcgccggct aaccttgcta accattagga attgctatta    360 
agaaaagaga gatacaattg tttgttttga gcagtttgtt ctataagctg actcatcatg    420 
tctgccctga cgcctccgac tgatatgcca acccccacca ctgacaagat aacccaggct    480 
gccatggaga ccatctacct ctgcaaattc cgggtgtcta tggatggaga atggctctgc    540 
cttcgagagc tggatgacat ctcccttact gacccagagc ctacccatga agatcctaat    600 
tatctcatgg ctaacgagcg catgaacctg atgaacatgg cgaagctgag catcaagggc    660 
ttgattgagt cggctctgaa cctggggcgg accctggact ctgactacgc acctctccag    720 
cagttcttcg tggtgatgga acactgcctg aaacatggct tgaaagccaa gaaaactttt    780 
cttggacaaa ataagtcctt ctggggtcct ctagagctgg tagaaaagct tgttccagaa    840 
gctgcagaga taacagcaag tgtaaaagat ctcccaggac tcaagacacc agttggcaga    900 
ggaagagcct ggcttcggtt ggcattaatg caaaagaagc tttctgagta catgaaggcc    960 
ttgatcaata agaaggaact tctcagtgag ttctatgaag ccaatgctct catgatggaa   1020 
gaagaaggcg caattattgc tggcctcctg gtcggtctga atgtcatcga tgccaatttc   1080 
tgcatgaaag gagaagacct ggactctcag gttggcgtta tagacttttc aatgtatctc   1140 
aaagatggga acagcagtaa aggcagtgaa ggggatggac agattactgc gattctggac   1200 
cagaaaaact atgtagaaga actcaacaga catctgaatg ctactgtaaa caaccttcag   1260 
gcaaaagtag atgcgttaga aaaatccaac acgaaattga cagaggaact tgccgtcgcc   1320 
aacaacagaa ttattacctt acaagaagaa atggaacggg ttaaagaaga aagttcctat   1380 
ctactggaat ccaatcggaa gggtcctaag caagacagaa ctgcagaagg gcaagcgctg   1440 
agcgaagcca gaaagcatct aaaggaggag acacagttac gattggacgt tgaaaaggag   1500 
ctggagctgc agatcagcat gaggcaggag atggaactgg ctatgaagat gctggagaag   1560 
gatgtctgtg agaagcagga tgccctggtg tccctgcggc agcagctgga tgatctccga   1620 
gctcttaaac acgagcttgc ctttaagctg cagagttcag acctaggagt gaaacagaaa   1680 
agtgaattaa acagtcgctt ggaagagaag accaatcaga tggctgccac cattaaacag   1740 
ctggagcaaa gtgaaaaaga tttggtgaaa caggcaaaga ccttaaatag tgcagcaaat   1800 
aaactgatcc caaaacatca ttaaacgttt tgcagttggt cacctcacga gtctgatgtc   1860 
gcagattaac tataaaagga agaaatctga aattcctaca tttaagctcc gattctatat   1920 
aaaatatcac gagacgttga ccttgaattt gttggactta aaagcactag gtggatatat   1980 
aggttgggat atataggttg ggttttgttg ttgtggttgc cgctgttatt ttgcccccag   2040 
agttagaaat tttggtatgg attcctcatt aagtaccaaa taaactttga gaaatatttc   2100 
tgagttgaac agtaaatcaa aagaccattt taggaagccc gggctatgga agcactgtgt   2160 
ttgtgtgctt ggtagtggtc atactctgta ggtgtggctc cctccgcacc agcgagcgag   2220 
cctgccctgt gcaggggtca cctggcgacc aggaactagt ctaacatagc tctgcctctc   2280 
aggccatgac ccctctcttc tcttgcctcc tgtaggttta acccccagcc caagataaat   2340 
atttagtatt tccttacagt tctgttctga gtaaccgagg ctgcttgcaa tttatttttg   2400 
ccttcgtgat gttggacaaa aagaaaaaca gcatccttcc tttctttaaa gtccttagaa   2460 
acaaagtagt aattaggtag ctcttaacat cacagtgtgg aagctggagc aacccctctt   2520 
aacactgtca tcttctacct ctgcccttct ctgtcatcct gcttactact taggtagctc   2580 
agagagtaca atgctcacgt ccgccctgcg tttcctgctg gagtttgtga ggccacagtg   2640 
tagtcatgag ttgcaactcc ctgcctgttg tcttcgcctg gaacacttgc ccaagagctt   2700 
caaacacttt ttctctaatg agaatttgct aaaggttctg ggaaactaat ctagttacta   2760 
aaaaataaac atttctaaat gagaaataaa taagatacta gcattattgt ttaatatcag   2820 
aatgaagctc ttcagtagcc acaggcagtg tgagcaggac cttctctaag tgaccgcaga   2880 
tatcaccctt ttaggctcta catcgtaaat aactctatac atactttgat ttaaaaaaag   2940 
actattttgg ggaggcaggc ttttatagac aggagccttt actccatccc gcggtattca   3000 
cacaataccc agggtttggt tccatgtttt ctgtctcccc ttctggcagg ctatgtagca   3060 
tagcctgtgc taagagagag gcaaagataa tccctttgct tccagctctt caaaatcttt   3120 
accttcatgg caaaccagaa ttaagagtac agcagagttc atgtttctat gggtcctcaa   3180 
aaggccggtt agaggcaact tcatggacag tcctgtgccc ctgaactcac tttaattctt   3240 
acagctgtgc acctgcataa gcaaagctcc tactgcattc tgctgttcat cagcctttca   3300 
cggtgaggag ttgcctttta cttaagcgtc taaaaagaat aatcaaatca ataaaagtta   3360 
gactaaacat agcatgcctc tcaatcctac tatagaaagc ctcgagtatt tcaccttcta   3420 
aaagtgattc tttataggta caaagttata agacattcag aagggagcat ccacgagaat   3480 
cttccagaga acatggtcag gagcttagga accccaatgc tgactggtca gctgggtcac   3540 
aaaccacctg ataggaatgg ccgggaaaga gccaggcact cgccaggcgc ttgctcagag   3600 
tgtgaccttg tggaaggtga agtctgggta agggttgcta tggaatgtcc tccagcgtcc   3660 
tgcagcacaa ggaggaccag gaaatcgtga gaagcccatg tgagaaggag ctgctcccgc   3720 
gtgctcccgc tgtgtgtgaa aggcagagtg ttaggaaaga aaggcagcgg cttcgacgtc   3780 
aattgctctg tacttgaggg tggctctgga aatggatttc caaacagtga tgtcttgttg   3840 
ttgatcatct aatggctgta aactgtagta atccagattg cgccaggctg agcgaggccg   3900 
ccagtctgcc gagctggaca accggctctt caaacaggac ttcggagaca agatcaacag   3960 
cctgcagctg gaggtggagg cgctcaccag gcagcggtga gcaggggcag cttggctggc   4020 
agggtgctgt ggtgggcact gcagacctaa acagcaagga gggagtcagg tcctgagtca   4080 
tcttggtttg ttcttgc                                                  4097 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>14 </s210>
<s211>468 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>rattus sp. </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 14 
Met Ser Ala Leu Thr Pro Pro Thr Asp Met Pro Thr Pro Thr Thr Asp 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Lys Ile Thr Gln Ala Ala Met Glu Thr Ile Tyr Leu Cys Lys Phe Arg 
            20                  25                  30 
Val Ser Met Asp Gly Glu Trp Leu Cys Leu Arg Glu Leu Asp Asp Ile 
        35                  40                  45 
Ser Leu Thr Asp Pro Glu Pro Thr His Glu Asp Pro Asn Tyr Leu Met 
    50                  55                  60 
Ala Asn Glu Arg Met Asn Leu Met Asn Met Ala Lys Leu Ser Ile Lys 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Gly Leu Ile Glu Ser Ala Leu Asn Leu Gly Arg Thr Leu Asp Ser Asp 
                85                  90                  95 
Tyr Ala Pro Leu Gln Gln Phe Phe Val Val Met Glu His Cys Leu Lys 
            100                 105                 110 
His Gly Leu Lys Ala Lys Lys Thr Phe Leu Gly Gln Asn Lys Ser Phe 
        115                 120                 125 
Trp Gly Pro Leu Glu Leu Val Glu Lys Leu Val Pro Glu Ala Ala Glu 
    130                 135                 140 
Ile Thr Ala Ser Val Lys Asp Leu Pro Gly Leu Lys Thr Pro Val Gly 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Arg Gly Arg Ala Trp Leu Arg Leu Ala Leu Met Gln Lys Lys Leu Ser 
                165                 170                 175 
Glu Tyr Met Lys Ala Leu Ile Asn Lys Lys Glu Leu Leu Ser Glu Phe 
            180                 185                 190 
Tyr Glu Ala Asn Ala Leu Met Met Glu Glu Glu Gly Ala Ile Ile Ala 
        195                 200                 205 
Gly Leu Leu Val Gly Leu Asn Val Ile Asp Ala Asn Phe Cys Met Lys 
    210                 215                 220 
Gly Glu Asp Leu Asp Ser Gln Val Gly Val Ile Asp Phe Ser Met Tyr 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Leu Lys Asp Gly Asn Ser Ser Lys Gly Ser Glu Gly Asp Gly Gln Ile 
                245                 250                 255 
Thr Ala Ile Leu Asp Gln Lys Asn Tyr Val Glu Glu Leu Asn Arg His 
            260                 265                 270 
Leu Asn Ala Thr Val Asn Asn Leu Gln Ala Lys Val Asp Ala Leu Glu 
        275                 280                 285 
Lys Ser Asn Thr Lys Leu Thr Glu Glu Leu Ala Val Ala Asn Asn Arg 
    290                 295                 300 
Ile Ile Thr Leu Gln Glu Glu Met Glu Arg Val Lys Glu Glu Ser Ser 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Tyr Leu Leu Glu Ser Asn Arg Lys Gly Pro Lys Gln Asp Arg Thr Ala 
                325                 330                 335 
Glu Gly Gln Ala Leu Ser Glu Ala Arg Lys His Leu Lys Glu Glu Thr 
            340                 345                 350 
Gln Leu Arg Leu Asp Val Glu Lys Glu Leu Glu Leu Gln Ile Ser Met 
        355                 360                 365 
Arg Gln Glu Met Glu Leu Ala Met Lys Met Leu Glu Lys Asp Val Cys 
    370                 375                 380 
Glu Lys Gln Asp Ala Leu Val Ser Leu Arg Gln Gln Leu Asp Asp Leu 
385                 390                 395                 400 
Arg Ala Leu Lys His Glu Leu Ala Phe Lys Leu Gln Ser Ser Asp Leu 
                405                 410                 415 
Gly Val Lys Gln Lys Ser Glu Leu Asn Ser Arg Leu Glu Glu Lys Thr 
            420                 425                 430 
Asn Gln Met Ala Ala Thr Ile Lys Gln Leu Glu Gln Ser Glu Lys Asp 
        435                 440                 445 
Leu Val Lys Gln Ala Lys Thr Leu Asn Ser Ala Ala Asn Lys Leu Ile 
    450                 455                 460 
Pro Lys His His 
465 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>15 </s210>
<s211>18946 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>human </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 15 
atgtctgatc tcaaagaagg gatgccctct gcatctttat tagtaaatct tctttcagct     60 
ttactcatcc tatttgtgtt tggagaaaca gaaataagat ttactggaca aactgaattt    120 
gttgttaatg aaacaagtac aacagttatt cgtcttatca ttgaaaggat aggagagcca    180 
gcaaatgtta ctgcaattgt atcgctgtat ggagaggacg ctggtgactt ttttgacaca    240 
tatgctgcag cttttatacc tgccggagaa acaaacagaa cagtgtacat agcagtatgt    300 
gatgatgact taccagagcc tgacgaaact tttatttttc acttaacatt acagaaacct    360 
tcagcaaatg tgaagcttgg atggccaagg actgttactg tgacaatatt atcaaatgac    420 
aatgcatttg gaattatttc atttaatatg cttccctcaa tcgcagtgag tgagcccaag    480 
ggcagaaatg agtctatgcc tcttactctc atcagggaaa agggaaccta tggaatggtc    540 
atggtgactt ttgaggtaga gggtggccca aatccccctg atgaagattt gagtccagtt    600 
aaaggaaata tcacctttcc ccctggcaga gcaacagtaa tttataactt gacagtactc    660 
gatgacgagg taccagaaaa tgatgaaata tttttaattc aactgaaaag tgtagaagga    720 
ggagctgaga ttaacacctc taggaattcc attgagatca tcattaagaa aaatgatagt    780 
cccgtgagat tccttcagag tatttatttg gttcctgagg aagaccacat actcataatt    840 
ccagtagttc gtggaaagga caacaatgga aatctgattg gatctgatga atatgaggtt    900 
tcaatcagtt atgctgtcac aactgggaat tccacagcac atgcccagca aaatctggac    960 
ttcattgatc ttcagccaaa cacaactgtt gtttttccac cttttattca tgaatctcac   1020 
ttgaaatttc aaatagttga tgacaccata ccggagattg ctgaatcgtt tcacattatg   1080 
ttactaaaag ataccttaca gggagatgct gtgctaataa gcccttctgt tgtacaagtc   1140 
accattaagc caaatgataa accttatgga gtcctttcat tcaacagtgt tttgtttgaa   1200 
aggacagtta taattgatga agatagaata tcaagatatg aagaaatcac agtggttaga   1260 
aatggaggaa cccatgggaa tgtctctgcg aattgggtgt tgacacggaa cagcactgat   1320 
ccctcaccag taacagcaga tatcagaccg agctctggag ttctccattt tgcacaaggg   1380 
cagatgttgg caacaattcc tcttactgtg gttgatgatg atcttccaga agaggcagaa   1440 
gcttatctac ttcaaattct gcctcataca atacgaggag gtgcagaagt gagcgagcca   1500 
gcggagcttt tgttctacat tcaggatagt gatgatgtct atggcctaat aacatttttt   1560 
cctatggaaa accagaagat tgaaagcagc ccatgtgaac gatacttatc cttgagtttt   1620 
acaagactag gagggactaa aggagatgtg aggttgcttt attctgtact ttacattcct   1680 
gctggagctg tggacccctt gcaagcaaaa gaaggcatct taaatatatc aaggagaaat   1740 
gacctcattt ttccagagca aaaaactcaa gtcactacaa aattaccaat aagaaatgat   1800 
gcattccttc aaaatggagc tcactttcta gtacagttgg aaactgtgga gttgttaaac   1860 
ataattcctc taatcccacc cataagccct agatttgggg aaatctgcaa tatttcttta   1920 
ctggttactc cagccattgc aaatggagaa attggctttc tcagcaatct tccaattatt   1980 
ttgcatgaac cagaagattt tgctgctgaa gtggtataca ttcccttaca tcgggatgga   2040 
actgatggcc aggctactgt ctactggagt ttgaagccct ctggctttaa ttcaaaagca   2100 
gtgaccccgg atgatatagg cccctttaat ggctctgttt tgtttttatc tgggcaaagt   2160 
gacacaacaa tcaacattac tatcaaaggt gatgacatac cggaaatgaa tgaaactgta   2220 
acactttctc tagacagggt taacgtggaa aaccaagtgc tgaaatctgg atatactagc   2280 
cgtgacctaa ttattttgga aaatgatgac cctgggggag tttttgaatt ttctcctgct   2340 
tccagaggac cctatgttat aaaagaagga gaatctgtag agctccacat catccgatca   2400 
agggggtccc ttgttaagca gtttctacac taccgagtag agccaagaga tagcaatgaa   2460 
ttctatggaa acacgggagt actagaattt aaacctggag aaagggagat agtgatcacc   2520 
ttgctagcaa gattggatgg gataccagag ttggatgaac actactgggt ggtcctcagc   2580 
agccacggag aacgggaaag caagttggga agtgccacca ttgtcaatat aacgattctg   2640 
aaaaatgatg atcctcatgg cattatagaa tttgtttctg atggtctaat tgtgatgata   2700 
aatgaaagca aaggagatgc tatctatagt gctgtttatg atgtagtaag aaatcgaggc   2760 
aactttggtg atgttagtgt atcatgggtg gttagtccag actttacaca agatgtattt   2820 
cctgtacaag ggactgttgt ctttggagat caggaatttt caaaaaatat caccatttac   2880 
tcccttccag atgagattcc agaagaaatg gaagaattta ccgttatcct actgaatggc   2940 
actggaggag ctaaagtggg aaatagaaca actgcaactc tgaggattag aagaattgat   3000 
gaccccattt attttgcaga acctcgtgta gtgagggttc aggaaggtga gactgccaac   3060 
tttacagttc tcagaaatgg atctgttgat gtgacttgca tggtccagta tgctaccaag   3120 
gatgggaagg ctactgcaag agagagagat ttcattcctg ttgaaaaagg agaaacgctc   3180 
atttttgagg ttggaagtag acagcagagc atatccatat ttgttaatga agatggtatc   3240 
ccggaaacag atgagccctt ttatataatc ctcttgaatt caacaggtga tacagtagta   3300 
tatcaatatg gagtagctac agtaataatt gaagctaatg atgacccaaa tggcattttt   3360 
tctctggagc ccatagacaa agcagtggaa gaaggaaaga ctaatgcatt ttggattttg   3420 
aggcaccgag gatactttgg tagtgtttct gtatcttggc agctctttca gaatgattct   3480 
gctttgcagc ctgggcagga gttctatgaa acttcaggaa ctgttaactt catggatgga   3540 
gaagaagcaa aaccaatcat tctccatgct tttccagata aaattcctga attcaatgaa   3600 
ttttatttcc taaaacttgt aaacatttca ggtggatccc caggtcctgg gggccagcta   3660 
gcagaaacca acctccaggt gacagtaatg gttccattca atgatgatcc ctttggagtt   3720 
tttatcttgg atccagagtg tttagagaga gaagtggcag aagatgtcct gtctgaagat   3780 
gatatgtctt atattaccaa cttcaccatt ttgaggcagc agggtgtgtt tggtgatgta   3840 
caactgggct gggaaatact gtccagtgag ttccctgctg gtttgccacc aatgatagat   3900 
tttttactgg ttggaatttt ccccaccacc gtgcatttac aacagcacat gcggcgtcac   3960 
cacagtggaa cggatgcttt gtactttacc ggactagagg gtgcatttgg gactgttaat   4020 
ccaaaatacc atccctccag gaataataca attgccaact ttacattctc agcttgggta   4080 
atgcccaatg ccaatacgaa tggattcatt atagcgaagg atgacggtaa tggaagcatc   4140 
tactacgggg taaaaataca aacaaacgaa tcccatgtga cactttccct tcattataaa   4200 
accttgggtt ccaatgctac atacattgcc aagacaacag tcatgaaata tttagaagaa   4260 
agtgtttggc ttcatctact aattatcctg gaggatggta taatcgaatt ctacctggat   4320 
ggaaatgcaa tgcccagggg aatcaagagt ctgaaaggag aagccattac tgacggtcct   4380 
gggatactga gaattggagc agggataaat ggcaatgaca gatttacagg tctgatgcag   4440 
gatgtgaggt cctatgagcg gaaactgacg cttgaagaaa tttatgaact tcatgccatg   4500 
cccgcaaaaa gtgatttaca cccaatttct ggatatctgg agttcagaca gggagaaact   4560 
aacaaatcat tcattatttc tgcaagagat gacaatgacg aggaaggaga agaattattc   4620 
attcttaaac tagtttctgt atatggagga gctcgtattt cggaagaaaa tactactgca   4680 
agattaacaa tacaaaaaag tgacaatgca aatggcttgt ttggtttcac aggagcttgt   4740 
ataccagaga ttgcagagga gggatcaacc atttcttgtg tggttgagag aaccagagga   4800 
gctctggatt atgtgcatgt tttttacacc atttcacaga ttgaaactga tggcattaat   4860 
taccttgttg atgactttgc taatgccagt ggaactatta cattccttcc ttggcagaga   4920 
tcagaggttc tgaatatata tgttcttgat gatgatattc ctgaacttaa tgagtatttc   4980 
cgtgtgacat tggtttctgc aattcctgga gatgggaagc taggctcaac tcctaccagt   5040 
ggtgcaagca tagatcctga aaaggaaacg actgatatca ccatcaaagc tagtgatcat   5100 
ccatatggct tgctgcagtt ctccacaggg ctgcctcctc agcctaagga cgcaatgacc   5160 
ctgcctgcaa gcagcgttcc acatatcact gtggaggagg aagatggaga aatcaggtta   5220 
ttggtcatcc gtgcacaggg acttctggga agggtgactg cggaatttag aacagtgtcc   5280 
ttgacagcat tcagtcctga ggattaccag aatgttgctg gcacattaga atttcaacca   5340 
ggagaaagat ataaatacat tttcataaac atcactgata attctattcc tgaactggaa   5400 
aaatctttta aagttgagtt gttaaacttg gaaggagggg ctgaactctt tagggttgat   5460 
ggaagtggta gtggtgatgg ggacatggaa ttcttccttc caactattca caaacgtgcc   5520 
agtctaggag tggcttccca aattctagtg acaattgcag cctctgacca cgctcatggc   5580 
gtatttgaat ttagccctga gtcactcttt gtcagtggaa ctgaaccaga agatgggtat   5640 
agcactgtta cattaaatgt tataagacat catggaactc tgtctccagt gactttgcat   5700 
tggaacatag actctgatcc tgatggtgat ctcgccttca cctctggcaa catcacattt   5760 
gagattgggc agatgagcgc caatatcact gtggagatat tgtctgacga agacccagaa   5820 
ctggataagg cattctctgt gtcaatcctc agtgtttcca gtggttcttt gggagctcat   5880 
attaatgcca cgttaacagt tttggctagt gatgatccat atgggatatt cattttttct   5940 
gagaaaaaca gacctgttaa agttgaggaa gcaacccaga acatcacact atcaataata   6000 
aggttgaaag gcctcatggg aaaagtcctt gtctcatatg caacactaga tgatatggaa   6060 
aaaccacctt attttccacc taatttagcg agagcaactc aaggaagaga ctatatacca   6120 
gcttctggat ttgctctttt tggagctaat cagagtgagg caacaatagc tatttcaatt   6180 
ttggatgatg atgagccaga aaggtccgaa tctgtcttta tcgaactact caactctact   6240 
ttagtagcga aagtacagag tcgttcaatt ccaaattctc cacgtcttgg gcctaaggta   6300 
gaaactattg cgcaactaat tatcattgcc aatgatgatg catttggaac tcttcagctc   6360 
tcagcaccaa ttgtccgagt ggcagaaaat catgttggac ccattatcaa tgtgactaga   6420 
acaggaggag catttgcaga tgtctctgtg aagtttaaag ctgtgccaat aactgcaata   6480 
gctggtgaag attatagtat agcttcatca gatgtggtct tgctagaagg ggaaaccagt   6540 
aaagccgtgc caatatatgt cattaatgat atctatcctg aactggaaga atcttttctt   6600 
gtgcaactga tgaatgaaac aacaggagga gccagactag gggctttaac agaggcagtc   6660 
attattattg aggcctctga tgacccctat ggattatttg gttttcagat tactaaactt   6720 
attgtagagg aacctgagtt taactcagtg aagataaacc tgccaataat tcgaaattct   6780 
gggacactcg gcaatgttac tgttcagtgg gttgccacca ttaatggaca gcttgctact   6840 
ggcgacctgc gagttgtctc aggtaatgtg acctttgccc ctggggaaac cattcaaacc   6900 
ttgttgttag aggtcctggc tgacgacgtt ccggagattg aagaggttat ccaagtgcaa   6960 
ctaactgatg cctctggtgg aggtactatt gggttagatc gaattgcaaa tattattatt   7020 
cctgccaatg atgatcctta tggtacagta gcctttgctc agatggttta tcgtgttcaa   7080 
gagcctctgg aaagaagttc ctgtgctaat ataactgtca ggcgaagcgg agggcacttt   7140 
ggtcggctgt tgttgttcta cagtacttcc gacattgatg tagtggctct ggcaatggag   7200 
gaaggtcaag atttactgtc ctactatgaa tctccaattc aaggggtgcc tgacccactt   7260 
tggagaactt ggatgaatgt ctctgccgtg ggggagcccc tgtatacctg tgccactttg   7320 
tgccttaagg aacaagcttg ctcagcgttt tcatttttca gtgcttctga gggtccccag   7380 
cgtttctgga tgacatcatg gatcagccca gctgtcaaca attcagactt ctggacctac   7440 
aggaaaaaca tgaccagggt agcatctctt tttagtggtc aggctgtggc tgggagtgac   7500 
tatgagcctg tgacaaggca atgggccata atgcaggaag gtgatgaatt cgcaaatctc   7560 
acagtgtcta ttcttcctga tgatttccca gagatggatg agagttttct aatttctctc   7620 
cttgaagttc acctcatgaa catttcagcc agtttgaaaa atcagccaac cataggacag   7680 
ccaaatattt ctacagttgt catagcacta aatggtgatg cctttggagt gtttgtgatc   7740 
tacagtatta gtcccaatac ttccgaagat ggcttatttg ttgaagttca ggagcagccc   7800 
caaaccttgg tggagctgat gatacacagg acagggggca gcttaggtca agtggcagtc   7860 
gaatggcgtg ttgttggtgg aacagctact gaaggtttag attttatagg tgctggagag   7920 
attctgacct ttgctgaagg tgaaaccaaa aagacagtca ttttaaccat cttggatgac   7980 
tctgaaccag aggatgacga aagtatcata gttagtttgg tgtacactga aggtggaagt   8040 
agaattttgc caagctccga cactgttaga gtgaacattt tggccaatga caatgtggca   8100 
ggaattgtta gctttcagac agcttccaga tctgtcatag gtcatgaagg agaaatttta   8160 
caattccatg tgataagaac tttccctggt cgaggaaatg ttactgttaa ctggaaaatt   8220 
attgggcaaa atctagaact caattttgct aactttagcg gacaactttt ctttcctgag   8280 
gggtcgttga atacaacatt gtttgtgcat ttgttggatg acaacattcc tgaggagaaa   8340 
gaagtatacc aagtcattct gtatgatgtc aggacacaag gagttccacc agccggaatc   8400 
gccctgcttg atgctcaagg atatgcagct gtcctcacag tagaagccag tgatgaacca   8460 
catggagttt taaattttgc tctttcatca agatttgtgt tactacaaga ggctaacata   8520 
acaattcagc ttttcatcaa cagagaattt ggatctctag gagctatcaa tgtcacatat   8580 
accacggttc ctggaatgct gagtctgaag aaccaaacag taggaaacct agcagagcca   8640 
gaagttgatt ttgtccctat cattggcttt ctgattttag aagaagggga aacagcagca   8700 
gccatcaaca ttaccattct tgaggatgat gtaccagagc tagaagaata tttcctggtg   8760 
aatttaactt acgttggact taccatggct gcttcaactt catttcctcc cagactagat   8820 
tcagaaggtt tgactgcaca agttattatt gatgccaatg atggggcccg aggtgtaatt   8880 
gaatggcaac aaagcaggtt tgaagtaaat gaaacccatg gaagtttaac attggtagcc   8940 
cagaggagca gagaacctct tggccatgtt tccttatttg tgtatgctca gaatttggaa   9000 
gcacaagtgg ggctggatta tatcttcacc ccaatgattc ttcattttgc tgatggagaa   9060 
aggtataaaa atgtcaatat catgattctt gatgatgaca ttccagaagg agatgaaaaa   9120 
tttcagctga ttttaacaaa tccttctcct ggactagagc tagggaaaaa tacaatagcc   9180 
ttaattattg tccttgctaa tgatgacggc cctggagttc tatcatttaa caacagtgag   9240 
cactttttcc taagagagcc aacagctctc tacgtccagg agagtgttgc agtattgtac   9300 
attgttcggg aacctgcaca aggattgttt ggaacagtga cagttcagtt cattgtgaca   9360 
gaagtgaatt cctcaaatga atctaaagat ctgactcctt ccaaaggcta tattgtttta   9420 
gaagaaggtg ttcgattcaa ggccctacaa atatctgcca tattagacac ggaaccagaa   9480 
atggatgagt attttgtttg caccttgttt aatccaactg gaggtgctag actaggggtg   9540 
catgttcaaa ccctgataac agttttgcaa aaccaggccc ctttggggct attcagtatc   9600 
tctgcagttg aaaatagagc cacctccata gacatcgaag aagccaatag gaccgtgtat   9660 
ttaaatgtat ctcgaactaa tggcattgat ttggctgtga gtgtgcagtg ggagacagta   9720 
tctgaaacag cctttggcat ggggggaatg gatgttgtgt tttccgtatt tcaaagtttt   9780 
ttggatgaat cagcttctgg ctggtgtttc tttactttgg aaaatttaat atatggtata   9840 
atgttaagaa aatcatctgt tactgtttac cgatggcagg ggatttttat tccagttgag   9900 
gatttaaata tagaaaatcc taaaacttgt gaggccttta atattggttt ttctccctac   9960 
ttcgtgatta ctcatgaaga aagaaatgaa gaaaagcctt ctcttaacag tgtgtttaca  10020 
ttcacatctg gatttaaatt attcctggta caaacaatca ttattctgga aagttctcaa  10080 
gtaagatatt ttacttcaga cagccaagat tatttaatca ttgcaagtca aagagatgat  10140 
tccgaattaa ctcaggtctt caggtggaat ggaggaagct tcgtgttgca tcaaaaactc  10200 
cctgtccgag gtgtgctgac cgtggccttg ttcaacaagg gaggctctgt gttcttagcc  10260 
atttcccagg ctaatgccag gctaaactcc cttttattca gatggtctgg cagtgggttt  10320 
attaactttc aagaggtgcc tgtcagtggg acaacagaag ttgaggcttt gtcttcagcc  10380 
aatgatattt acctaatatt tgccaaaaat gtctttctag gagatcagaa ttcaattgat  10440 
attttcatct gggagatggg acagtcttcc ttcaggtatt ttcagtctgt agattttgct  10500 
gctgttaaca gaatccactc cttcacacca gcctcaggaa tagcccacat acttcttatt  10560 
ggccaagata tgtctgctct ttactgctgg aattcggagc gtaatcaatt ctcttttgtt  10620 
ctggaagtac cttctgctta tgatgtggct tctgttacag taaagtccct taattcaagc  10680 
aagaatttaa tagctctagt gggagctcat tcacatatat atgagctagc ctacatttcc  10740 
agccattctg actttattcc tagttcaggt gaactgatat ttgaacctgg tgagagagaa  10800 
gctacaatag cagtaaatat ccttgatgat acagttccag aaaaagaaga atccttcaaa  10860 
gttcaactta aaaatcccaa aggaggagca gagattggca ttaatgattc tgtaacaata  10920 
accattctgt ctaatgatga tgcctatgga attgttgcat ttgctcagaa ttcattatat  10980 
aagcaagtgg aagaaatgga gcaagatagc ctagtaacct tgaacgttga acgcttaaaa  11040 
ggaacatatg gccgtataac catagcatgg gaagctgatg gaagtattag tgatatattt  11100 
cctacctcag gagtgatttt atttactgaa ggccaggtac tgtcaacaat cactctaact  11160 
attcttgctg ataatatacc agagttatca gaggttgtga ttgtaaccct cacccgtatc  11220 
accacagaag gggttgagga ctcatacaaa ggtgctacta ttgatcagga cagaagcaag  11280 
tctgttataa caactttgcc caatgactca ccttttggct tggtgggctg gcgtgctgcg  11340 
tctgtcttca ttagagtagc agagcctaaa gaaaacacca ccactcttca gttacaaata  11400 
gctcgagata aaggactact tggggatatt gccattcact tgagagctca acccaatttc  11460 
ttactgcatg tcgataatca agctactgag aatgaagatt atgtattgca agaaacaata  11520 
ataataatga aagaaaacat aaaagaagct catgccgaag tttccatttt gccggatgac  11580 
cttcctgaat tggaggaagg atttattgtc actatcactg aggtgaacct ggtgaactct  11640 
gacttctcta caggacagcc aagtgtgcgg aggcccggaa tggaaatagc tgagataatg  11700 
atagaagaaa atgacgatcc cagaggaatt tttatgtttc atgttactag aggcgctggg  11760 
gaagttatta ctgcctatga ggtgcctcca cccttgaacg ttcttcaagt tcctgtagtc  11820 
cggctggctg gaagctttgg ggcagtaaat gtttattgga aagcatcacc agacagtgct  11880 
ggcctggaag actttaaacc atctcatggg attcttgaat ttgcagataa acaggttact  11940 
gcaatgatag aaatcaccat aattgatgat gctgaatttg aattgacaga gacgttcaat  12000 
acttccttga tcagtgttgc tggaggtggc agacttggtg atgatgttgt ggtaactgtt  12060 
gttattccac aaaatgattc tccatttgga gtatttggat ttgaagaaaa gactgtaatg  12120 
attgatgaat ccctttcatc cgatgaccct gattcatatg tgacattgac ggttgtccgg  12180 
tccccaggag gaaaaggaac cgtccgactt gagtggacca tagatgagaa ggctaaacat  12240 
aaccttagtc ctttgaatgg gacccttcat tttgatgaga ctgagtccca gaagaccatt  12300 
gtgttgcaca cacttcaaga cacagtgttg gaggaggaca ggcgtttcac cattcagctg  12360 
atatcaattg atgaggtaga aatatctcca gtaaaaggta gtgcatcaat aattattcgg  12420 
ggtgataagc gagcatcagg agaagttggg atagctccgt catctaggca catcctcatt  12480 
ggggaaccct cagcaaaata taatggtacc gctattatca gccttgttcg aggcccaggg  12540 
attttggggg aggtcacagt gttctggagg atattccctc cttccgtggg ggaatttgct  12600 
gaaacatcag gaaaactgac aatgcgagac gaacagtctg cagtcattgt agtaatacag  12660 
gctttgaacg atgacattcc cgaggaaaaa agcttctatg agtttcagct cactgcagtc  12720 
agtgagggag gagttctgag tgaatccagc agcactgcca acatcacggt ggtggccagc  12780 
gactctccct atggccgatt tgccttttca catgagcaac ttcgagtgtc agaagcacag  12840 
agggttaaca tcacaatcat ccgttccagt ggagattttg gccatgtgcg actctggtac  12900 
aagacgatga gcgggacagc ggaagcaggc ttggattttg ttcctgcagc aggggagctc  12960 
ctctttgaag caggggagat gaggaaaagt ctgcatgttg aaatccttga tgatgactat  13020 
cctgaaggcc cagaggaatt ttctctaaca attacaaagg tggaactcca gggaagaggg  13080 
tatgatttta ccattcaaga aaatggactt cagatagatc aacctcctga aataggaaac  13140 
atctccattg ttcgcatcat aataatgaaa aatgataacg cagaaggcat cattgaattt  13200 
gacccaaagt atactgcctt cgaagtggag gaagatgttg ggctgatcat gatcccagtg  13260 
gtgaggctac atggaactta tggctatgtg acagctgatt tcatctctca gagctcctct  13320 
gccagtcccg gaggtgttga ttacattttg catggcagta cagtcacctt tcagcatggg  13380 
caaaacttaa gttttataaa tatctccatc attgatgaca atgaaagtga atttgaggag  13440 
cccattgaaa ttctactcac tggagctact ggaggagcgg tccttgggcg ccacctagtg  13500 
agcagaatca taatagctaa gagtgactct ccctttggag ttataaggtt tctcaatcaa  13560 
agcaaaattt ctattgctaa tcccaattcc acaatgattt tatcactggt gctggagcgg  13620 
actggaggac tcttgggaga gattcaggtg aactgggaga cagtaggacc caactctcaa  13680 
gaagccttac tgccacagaa tagagacatt gcagacccag tgagcgggtt gttctatttt  13740 
ggagaaggag aaggaggagt gagaaccata attctgacaa tctatcctca tgaagaaatt  13800 
gaagttgaag agacattcat tattaaactt catcttgtga aaggagaagc taaattagac  13860 
tccagagcta aagatgttac attaaccata caagagtttg gtgacccaaa tggagttgtt  13920 
cagtttgctc ctgaaacttt gtctaagaag acttattcag agcctctggc tctggaaggg  13980 
cccctgctca ttaccttctt tgtcagaaga gtcaagggca cctttggaga gattatggtt  14040 
tactgggaat taagtagtga gtttgacatt actgaagact ttctttccac cagtggattt  14100 
ttcaccattg ctgatggaga gagtgaagct agctttgatg ttcatttgct accagatgag  14160 
gtacctgaga tagaggaaga ttatgtgatc cagcttgttt ctgtagaggg aggagccgaa  14220 
ctggatctgg agaagagtat cacatggttc tctgtttatg caaatgatga cccacatgga  14280 
gtatttgccc tgtattcgga tcgccagtca atacttattg ggcagaacct tattagatcc  14340 
atccaaatta acataacccg gcttgctgga acatttggag atgtggctgt tgggcttcga  14400 
atatcatcgg atcataaaga acagccgatt gttaccgaaa atgcagagag gcagctggtg  14460 
gtcaaagatg gtgccacata taaagtggac gtggtgccaa taaagaatca ggtcttccta  14520 
tcactgggct ctaatttcac tttgcaactg gtgactgtga tgcttgtcgg tggacgtttc  14580 
tatggaatgc caacaattct tcaggaagca aaatctgctg tccttccagt ctctgagaaa  14640 
gctgccaatt ctcaggtcgg atttgaatcc actgcttttc aactcatgaa catcactgct  14700 
ggcacaagcc acgttatgat ttctaggaga ggcacatatg gagctctctc ggttgcctgg  14760 
accactggat atgctcctgg gttagaaatt cctgaattca ttgttgttgg caacatgacc  14820 
ccaacactgg ggagcctttc attttcccac ggtgaacaaa ggaaaggagt tttcctgtgg  14880 
acgtttccta gccctggttg gccagaggcc tttgttcttc acctatcagg agtgcagagc  14940 
agtgctcctg gcggagctca actccgatca ggtttcattg ttgctgaaat tgaaccaatg  15000 
ggcgtcttcc aattttccac tagctcaaga aatatcatag tgtcagaaga tacacagatg  15060 
atcagattac atgtacaaag actatttggg ttccacagcg atcttattaa agtttcttat  15120 
cagaccactg caggaagcgc caagccactg gaagattttg agcctgttca gaatggggaa  15180 
ctgttttttc aaaaattcca aactgaggtt gattttgaaa taaccattat taatgatcag  15240 
ctttctgaga tagaagaatt tttttacatt aaccttactt cagtagaaat taggggatta  15300 
caaaagtttg atgttaattg gagcccacgc ctgaatctag atttcagtgt tgcagtgatt  15360 
acaatattgg ataatgatga cctggcagga atggatattt ccttccccga gacaactgtg  15420 
gctgtagcag ttgacacaac tctcattcct gtagaaactg aatccaccac atacctcagc  15480 
acaagcaaga cgactaccat tctgcagcca accaacgtgg ttgccattgt tactgaggca  15540 
actggtgtat ctgccatccc tgagaaactt gtcacccttc atggcacacc tgctgtgtct  15600 
gaaaagcctg atgtggccac tgtaactgcc aatgtttcca ttcatggaac attcagcctt  15660 
gggccatcca ttgtttatat tgaagaggag atgaagaatg gcacattcaa cactgcagaa  15720 
gttcttatcc gaagaactgg tgggtttact ggcaatgtca gcataacagt taaaactttc  15780 
ggtgaaagat gtgctcagat ggaaccaaat gcattgccct ttcgtggtat ctatgggatt  15840 
tccaacctaa catgggcagt tgaagaagaa gactttgaag aacaaactct tacccttata  15900 
ttcctagatg gagaaagaga acgtaaagta tcagttcaaa ttttggatga tgatgagcct  15960 
gaggggcagg aattcttcta cgtgtttctc acaaaccctc aagggggagc acagattgtg  16020 
gaggggaagg atgatactgg atttgcagct tttgccatgg ttattattac agggagtgac  16080 
cttcacaatg gcatcatagg attcagtgag gagtcccaga gtggactaga actcagggaa  16140 
ggagctgtta tgagaagatt gcaccttatt gtcacaagac agccaaacag ggcctttgaa  16200 
gatgtcaagg tcttttggcg agtcacactt aacaaaacag tcgtcgtgct ccagaaggat  16260 
ggggtaaacc tgatggagga acttcagtct gtgtcaggga ccacaacctg tacaatgggt  16320 
caaacaaaat gctttatcag cattgaactc aaaccagaaa aggtaccaca ggttgaagtg  16380 
tatttttttg tggaactata tgaagctact gctggagcag caataaacaa cagtgccaga  16440 
ttcgcacaga ttaaaatctt agaaagtgat gaatctcaaa gccttgtgta tttttctgtg  16500 
ggttctcggc tggcagtggc tcacaagaag gccactttaa tcagtctgca ggtggccaga  16560 
gattctggga caggactaat gatgtctgtt aactttagta cccaggagtt gaggagtgct  16620 
gaaacaattg gtcgtaccat catatctcca gctatttctg gaaaggattt tgtgataact  16680 
gaaggcacat tggtctttga acctggccag agaagcactg tattggatgt catcctaacg  16740 
ccagagacag gatctttaaa ttcatttcct aaacgcttcc agattgtcct ttttgaccca  16800 
aaaggtggtg ccagaattga taaagtgtat gggactgcca acatcactct tgtctcagat  16860 
gcagattcgc aggccatttg ggggcttgca gatcagctac atcagcctgt gaatgatgat  16920 
attctcaaca gagtgctcca taccatcagc atgaaagtgg ccacagaaaa cacagatgaa  16980 
caactcagtg ccatgatgca tttaatagaa aagataacta ctgaaggaaa aattcaagct  17040 
ttcagtgttg ccagccgaac tcttttctat gagattcttt gttctcttat taacccaaag  17100 
cgcaaggaca ctaggggatt cagtcacttt gctgaagtga ctgagaattt tgccttttct  17160 
ctgctgacta atgttacttg cggctctcct ggtgaaaaaa gcaaaaccat ccttgatagt  17220 
tgcccatatt tgtcaatatt ggctcttcac tggtatcctc agcaaatcaa tggacacaag  17280 
tttgaaggaa aggaaggaga ttacattcga attccagaga ggctactgga tgtccaggat  17340 
gcagaaataa tggctgggaa aagtacatgt aaattagtcc agtttacaga gtatagcagc  17400 
caacagtggt ttataagtgg aaacaatctt cctaccctaa aaaataaggt attatctttg  17460 
agtgtgaaag gtcagagttc acaactcctg actaatgaca atgaggttct ctacaggatt  17520 
tatgctgctg agcctagaat tattcctcag acatctctgt gtctcctttg gaatcaggct  17580 
gctgcaagct ggttgtctga cagtcagttt tgcaaagtgg ttgaggaaac tgcagactat  17640 
gtggaatgtg cctgttcaca catgtctgtg tatgctgtct atgctcggac tgacaacttg  17700 
tcttcataca atgaagcctt cttcacttct ggatttatat gtatctcagg tctttgcttg  17760 
gctgttcttt cccatatctt ctgtgccagg tactccatgt ttgcagctaa acttctgact  17820 
cacatgatgg cagccagctt aggtacacag attctgtttc tggcgtctgc atacgcaagt  17880 
ccccaactcg ctgaggagag ctgttcagct atggctgctg tcacacatta cctgtatctt  17940 
tgccagttta gctggatgct cattcagtct gtgaatttct ggtacgtgct ggtgatgaat  18000 
gatgagcaca cagagaggcg atatctgctg tttttccttc tgagttgggg actaccagct  18060 
tttgtggtga ttctcctcat agttattttg aaaggaatct atcatcagag catgtcacag  18120 
atctatggac tcattcatgg tgacctgtgt tttattccaa acgtctatgc tgctttgttc  18180 
actgcagctc ttgttccttt gacgtgcctc gtggtggtgt tcgtggtgtt catccatgcc  18240 
taccaggtga agccacagtg gaaagcatat gatgatgtct tcagaggaag gacaaatgct  18300 
gcagaaattc cactgatttt atatctcttt gctctgattt ccgtgacatg gctttgggga  18360 
ggactacaca tggcctacag acacttctgg atgttggttc tctttgtcat tttcaacagt  18420 
ctgcagggac tttatgtttt catggtttat ttcattttac acaaccaaat gtgttgccct  18480 
atgaaggcca gttacactgt ggaaatgaat gggcatcctg gacccagcac agcctttttc  18540 
acgcccggga gtggaatgcc tcctgctgga ggggaaatca gcaagtccac ccagaatctc  18600 
atcggtgcta tggaggaggt gccacctgac tgggagagag catccttcca acagggcagt  18660 
caggccagcc ctgatttaaa gccaagtcca caaaatggag ccacgttccc gtcctctgga  18720 
ggatatggcc aggggtcact gatagccgat gaggagtccc aggagtttga tgatttaata  18780 
tttgcattaa aaactggtgc tggtctcagt gtcagtgata atgaatctgg tcaaggcagc  18840 
caggaggggg gcaccttgac tgactcccag atcgtggagc tcaggaggat acccatcgcc  18900 
gacactcacc tgtagcacct cactaaccat tcgactgagc acactt                 18946 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>16 </s210>
<s211>6304 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>human </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 16 
Met Ser Asp Leu Lys Glu Gly Met Pro Ser Ala Ser Leu Leu Val Asn 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Leu Leu Ser Ala Leu Leu Ile Leu Phe Val Phe Gly Glu Thr Glu Ile 
            20                  25                  30 
Arg Phe Thr Gly Gln Thr Glu Phe Val Val Asn Glu Thr Ser Thr Thr 
        35                  40                  45 
Val Ile Arg Leu Ile Ile Glu Arg Ile Gly Glu Pro Ala Asn Val Thr 
    50                  55                  60 
Ala Ile Val Ser Leu Tyr Gly Glu Asp Ala Gly Asp Phe Phe Asp Thr 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Tyr Ala Ala Ala Phe Ile Pro Ala Gly Glu Thr Asn Arg Thr Val Tyr 
                85                  90                  95 
Ile Ala Val Cys Asp Asp Asp Leu Pro Glu Pro Asp Glu Thr Phe Ile 
            100                 105                 110 
Phe His Leu Thr Leu Gln Lys Pro Ser Ala Asn Val Lys Leu Gly Trp 
        115                 120                 125 
Pro Arg Thr Val Thr Val Thr Ile Leu Ser Asn Asp Asn Ala Phe Gly 
    130                 135                 140 
Ile Ile Ser Phe Asn Met Leu Pro Ser Ile Ala Val Ser Glu Pro Lys 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Gly Arg Asn Glu Ser Met Pro Leu Thr Leu Ile Arg Glu Lys Gly Thr 
                165                 170                 175 
Tyr Gly Met Val Met Val Thr Phe Glu Val Glu Gly Gly Pro Asn Pro 
            180                 185                 190 
Pro Asp Glu Asp Leu Ser Pro Val Lys Gly Asn Ile Thr Phe Pro Pro 
        195                 200                 205 
Gly Arg Ala Thr Val Ile Tyr Asn Leu Thr Val Leu Asp Asp Glu Val 
    210                 215                 220 
Pro Glu Asn Asp Glu Ile Phe Leu Ile Gln Leu Lys Ser Val Glu Gly 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Gly Ala Glu Ile Asn Thr Ser Arg Asn Ser Ile Glu Ile Ile Ile Lys 
                245                 250                 255 
Lys Asn Asp Ser Pro Val Arg Phe Leu Gln Ser Ile Tyr Leu Val Pro 
            260                 265                 270 
Glu Glu Asp His Ile Leu Ile Ile Pro Val Val Arg Gly Lys Asp Asn 
        275                 280                 285 
Asn Gly Asn Leu Ile Gly Ser Asp Glu Tyr Glu Val Ser Ile Ser Tyr 
    290                 295                 300 
Ala Val Thr Thr Gly Asn Ser Thr Ala His Ala Gln Gln Asn Leu Asp 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Phe Ile Asp Leu Gln Pro Asn Thr Thr Val Val Phe Pro Pro Phe Ile 
                325                 330                 335 
His Glu Ser His Leu Lys Phe Gln Ile Val Asp Asp Thr Ile Pro Glu 
            340                 345                 350 
Ile Ala Glu Ser Phe His Ile Met Leu Leu Lys Asp Thr Leu Gln Gly 
        355                 360                 365 
Asp Ala Val Leu Ile Ser Pro Ser Val Val Gln Val Thr Ile Lys Pro 
    370                 375                 380 
Asn Asp Lys Pro Tyr Gly Val Leu Ser Phe Asn Ser Val Leu Phe Glu 
385                 390                 395                 400 
Arg Thr Val Ile Ile Asp Glu Asp Arg Ile Ser Arg Tyr Glu Glu Ile 
                405                 410                 415 
Thr Val Val Arg Asn Gly Gly Thr His Gly Asn Val Ser Ala Asn Trp 
            420                 425                 430 
Val Leu Thr Arg Asn Ser Thr Asp Pro Ser Pro Val Thr Ala Asp Ile 
        435                 440                 445 
Arg Pro Ser Ser Gly Val Leu His Phe Ala Gln Gly Gln Met Leu Ala 
    450                 455                 460 
Thr Ile Pro Leu Thr Val Val Asp Asp Asp Leu Pro Glu Glu Ala Glu 
465                 470                 475                 480 
Ala Tyr Leu Leu Gln Ile Leu Pro His Thr Ile Arg Gly Gly Ala Glu 
                485                 490                 495 
Val Ser Glu Pro Ala Glu Leu Leu Phe Tyr Ile Gln Asp Ser Asp Asp 
            500                 505                 510 
Val Tyr Gly Leu Ile Thr Phe Phe Pro Met Glu Asn Gln Lys Ile Glu 
        515                 520                 525 
Ser Ser Pro Cys Glu Arg Tyr Leu Ser Leu Ser Phe Thr Arg Leu Gly 
    530                 535                 540 
Gly Thr Lys Gly Asp Val Arg Leu Leu Tyr Ser Val Leu Tyr Ile Pro 
545                 550                 555                 560 
Ala Gly Ala Val Asp Pro Leu Gln Ala Lys Glu Gly Ile Leu Asn Ile 
                565                 570                 575 
Ser Arg Arg Asn Asp Leu Ile Phe Pro Glu Gln Lys Thr Gln Val Thr 
            580                 585                 590 
Thr Lys Leu Pro Ile Arg Asn Asp Ala Phe Leu Gln Asn Gly Ala His 
        595                 600                 605 
Phe Leu Val Gln Leu Glu Thr Val Glu Leu Leu Asn Ile Ile Pro Leu 
    610                 615                 620 
Ile Pro Pro Ile Ser Pro Arg Phe Gly Glu Ile Cys Asn Ile Ser Leu 
625                 630                 635                 640 
Leu Val Thr Pro Ala Ile Ala Asn Gly Glu Ile Gly Phe Leu Ser Asn 
                645                 650                 655 
Leu Pro Ile Ile Leu His Glu Pro Glu Asp Phe Ala Ala Glu Val Val 
            660                 665                 670 
Tyr Ile Pro Leu His Arg Asp Gly Thr Asp Gly Gln Ala Thr Val Tyr 
        675                 680                 685 
Trp Ser Leu Lys Pro Ser Gly Phe Asn Ser Lys Ala Val Thr Pro Asp 
    690                 695                 700 
Asp Ile Gly Pro Phe Asn Gly Ser Val Leu Phe Leu Ser Gly Gln Ser 
705                 710                 715                 720 
Asp Thr Thr Ile Asn Ile Thr Ile Lys Gly Asp Asp Ile Pro Glu Met 
                725                 730                 735 
Asn Glu Thr Val Thr Leu Ser Leu Asp Arg Val Asn Val Glu Asn Gln 
            740                 745                 750 
Val Leu Lys Ser Gly Tyr Thr Ser Arg Asp Leu Ile Ile Leu Glu Asn 
        755                 760                 765 
Asp Asp Pro Gly Gly Val Phe Glu Phe Ser Pro Ala Ser Arg Gly Pro 
    770                 775                 780 
Tyr Val Ile Lys Glu Gly Glu Ser Val Glu Leu His Ile Ile Arg Ser 
785                 790                 795                 800 
Arg Gly Ser Leu Val Lys Gln Phe Leu His Tyr Arg Val Glu Pro Arg 
                805                 810                 815 
Asp Ser Asn Glu Phe Tyr Gly Asn Thr Gly Val Leu Glu Phe Lys Pro 
            820                 825                 830 
Gly Glu Arg Glu Ile Val Ile Thr Leu Leu Ala Arg Leu Asp Gly Ile 
        835                 840                 845 
Pro Glu Leu Asp Glu His Tyr Trp Val Val Leu Ser Ser His Gly Glu 
    850                 855                 860 
Arg Glu Ser Lys Leu Gly Ser Ala Thr Ile Val Asn Ile Thr Ile Leu 
865                 870                 875                 880 
Lys Asn Asp Asp Pro His Gly Ile Ile Glu Phe Val Ser Asp Gly Leu 
                885                 890                 895 
Ile Val Met Ile Asn Glu Ser Lys Gly Asp Ala Ile Tyr Ser Ala Val 
            900                 905                 910 
Tyr Asp Val Val Arg Asn Arg Gly Asn Phe Gly Asp Val Ser Val Ser 
        915                 920                 925 
Trp Val Val Ser Pro Asp Phe Thr Gln Asp Val Phe Pro Val Gln Gly 
    930                 935                 940 
Thr Val Val Phe Gly Asp Gln Glu Phe Ser Lys Asn Ile Thr Ile Tyr 
945                 950                 955                 960 
Ser Leu Pro Asp Glu Ile Pro Glu Glu Met Glu Glu Phe Thr Val Ile 
                965                 970                 975 
Leu Leu Asn Gly Thr Gly Gly Ala Lys Val Gly Asn Arg Thr Thr Ala 
            980                 985                 990 
Thr Leu Arg Ile Arg Arg Ile Asp Asp Pro Ile Tyr Phe Ala Glu Pro 
        995                 1000                1005 
Arg Val Val Arg Val Gln Glu Gly Glu Thr Ala Asn Phe Thr Val Leu 
    1010                1015                1020 
Arg Asn Gly Ser Val Asp Val Thr Cys Met Val Gln Tyr Ala Thr Lys 
1025                1030                1035                1040 
Asp Gly Lys Ala Thr Ala Arg Glu Arg Asp Phe Ile Pro Val Glu Lys 
                1045                1050                1055 
Gly Glu Thr Leu Ile Phe Glu Val Gly Ser Arg Gln Gln Ser Ile Ser 
            1060                1065                1070 
Ile Phe Val Asn Glu Asp Gly Ile Pro Glu Thr Asp Glu Pro Phe Tyr 
        1075                1080                1085 
Ile Ile Leu Leu Asn Ser Thr Gly Asp Thr Val Val Tyr Gln Tyr Gly 
    1090                1095                1100 
Val Ala Thr Val Ile Ile Glu Ala Asn Asp Asp Pro Asn Gly Ile Phe 
1105                1110                1115                1120 
Ser Leu Glu Pro Ile Asp Lys Ala Val Glu Glu Gly Lys Thr Asn Ala 
                1125                1130                1135 
Phe Trp Ile Leu Arg His Arg Gly Tyr Phe Gly Ser Val Ser Val Ser 
            1140                1145                1150 
Trp Gln Leu Phe Gln Asn Asp Ser Ala Leu Gln Pro Gly Gln Glu Phe 
        1155                1160                1165 
Tyr Glu Thr Ser Gly Thr Val Asn Phe Met Asp Gly Glu Glu Ala Lys 
    1170                1175                1180 
Pro Ile Ile Leu His Ala Phe Pro Asp Lys Ile Pro Glu Phe Asn Glu 
1185                1190                1195                1200 
Phe Tyr Phe Leu Lys Leu Val Asn Ile Ser Gly Gly Ser Pro Gly Pro 
                1205                1210                1215 
Gly Gly Gln Leu Ala Glu Thr Asn Leu Gln Val Thr Val Met Val Pro 
            1220                1225                1230 
Phe Asn Asp Asp Pro Phe Gly Val Phe Ile Leu Asp Pro Glu Cys Leu 
        1235                1240                1245 
Glu Arg Glu Val Ala Glu Asp Val Leu Ser Glu Asp Asp Met Ser Tyr 
    1250                1255                1260 
Ile Thr Asn Phe Thr Ile Leu Arg Gln Gln Gly Val Phe Gly Asp Val 
1265                1270                1275                1280 
Gln Leu Gly Trp Glu Ile Leu Ser Ser Glu Phe Pro Ala Gly Leu Pro 
                1285                1290                1295 
Pro Met Ile Asp Phe Leu Leu Val Gly Ile Phe Pro Thr Thr Val His 
            1300                1305                1310 
Leu Gln Gln His Met Arg Arg His His Ser Gly Thr Asp Ala Leu Tyr 
        1315                1320                1325 
Phe Thr Gly Leu Glu Gly Ala Phe Gly Thr Val Asn Pro Lys Tyr His 
    1330                1335                1340 
Pro Ser Arg Asn Asn Thr Ile Ala Asn Phe Thr Phe Ser Ala Trp Val 
1345                1350                1355                1360 
Met Pro Asn Ala Asn Thr Asn Gly Phe Ile Ile Ala Lys Asp Asp Gly 
                1365                1370                1375 
Asn Gly Ser Ile Tyr Tyr Gly Val Lys Ile Gln Thr Asn Glu Ser His 
            1380                1385                1390 
Val Thr Leu Ser Leu His Tyr Lys Thr Leu Gly Ser Asn Ala Thr Tyr 
        1395                1400                1405 
Ile Ala Lys Thr Thr Val Met Lys Tyr Leu Glu Glu Ser Val Trp Leu 
    1410                1415                1420 
His Leu Leu Ile Ile Leu Glu Asp Gly Ile Ile Glu Phe Tyr Leu Asp 
1425                1430                1435                1440 
Gly Asn Ala Met Pro Arg Gly Ile Lys Ser Leu Lys Gly Glu Ala Ile 
                1445                1450                1455 
Thr Asp Gly Pro Gly Ile Leu Arg Ile Gly Ala Gly Ile Asn Gly Asn 
            1460                1465                1470 
Asp Arg Phe Thr Gly Leu Met Gln Asp Val Arg Ser Tyr Glu Arg Lys 
        1475                1480                1485 
Leu Thr Leu Glu Glu Ile Tyr Glu Leu His Ala Met Pro Ala Lys Ser 
    1490                1495                1500 
Asp Leu His Pro Ile Ser Gly Tyr Leu Glu Phe Arg Gln Gly Glu Thr 
1505                1510                1515                1520 
Asn Lys Ser Phe Ile Ile Ser Ala Arg Asp Asp Asn Asp Glu Glu Gly 
                1525                1530                1535 
Glu Glu Leu Phe Ile Leu Lys Leu Val Ser Val Tyr Gly Gly Ala Arg 
            1540                1545                1550 
Ile Ser Glu Glu Asn Thr Thr Ala Arg Leu Thr Ile Gln Lys Ser Asp 
        1555                1560                1565 
Asn Ala Asn Gly Leu Phe Gly Phe Thr Gly Ala Cys Ile Pro Glu Ile 
    1570                1575                1580 
Ala Glu Glu Gly Ser Thr Ile Ser Cys Val Val Glu Arg Thr Arg Gly 
1585                1590                1595                1600 
Ala Leu Asp Tyr Val His Val Phe Tyr Thr Ile Ser Gln Ile Glu Thr 
                1605                1610                1615 
Asp Gly Ile Asn Tyr Leu Val Asp Asp Phe Ala Asn Ala Ser Gly Thr 
            1620                1625                1630 
Ile Thr Phe Leu Pro Trp Gln Arg Ser Glu Val Leu Asn Ile Tyr Val 
        1635                1640                1645 
Leu Asp Asp Asp Ile Pro Glu Leu Asn Glu Tyr Phe Arg Val Thr Leu 
    1650                1655                1660 
Val Ser Ala Ile Pro Gly Asp Gly Lys Leu Gly Ser Thr Pro Thr Ser 
1665                1670                1675                1680 
Gly Ala Ser Ile Asp Pro Glu Lys Glu Thr Thr Asp Ile Thr Ile Lys 
                1685                1690                1695 
Ala Ser Asp His Pro Tyr Gly Leu Leu Gln Phe Ser Thr Gly Leu Pro 
            1700                1705                1710 
Pro Gln Pro Lys Asp Ala Met Thr Leu Pro Ala Ser Ser Val Pro His 
        1715                1720                1725 
Ile Thr Val Glu Glu Glu Asp Gly Glu Ile Arg Leu Leu Val Ile Arg 
    1730                1735                1740 
Ala Gln Gly Leu Leu Gly Arg Val Thr Ala Glu Phe Arg Thr Val Ser 
1745                1750                1755                1760 
Leu Thr Ala Phe Ser Pro Glu Asp Tyr Gln Asn Val Ala Gly Thr Leu 
                1765                1770                1775 
Glu Phe Gln Pro Gly Glu Arg Tyr Lys Tyr Ile Phe Ile Asn Ile Thr 
            1780                1785                1790 
Asp Asn Ser Ile Pro Glu Leu Glu Lys Ser Phe Lys Val Glu Leu Leu 
        1795                1800                1805 
Asn Leu Glu Gly Gly Ala Glu Leu Phe Arg Val Asp Gly Ser Gly Ser 
    1810                1815                1820 
Gly Asp Gly Asp Met Glu Phe Phe Leu Pro Thr Ile His Lys Arg Ala 
1825                1830                1835                1840 
Ser Leu Gly Val Ala Ser Gln Ile Leu Val Thr Ile Ala Ala Ser Asp 
                1845                1850                1855 
His Ala His Gly Val Phe Glu Phe Ser Pro Glu Ser Leu Phe Val Ser 
            1860                1865                1870 
Gly Thr Glu Pro Glu Asp Gly Tyr Ser Thr Val Thr Leu Asn Val Ile 
        1875                1880                1885 
Arg His His Gly Thr Leu Ser Pro Val Thr Leu His Trp Asn Ile Asp 
    1890                1895                1900 
Ser Asp Pro Asp Gly Asp Leu Ala Phe Thr Ser Gly Asn Ile Thr Phe 
1905                1910                1915                1920 
Glu Ile Gly Gln Met Ser Ala Asn Ile Thr Val Glu Ile Leu Ser Asp 
                1925                1930                1935 
Glu Asp Pro Glu Leu Asp Lys Ala Phe Ser Val Ser Ile Leu Ser Val 
            1940                1945                1950 
Ser Ser Gly Ser Leu Gly Ala His Ile Asn Ala Thr Leu Thr Val Leu 
        1955                1960                1965 
Ala Ser Asp Asp Pro Tyr Gly Ile Phe Ile Phe Ser Glu Lys Asn Arg 
    1970                1975                1980 
Pro Val Lys Val Glu Glu Ala Thr Gln Asn Ile Thr Leu Ser Ile Ile 
1985                1990                1995                2000 
Arg Leu Lys Gly Leu Met Gly Lys Val Leu Val Ser Tyr Ala Thr Leu 
                2005                2010                2015 
Asp Asp Met Glu Lys Pro Pro Tyr Phe Pro Pro Asn Leu Ala Arg Ala 
            2020                2025                2030 
Thr Gln Gly Arg Asp Tyr Ile Pro Ala Ser Gly Phe Ala Leu Phe Gly 
        2035                2040                2045 
Ala Asn Gln Ser Glu Ala Thr Ile Ala Ile Ser Ile Leu Asp Asp Asp 
    2050                2055                2060 
Glu Pro Glu Arg Ser Glu Ser Val Phe Ile Glu Leu Leu Asn Ser Thr 
2065                2070                2075                2080 
Leu Val Ala Lys Val Gln Ser Arg Ser Ile Pro Asn Ser Pro Arg Leu 
                2085                2090                2095 
Gly Pro Lys Val Glu Thr Ile Ala Gln Leu Ile Ile Ile Ala Asn Asp 
            2100                2105                2110 
Asp Ala Phe Gly Thr Leu Gln Leu Ser Ala Pro Ile Val Arg Val Ala 
        2115                2120                2125 
Glu Asn His Val Gly Pro Ile Ile Asn Val Thr Arg Thr Gly Gly Ala 
    2130                2135                2140 
Phe Ala Asp Val Ser Val Lys Phe Lys Ala Val Pro Ile Thr Ala Ile 
2145                2150                2155                2160 
Ala Gly Glu Asp Tyr Ser Ile Ala Ser Ser Asp Val Val Leu Leu Glu 
                2165                2170                2175 
Gly Glu Thr Ser Lys Ala Val Pro Ile Tyr Val Ile Asn Asp Ile Tyr 
            2180                2185                2190 
Pro Glu Leu Glu Glu Ser Phe Leu Val Gln Leu Met Asn Glu Thr Thr 
        2195                2200                2205 
Gly Gly Ala Arg Leu Gly Ala Leu Thr Glu Ala Val Ile Ile Ile Glu 
    2210                2215                2220 
Ala Ser Asp Asp Pro Tyr Gly Leu Phe Gly Phe Gln Ile Thr Lys Leu 
2225                2230                2235                2240 
Ile Val Glu Glu Pro Glu Phe Asn Ser Val Lys Ile Asn Leu Pro Ile 
                2245                2250                2255 
Ile Arg Asn Ser Gly Thr Leu Gly Asn Val Thr Val Gln Trp Val Ala 
            2260                2265                2270 
Thr Ile Asn Gly Gln Leu Ala Thr Gly Asp Leu Arg Val Val Ser Gly 
        2275                2280                2285 
Asn Val Thr Phe Ala Pro Gly Glu Thr Ile Gln Thr Leu Leu Leu Glu 
    2290                2295                2300 
Val Leu Ala Asp Asp Val Pro Glu Ile Glu Glu Val Ile Gln Val Gln 
2305                2310                2315                2320 
Leu Thr Asp Ala Ser Gly Gly Gly Thr Ile Gly Leu Asp Arg Ile Ala 
                2325                2330                2335 
Asn Ile Ile Ile Pro Ala Asn Asp Asp Pro Tyr Gly Thr Val Ala Phe 
            2340                2345                2350 
Ala Gln Met Val Tyr Arg Val Gln Glu Pro Leu Glu Arg Ser Ser Cys 
        2355                2360                2365 
Ala Asn Ile Thr Val Arg Arg Ser Gly Gly His Phe Gly Arg Leu Leu 
    2370                2375                2380 
Leu Phe Tyr Ser Thr Ser Asp Ile Asp Val Val Ala Leu Ala Met Glu 
2385                2390                2395                2400 
Glu Gly Gln Asp Leu Leu Ser Tyr Tyr Glu Ser Pro Ile Gln Gly Val 
                2405                2410                2415 
Pro Asp Pro Leu Trp Arg Thr Trp Met Asn Val Ser Ala Val Gly Glu 
            2420                2425                2430 
Pro Leu Tyr Thr Cys Ala Thr Leu Cys Leu Lys Glu Gln Ala Cys Ser 
        2435                2440                2445 
Ala Phe Ser Phe Phe Ser Ala Ser Glu Gly Pro Gln Arg Phe Trp Met 
    2450                2455                2460 
Thr Ser Trp Ile Ser Pro Ala Val Asn Asn Ser Asp Phe Trp Thr Tyr 
2465                2470                2475                2480 
Arg Lys Asn Met Thr Arg Val Ala Ser Leu Phe Ser Gly Gln Ala Val 
                2485                2490                2495 
Ala Gly Ser Asp Tyr Glu Pro Val Thr Arg Gln Trp Ala Ile Met Gln 
            2500                2505                2510 
Glu Gly Asp Glu Phe Ala Asn Leu Thr Val Ser Ile Leu Pro Asp Asp 
        2515                2520                2525 
Phe Pro Glu Met Asp Glu Ser Phe Leu Ile Ser Leu Leu Glu Val His 
    2530                2535                2540 
Leu Met Asn Ile Ser Ala Ser Leu Lys Asn Gln Pro Thr Ile Gly Gln 
2545                2550                2555                2560 
Pro Asn Ile Ser Thr Val Val Ile Ala Leu Asn Gly Asp Ala Phe Gly 
                2565                2570                2575 
Val Phe Val Ile Tyr Ser Ile Ser Pro Asn Thr Ser Glu Asp Gly Leu 
            2580                2585                2590 
Phe Val Glu Val Gln Glu Gln Pro Gln Thr Leu Val Glu Leu Met Ile 
        2595                2600                2605 
His Arg Thr Gly Gly Ser Leu Gly Gln Val Ala Val Glu Trp Arg Val 
    2610                2615                2620 
Val Gly Gly Thr Ala Thr Glu Gly Leu Asp Phe Ile Gly Ala Gly Glu 
2625                2630                2635                2640 
Ile Leu Thr Phe Ala Glu Gly Glu Thr Lys Lys Thr Val Ile Leu Thr 
                2645                2650                2655 
Ile Leu Asp Asp Ser Glu Pro Glu Asp Asp Glu Ser Ile Ile Val Ser 
            2660                2665                2670 
Leu Val Tyr Thr Glu Gly Gly Ser Arg Ile Leu Pro Ser Ser Asp Thr 
        2675                2680                2685 
Val Arg Val Asn Ile Leu Ala Asn Asp Asn Val Ala Gly Ile Val Ser 
    2690                2695                2700 
Phe Gln Thr Ala Ser Arg Ser Val Ile Gly His Glu Gly Glu Ile Leu 
2705                2710                2715                2720 
Gln Phe His Val Ile Arg Thr Phe Pro Gly Arg Gly Asn Val Thr Val 
                2725                2730                2735 
Asn Trp Lys Ile Ile Gly Gln Asn Leu Glu Leu Asn Phe Ala Asn Phe 
            2740                2745                2750 
Ser Gly Gln Leu Phe Phe Pro Glu Gly Ser Leu Asn Thr Thr Leu Phe 
        2755                2760                2765 
Val His Leu Leu Asp Asp Asn Ile Pro Glu Glu Lys Glu Val Tyr Gln 
    2770                2775                2780 
Val Ile Leu Tyr Asp Val Arg Thr Gln Gly Val Pro Pro Ala Gly Ile 
2785                2790                2795                2800 
Ala Leu Leu Asp Ala Gln Gly Tyr Ala Ala Val Leu Thr Val Glu Ala 
                2805                2810                2815 
Ser Asp Glu Pro His Gly Val Leu Asn Phe Ala Leu Ser Ser Arg Phe 
            2820                2825                2830 
Val Leu Leu Gln Glu Ala Asn Ile Thr Ile Gln Leu Phe Ile Asn Arg 
        2835                2840                2845 
Glu Phe Gly Ser Leu Gly Ala Ile Asn Val Thr Tyr Thr Thr Val Pro 
    2850                2855                2860 
Gly Met Leu Ser Leu Lys Asn Gln Thr Val Gly Asn Leu Ala Glu Pro 
2865                2870                2875                2880 
Glu Val Asp Phe Val Pro Ile Ile Gly Phe Leu Ile Leu Glu Glu Gly 
                2885                2890                2895 
Glu Thr Ala Ala Ala Ile Asn Ile Thr Ile Leu Glu Asp Asp Val Pro 
            2900                2905                2910 
Glu Leu Glu Glu Tyr Phe Leu Val Asn Leu Thr Tyr Val Gly Leu Thr 
        2915                2920                2925 
Met Ala Ala Ser Thr Ser Phe Pro Pro Arg Leu Asp Ser Glu Gly Leu 
    2930                2935                2940 
Thr Ala Gln Val Ile Ile Asp Ala Asn Asp Gly Ala Arg Gly Val Ile 
2945                2950                2955                2960 
Glu Trp Gln Gln Ser Arg Phe Glu Val Asn Glu Thr His Gly Ser Leu 
                2965                2970                2975 
Thr Leu Val Ala Gln Arg Ser Arg Glu Pro Leu Gly His Val Ser Leu 
            2980                2985                2990 
Phe Val Tyr Ala Gln Asn Leu Glu Ala Gln Val Gly Leu Asp Tyr Ile 
        2995                3000                3005 
Phe Thr Pro Met Ile Leu His Phe Ala Asp Gly Glu Arg Tyr Lys Asn 
    3010                3015                3020 
Val Asn Ile Met Ile Leu Asp Asp Asp Ile Pro Glu Gly Asp Glu Lys 
3025                3030                3035                3040 
Phe Gln Leu Ile Leu Thr Asn Pro Ser Pro Gly Leu Glu Leu Gly Lys 
                3045                3050                3055 
Asn Thr Ile Ala Leu Ile Ile Val Leu Ala Asn Asp Asp Gly Pro Gly 
            3060                3065                3070 
Val Leu Ser Phe Asn Asn Ser Glu His Phe Phe Leu Arg Glu Pro Thr 
        3075                3080                3085 
Ala Leu Tyr Val Gln Glu Ser Val Ala Val Leu Tyr Ile Val Arg Glu 
    3090                3095                3100 
Pro Ala Gln Gly Leu Phe Gly Thr Val Thr Val Gln Phe Ile Val Thr 
3105                3110                3115                3120 
Glu Val Asn Ser Ser Asn Glu Ser Lys Asp Leu Thr Pro Ser Lys Gly 
                3125                3130                3135 
Tyr Ile Val Leu Glu Glu Gly Val Arg Phe Lys Ala Leu Gln Ile Ser 
            3140                3145                3150 
Ala Ile Leu Asp Thr Glu Pro Glu Met Asp Glu Tyr Phe Val Cys Thr 
        3155                3160                3165 
Leu Phe Asn Pro Thr Gly Gly Ala Arg Leu Gly Val His Val Gln Thr 
    3170                3175                3180 
Leu Ile Thr Val Leu Gln Asn Gln Ala Pro Leu Gly Leu Phe Ser Ile 
3185                3190                3195                3200 
Ser Ala Val Glu Asn Arg Ala Thr Ser Ile Asp Ile Glu Glu Ala Asn 
                3205                3210                3215 
Arg Thr Val Tyr Leu Asn Val Ser Arg Thr Asn Gly Ile Asp Leu Ala 
            3220                3225                3230 
Val Ser Val Gln Trp Glu Thr Val Ser Glu Thr Ala Phe Gly Met Gly 
        3235                3240                3245 
Gly Met Asp Val Val Phe Ser Val Phe Gln Ser Phe Leu Asp Glu Ser 
    3250                3255                3260 
Ala Ser Gly Trp Cys Phe Phe Thr Leu Glu Asn Leu Ile Tyr Gly Ile 
3265                3270                3275                3280 
Met Leu Arg Lys Ser Ser Val Thr Val Tyr Arg Trp Gln Gly Ile Phe 
                3285                3290                3295 
Ile Pro Val Glu Asp Leu Asn Ile Glu Asn Pro Lys Thr Cys Glu Ala 
            3300                3305                3310 
Phe Asn Ile Gly Phe Ser Pro Tyr Phe Val Ile Thr His Glu Glu Arg 
        3315                3320                3325 
Asn Glu Glu Lys Pro Ser Leu Asn Ser Val Phe Thr Phe Thr Ser Gly 
    3330                3335                3340 
Phe Lys Leu Phe Leu Val Gln Thr Ile Ile Ile Leu Glu Ser Ser Gln 
3345                3350                3355                3360 
Val Arg Tyr Phe Thr Ser Asp Ser Gln Asp Tyr Leu Ile Ile Ala Ser 
                3365                3370                3375 
Gln Arg Asp Asp Ser Glu Leu Thr Gln Val Phe Arg Trp Asn Gly Gly 
            3380                3385                3390 
Ser Phe Val Leu His Gln Lys Leu Pro Val Arg Gly Val Leu Thr Val 
        3395                3400                3405 
Ala Leu Phe Asn Lys Gly Gly Ser Val Phe Leu Ala Ile Ser Gln Ala 
    3410                3415                3420 
Asn Ala Arg Leu Asn Ser Leu Leu Phe Arg Trp Ser Gly Ser Gly Phe 
3425                3430                3435                3440 
Ile Asn Phe Gln Glu Val Pro Val Ser Gly Thr Thr Glu Val Glu Ala 
                3445                3450                3455 
Leu Ser Ser Ala Asn Asp Ile Tyr Leu Ile Phe Ala Lys Asn Val Phe 
            3460                3465                3470 
Leu Gly Asp Gln Asn Ser Ile Asp Ile Phe Ile Trp Glu Met Gly Gln 
        3475                3480                3485 
Ser Ser Phe Arg Tyr Phe Gln Ser Val Asp Phe Ala Ala Val Asn Arg 
    3490                3495                3500 
Ile His Ser Phe Thr Pro Ala Ser Gly Ile Ala His Ile Leu Leu Ile 
3505                3510                3515                3520 
Gly Gln Asp Met Ser Ala Leu Tyr Cys Trp Asn Ser Glu Arg Asn Gln 
                3525                3530                3535 
Phe Ser Phe Val Leu Glu Val Pro Ser Ala Tyr Asp Val Ala Ser Val 
            3540                3545                3550 
Thr Val Lys Ser Leu Asn Ser Ser Lys Asn Leu Ile Ala Leu Val Gly 
        3555                3560                3565 
Ala His Ser His Ile Tyr Glu Leu Ala Tyr Ile Ser Ser His Ser Asp 
    3570                3575                3580 
Phe Ile Pro Ser Ser Gly Glu Leu Ile Phe Glu Pro Gly Glu Arg Glu 
3585                3590                3595                3600 
Ala Thr Ile Ala Val Asn Ile Leu Asp Asp Thr Val Pro Glu Lys Glu 
                3605                3610                3615 
Glu Ser Phe Lys Val Gln Leu Lys Asn Pro Lys Gly Gly Ala Glu Ile 
            3620                3625                3630 
Gly Ile Asn Asp Ser Val Thr Ile Thr Ile Leu Ser Asn Asp Asp Ala 
        3635                3640                3645 
Tyr Gly Ile Val Ala Phe Ala Gln Asn Ser Leu Tyr Lys Gln Val Glu 
    3650                3655                3660 
Glu Met Glu Gln Asp Ser Leu Val Thr Leu Asn Val Glu Arg Leu Lys 
3665                3670                3675                3680 
Gly Thr Tyr Gly Arg Ile Thr Ile Ala Trp Glu Ala Asp Gly Ser Ile 
                3685                3690                3695 
Ser Asp Ile Phe Pro Thr Ser Gly Val Ile Leu Phe Thr Glu Gly Gln 
            3700                3705                3710 
Val Leu Ser Thr Ile Thr Leu Thr Ile Leu Ala Asp Asn Ile Pro Glu 
        3715                3720                3725 
Leu Ser Glu Val Val Ile Val Thr Leu Thr Arg Ile Thr Thr Glu Gly 
    3730                3735                3740 
Val Glu Asp Ser Tyr Lys Gly Ala Thr Ile Asp Gln Asp Arg Ser Lys 
3745                3750                3755                3760 
Ser Val Ile Thr Thr Leu Pro Asn Asp Ser Pro Phe Gly Leu Val Gly 
                3765                3770                3775 
Trp Arg Ala Ala Ser Val Phe Ile Arg Val Ala Glu Pro Lys Glu Asn 
            3780                3785                3790 
Thr Thr Thr Leu Gln Leu Gln Ile Ala Arg Asp Lys Gly Leu Leu Gly 
        3795                3800                3805 
Asp Ile Ala Ile His Leu Arg Ala Gln Pro Asn Phe Leu Leu His Val 
    3810                3815                3820 
Asp Asn Gln Ala Thr Glu Asn Glu Asp Tyr Val Leu Gln Glu Thr Ile 
3825                3830                3835                3840 
Ile Ile Met Lys Glu Asn Ile Lys Glu Ala His Ala Glu Val Ser Ile 
                3845                3850                3855 
Leu Pro Asp Asp Leu Pro Glu Leu Glu Glu Gly Phe Ile Val Thr Ile 
            3860                3865                3870 
Thr Glu Val Asn Leu Val Asn Ser Asp Phe Ser Thr Gly Gln Pro Ser 
        3875                3880                3885 
Val Arg Arg Pro Gly Met Glu Ile Ala Glu Ile Met Ile Glu Glu Asn 
    3890                3895                3900 
Asp Asp Pro Arg Gly Ile Phe Met Phe His Val Thr Arg Gly Ala Gly 
3905                3910                3915                3920 
Glu Val Ile Thr Ala Tyr Glu Val Pro Pro Pro Leu Asn Val Leu Gln 
                3925                3930                3935 
Val Pro Val Val Arg Leu Ala Gly Ser Phe Gly Ala Val Asn Val Tyr 
            3940                3945                3950 
Trp Lys Ala Ser Pro Asp Ser Ala Gly Leu Glu Asp Phe Lys Pro Ser 
        3955                3960                3965 
His Gly Ile Leu Glu Phe Ala Asp Lys Gln Val Thr Ala Met Ile Glu 
    3970                3975                3980 
Ile Thr Ile Ile Asp Asp Ala Glu Phe Glu Leu Thr Glu Thr Phe Asn 
3985                3990                3995                4000 
Thr Ser Leu Ile Ser Val Ala Gly Gly Gly Arg Leu Gly Asp Asp Val 
                4005                4010                4015 
Val Val Thr Val Val Ile Pro Gln Asn Asp Ser Pro Phe Gly Val Phe 
            4020                4025                4030 
Gly Phe Glu Glu Lys Thr Val Met Ile Asp Glu Ser Leu Ser Ser Asp 
        4035                4040                4045 
Asp Pro Asp Ser Tyr Val Thr Leu Thr Val Val Arg Ser Pro Gly Gly 
    4050                4055                4060 
Lys Gly Thr Val Arg Leu Glu Trp Thr Ile Asp Glu Lys Ala Lys His 
4065                4070                4075                4080 
Asn Leu Ser Pro Leu Asn Gly Thr Leu His Phe Asp Glu Thr Glu Ser 
                4085                4090                4095 
Gln Lys Thr Ile Val Leu His Thr Leu Gln Asp Thr Val Leu Glu Glu 
            4100                4105                4110 
Asp Arg Arg Phe Thr Ile Gln Leu Ile Ser Ile Asp Glu Val Glu Ile 
        4115                4120                4125 
Ser Pro Val Lys Gly Ser Ala Ser Ile Ile Ile Arg Gly Asp Lys Arg 
    4130                4135                4140 
Ala Ser Gly Glu Val Gly Ile Ala Pro Ser Ser Arg His Ile Leu Ile 
4145                4150                4155                4160 
Gly Glu Pro Ser Ala Lys Tyr Asn Gly Thr Ala Ile Ile Ser Leu Val 
                4165                4170                4175 
Arg Gly Pro Gly Ile Leu Gly Glu Val Thr Val Phe Trp Arg Ile Phe 
            4180                4185                4190 
Pro Pro Ser Val Gly Glu Phe Ala Glu Thr Ser Gly Lys Leu Thr Met 
        4195                4200                4205 
Arg Asp Glu Gln Ser Ala Val Ile Val Val Ile Gln Ala Leu Asn Asp 
    4210                4215                4220 
Asp Ile Pro Glu Glu Lys Ser Phe Tyr Glu Phe Gln Leu Thr Ala Val 
4225                4230                4235                4240 
Ser Glu Gly Gly Val Leu Ser Glu Ser Ser Ser Thr Ala Asn Ile Thr 
                4245                4250                4255 
Val Val Ala Ser Asp Ser Pro Tyr Gly Arg Phe Ala Phe Ser His Glu 
            4260                4265                4270 
Gln Leu Arg Val Ser Glu Ala Gln Arg Val Asn Ile Thr Ile Ile Arg 
        4275                4280                4285 
Ser Ser Gly Asp Phe Gly His Val Arg Leu Trp Tyr Lys Thr Met Ser 
    4290                4295                4300 
Gly Thr Ala Glu Ala Gly Leu Asp Phe Val Pro Ala Ala Gly Glu Leu 
4305                4310                4315                4320 
Leu Phe Glu Ala Gly Glu Met Arg Lys Ser Leu His Val Glu Ile Leu 
                4325                4330                4335 
Asp Asp Asp Tyr Pro Glu Gly Pro Glu Glu Phe Ser Leu Thr Ile Thr 
            4340                4345                4350 
Lys Val Glu Leu Gln Gly Arg Gly Tyr Asp Phe Thr Ile Gln Glu Asn 
        4355                4360                4365 
Gly Leu Gln Ile Asp Gln Pro Pro Glu Ile Gly Asn Ile Ser Ile Val 
    4370                4375                4380 
Arg Ile Ile Ile Met Lys Asn Asp Asn Ala Glu Gly Ile Ile Glu Phe 
4385                4390                4395                4400 
Asp Pro Lys Tyr Thr Ala Phe Glu Val Glu Glu Asp Val Gly Leu Ile 
                4405                4410                4415 
Met Ile Pro Val Val Arg Leu His Gly Thr Tyr Gly Tyr Val Thr Ala 
            4420                4425                4430 
Asp Phe Ile Ser Gln Ser Ser Ser Ala Ser Pro Gly Gly Val Asp Tyr 
        4435                4440                4445 
Ile Leu His Gly Ser Thr Val Thr Phe Gln His Gly Gln Asn Leu Ser 
    4450                4455                4460 
Phe Ile Asn Ile Ser Ile Ile Asp Asp Asn Glu Ser Glu Phe Glu Glu 
4465                4470                4475                4480 
Pro Ile Glu Ile Leu Leu Thr Gly Ala Thr Gly Gly Ala Val Leu Gly 
                4485                4490                4495 
Arg His Leu Val Ser Arg Ile Ile Ile Ala Lys Ser Asp Ser Pro Phe 
            4500                4505                4510 
Gly Val Ile Arg Phe Leu Asn Gln Ser Lys Ile Ser Ile Ala Asn Pro 
        4515                4520                4525 
Asn Ser Thr Met Ile Leu Ser Leu Val Leu Glu Arg Thr Gly Gly Leu 
    4530                4535                4540 
Leu Gly Glu Ile Gln Val Asn Trp Glu Thr Val Gly Pro Asn Ser Gln 
4545                4550                4555                4560 
Glu Ala Leu Leu Pro Gln Asn Arg Asp Ile Ala Asp Pro Val Ser Gly 
                4565                4570                4575 
Leu Phe Tyr Phe Gly Glu Gly Glu Gly Gly Val Arg Thr Ile Ile Leu 
            4580                4585                4590 
Thr Ile Tyr Pro His Glu Glu Ile Glu Val Glu Glu Thr Phe Ile Ile 
        4595                4600                4605 
Lys Leu His Leu Val Lys Gly Glu Ala Lys Leu Asp Ser Arg Ala Lys 
    4610                4615                4620 
Asp Val Thr Leu Thr Ile Gln Glu Phe Gly Asp Pro Asn Gly Val Val 
4625                4630                4635                4640 
Gln Phe Ala Pro Glu Thr Leu Ser Lys Lys Thr Tyr Ser Glu Pro Leu 
                4645                4650                4655 
Ala Leu Glu Gly Pro Leu Leu Ile Thr Phe Phe Val Arg Arg Val Lys 
            4660                4665                4670 
Gly Thr Phe Gly Glu Ile Met Val Tyr Trp Glu Leu Ser Ser Glu Phe 
        4675                4680                4685 
Asp Ile Thr Glu Asp Phe Leu Ser Thr Ser Gly Phe Phe Thr Ile Ala 
    4690                4695                4700 
Asp Gly Glu Ser Glu Ala Ser Phe Asp Val His Leu Leu Pro Asp Glu 
4705                4710                4715                4720 
Val Pro Glu Ile Glu Glu Asp Tyr Val Ile Gln Leu Val Ser Val Glu 
                4725                4730                4735 
Gly Gly Ala Glu Leu Asp Leu Glu Lys Ser Ile Thr Trp Phe Ser Val 
            4740                4745                4750 
Tyr Ala Asn Asp Asp Pro His Gly Val Phe Ala Leu Tyr Ser Asp Arg 
        4755                4760                4765 
Gln Ser Ile Leu Ile Gly Gln Asn Leu Ile Arg Ser Ile Gln Ile Asn 
    4770                4775                4780 
Ile Thr Arg Leu Ala Gly Thr Phe Gly Asp Val Ala Val Gly Leu Arg 
4785                4790                4795                4800 
Ile Ser Ser Asp His Lys Glu Gln Pro Ile Val Thr Glu Asn Ala Glu 
                4805                4810                4815 
Arg Gln Leu Val Val Lys Asp Gly Ala Thr Tyr Lys Val Asp Val Val 
            4820                4825                4830 
Pro Ile Lys Asn Gln Val Phe Leu Ser Leu Gly Ser Asn Phe Thr Leu 
        4835                4840                4845 
Gln Leu Val Thr Val Met Leu Val Gly Gly Arg Phe Tyr Gly Met Pro 
    4850                4855                4860 
Thr Ile Leu Gln Glu Ala Lys Ser Ala Val Leu Pro Val Ser Glu Lys 
4865                4870                4875                4880 
Ala Ala Asn Ser Gln Val Gly Phe Glu Ser Thr Ala Phe Gln Leu Met 
                4885                4890                4895 
Asn Ile Thr Ala Gly Thr Ser His Val Met Ile Ser Arg Arg Gly Thr 
            4900                4905                4910 
Tyr Gly Ala Leu Ser Val Ala Trp Thr Thr Gly Tyr Ala Pro Gly Leu 
        4915                4920                4925 
Glu Ile Pro Glu Phe Ile Val Val Gly Asn Met Thr Pro Thr Leu Gly 
    4930                4935                4940 
Ser Leu Ser Phe Ser His Gly Glu Gln Arg Lys Gly Val Phe Leu Trp 
4945                4950                4955                4960 
Thr Phe Pro Ser Pro Gly Trp Pro Glu Ala Phe Val Leu His Leu Ser 
                4965                4970                4975 
Gly Val Gln Ser Ser Ala Pro Gly Gly Ala Gln Leu Arg Ser Gly Phe 
            4980                4985                4990 
Ile Val Ala Glu Ile Glu Pro Met Gly Val Phe Gln Phe Ser Thr Ser 
        4995                5000                5005 
Ser Arg Asn Ile Ile Val Ser Glu Asp Thr Gln Met Ile Arg Leu His 
    5010                5015                5020 
Val Gln Arg Leu Phe Gly Phe His Ser Asp Leu Ile Lys Val Ser Tyr 
5025                5030                5035                5040 
Gln Thr Thr Ala Gly Ser Ala Lys Pro Leu Glu Asp Phe Glu Pro Val 
                5045                5050                5055 
Gln Asn Gly Glu Leu Phe Phe Gln Lys Phe Gln Thr Glu Val Asp Phe 
            5060                5065                5070 
Glu Ile Thr Ile Ile Asn Asp Gln Leu Ser Glu Ile Glu Glu Phe Phe 
        5075                5080                5085 
Tyr Ile Asn Leu Thr Ser Val Glu Ile Arg Gly Leu Gln Lys Phe Asp 
    5090                5095                5100 
Val Asn Trp Ser Pro Arg Leu Asn Leu Asp Phe Ser Val Ala Val Ile 
5105                5110                5115                5120 
Thr Ile Leu Asp Asn Asp Asp Leu Ala Gly Met Asp Ile Ser Phe Pro 
                5125                5130                5135 
Glu Thr Thr Val Ala Val Ala Val Asp Thr Thr Leu Ile Pro Val Glu 
            5140                5145                5150 
Thr Glu Ser Thr Thr Tyr Leu Ser Thr Ser Lys Thr Thr Thr Ile Leu 
        5155                5160                5165 
Gln Pro Thr Asn Val Val Ala Ile Val Thr Glu Ala Thr Gly Val Ser 
    5170                5175                5180 
Ala Ile Pro Glu Lys Leu Val Thr Leu His Gly Thr Pro Ala Val Ser 
5185                5190                5195                5200 
Glu Lys Pro Asp Val Ala Thr Val Thr Ala Asn Val Ser Ile His Gly 
                5205                5210                5215 
Thr Phe Ser Leu Gly Pro Ser Ile Val Tyr Ile Glu Glu Glu Met Lys 
            5220                5225                5230 
Asn Gly Thr Phe Asn Thr Ala Glu Val Leu Ile Arg Arg Thr Gly Gly 
        5235                5240                5245 
Phe Thr Gly Asn Val Ser Ile Thr Val Lys Thr Phe Gly Glu Arg Cys 
    5250                5255                5260 
Ala Gln Met Glu Pro Asn Ala Leu Pro Phe Arg Gly Ile Tyr Gly Ile 
5265                5270                5275                5280 
Ser Asn Leu Thr Trp Ala Val Glu Glu Glu Asp Phe Glu Glu Gln Thr 
                5285                5290                5295 
Leu Thr Leu Ile Phe Leu Asp Gly Glu Arg Glu Arg Lys Val Ser Val 
            5300                5305                5310 
Gln Ile Leu Asp Asp Asp Glu Pro Glu Gly Gln Glu Phe Phe Tyr Val 
        5315                5320                5325 
Phe Leu Thr Asn Pro Gln Gly Gly Ala Gln Ile Val Glu Gly Lys Asp 
    5330                5335                5340 
Asp Thr Gly Phe Ala Ala Phe Ala Met Val Ile Ile Thr Gly Ser Asp 
5345                5350                5355                5360 
Leu His Asn Gly Ile Ile Gly Phe Ser Glu Glu Ser Gln Ser Gly Leu 
                5365                5370                5375 
Glu Leu Arg Glu Gly Ala Val Met Arg Arg Leu His Leu Ile Val Thr 
            5380                5385                5390 
Arg Gln Pro Asn Arg Ala Phe Glu Asp Val Lys Val Phe Trp Arg Val 
        5395                5400                5405 
Thr Leu Asn Lys Thr Val Val Val Leu Gln Lys Asp Gly Val Asn Leu 
    5410                5415                5420 
Met Glu Glu Leu Gln Ser Val Ser Gly Thr Thr Thr Cys Thr Met Gly 
5425                5430                5435                5440 
Gln Thr Lys Cys Phe Ile Ser Ile Glu Leu Lys Pro Glu Lys Val Pro 
                5445                5450                5455 
Gln Val Glu Val Tyr Phe Phe Val Glu Leu Tyr Glu Ala Thr Ala Gly 
            5460                5465                5470 
Ala Ala Ile Asn Asn Ser Ala Arg Phe Ala Gln Ile Lys Ile Leu Glu 
        5475                5480                5485 
Ser Asp Glu Ser Gln Ser Leu Val Tyr Phe Ser Val Gly Ser Arg Leu 
    5490                5495                5500 
Ala Val Ala His Lys Lys Ala Thr Leu Ile Ser Leu Gln Val Ala Arg 
5505                5510                5515                5520 
Asp Ser Gly Thr Gly Leu Met Met Ser Val Asn Phe Ser Thr Gln Glu 
                5525                5530                5535 
Leu Arg Ser Ala Glu Thr Ile Gly Arg Thr Ile Ile Ser Pro Ala Ile 
            5540                5545                5550 
Ser Gly Lys Asp Phe Val Ile Thr Glu Gly Thr Leu Val Phe Glu Pro 
        5555                5560                5565 
Gly Gln Arg Ser Thr Val Leu Asp Val Ile Leu Thr Pro Glu Thr Gly 
    5570                5575                5580 
Ser Leu Asn Ser Phe Pro Lys Arg Phe Gln Ile Val Leu Phe Asp Pro 
5585                5590                5595                5600 
Lys Gly Gly Ala Arg Ile Asp Lys Val Tyr Gly Thr Ala Asn Ile Thr 
                5605                5610                5615 
Leu Val Ser Asp Ala Asp Ser Gln Ala Ile Trp Gly Leu Ala Asp Gln 
            5620                5625                5630 
Leu His Gln Pro Val Asn Asp Asp Ile Leu Asn Arg Val Leu His Thr 
        5635                5640                5645 
Ile Ser Met Lys Val Ala Thr Glu Asn Thr Asp Glu Gln Leu Ser Ala 
    5650                5655                5660 
Met Met His Leu Ile Glu Lys Ile Thr Thr Glu Gly Lys Ile Gln Ala 
5665                5670                5675                5680 
Phe Ser Val Ala Ser Arg Thr Leu Phe Tyr Glu Ile Leu Cys Ser Leu 
                5685                5690                5695 
Ile Asn Pro Lys Arg Lys Asp Thr Arg Gly Phe Ser His Phe Ala Glu 
            5700                5705                5710 
Val Thr Glu Asn Phe Ala Phe Ser Leu Leu Thr Asn Val Thr Cys Gly 
        5715                5720                5725 
Ser Pro Gly Glu Lys Ser Lys Thr Ile Leu Asp Ser Cys Pro Tyr Leu 
    5730                5735                5740 
Ser Ile Leu Ala Leu His Trp Tyr Pro Gln Gln Ile Asn Gly His Lys 
5745                5750                5755                5760 
Phe Glu Gly Lys Glu Gly Asp Tyr Ile Arg Ile Pro Glu Arg Leu Leu 
                5765                5770                5775 
Asp Val Gln Asp Ala Glu Ile Met Ala Gly Lys Ser Thr Cys Lys Leu 
            5780                5785                5790 
Val Gln Phe Thr Glu Tyr Ser Ser Gln Gln Trp Phe Ile Ser Gly Asn 
        5795                5800                5805 
Asn Leu Pro Thr Leu Lys Asn Lys Val Leu Ser Leu Ser Val Lys Gly 
    5810                5815                5820 
Gln Ser Ser Gln Leu Leu Thr Asn Asp Asn Glu Val Leu Tyr Arg Ile 
5825                5830                5835                5840 
Tyr Ala Ala Glu Pro Arg Ile Ile Pro Gln Thr Ser Leu Cys Leu Leu 
                5845                5850                5855 
Trp Asn Gln Ala Ala Ala Ser Trp Leu Ser Asp Ser Gln Phe Cys Lys 
            5860                5865                5870 
Val Val Glu Glu Thr Ala Asp Tyr Val Glu Cys Ala Cys Ser His Met 
        5875                5880                5885 
Ser Val Tyr Ala Val Tyr Ala Arg Thr Asp Asn Leu Ser Ser Tyr Asn 
    5890                5895                5900 
Glu Ala Phe Phe Thr Ser Gly Phe Ile Cys Ile Ser Gly Leu Cys Leu 
5905                5910                5915                5920 
Ala Val Leu Ser His Ile Phe Cys Ala Arg Tyr Ser Met Phe Ala Ala 
                5925                5930                5935 
Lys Leu Leu Thr His Met Met Ala Ala Ser Leu Gly Thr Gln Ile Leu 
            5940                5945                5950 
Phe Leu Ala Ser Ala Tyr Ala Ser Pro Gln Leu Ala Glu Glu Ser Cys 
        5955                5960                5965 
Ser Ala Met Ala Ala Val Thr His Tyr Leu Tyr Leu Cys Gln Phe Ser 
    5970                5975                5980 
Trp Met Leu Ile Gln Ser Val Asn Phe Trp Tyr Val Leu Val Met Asn 
5985                5990                5995                6000 
Asp Glu His Thr Glu Arg Arg Tyr Leu Leu Phe Phe Leu Leu Ser Trp 
                6005                6010                6015 
Gly Leu Pro Ala Phe Val Val Ile Leu Leu Ile Val Ile Leu Lys Gly 
            6020                6025                6030 
Ile Tyr His Gln Ser Met Ser Gln Ile Tyr Gly Leu Ile His Gly Asp 
        6035                6040                6045 
Leu Cys Phe Ile Pro Asn Val Tyr Ala Ala Leu Phe Thr Ala Ala Leu 
    6050                6055                6060 
Val Pro Leu Thr Cys Leu Val Val Val Phe Val Val Phe Ile His Ala 
6065                6070                6075                6080 
Tyr Gln Val Lys Pro Gln Trp Lys Ala Tyr Asp Asp Val Phe Arg Gly 
                6085                6090                6095 
Arg Thr Asn Ala Ala Glu Ile Pro Leu Ile Leu Tyr Leu Phe Ala Leu 
            6100                6105                6110 
Ile Ser Val Thr Trp Leu Trp Gly Gly Leu His Met Ala Tyr Arg His 
        6115                6120                6125 
Phe Trp Met Leu Val Leu Phe Val Ile Phe Asn Ser Leu Gln Gly Leu 
    6130                6135                6140 
Tyr Val Phe Met Val Tyr Phe Ile Leu His Asn Gln Met Cys Cys Pro 
6145                6150                6155                6160 
Met Lys Ala Ser Tyr Thr Val Glu Met Asn Gly His Pro Gly Pro Ser 
                6165                6170                6175 
Thr Ala Phe Phe Thr Pro Gly Ser Gly Met Pro Pro Ala Gly Gly Glu 
            6180                6185                6190 
Ile Ser Lys Ser Thr Gln Asn Leu Ile Gly Ala Met Glu Glu Val Pro 
        6195                6200                6205 
Pro Asp Trp Glu Arg Ala Ser Phe Gln Gln Gly Ser Gln Ala Ser Pro 
    6210                6215                6220 
Asp Leu Lys Pro Ser Pro Gln Asn Gly Ala Thr Phe Pro Ser Ser Gly 
6225                6230                6235                6240 
Gly Tyr Gly Gln Gly Ser Leu Ile Ala Asp Glu Glu Ser Gln Glu Phe 
                6245                6250                6255 
Asp Asp Leu Ile Phe Ala Leu Lys Thr Gly Ala Gly Leu Ser Val Ser 
            6260                6265                6270 
Asp Asn Glu Ser Gly Gln Gly Ser Gln Glu Gly Gly Thr Leu Thr Asp 
        6275                6280                6285 
Ser Gln Ile Val Glu Leu Arg Arg Ile Pro Ile Ala Asp Thr His Leu 
    6290                6295                6300
</s400>
</sequence-list-new-rules>
</sequence-cwu>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An isolated polynucleotide encoding a NPG polypeptide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polynucleotide encodes a NPG polypeptide comprising the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:2, 4, 6, 8,10,12, 14, or 16. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polynucleotide is detectably labeled. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An isolated polynucleotide which is the complement of the polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The isolated polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polynucleotide is detectably labeled. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polynucleotide comprises the nucleic acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, or 15. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An expression vector comprising the polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A host cell comprising the expression vector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The host cell of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the host cell is a prokaryotic cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The host cell of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the host cell is a eukaryotic cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method of producing an NPG polypeptide comprising: 
<claim-text>a) culturing the host cell of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> under conditions suitable for expression of the NPG polypeptide; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) recovering the polypeptide from the host cell. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method of detecting a polynucleotide encoding an NPG polypeptide in a sample containing nucleic acid material comprising: 
<claim-text>a) contacting the sample with the polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> under conditions suitable for formation of a hybridization complex; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) detecting the complex, wherein the presence of the complex is indicative of the presence of the polynucleotide encoding the polypeptide in the sample. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A diagnostic test kit comprising: 
<claim-text>a) the polynucleotide of claim <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) instructions for conducting the diagnostic test. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method of screening for a compound that modulates NPG activity, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>a) contacting NPG, or fragment thereof with the compound; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) detecting modulation of NPG activity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein NPG is: 
<claim-text>a) expressed on a cell or tissue; or </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) immobilized on a solid support. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the compound is: 
<claim-text>a) an antagonist of NPG activity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) an agonist of NPG activity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An isolated NPG polypeptide comprising the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, or 16. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The polypeptide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polypeptide is: 
<claim-text>a) recombinantly produced; or </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) synthetically produced. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An isolated antibody which specifically binds to the polypeptide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A transgenic nonhuman mammal comprising the polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A transgenic nonhuman mammal comprising the polynucleotide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> capable of hybridizing to a polynucleotide encoding NPG, thereby reducing expression of NPG.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003538A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003538A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003538A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
