<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002897A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002897A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002897</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10172011</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020617</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-195288</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-342271</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20011107</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03G015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>399</class>
<subclass>365000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Image forming apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yoshihide</given-name>
<family-name>Amagai</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ibaraki</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tomonori</given-name>
<family-name>Kitan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chiba</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kenichi</given-name>
<family-name>Yukinari</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ibaraki</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Canon Kabushiki Kaisha</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>FITZPATRICK CELLA HARPER &amp; SCINTO</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>30 ROCKEFELLER PLAZA</address-1>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10112</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A conveying guide base is formed integrally with an original base frame. Also, when an original base glass is fixed to the original base frame, the original base glass is abutted against the conveying guide base. Further, the conveying guide base is formed in the vicinity of the other end portion of the original base glass on a side opposite to one end portion in which an original abutting board is formed. When an original fed by an automatic original feeding apparatus is read, an image reading unit is set to stay at a predetermined reading position and an image of the original is read by the image reading unit under this condition. Also, a detecting unit detects that an original is placed on an original placing unit provided for the automatic original feeding apparatus. Then, if an image reading operation start unit is operated to start an image reading operation, in the case where a detection signal is inputted from the detecting unit, a position control unit performs control so that the image reading unit is moved from a stand-by position to a predetermined reading position before the original is fed by the automatic original feeding apparatus. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an image forming apparatus that forms an image on a recording medium. In particular, the present invention relates to an image reading apparatus that supports both of a flow reading method and an original fixing method and has a size that is smaller than that of a conventional one, and relates to an image forming apparatus equipped with this image reading apparatus. Also, the present invention relates to an image reading apparatus that is capable of increasing productivity by preventing the occurrence of a time that is unnecessarily consumed to move an image reading means, and relates to an image forming apparatus equipped with this image reading apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Related Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, there has been used an image forming apparatus that reads an image recorded on an original (reads the original) and forms this read image on a recording medium such as recording paper. As a method for reading the original, there have been known so-called flow reading method and original fixing method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> With the flow reading method, a contact image sensor (hereinafter referred to as the &ldquo;CIS&rdquo;) or the like for reading an original is fixed below an original base glass and the original is moved to pass through a region (a reading region) of this original base glass above the CIS, thereby reading the original using the CIS. On the other hand, with the original fixing method, an original is abutted against an original abutting board formed in the vicinity of one end portion of the original base glass, and the original is placed on the original base glass. The CIS is moved in a predetermined reading direction under this condition, thereby reading the original. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Image forming apparatuses that are capable of performing the flow reading method are classified into a type where a conveying member for conveying an original is arranged on the entire upper surface of an original base glass and a type where a sheet feeding unit for feeding an original to a reading region is arranged in one end portion of an original base glass. In the case of the type where there is used this sheet feeding unit, it is not required to arrange a conveying member on the entire upper surface of the original base glass, whereby weight reduction is realized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A conventional example of the image forming apparatus of the type where the sheet feeding unit described above is used will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an example of the conventional image forming apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The image forming apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is broadly divided into a reading portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for reading an original and an image forming portion <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for forming an image read by this reading portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> on a recording medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The reading portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes an automatic original feeding unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> having an original placing tray <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> on which an original is placed, a plurality of conveying rollers <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> for conveying the original placed on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to a reading region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in which the original is to be read, and an original discharging tray <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> on which the original having passed through the reading region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is placed. In the reading region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, there is arranged a platen glass <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> above which the original passes. Also, a CIS <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is arranged below the platen glass <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The original placed on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is fed to the reading region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by the plurality of conveying rollers <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, is read by the CIS <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> while passing through the reading region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and is discharged to the original discharging tray <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> while being guided by a conveying guide base <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The image forming apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is also equipped with an original base glass <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> for fixing and reading an original. Also, an original abutting board <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, against which an original placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is abutted, is arranged in the vicinity of one end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In the case where the original is read with the original fixing method described above, a user abuts the original against the original abutting board <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to position the original on the original base glass <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and the original is read by moving the CIS <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in a reading direction (a direction indicated by an arrow E). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The original read with the flow reading method or the original fixing method in the manner described above is formed on a recording medium in the image forming portion <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> arranged below the original base glass <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A construction of this image forming portion <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> will be described later with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In the image forming apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> described above, the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> becomes an indispensable construction element in the case of the flow reading method and the original abutting board <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> becomes an indispensable construction element in the case of the original fixing method. The conveying guide base <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and the platen glass <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are arranged outside of the original abutting board <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> so as to avoid the original abutting board <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Consequently, the platen glass <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for performing a flow reading operation is provided separately from the original base glass <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, thereby the size of the image forming apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is increased accordingly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Also, in a conventional image reading apparatus that reads an image of an original fed by such an automatic original feeding apparatus and in an image forming apparatus equipped with this image reading apparatus, an image reading unit <highlight><bold>1106</bold></highlight> is ordinarily positioned at a stand-by position for performing a leftward fixed reading operation indicated by a broken line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. In the case where a flow reading operation is performed, it is required to move the image reading unit from this stand-by position to a rightward predetermined reading position indicated by a solid line in this drawing. Consequently, in the case where a flow reading operation is performed, a redundant time is consumed to move the image reading unit <highlight><bold>1106</bold></highlight> from the stand-by position to the reading position, which elongates an image reading operation start time for the first sheet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In view of this problem, in order to shorten the image reading operation start time for the first sheet, for instance, there is proposed a construction where before a user performs an operation to designate the start of a reading operation, when an original S is placed on an original placing tray <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight> of the automatic original feeding apparatus, a sensor <highlight><bold>1104</bold></highlight> detects this situation and the image reading unit <highlight><bold>1106</bold></highlight> starts to move from a stand-by position to a reading position in advance on the basis of a detection signal from this sensor <highlight><bold>1104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> However, with this method, once the original S is set on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight>, the image reading unit <highlight><bold>1106</bold></highlight> starts to move. Consequently, in the case where the user of the apparatus erroneously places an original on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>1102</bold></highlight> and the original should be placed on an original base glass <highlight><bold>1127</bold></highlight>, or in the case where a reading operation is performed by directly placing the original S on the original base glass <highlight><bold>1127</bold></highlight> after an original reading operation that uses the automatic original feeding apparatus is performed, it becomes impossible to start the reading operation until the image reading unit <highlight><bold>1106</bold></highlight> returns to the stand-by position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> That is, there occurs a time that is unnecessarily consumed to move the image reading unit <highlight><bold>1106</bold></highlight>. Also, in the case where there occurs such a time that is unnecessarily consumed to move the image reading unit, the productivity of the image forming apparatus is decreased. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In view of the circumstances described above, an object of the present invention is to provide an image forming apparatus that supports both of a flow reading method and an original fixing method and also has a size that is smaller than that of a conventional one. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Also, the present invention has been made in view of the stated current circumstances, and another object of the present invention is to provide an image reading apparatus that is capable of increasing productivity by preventing the occurrence of a time that is unnecessarily consumed to move a reading unit (an image reading means), and an image forming apparatus equipped with this image reading apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve the above-mentioned object, according to the present invention, there is provided an image forming apparatus including an original base glass for which a predetermined image reading region is formed and on which an original is placed, image reading means that is arranged below the original base glass and reads an image of the original, and an original automatic conveying apparatus that conveys the original to the image reading region, the image forming apparatus forming the read image on a recording medium by reading the image of the original by selecting one of an original fixing scanning mode and an image flow reading scanning mode, the original fixing scanning mode being a mode with which the original is placed on the original base glass and the image of the original is read by having the image reading means perform scanning in a predetermined scanning direction below the original base glass, and the image flow reading scanning mode being a mode with which the image reading means is set to stay below the image reading region and the image of the original is read using the image reading means in the image reading region by conveying the original to the image reading region using the original automatic conveying apparatus, the image forming apparatus characterized by comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> (1) an abutting member which is formed in the vicinity of one end portion of the original base glass and against which the original placed on the original base glass is abutted when the original fixing scanning mode is selected; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> (2) a conveying guide base that is formed on the other end portion side of the original base glass opposite to the abutting member and guides the original conveyed to the image reading region by the original automatic conveying apparatus to a predetermined sheet discharging tray. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In this case, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> (3) at least one of the abutting member and the conveying guide base may be formed integrally with an original base frame to which the original base glass is fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Also, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> (4) in the conveying guide base, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> (4-1) the conveying guide base may be formed integrally with the original base frame to which the original base glass is fixed, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> (4-2) a position, at which the original base glass may be fixed, is determined by abutment of the original base glass against the original base frame when the original base glass is fixed to the original base frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Further, the image forming apparatus may comprise </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> (5) a photosensitive drum on which a developed image of an image read by the image reading means is formed, and a fixing device that fixes the developed image on the recording medium conveyed from the photosensitive drum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> (6) The original base glass may have the image reading region formed in one end portion thereof on a side opposite to the fixing device with the photosensitive drum being sandwiched therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> (7) The image reading means may stay below the image reading region when the image flow reading scanning mode is selected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Still further, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> (8) the original base glass may include the image reading region that is formed to be used in the image flow reading scanning mode, and the original glass is placed on the original base when the original fixing scanning mode is selected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Also, the present invention is an image reading apparatus that includes an image reading means for reading an image of an original, that reads the image of the original by moving the image reading means from a stand-by position along a platen glass when the original is placed on the platen glass, and that reads the image of the original under a condition where the image reading means stays at a predetermined reading position when the original is fed from an automatic original feeding apparatus. The image reading apparatus according to the present invention is characterized in that: a detecting means for detecting that the original is placed on an original placing means provided for the automatic original feeding apparatus, an image reading operation start means that is operated to start an image reading operation, and a position control means that moves the image reading means from the stand-by position to the predetermined reading position before the original is fed by the automatic original feeding apparatus are provided; and if a detection signal is inputted from the detecting means when the image reading operation start means is operated, the position control means moves the image reading means from the stand-by position to the predetermined reading position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Also, the present invention is characterized by that when no detection signal is inputted from the detecting means, the position control means judges that the image reading is finished and moves the image reading means from the predetermined reading position to the stand-by position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As described above, in the image forming apparatus of the present invention, an original abutting member, against which the original placed on the original base glass is abutted, is formed in the vicinity of one end portion of the original base glass. In the case where the conveying guide base is formed in the vicinity of the other end portion of the original base glass on a side opposite to the one end portion, an automatic original feeding unit can be arranged in the vicinity of the other end portion of the original base glass. This makes it possible to widen the original base glass (or to arrange a small original base glass separately from the original base glass), thereby reducing the size of the original base frame in comparison with a construction where the automatic original feeding unit is arranged in the vicinity of the one end portion of the original base glass. As a result, it becomes possible to reduce the size of the original base frame and to reduce the size of the image forming apparatus accordingly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Here, in the case where at least one of the abutting member and the conveying guide base is formed integrally with the original base frame to which the original base glass is fixed, it is possible to produce these construction elements without difficulty and also to reduce the number of components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Also, in the case where the conveying guide base is formed integrally with the original base frame to which the original base glass is fixed and the position, at which the original base glass is fixed, is determined by the abutment of the original base glass against the original base frame when the original base glass is fixed to the original base frame, the conveying guide base doubles as a member for positioning the original base glass and the number of components can be reduced accordingly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Further, there are provided a photosensitive drum, on which a developed image of an image read by the image reading means is formed, and a fixing device that fixes the developed image on a recording medium conveyed from the photosensitive drum. The image reading region is formed in one end portion of the original base glass on a side opposite to the fixing device with the photosensitive drum being sandwiched therebetween. In the case where the image reading means stays below the image reading region because the image flow reading scanning mode is selected, the image reading region is formed in the one end portion of the original base glass on a side opposite to the fixing device with the photosensitive drum being sandwiched therebetween. Accordingly, the image reading means is separated from the fixing device in the image flow reading scanning mode. Consequently, the image reading means is hardly influenced by heat generated by the fixing device. As a result, even if the image reading means is vulnerable to heat, it becomes unnecessary to provide a cooling apparatus or the like that cools this image reading means and thereby the number of components can be reduced accordingly. As a result, it becomes possible to reduce the size of the image forming apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Further, in the case where the original base glass includes the image reading region formed to be used in the image flow reading scanning mode and an original is placed on the original base glass when the original fixing scanning mode is selected, a single original base glass is commonly used in both of the image flow reading scanning mode and the original fixing scanning mode, which means that it is not required to use two original base glasses. As a result, it becomes possible to further reduce the number of components accordingly and to reduce the size of the image forming apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Also, with the present invention, in the case where an original is placed on the original placing means when the image reading operation start means is operated to start an operation for reading an image of an original fed from the automatic original feeding apparatus, it becomes possible to prevent the occurrence of a time that is unnecessarily consumed to move the image reading means and to increase productivity by moving the image reading means from the stand-by position to the predetermined reading position before the original is fed.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing an external appearance of a digital copying machine that is an embodiment of an image forming apparatus of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing the external appearance of the digital copying machine in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> under a condition where an original pressure board is opened; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an internal construction of the copying machine in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top view taken from above of the copying machine under a condition where the original pressure board is removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view that schematically shows a state where an original is fed by an automatic original feeding unit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an internal construction of a digital copying machine of a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a control block diagram showing a part of a control of a digital copying machine that is an example of an image forming apparatus according to a third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows an outline of a construction of the digital copying machine; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates an operation for performing image formation after the digital copying machine performs a flow reading operation for an original; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an example of a conventional image forming apparatus; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows constructions of a conventional automatic original feeding apparatus and a conventional original reading apparatus.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the present invention will be described below with reference to the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> First Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> A first embodiment of an image forming apparatus of the present invention will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing an external appearance of a digital copying machine that is the first embodiment of the image forming apparatus of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing the external appearance of the digital copying machine in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> under a condition where an original pressure board is opened. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes a first case <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, in which there are installed a plurality of components for reading an image recorded on an original, and a second case (image forming portion) <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in which there are installed a plurality of components for forming the image on a recording medium. The second case <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is arranged below the first case <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> as shown in the drawings. Accordingly, the first case <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is placed on the second case <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> On the top surface of the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, there is arranged an original pressure board <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> having a cuboid shape. It is possible to freely open and close this original pressure board. Under the original pressure board <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, there is arranged an optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> in which there is installed a well-known optical system (not shown). The optical system is provided with a light source LED (not shown) and the like. The upper surface (upper wall) of the optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is an original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> on which an original is placed. The original pressure board <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and the optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> constitute the first case <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> In one end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> on a side opposite to a fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> with a photosensitive drum (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) being sandwiched therebetween, there is formed an image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in which an image of an original is read. Also, on a slightly downstream side in a direction indicated by an arrow B with reference to the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, there is formed a conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> that guides an original conveyed to the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to a sheet discharging tray <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> has a long and narrow shape that extends in a direction orthogonal to the directions indicated by the arrows A and B. The conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> includes an inclined plane <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed so as to direct the original upward while contacting the original. On the other hand, in the other end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> on a side opposite to the one end portion in which the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> is formed, there is formed an abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> (an example of the abutting member of the present invention) against which the original placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is abutted. This abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> has a long and narrow shape that extends in a direction orthogonal to the directions indicated by the arrows A and B. As described above, the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> and the abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> are respectively formed on both end sides of the single original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, which precludes the necessity to use two original base glasses. Consequently, the number of components is reduced accordingly, which makes it possible to reduce the size of the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In the original pressure board <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, there is installed an original automatic conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> that automatically feeds the original. This original automatic conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> will be described later with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and other drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> On a side (front side) of the second case <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> existing frontward with reference to the first case <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, there is arranged an operation panel <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> with which the number of copies to be made and the like are inputted. In the lower portion of the second case <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, there is provided a cassette <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> in which a plurality of pieces of cut paper are contained. It is possible to freely insert and extract this cassette into and from the second case <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. On the right wall of the second case <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, there is provided a manual paper feeding tray <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> having a rectangular shape, thereby making it possible to feed small sized recording paper like a postal card. This manual paper feeding tray <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> rotates in a direction indicated by an arrow C (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) about a low side portion <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and is opened to a position at which it is possible to place a recoding medium. Also, a space is formed in the leftward portion of the second case <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and there is formed a sheet discharging tray <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> on which discharged recording paper is stacked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> A procedure by which the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> forms an image and the like will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an internal construction of the copying machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is capable of selecting one of the flow reading method and the original fixing method to form an image recorded on an original on a recording medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In the case where the original fixing method is selected, the original pressure board <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is first opened. Then, an original is placed on the upper surface of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and this original is pressed and fixed with the original pressure board <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Next, by pushing a predetermined operation button or the like, a CIS (contact image sensor) <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> (an example of the reading means of the present invention) installed in the optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> performs scanning in the direction indicated by the arrow B from a position indicated by a chain double-dashed line. With this CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, an image recorded on the original is read. The read image is converted into a digital signal, which is then sent to a laser scanner <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Note that the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is fixed to a rectangular original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> formed in the optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Also, the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is installed in an image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is driven by a drive motor (not shown) or a drive belt (not shown) and moves in the directions indicated by the arrows A and B while being guided by a guide axis <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> described above is fixed to the rectangular original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> formed in the optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. In the vicinity of one end portion <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> fixed to this original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, there is formed an original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> (an example of the original abutting member of the present invention) against which an original is abutted when this original is placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. This original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> extends in a direction perpendicular to the directions indicated by the arrows A and B and is used to position the original when the original is placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> There will be described a case where the flow reading method is selected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> To perform a flow reading operation for an original, the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is equipped with an automatic original feeding unit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The automatic original feeding unit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> automatically feeds an original so that the original passes through the reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in which an image recorded on the original is read (the original is read). The reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is formed in a portion on the downstream side of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> in the direction indicated by the arrow B, and extends in a direction perpendicular to the direction indicated by the arrow B. Note that in the case where the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> selects the flow reading method, the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> moves to a side opposite to the reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> (the lower side of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) with the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> being sandwiched therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In the automatic original feeding unit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, there are formed an original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, on which the original is placed, and the original discharging tray <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> on which the original having passed through the reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is placed. Also, in the automatic original feeding unit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, there are installed a plurality of rollers (a sheet feeding roller <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, a registration roller pair <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, and the like) that convey the original placed on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> to the original discharging tray <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> through the reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The original placed on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is fed to the registration roller pair <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> from a sheet feeding opening <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by the sheet feeding roller <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The registration roller pair <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> performs skew feeding correction. The original that has been subjected to the skew feeding correction is conveyed to a platen roller <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> by the registration roller pair <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and passes through the reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is positioned in this reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the original is read by the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> while passing through the reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The read image is converted into a digital signal, which is then sent to the laser scanner <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The original that has passed through the reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is guided to a reversing roller <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> by the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> including an inclined plane formed to direct the original upward. The reversing roller <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> reverses the front surface and the rear surface of the original and conveys it to a sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. The original conveyed to the sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> is discharged to the original discharging tray <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> by this sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> As described above, in the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, regardless of which one of the flow reading method or the original fixing method is used, a read image of an original is converted into a digital signal, which is then sent to the laser scanner <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The signal sent to the laser scanner <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is converted into a laser light, which is then irradiated onto a photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> through a scanner mirror <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that rotates at high speed and a return mirror <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is uniformly charged by a charger <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and an electrostatic latent image is formed on the photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> onto which the laser light is irradiated. This electrostatic latent image is developed by a developer supplied from a developing roller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, thereby forming a developed image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, a recording medium, such as recording paper, is fed from the cassette <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> by the sheet feeding roller <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> in a direction indicated by an arrow D (in a sheet feeding direction) and is conveyed to a transferring device <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> by a conveying roller <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and a registration roller <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. In the transferring device <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, the developed image on the photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is transferred onto the conveyed recording medium. The recording medium, on which the developed image has been transferred, is conveyed to a fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> by a conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. In the fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, there are arranged a fixing roller <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a pressurizing roller <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The recording medium is conveyed while being nipped between these two rollers <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, thereby fixing the developed image on the recording medium. The recording medium, on which the developed image has been fixed in this manner, is discharged by the sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and is stacked on the sheet discharging tray <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> It should be noted here that it is possible to feed a recording medium from the manual paper feeding tray <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The formation of an image on the recording medium fed from the manual paper feeding tray <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is performed by the same procedure as described above. Further, in the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, there is also embedded an electrical substrate <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> on which a power source and electrical components for driving various components are placed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> As described above, various components and members are installed in the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Among these components, the charger <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, the photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the developing roller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and the like are installed in a process cartridge <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. This process cartridge <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is provided detachably attachable to the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and members around this glass will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top view taken from above of the copying machine under a condition where the original pressure board is removed. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view that schematically shows a state where an original is fed by the automatic original feeding unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> As described above, the original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is formed in the optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The aforementioned conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> is formed integrally with this original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> with injection molding or the like. This makes it possible to reduce the size of the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in comparison with a case where the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> is formed at a position that is different from the position of the original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. It is also possible to reduce the number of components in comparison with a case where the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> is formed as a component separated from the original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Also, when the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is fixed to the original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is abutted against the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the position, at which the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is fixed, is determined by the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>, so that the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> doubles as a member for positioning the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and therefore the number of components is reduced accordingly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> By the way, in the vicinity of the one end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, in the case where the original fixing method is selected, there is formed the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> against which an original placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is abutted for positioning. On the other hand, the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> described above is formed in the vicinity of the other end portion on a side opposite to the one end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, it becomes possible to arrange the automatic original feeding unit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the other end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. In the case of a construction where the automatic original feeding unit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is conversely arranged in the vicinity of the one end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, it is required to widen the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> (or to arrange a small original base glass separated from the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>), thereby the size of the original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is increased (widened) accordingly. As described above, in the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the conveying guide <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> and the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> are respectively formed at both end sides of the single original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, which precludes the necessity to use two original base glasses and makes it possible to reduce the size of the original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. As a result, it becomes possible to reduce the size of the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> accordingly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Also, in the copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, when the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> reads an original placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> starts to read the original from the vicinity of the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and continues the reading of the original while moving in the direction indicated by the arrow B. Accordingly, it becomes possible to swiftly start the reading of the original without moving the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> from the vicinity of the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Second Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> A digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (an image forming apparatus of according to a second invention of the present invention) of a second embodiment will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an internal construction of the digital copying machine of the second embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The basic construction of the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of the second embodiment is the same as that of the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment and construction elements that are the same as those shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> are given the same reference symbols. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> When forming an image recorded on an original on a recording medium, the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is capable of selecting one of an original fixing scanning mode and an image flow reading scanning mode. The original fixing scanning mode means a mode with which an original is placed on an original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and an image of the original is read through scanning where a CIS (contact image sensor) <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> (an example of the reading means of the present invention) moves below the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> in a direction indicated by an arrow B (a scanning direction). On the other hand, the image flow reading scanning mode means a mode with which under a condition where the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> stays below an image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, an image on an original is read in the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> using the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> while an original automatic conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> conveys the original to the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> In the case where the original fixing scanning mode is selected, an original pressure board <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is first opened. Then, an original is placed on the upper surface of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and is abutted against an abutting board <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, thereby positioning this original. Following this, the original is pressed and fixed with the original pressure board <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Next, by pushing a predetermined operation button or the like, the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> installed in an optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> performs scanning in the direction indicated by the arrow B from a position indicated by a chain double-dashed line, thereby reading an image recorded on the original with this CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The read image is converted into a digital signal, which is then sent to a laser scanner <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Note that the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is fixed to a rectangular original base frame <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> formed in the optical case <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Also, the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is installed in an image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is driven by a drive motor (not shown) or a drive belt (not shown) and moves in the directions indicated by the arrows A and B while being guided by the guide axis <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> There will be described a case where the image flow reading scanning mode is selected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> To perform a flow reading operation for an original, the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is equipped with the original automatic conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. This original automatic conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> automatically feeds an original so that the original passes through the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in which an image recorded on the original is read (an image of the original is read). The image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is formed in a portion on the downstream side of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> in the direction indicated by the arrow B as described above, and extends in a direction perpendicular to the direction indicated by arrow B. Also, in the case where the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> selects the image flow reading scanning mode, the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> stays on a side opposite to the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> (the lower side of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>) with the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> being sandwiched therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> described above is formed in one end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> on a side opposite to a fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, with a photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> being sandwiched therebetween. Also, if the number of originals that should be read is large when the image flow reading scanning mode is selected, a time, during which the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> stays, is elongated. The CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is generally vulnerable to heat, but in the image flow reading scanning mode of this embodiment, the staying CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> exists separately from the fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is hardly influenced by the heat generated by the fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. As a result, it is not required to provide the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> with a cooling apparatus or the like for cooling the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, it becomes possible to reduce the number of components and to reduce the size of the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> In the original automatic conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, there are formed an original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, on which an original is placed, and an original discharging tray <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> on which the original having passed through the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is placed. Also, in the original automatic conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, there are installed a plurality of rollers (a sheet feeding roller <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, a registration roller pair <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, and the like) that convey the original placed on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> to the original discharging tray <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> through the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The original placed on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is fed to the registration roller pair <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> from a sheet feeding opening <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by the sheet feeding roller <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The registration roller pair <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> performs skew feeding correction. The original that has been subjected to the skew feeding correction is conveyed to a platen roller <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> by the registration roller pair <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and passes through the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. A spacer (not shown) for forming a space between the roller surface of the platen roller <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and the upper surface of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is provided at both end portions of the platen roller <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> in a lengthwise direction. This spacer makes it possible to convey this original while having the image surface of the original contact the upper surface of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. Note that in the vicinity of the sheet feeding roller <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, there is arranged a detection sensor <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> for detecting the presence or absence of a recording medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is positioned below the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the original passing through the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is illuminated by an LED (not shown) and is read by the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The read image is converted into a digital signal, which is then sent to the laser scanner <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> The original having passed through the image reading region <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is guided to a reversing roller <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> by the conveying guide base <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> that includes an inclined surface <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed so as to direct the original upward. The reversing roller <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> reverses the front surface and the rear surface of the original and conveys it to a sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. The original conveyed to the sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> is discharged to the original discharging tray <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> by this sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> As described above, in the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, regardless of which one of the image flow reading scanning mode or the original fixing scanning mode is used, a read image of an original is converted into a digital signal, which is then sent to a laser scanner <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The signal sent to the laser scanner <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is converted into a laser light, which is then irradiated onto the photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> through a scanner mirror <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that rotates at high speed and a return mirror <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is uniformly charged by a charger <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and an electrostatic latent image is formed on the photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> through the irradiation of the laser light. This electrostatic latent image is developed by a developer supplied from a developing roller <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, thereby forming a developed image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, a recording medium, such as recording paper, is fed from a cassette <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> by a sheet feeding roller <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> in a direction indicated by an arrow D (in a sheet feeding direction) and is conveyed to a transferring device <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> by a conveying roller <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and a registration roller <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. In the transferring device <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, the developed image on the photosensitive drum <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is transferred onto the conveyed recording medium. The recording medium, on which the developed image has been transferred, is conveyed to the fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> by a conveying apparatus <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. In the fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, there are arranged a heating roller <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a pressurizing roller <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The recording medium is conveyed while being nipped between these two rollers <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, so that the developed image is fixed on the recording medium. The recording medium, on which the developed image has been fixed in this manner, is discharged by the sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and is stacked on the sheet discharging tray <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> It should be noted here that a heater <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is embedded in the heating roller <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the fixing device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> described above. Control is performed so that the heater <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is heated when an image is to be formed on a recording medium but is not heated when no image is to be formed on a recording medium. That is, the heater <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is controlled using a so-called on-demand method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Third Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Next, there will be described a third embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a drawing showing an outline of a construction of a digital copying machine that is an example of an image forming apparatus according to this embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> In this drawing, reference numeral <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> denotes a CIS that is provided in an image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and reads an original placed on an original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, and reference numeral <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> represents a guide axis that guides the movement and scanning of the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> It should be noted here that the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> includes the CIS <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and an unillustrated LED for illuminating an original to be read through the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Also, reference numeral <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> denotes an original abutting board that is provided in one end portion of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and positions the original placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, and reference numeral <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> represents a white reference board (shading correction board) for detecting data concerning the amount of light of the LED at the center and both ends of the original, the variations of the sensitivity of a light-receiving element arranged within the CIS, and the like. This white reference board <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is arranged on the underside of the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> It should be noted here that in this embodiment, as shown in the drawing, the stand-by position of the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is a position in the vicinity of the white reference board <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> that opposes the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>, with the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> being sandwiched therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> Also, a platen roller <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is provided on a side opposite to the one end side of the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> on which the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is provided, as shown in the drawing. Accordingly, in this embodiment, a position at which the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> performs the original flow reading exists on the other end side of the original base glass that is separated from the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> by a region in which an original placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is read and scanned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Also, in the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> having a construction like this, in the case where an original is subjected to a flow reading operation, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, an original S is first stacked on an original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> so that the image surface faces down. Then, after the original S is stacked in this manner, a signal showing that an original is set on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is inputted from a sensor <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> into a control device <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. On the basis of this signal, the control device <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> detects that the original is set on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when a copy start key <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is operated to input an image reading operation start signal after the original S is placed on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, on the basis of this signal and a detection signal from the sensor <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, the control device <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> inputs a drive signal into a motor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in order to move the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> from a stand-by position indicated by a broken line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> to an original flow reading position indicated by a solid line. By this operation, the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> moves in a direction indicated by an arrow B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Here, in this embodiment, the original flow reading position is set on the other end side of the original base glass that is separated from the original abutting board <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> by the region in which an original placed on the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is read and scanned, as described above. Also, in the case where the original flow reading position is set at such a position, a distance, by which the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> moves to the flow reading position, is increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> However, even in the case where the distance, by which the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> moves to the flow reading position, is increased like this, by moving the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> to the original flow reading position after a reading instruction is issued, it is possible to further increase the productivity of the digital copying machine <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> because no time is unnecessarily consumed to move the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Next, when it is detected that the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> reaches the original flow reading position using an unillustrated timer or sensor, the control device <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> drives a sheet feeding roller <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> so that each sheet of the original S placed on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is separately fed. Then, the original S separately fed in this manner is subjected to skew correction by a pair of registration rollers <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and is conveyed to a platen roller <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> During this operation, that is, when the original S is conveyed to the platen roller <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> has already moved to the original flow reading position that opposes the platen roller <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> with the original base glass <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> being sandwiched therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, after passing above the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, the original S, whose image has been read, passes through a conveying guide base <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and is stacked on an original discharging tray <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> through the sheet discharging roller <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. Note that after this operation, when all sheets of the original S are read and no sheet of the original S remains on the original placing tray <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, no detection signal is inputted from the sensor <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. As a result, the control device <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> judges that the reading operation is finished, and drives the motor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to return the image reading unit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> to the stand-by position. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An image reading apparatus including an original base for which a predetermined image reading region is formed and on which an original is placed, image reading means that is arranged below said original base and reads an image of the original, and an original automatic conveying apparatus that conveys the original to said image reading region, 
<claim-text>said image reading apparatus reading the image of the original by selecting one of an original fixing scanning mode and an image flow reading scanning mode, the original fixing scanning mode being a mode with which the original is placed on said original base and the image of the original is read by having said image reading means perform scanning in a predetermined scanning direction below said original base, and the image flow reading scanning mode being a mode with which said image reading means is set to stay below said image reading region and the image of the original is read using said image reading means in said image reading region by conveying the original to said image reading region using said original automatic conveying apparatus, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said image reading apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an abutting member which is formed in the vicinity of one end portion of said original base and against which the original placed on said original base is abutted when the original fixing scanning mode is selected; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveying guide base that is formed on the other end portion side of said original base opposite to said abutting member and guides the original conveyed to said image reading region by said original automatic conveying apparatus to a predetermined original discharging tray. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An image reading apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said original base has an original base glass, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of said abutting member and said conveying guide base is formed integrally with an original base frame to which said original base glass is fixed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An image reading apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said original base has an original base glass, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said conveying guide base is formed integrally with said original base frame to which said original base glass is fixed, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a position, at which said original base glass is fixed, is determined by abutment of said original base glass against said original base frame when said original base glass is fixed to said original base frame. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An image reading apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said original base includes said image reading region that is formed to be used in the image flow reading scanning mode, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the original is placed on said original base when the original fixing scanning mode is selected. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An image forming apparatus including an original base for which a predetermined image reading region is formed and on which an original is placed, image reading means that is arranged below said original base and reads an image of the original, and an original automatic conveying apparatus that conveys the original to said image reading region, 
<claim-text>said image forming apparatus forming the read image on a recording medium by reading the image of the original by selecting one of an original fixing scanning mode and an image flow reading scanning mode, the original fixing scanning mode being a mode with which the original is placed on said original base and the image of the original is read by having said image reading means perform scanning in a predetermined scanning direction below said original base, and the image flow reading scanning mode being a mode with which said image reading means is set to stay below said image reading region and the image of the original is read using said image reading means in said image reading region by conveying the original to said image reading region using said original automatic conveying apparatus, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said image forming apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an abutting member which is formed in the vicinity of one end portion of said original base and against which the original placed on said original base is abutted when the original fixing scanning mode is selected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveying guide base that is formed on the other end portion side of said original base opposite to said abutting member and guides the original conveyed to said image reading region by said original automatic conveying apparatus to a predetermined original discharging tray; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a photosensitive drum on which a developed image of an image read by said image reading means is formed; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fixing device that fixes the developed image on the recording medium conveyed from said photosensitive drum, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said original base has said image reading region formed in one end portion thereof on a side opposite to said fixing device with said photosensitive drum being sandwiched therebetween, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said image reading means stays below said image reading region when the image flow reading scanning mode is selected. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An image forming apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said original base has an original base glass, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of said abutting member and said conveying guide base is formed integrally with an original base frame to which said original base glass is fixed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An image forming apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said original base has an original base glass, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said conveying guide base is formed integrally with said original base frame to which said original base glass is fixed, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a position, at which said original base glass is fixed, is determined by abutment of said original base glass against said original base frame when said original base glass is fixed to said original base frame. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An image forming apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said original base includes said image reading region that is formed to be used in the image flow reading scanning mode, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the original is placed on said original base when the original fixing scanning mode is selected. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An image reading apparatus for an image forming apparatus including an original base for which a predetermined image reading region is formed and on which an original is placed, image reading means that is arranged below said original base and reads an image of the original, and an original automatic conveying apparatus that conveys the original to said image reading region, 
<claim-text>said image forming apparatus forming the read image on a recording medium by reading the image of the original by selecting one of an original fixing scanning mode and an image flow reading scanning mode, the original fixing scanning mode being a mode with which the original is placed on said original base and the image of the original is read by having said image reading means perform scanning in a predetermined scanning direction below said original base, and the image flow reading scanning mode being a mode with which said image reading means is set to stay below said image reading region and the image of the original is read using said image reading means in said image reading region by conveying the original to said image reading region using said original automatic conveying apparatus, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said image reading apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an abutting member which is formed in the vicinity of one end portion of said original base and against which the original placed on said original base is abutted when the original fixing scanning mode is selected; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveying guide base that is formed on the other end portion side of said original base opposite to said abutting member and guides the original conveyed to said image reading region by said original automatic conveying apparatus to a predetermined original discharging tray; </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting means for detecting that the original is placed on original placing means provided for said original automatic feeding apparatus; </claim-text>
<claim-text>image reading operation start means that is operated to start an image reading operation; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>position control means for moving said image reading means from a stand-by position to the predetermined reading position before the original is fed by said original automatic feeding apparatus, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein if a detection signal is inputted from said detecting means when said image reading operation start means is operated, said position control means moves said image reading means from the stand-by position to the predetermined reading position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An image reading apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein when no detection signal is inputted from said detecting means, said position control means judges that image reading is finished and moves said image reading means from the predetermined reading position to the stand-by position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An image forming apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an image reading apparatus that reads an image of an original; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an image forming portion that forms an image based on image information read by said image reading apparatus, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said image reading apparatus is an image reading apparatus according to one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00010">10</dependent-claim-reference>.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002897A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
