<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002557A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002557A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002557A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002557A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002557A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002557A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002557A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002557A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002557</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10235714</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020906</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01S005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01S003/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>372</class>
<subclass>050000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>372</class>
<subclass>096000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>022000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Low temperature distributed feedback laser with loss grating and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10235714</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020906</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09437424</doc-number>
<document-date>19991115</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6477194</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lars</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Eng</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fogelsville</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ram</given-name>
<family-name>Jambunathan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Allentown</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kishore</given-name>
<middle-name>K.</middle-name>
<family-name>Kamath</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Whitehall</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alexander</given-name>
<family-name>Robertson</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lawrenceville</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Daniel</given-name>
<middle-name>Paul</middle-name>
<family-name>Wilt</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Orefield</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>DICKSTEIN SHAPIRO MORIN &amp; OSHINSKY LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2101 L STREET NW</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20037-1526</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A low threshold distributed feedback (DFB) laser is constructed for improved performance at subzero temperatures. A loss grating is employed to enhance the probability that lasing occurs near the short wavelength side of the stopband and to counteract the effect of negative gain tilt that occurs when DFB lasers are positively detuned. A method of making DFB lasers from wafers with improved yield for low temperature side mode suppression ratio (SMSR) is also disclosed. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to semiconductor lasers and methods of making and using such devices, and more particularly, to distributed feedback (DFB) lasers that operate satisfactorily at low temperatures. The invention also relates to a method of making DFB lasers from semiconductor wafers and the like. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Distributed feedback (DFB) lasers may be used, for example, as sources of signal radiation for optical fiber communications systems, as optical pumps, and as devices for generating coherent optical pulses. In a conventional DFB device, feedback is provided in the longitudinal direction (the emission direction) by an index grating (a periodic array of materials having different optical indices). In another type of DFB laser, a loss grating is used to provide a periodic variation in loss in the longitudinal direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> There is a need in the art for semiconductor DFB lasers that provide improved performance under conditions, such as low temperature, where they would be positively detuned and suffer degradation in side mode suppression ratio (SMSR, discussed in more detail below). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows the relationship between output light intensity I and wavelength &lgr; for a typical DFB laser, where: &lgr;<highlight><subscript>m </subscript></highlight>corresponds to the side mode on the short wavelength side of the stopband; &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>corresponds to the selected lasing mode; and &lgr;<highlight><subscript>p </subscript></highlight>corresponds to the side mode on the long wavelength side of the stopband. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the lasing symmetry L<highlight><subscript>sym </subscript></highlight>for a particular device may be defined as follows:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>L</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>sym</subscript></highlight>&equals;(&lgr;<highlight><subscript>p</subscript></highlight>&minus;&lgr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>)/(&lgr;<highlight><subscript>p</subscript></highlight>&minus;&lgr;<highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>).&emsp;&emsp;(1)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> According to equation (1), if the lasing symmetry L<highlight><subscript>sym </subscript></highlight>is smaller than 0.5, then &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>is closer to &lgr;<highlight><subscript>p</subscript></highlight>, and if L<highlight><subscript>sym </subscript></highlight>is greater than 0.5, then &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>is closer to &lgr;<highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The loss function for a DFB laser may be expressed in terms of the coupling coefficient &kgr;, as follows:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&kgr;&equals;&kgr;<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&plus;jn</italic></highlight>, where&emsp;&emsp;(2)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> &kgr;<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>represents the real part of the coupling coefficient &kgr;, and jn represents the imaginary part of the coefficient &kgr;. In a pure index grating DFB laser, jn&equals;0, and there is an equal probability of lasing on the long or short wavelength sides of the stopband, as discussed in more detail below. The term &ldquo;side mode suppression ratio&rdquo;(or sub-mode suppression ratio) refers to the ratio of main longitudinal mode power to side longitudinal mode power. Some high capacity fiber optic communications systems require a light source that generates a single longitudinal laser mode. A communications system may require a side mode suppression ratio exceeding 30 dB, for example. For a DFB laser to operate in a single longitudinal mode, the side longitudinal modes should be suppressed to relatively insignificant power levels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The side mode suppression ratio (SMSR) changes when the laser is tuned to different operating wavelengths. A DFB laser may exhibit acceptable side mode suppression at certain wavelengths, but unacceptable side mode suppression when tuned to other wavelengths. A small tuning change may cause a 10 dB to 20 dB decrease in the SMSR. This is because the relative net threshold gain required for each mode varies as the laser is tuned. When the main longitudinal mode is centered within the reflection characteristics of the laser, side mode suppression is usually optimized. As the device is tuned away from the optimum position, one of the side longitudinal modes is moved closer to the center of the reflection characteristics. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A distributed feedback (DFB) laser having a lasing symmetry L<highlight><subscript>sym</subscript></highlight>&gt;0.5 provides improved performance (high SMSR) under conditions where it would be positively detuned. An example of a condition where a DFB laser would be positively detuned is at low temperatures (for example, &minus;15&deg; C. to &minus;40&deg; C.). Thus, the production yield of DFB devices that perform well at low temperature can be increased by forming them in such a way as to increase the likelihood that the devices have lasing symmetries greater than 0.5. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A DFB laser is &ldquo;positively detuned&rdquo; when its lasing wavelength (selected mode) is on the long wavelength side of the peak of the material gain spectrum. If the lasing mode is on the long wavelength side, the inherent gain margin is reduced by the relatively large negative gain tilt (dg/d&lgr;) on the long wavelength side. By adding a small amount of loss to the laser grating (that is, by making jn&gt;0), the likelihood that the device will lase on the long-wavelength side of the stop band is reduced. In other words, a DFB laser with a loss grating is more likely to have a lasing symmetry L<highlight><subscript>sym</subscript></highlight>&gt;0.5. If more devices from a wafer are produced with L<highlight><subscript>sym</subscript></highlight>&gt;0.5, then the yield to the low temperature performance requirement is increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method of making low threshold semiconductor DFB lasers for low temperature operation. The method includes the steps of: (1) providing a multi-layer semiconductor structure, such as a wafer, having an active layer, a loss grating, and a spacer layer; and (2) cleaving the multi-layer structure such that opposed facets intersect the loss grating. The cleaving process is such that the precise location at which a particular facet intersects the loss grating cannot be controlled in advance. As discussed in more detail below, the performance characteristics of the laser depend in part on the phase relationships between the randomly determined locations of the facets and the periodic structure of the loss grating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, the facets may be covered by highly reflective and anti-reflective coatings, and other structures such as claddings, substrates, electrodes, etc. may also be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, the loss grating may be grown on a semiconductor substrate by a metal organic chemical vapor deposition (MOCVD) process. In a preferred embodiment of the invention, the loss grating has a high As content and therefore is well suited for reliable growth according to an MOCVD process. In another embodiment of the invention, the loss grating may be formed by molecular beam epitaxy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, lasers are constructed to provide high side mode suppression under conditions where they would be positively detuned. An example of such conditions is where the operating temperature is less than about minus fifteen degrees Celsius (&minus;15&deg; C.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The present invention also relates to a DFB laser for low temperature single mode operation, including: an active layer for producing optical gain; a loss grating for shifting the emission spectrum to the short wavelength side of the stopband; and a spacer layer located between the active layer and the loss grating. According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, the device has a lasing symmetry L<highlight><subscript>sym</subscript></highlight>&gt;0.5. Consequently, the device does not lase on the long wavelength side of the stopband under low temperature conditions. The low operating temperature may be, for example in the range of from &minus;150&deg; to &minus;400&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, a DFB laser is constructed to have a high SMSR, to operate at a low threshold, and to exhibit minimal mode hopping, all at low temperatures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, a device is provided that operates in a single longitudinal mode, with a large gain threshold difference, and that has facet-reflectivity-independent parameters, and low sensitivity to feedback. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the invention, the problems of the prior art are overcome by using a loss grating to shift the distribution of lasing modes, generated by random facet phases, to the short wavelength side of the stopband. The loss grating counteracts the effect of the negative gain tilt that occurs in DFB lasers due to positive detuning at subzero temperatures. According to the present invention, temperature-induced variations of the operational characteristics of a DFB laser are minimized.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates the mode intensity distribution for a typical distributed feedback laser. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a DFB laser constructed in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a histogram showing the distribution of lasing symmetries for DFB lasers with index gratings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> are histograms showing the distribution of lasing symmetries for DFB lasers with loss gratings, where jn&equals;0.1 and 0.2, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flowchart for a method of making semiconductor lasers according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the drawings, where like reference numerals designate like elements, there is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2 a</cross-reference> distributed feedback (DFB) laser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> constructed in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention. The device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a spacer layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, an active region <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and a cladding structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The cladding structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be formed of plural layers in a manner known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In addition, the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has front and back facets <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The facets <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may be formed by cleaving the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from a wafer (not shown). An anti-reflective (AR) layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is coated on the front facet <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A highly reflective (HR) layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is coated on the back facet <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The thicknesses of the two coatings <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> correspond to the wavelength of the emitted light <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In operation, an electrical current is caused to flow through the active region <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in a known manner. The current causes the active region <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to generate light (or gain), such that a signal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is emitted through the AR layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The signal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may have a wavelength in the range of from 1.3 &mgr;m to 1.6 &mgr;m for use in an optical communications system, for example. As discussed in more detail below, the illustrated laser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> performs satisfactorily, with high side mode suppression, even at low temperatures, for example, in the range of from &minus;15&deg; C. to &minus;<highlight><bold>40 &deg; C. </bold></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be formed of doped InP or another suitable semiconductor material. The loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be formed of InGaAsP, with a high As mole fraction, and is preferably lattice matched to the substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with a band gap that is 50 nm to 100 nm greater than the targeted lasing wavelength. The loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> has an alternating, periodic structure in the longitudinal direction of the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (the longitudinal direction is the direction of light emission). The grating period A is preferably in the range of from about 2,000&angst; to about 2,500&angst;. The thickness t of the loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be in the range of from about 200&angst; to about 500&angst;, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The spacer layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is located between the loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a lower portion of the active region <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The spacer layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be formed of InP. In the illustrated embodiment, the thickness <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the spacer layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be in the range of from about 3,000&angst; to about 6,000&angst;. The present invention should not be limited, however, to the details of the preferred embodiments described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The active region <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be formed of bulk InGaAsP and/or multiple quantum wells. There may be for example, five to nine quantum wells with a 1% compressive strain. Each quantum well layer may have a width of about 70&angst;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Since the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is cleaved from a wafer, the cleaved facets <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> intersect the periodic grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at random, arbitrary locations. When a plurality of devices <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are cleaved from a single wafer (not shown), the performance of each device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> depends on the randomly determined locations of the facets <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> relative to the grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is formed across the entire wafer before the cleaving operation. Consequently, the lasers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> have facets <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> intersecting the periodic loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at different phases &Oslash;. Some devices <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will perform differently than others, depending on the phases &Oslash; of the loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at the points of intersection with the facets <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The relationship between the facet reflectivity R on either end of the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the respective facet phase &Oslash; is as follows:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>R&equals;e</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>i&Oslash;</superscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(3)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> By employing equation (3), the expected lasing symmetry L<highlight><superscript>sym </superscript></highlight>for a cleaved laser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be calculated for each possible combination of facet phases &Oslash;. FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> show histograms of L<highlight><subscript>sym </subscript></highlight>values for distributions calculated by varying the phases &Oslash; at the ends of different devices in steps of 10&deg; , from 0&deg; to 350&deg;, for a total of 1296 facet phase combinations for each distribution. For each histogram, the lasing symmetry distribution is characterized as a function of &mgr; and &sgr;, where &mgr; represents the calculated numerical median of the distribution and &sgr; represents the standard deviation, on the assumption that it would be normal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the distribution of lasing symmetries for DFB lasers with pure index gratings (&kgr; is real). For &kgr;L&equals;1.5, the calculated median is &mgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;0.4998, at a calculated standard deviation &sgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;0.1573. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, in contrast, show the distribution of lasing symmetries for DFB lasers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with loss gratings <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, where jn&equals;0.1 and 0.2, respectively. In the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> distributions, the complex part jn of the coupling coefficient K is nonzero because the bandgap of the grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is greater than the wavelength of the emitted radiation, and absorption occurs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the lasing symmetry distribution is shifted, and the calculated median is higher than the median for a pure index grating DFB laser because &lgr;<highlight><subscript>0 </subscript></highlight>is closer to &lgr;<highlight><subscript>m </subscript></highlight>The calculated median for <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, where jn&equals;0.1, is &mgr;&equals;0.5859, at a standard deviation &sgr;<highlight><subscript>2&equals;</subscript></highlight>0.1524. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> With respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, where the loss is increased relative to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the combination of facet phases yielding a lasing mode on the long wavelength side of the stopband is smaller than that calculated for <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. For <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the calculated median is &mgr;<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&equals;0.6435, considerably higher than the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> value, at a standard deviation &sgr;<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&equals;0.1322. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Thus, the loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be used to increase the probability that a laser <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> cleaved from a wafer (not illustrated) operates on the short wavelength side of the stopband. As demonstrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, the percentage of devices that lase on the long-wavelength side is smaller, and consequently the yield for high SMSR at low temperature increases. Because of the more advantageous distribution for low temperature performance, an increased number of low temperature devices can be cleaved from a single wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> wafer (not illustrated) may be constructed <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with layers corresponding to the substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, spacer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, active layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and cladding structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The loss grating layer advantageously may be formed by an MOCVD process. Each layer of the wafer (including the loss grating layer) may extend with a constant thickness across essentially the full extent of the wafer. The wafer may then be cleaved <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> into a large number of devices. The cleaving process <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> forms the facets <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at different phases &Oslash; of the loss grating <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The facets <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are then coated <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> with the desired coatings <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and the finished lasers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are then tested <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> for performance characteristics. The lasers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that will perform well at low temperatures may be selected or identified (by, for example, analyzing the DFB mode spectroscopy) for appropriate low temperature applications. A spectrum analyzer may thus be used to select only the shortwavelength devices cleaved from the wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The above description illustrates preferred embodiments which achieve the objects, features and advantages of the present invention. It is not intended that the present invention be limited to the illustrated embodiments. Any modification of the present invention that comes within the spirit and scope of the following claims should be considered part of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed as new and desired to be protected by Letters Patent of the United States is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of making semiconductor lasers for low temperature operation, said method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a multi-layer semiconductor structure having an active layer, a loss grating, and a spacer layer, said spacer layer being located between said active layer and said loss grating; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>cleaving said multi-layer semiconductor structure such that opposed facets intersect said loss grating. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of locating highly reflective and anti-reflective coatings on said facets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of forming said loss grating on a semiconductor substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said loss grating is formed by metal organic chemical vapor deposition or molecular beam epitaxy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of forming a semiconductor cladding structure on said active layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lasers are constructed to provide high side mode suppression in a positively detuned state. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method of producing a plurality of distributed feedback semiconductor lasers, said method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a multi-layer semiconductor wafer having an active layer, a loss grating, and a spacer layer, said spacer layer being located between said active layer and said loss grating; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>cleaving said multi-layer semiconductor structure such that opposed facets intersect said loss grating. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of locating highly reflective and anti-reflective coatings on said facets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said loss grating has a grating period in the direction of light emission in the range of from about two thousand angstroms to about two thousand five hundred angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of forming said grating on a semiconductor substrate by metal organic chemical vapor deposition. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of forming a semiconductor cladding on said active layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said spacer has a thickness in the range of from about three thousand angstroms to about six thousand angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lasers provide high side mode suppression when operated at less than &minus;15&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of using a spectrum analyzer to identify said lasers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A distributed feedback laser for low temperature operation, said laser comprising: 
<claim-text>an active layer for producing optical gain in response to an electrical current; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a loss grating for shifting the emission spectrum of said laser to the short wavelength side of a stopband; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a spacer layer located between said active layer and said loss grating. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The distributed feedback laser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising cleaved facets on opposed ends, and wherein said facets intersect said loss grating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The distributed feedback laser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising highly reflective and anti-reflective coatings on said facets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The distributed feedback laser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said loss grating has a grating period of from about two thousand angstroms to about two thousand five hundred angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The distributed feedback laser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the thickness of said loss grating is in the range of from about three thousand angstroms to about six thousand angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The distributed feedback laser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said active layer has compressive strain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The distributed feedback laser of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said active layer includes quantum wells.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002557A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002557A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002557A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002557A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
