<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001535A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001535A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001535</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896056</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B25J015/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G05B019/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>318</class>
<subclass>568210</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Four-bar linkage wafer clamping mechanism</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Venugopal</given-name>
<family-name>Menon</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Redwood City</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Damon</given-name>
<middle-name>Keith</middle-name>
<family-name>Cox</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Round Rock</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Applied Materials, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>APPLIED MATERIALS, INC.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2881 SCOTT BLVD. M/S 2061</address-1>
<city>SANTA CLARA</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95050</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The wafer clamping mechanism comprises a linkage mechanism and a wafer contact point coupled to the linkage mechanism. The linkage mechanism includes a four-bar linkage having: a first link having a first fixed pivot and a first floating pivot remote from the first fixed pivot; a second link having a second fixed pivot and a second floating pivot remote from the second fixed pivot; and a third link having a first coupling pivot rotatably coupled to the first floating pivot, and having a second coupling pivot rotatably coupled to the second floating pivot. In use motion of the linkage mechanism causes the wafer contact point to clamp a wafer. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a clamping mechanism for securing a semiconductor wafer during wafer handling. More particularly, the present invention is directed to a four bar linkage mechanism that securely clamps a semiconductor wafer near the distal end of a robot arm. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A wafer is the base material, usually silicon, used in semiconductor chip or integrated circuit fabrication. Typically, the wafer is a thin slice of base material cut from an ingot or &ldquo;boule.&rdquo; Each 8 inch (200 mm) production wafer is approximately {fraction (1/30)} inches (0.85 mm) thick and has a diameter that varies by &plusmn;1 mm. Because of the nature of the base material and the thinness of each slice, the wafer can easily be damaged through mishandling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Wafers are typically processed into semiconductor chips by sequentially exposing each wafer to a number of individual processes, such as photo masking, etching and implantation. Modem semiconductor processing systems include cluster tools that aggregate multiple chambers together, where one or more of the individual processes are performed in each chamber. These chambers may include, for example, degas chambers, substrate pre-conditioning chambers, cool down chambers, transfer chambers, chemical vapor deposition chambers, physical vapor deposition chambers, etch chambers, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Typically, these chambers surround a central chamber housing a wafer handling robot. The cluster tool also typically includes a cassette in which multiple wafers are stacked before and after semiconductor fabrication. The wafer handling robot has access to the multiple chambers and the cassette, through ports coupling each chamber and cassette to the central chamber. During operation the wafer handling robot repetitively transports wafers from one chamber to another, or to and from the cassette. Furthermore, the cluster tool forms a sealed environment that is controlled to limit potential contamination of the semiconductors and to ensure that optimal processing conditions are maintained. Examples of cluster tools can be found in U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,955,858, 5,447,409, and 5,469,035, all of which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To increase fabrication efficiency, a high throughput of wafers is desirable. A high throughput can be achieved in a number of ways. First, duplicate chambers can be provided. This potential solution, however, substantially increases the cost and complexity of each cluster tool. Second, additional wafer handling robots can be provided in each cluster tool. Again, this solution substantially increases the cost and complexity of each cluster tool. Third, the speed of any individual process can be increased. Although optimization of each process is always being improved upon, each process is typically completed in as short a time as is currently possible. Finally, the handling speed of each wafer by the wafer handling robot can be increased. This solution, however, is subject to a number of criteria, such as: each wafer must be securely grasped or clamped by the wafer handling robot in the minimum amount of time; the clamping of the wafer must be firm, but not overly so, so as not to damage the fragile wafer; the clamping and placement of each wafer must be precise and accurate since any misplacement might negatively impact the process and/or damage the wafer; transfer between chambers, or into or out of the cassette, must be smooth so that the wafer does not undergo any unnecessary stress and in the worst case, if the wafer is dislodged from the clamping mechanism, this condition must be sensed, and the wafer transfer system must be halted; the clamping mechanism must be heat resistant, as some of the processes may expose the clamping mechanism to high temperatures; the clamping mechanism must not introduce any particulates or contaminants into the closed environment that can ultimately damage the wafer or semiconductors (it has been found that particulates as small as the critical dimension or line width of a semiconductor device, currently 0.18 &mgr;m, can damage the integrity of an integrated circuit formed on a wafer); the wafer clamping mechanism should be able to automatically center a misplaced wafer; and finally, the wafer clamping mechanism must not introduce a static electric field into the wafer, which might discharge and damage the semiconductor devices being fabricated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> To maximize system throughput, the wafer handling robot must rotate and extend as fast as possible without causing the clamped wafer to slip during transport. Slip occurs when the robot accelerates the wafer such that its inertia overcomes the clamping force of the clamping mechanism. This causes undesired wafer movement and results in wafer misalignment and particle generation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Of the abovementioned potential solutions to increasing wafer throughput, increasing the handling speed of each wafer is the most practical and cost effective. Therefore, to address the above criteria, a more robust and better designed wafer clamping mechanism is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A number of prior art devices have attempted to clamp the wafer in a way that addresses some or all of the abovementioned criteria. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A, 1B</cross-reference> and U.S. Pat. No. 5,955,858, show a bottom view of a wrist assembly <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of one such prior art device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with its bottom cover plate removed. Clamp fingers <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, shown extended from the wrist assembly <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, engage a perimeter of a wafer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to clamp the wafer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> onto a wafer carrying blade <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The wafer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is held between the fingers <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and a blade bridge <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> under forces applied by a pair of parallelogram springs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference>. Parallelogram springs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> bias the fingers <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> toward the wafer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The wrist assembly <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is coupled to the distal end of frog-leg type robot arms <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of a wafer handling robot. During extension of the robot arms <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, i.e., when the robot arms are drawn toward one another, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A, a</cross-reference> rotation is imparted on pivots <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, which in turn rotate cogs <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The cogs <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> in turn engage with the fingers <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to retract the fingers <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> away from the wafer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the wafer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is released when the robot arms <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are extended and clamped when the robot arms <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are retracted. If the fingers were directly attached to the cogs <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> then the clamping force would depend on the motion characteristics of the robot, for example the speed of extension and retraction of the robot arms <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In this device the fingers can be set independently by controlling the stiffness of the parallelogram spring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A drawback of this wrist assembly <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is that the parallelogram springs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are easily deformed by out-of-plane forces, causing the clamping force direction to deviate from the norm. This leads to unreliable clamping and potential particle contamination caused by friction between the fingers and the wafer. Furthermore, the cycle life of the parallelogram springs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> (approximately 1 year or 10 million spring cycles) has been found to be inadequate. In addition, the wrist assembly <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> does not provide for clamping a wafer that is not centered correctly. If the spring is deformed, the capture pocket, i.e., the total area in which the clamping mechanism can capture a wafer, could easily change, thereby, reducing the tolerance of the wafer handling system to deviations in the position of the wafer during transfer to and from each chamber. It has also been found that manufactured parallelogram springs are highly sensitive to manufacturing defects and mishandling before, during, and after installation, leading to unreliable clamping. Furthermore, the manufacturing process for the spring requires an electropolish step that cannot be controlled reliably. Finally, any kinks in the spring caused by mishandling lead to stress concentration points that reduce the fatigue life of the spring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A partial bottom view of another prior art clamp wrist assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> with its bottom cover plate partially removed is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C and in U.S. Pat. No. 6,155,773. This clamp wrist assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> comprises a lever assembly <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, a flexure member <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, and a pair of clamp fingers <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> that engage a wafer <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Leaf springs <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> bias the flexure member <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> against the wafer <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. When the clamp wrist assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is in its extended position, a translational member <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> engages a first lever <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> to retract the fingers from their clamping position. However, this wrist assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> does not clamp a wafer that is not centered correctly. Moreover, space limitations prevent this clamp wrist assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> from being implemented on an opposed dual blade robot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Finally, a partial bottom view of another prior art wafer holder <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> with its bottom cover plate removed is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D and U</cross-reference>.S. Pat. No. 5,810,935. Wafer holder <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes holding means <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> for holding rounded edges of wafer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, and an actuating means <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> for operating the holding means <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. Tension springs <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> bias the holding means <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> towards the wafer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. Not only does the actuating means introduce additional complexity and cost into the system, but it leads to more potential areas of particle generation and potential electrical fields, both of which might damage the wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In light of the above, there is a need for a wafer clamping mechanism that securely clamps a wafer for speedy handling, meets the abovementioned criteria, and addresses the drawbacks presented by the prior art. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A preferred embodiment of wafer clamping mechanism of the present invention comprises a linkage mechanism and a wafer contact point coupled to the linkage mechanism. The linkage mechanism is preferably coupled near to the distal end of a robot arm. The linkage mechanism preferably comprises a four-bar linkage having: a first link having a first fixed pivot and a first floating pivot distal from the first fixed pivot; a second link having a second fixed pivot and a second floating pivot distal from the second fixed pivot; and a third link having a first coupling pivot rotatably coupled to the first floating pivot, and having a second coupling pivot rotatably coupled to the second floating pivot. In use motion of the robot arm activates the linkage mechanism, which in turn causes the wafer contact point to clamp a wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the above described clamping mechanism reliably increases throughput while reducing cost. The clamping mechanism also provides the benefit of passive wafer centering, versus more costly active center finding methods, thereby eliminating the potential for failure due to variances in wafer placement.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> For a better understanding of the nature and objects of the invention, reference should be made to the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</cross-reference> are bottom and isometric views of a prior art wrist assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a bottom view of another prior art wrist assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> is a bottom view of yet another prior art wafer holder; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic top view of a wafer clamping mechanism with its top cover plate removed, according to an embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference> are top views of the wafer clamping mechanism shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> in both an extended position and a retracted position, respectively; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a exploded view of the linkage mechanism of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</cross-reference> are an exploded view and an assembled view of the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, respectively; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6 a</cross-reference> diagrammatic top view of another wafer clamping mechanism with its top cover plate removed, according to another embodiment of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Like reference numerals refer to corresponding parts throughout the several views of the drawings. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic top view of a portion of a wafer clamping mechanism <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> with its top cover plate removed, according to an embodiment of the invention. The clamping mechanism <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> securely clamps a wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>, positioned on a wafer carrying blade <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, to the distal end of one or more robot arms <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> of a wafer handling robot (not shown). The robot arm <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> shown is preferably one side of a frog-leg type robot arm of a wafer handling robot similar to that disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,955,858 (incorporated herein). The clamping mechanism <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, also includes a mirror reflection of the elements of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> about line <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. The complete clamping mechanism is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The distal end of the robot arm <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> is rotatably coupled to a wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> that is preferably located near the distal end of the robot arm <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>. The clamping mechanism <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes a linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> partially anchored to the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is a four bar linkage, which is a linkage consisting of an assemblage of four links which are pinned together head to tail in a closed loop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> comprises an elongate first link <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> having a first fixed pivot <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and a first floating pivot <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. The first fixed pivot <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and first floating pivot <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> are preferably positioned near opposing ends of the first link <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>. The first fixed pivot <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is rotatably anchored to the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the first fixed pivot <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is rotatably anchored to a first end of a ground link <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> that is anchored to the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> also comprises an elongate second link <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> having a second fixed pivot <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and a second floating pivot <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The second fixed pivot <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and second floating pivot <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> are preferably positioned near opposing ends of the second link <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. The second fixed pivot <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> is rotatably anchored to the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the second fixed pivot <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> is rotatably anchored to a second end of a ground link <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> that is anchored to the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. The first link <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and second link <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> are preferably rocker links that are configured to oscillate between two limit positions, but preferably cannot rotate continuously through 360 degrees. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> additionally comprises an elongate third link <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> coupling the first link <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> to the second link <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. The third link <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> includes a first coupling pivot <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> rotatably coupled to the first floating pivot <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, and a second coupling pivot <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> rotatably coupled to the second floating pivot <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the first floating pivot <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and the first coupling pivot <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> are one and the same. Likewise, in a preferred embodiment, the second floating pivot <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and the second coupling pivot <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> are one and the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the third link <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is preferably a floating link whose movement is only constrained by the rotation of the first floating pivot <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> about the first fixed pivot <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, and the second floating pivot <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> about the second fixed pivot <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The clamping mechanism <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> also includes a wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> coupled to the linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. In use, motion of the linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> causes the wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> to contact the wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>, thereby clamping the wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> between the wafer contact points <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> of two clamping mechanisms <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and a bridge <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) located at the distal end of a wafer carrying blade <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> is preferably coupled to a portion of the third link <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> that extends axially beyond said first coupling pivot <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The third link <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> also preferably includes an activation contact point <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> near the second coupling pivot <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. The activation contact point <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> is preferably positioned at a distal end of an elongate lip <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>. The lip <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> preferably extends substantially perpendicular to the third link <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, near the second coupling pivot <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> A biasing mechanism <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is coupled to the linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. The biasing mechanism <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> urges the linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and hence the wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>, against the wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. The biasing mechanism <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is preferably a simple extension spring, which can be customized for different applications by selecting various spring stiffnesses. These springs are available off-the-shelf and typically have a fatigue life of over 10 million cycles if the restoring force at full deformation is under 45% of the spring&apos;s UTS (Ultimate Tensile Strength). The biasing mechanism <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is preferably coupled on its one end to the ground link <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and on its other end to the second link <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, biasing the second link <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> to rotate toward the wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The end of the robot arm <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> is preferably coupled to a cam <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. The cam <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> in turn is rotatably coupled to the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> allowing the cam <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> to rotate about a cam pivot point <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>. A cog <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> extends radially from the perimeter of the cam <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> so that the cog <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> rotates together with the cam <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. The cam <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> is also coupled to a gear <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> such that opposing gears of opposing clamping mechanisms <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> intermesh to assure an equal and opposite angular rotation of each cam <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. This ensures that the blade and wafer are accurately extended by the robot arms, i.e., that the wrist is kept substantially perpendicular to the direction of extension and retraction of the robot arms. To eliminate play between these two gears, caused by a loose intermeshing of the gears, a weak spring (not shown) may be extended between a point on one gear to a point on the other gear such that the spring tension lightly rotates these two gears in opposite directions until light contact between these gears is produced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The inter-relationship between the lengths of the ground <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, first <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, second <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, and third <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> links are selected such that in use the wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> follows a predetermined locus. Movement of the wafer from a predetermined release position in a chamber can occur due to sudden dechucking, a surge in backside cooling gas pressure, or wafer lift vibrations while the wafer is still in a process chamber. To address this problem, the effective capture range of the clamping mechanism is set at approximately 0.125 in (3.175 mm) from the nominal wafer placement location. In other words, if a wafer were to move less than 0.125 in any direction, the clamp wrist is still able to capture the wafer in its pocket, thereby recentering, and clamping the wafer. The increased capture area adds robustness of the clamping mechanism in the event there is abnormal wafer movement in a process chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In most cases, wafer movement in a process chamber is physically constrained to less than the effective capture rage of the clamping mechanism. However, for the remaining cases where the wafer movement is completely unconstrained, a sensing system can be used to detect a wafer out-of-pocket condition, preventing handling faults or wafer breakage. A suitable sensing system is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,166,509, which is incorporated herein by reference. The sensing system includes a visual identification marker <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>, which is preferably located near to the wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. The visual identification marker <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> is used by the system to determine the location of the wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. This allows the system to sense if the wafer is not properly clamped by detecting if the visual identification marker <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> moves beyond a threshold position. The location of the visual identification marker <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> is also used to calculate the center of the wafer so that the movement of the robotic arms <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> can be controlled to accurately position the wafer in a process chamber or the like. This clamping mechanism, hence provides a benefit of passive wafer centering, versus more costly active center-finding methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Each pivot <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> preferably comprises a bearing and a pin. The bearing in turn preferably comprises multiple balls positioned within races, where one link is attached to the races of the bearing and the other link to the pin. The pin and races are preferably made from stainless steel, such as SST 440C, while the bearing is preferably made from either stainless steel or a ceramic, such as silicon nitride. Each link is preferably made from aluminum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference> are top views of the wafer clamping mechanism <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> in both an extended <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> position and a retracted <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> position, respectively. In use, when the robot arms <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> are extended <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>, i.e., when the frog-leg type robot arms <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> are rotated towards one another, the cams <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> rotate causing each cog <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) to contact its respective activation contact point <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) and, thereby, retract the wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) from the wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. Therefore, when the robot arms <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> are extended <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>, the wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> can be released in a chamber or cassette. Similarly, when the robot arms <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> are retracted <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, i.e., when the frog-leg type robot arms <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> are rotated away from one another, the wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> is clamped by the wafer clamping mechanism <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) so that the wafer <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> can be transferred to a different chamber or cassette. The timing of the release or clamp can be adjusted based on link lengths, transfer chamber size, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a exploded view of the linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Because many processes are sensitive to metal contamination, and the wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> can potentially shed particles onto the wafer, the wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> preferably includes a bearing with a sleeve <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> around it. This sleeve can be selected from a passive material so as not to react with process gases and discharge by-products or particulates onto the wafer. Moreover, a non rotatable contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> may cause the wafer to roll on the fingertip rather than slide on it. The net effect of this rolling motion is to displace the wafer center from the blade center, causing an incomplete clamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The wafer contact point <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> is preferably removable to allow various linkage mechanisms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to use wafer contact points <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> made from different materials. For example, a high temperature process could use a quartz wafer contact point, while a low temperature process could use a wafer contact point made from Delrin or aluminum. The materials chosen for the wafer contact point are based on characteristics, such as Coefficient of Thermal Expansion (CTE), corrosion resistance, and machinability constraints. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, the sleeve <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> is preferably titanium. Alternatively, the entire bearing and sleeve combination can be ceramic, which is significantly more resistant to corrosive chemicals. These bearings are preferably run dry, i.e., without lubricant, because outgassing of the bearing lubricant close to the wafer edge leads to wafer contamination. Therefore, a hybrid bearing is preferred. A suitable hybrid bearing for medium temperature (up to 450&deg; C.) processes includes Si3N4 balls, and 440C Stainless Steel races, run with minimal lubricant. Full ceramic bearings (Si3N4 balls and races) are typically not used as they cost ten times more than the hybrid bearings. Since the standard ball separators, such as cages, crowns, retainers, etc., are not corrosion resistant and the loads at the bearing axis are small, a full complement shielded radial bearing configuration is preferred. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The activation contact point <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> as well as each of the pivot points (<highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) do not have similar sleeves or bearings to those described above, as off-the-shelf bearings can be used since these bearings are not in close proximity to the wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The linkage mechanism <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> preferably also includes built-in hard-stops <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> that restrict the range of motion of the links, thereby, restricting the maximum deformation of the biasing mechanism <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and B</cross-reference> are an exploded view <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> and an assembled view <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> of the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, respectively. As can be seen, two linkage mechanisms <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> are positioned within the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. The cog <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> on the cam <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> is also shown. A cover <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> is secured to the wrist <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> to enclose the aforementioned components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6 a</cross-reference> diagrammatic top view of another wafer clamping mechanism <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> with its top cover plate removed, according to another embodiment of the invention. In this embodiment, a biasing mechanism <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> is coupled between a first link <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> and a ground link <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the biasing mechanism <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is preferably a compression spring. The biasing mechanism <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> biases a wafer contact point <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> into contact with a wafer <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The foregoing descriptions of specific embodiments of the present invention are presented for purposes of illustration and description. They are not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed, obviously many modifications and variations are possible in view of the above teachings. The embodiments were chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the invention and its practical applications, to thereby enable others skilled in the art to best utilize the invention and various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated. Furthermore, the order of steps in the method are not necessarily intended to occur in the sequence laid out. It is intended that the scope of the invention be defined by the following claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A wafer clamping mechanism, comprising: 
<claim-text>a linkage mechanism, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first link having a first fixed pivot and a first floating pivot remote from said first fixed pivot; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second link having a second fixed pivot and a second floating pivot remote from said second fixed pivot; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third link having a first coupling pivot rotatably coupled to said first floating pivot and having a second coupling pivot rotatably coupled to said second floating pivot; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wafer contact point coupled to said linkage mechanism, such that in use motion of said linkage mechanism causes said wafer contact point to contact a wafer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first and second links are rocker links that are configured to oscillate between two limit positions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said third link is a floating link. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said linkage mechanism is a four-bar linkage, further comprising a ground link between said first fixed pivot and said second fixed pivot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a wrist coupled to the distal end of a robotic arm, where said first and second fixed pivots are rotatably anchored to said wrist. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said wrist is further coupled to a wafer carrying blade. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a clamping activation mechanism that actuates said linkage mechanism when said robotic arm is in a predetermined position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a biasing mechanism coupled to said linkage mechanism, said biasing mechanism biasing said wafer contact point towards said wafer carrying blade. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said biasing member is coupled to said second link. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said clamping activation mechanism retracts said wafer contact point away from said wafer carrying blade when said robotic arm is in its extended position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said third link includes an activation contact point near said second floating pivot, where said activation contact point is configured to engage with said clamping activation mechanism. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said activation contact point is roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said activation contact point is an at least partly ceramic bearing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said third link includes a portion thereof that extends axially beyond said first coupling pivot, and where said contact point is coupled to said portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said contact point is a roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said roller includes an at least partly ceramic bearing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The wafer clamping mechanism of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising two linkage mechanisms and two wafer contact points. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A wafer clamping mechanism, comprising: 
<claim-text>a robot arm; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wrist located near the distal end of said robotic arm; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wafer carrying blade coupled to said wrist; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least two four-bar linkage mechanisms coupled to said wrist, said four-bar linkage mechanisms automatically clamping a wafer onto said blade when said robotic arm is in its retracted position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001535A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
