<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003719A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003719A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003719A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003719A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003719A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003719A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003719A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003719A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003719A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003719A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003719</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10180754</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020626</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-37810</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/4763</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/469</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/31</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>643000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>653000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>656000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bi</given-name>
<middle-name>O.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Han</given-name>
<middle-name>Choon</middle-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Daejeon</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>WILDMAN, HARROLD, ALLEN &amp; DIXON</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>225 WEST WACKER DRIVE</address-1>
<city>CHICAGO</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60606</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Disclosed is a method and an apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device. The disclosed comprises the steps of: forming an interlayer insulating layer having a contact hole on a semiconductor substrate; forming a Ti layer on the contact hole and on the interlayer insulating layer; and reacting the Ti layer with nitrogen radical to transform a part of the Ti layer into a TiN layer. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device and, more particularly, to a method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device to form a high purity TiN layer without performing Metal Organic Chemical Vapor deposition (MOCVD) process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> As is generally known, tungsten has been widely used to electrically connect upper and lower metal wire or metal wire and silicon substrate in semiconductor devices since tungsten has excellent thermal stability and step coverage. Before tungsten is deposited, Ti/TiN barrier layer is deposited ahead. The Ti layer of Ti/TiN barrier layer is used as a lower adhesive layer for the tungsten layer having poor adhesion with oxide layer and the TiN layer prevents reaction of the Ti layer and WF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, As the semiconductor device has been highly integrated, the size of contact hole becomes decreased and the depth becomes increased, thereby increasing the aspect ratio. Therefore, the Ti/TiN layer deposition by conventional sputtering method has reached the limitation. Considering this limitation, Collimator sputtering method and Low Through Sputtering (LTS) method have been proposed as a solution. However, these methods also have several defects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Recently, a new method has been proposed that the Ti layer is deposited by Ionized Metal Plasma (IMP) and the TiN layer is deposited by Metal Organic Chemical Vapor Deposition (MOCVD). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are drawings showing a conventional method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, first, an interlayer insulating layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, such as oxide layer, is deposited to have a sufficient thickness on a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, such as silicon substrate having a predetermined contact region. Thereafter, the part of the interlayer insulating layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> on the contact region of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is completely removed in accordance with a photolithography to expose the contact region, thereby forming a contact hole <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Then, a Ti layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is deposited to have a thickness of 50&tilde;300 &angst; on the lower part and the side of contact hole <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and on the surface of interlayer insulating layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in accordance with IMP process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, a TiN layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is deposited to have a thickness of 300&tilde;900 &angst; on the Ti layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in accordance with MOCVD process, wherein the TiN layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has a very low density. And, Tetrakis Dimethylamidotitanium (TDMAT) gas is generally used as a precursor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> After the deposition of the TiN layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the TiN layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is subjected to nitrogen (N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) plasma treatment, thereby transforming the TiN layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> having a low density into the TiN layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> having a high density, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Therefore, a barrier layer is completed, comprising the Ti layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the TiN layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> After the barrier layer is formed, a tungsten layer is filled only in the contact hole in accordance with a conventional process. Then, a metal layer, such as aluminum layer, is formed on the barrier layer outside of the tungsten layer and the contact hole and a photolithography process is performed to complete a metal wiring pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> However, the conventional method has several problems that the TiN layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, formed by MOCVD process, has inferior properties and aging effect that properties are changed as time passes. And, the MOCVD device is very expensive and difficult to maintain. Moreover, the TDMAT gas is highly toxic and inflammable, thereby increasing possibility of accident and having a bad effect on the environment. And, as the TiN layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is damaged by impurities such as residual gas, the properties of the TiN layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are deteriorated. The TiN layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may also be damaged during the plasma treatment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Moreover, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, it is difficult to perform plasma treatment on the sidewall of contact hole <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, thereby impurities, such as residual carbon (C), tend to remain on the TiN layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> located on the sidewall of contact hole <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the present invention has been made to solve the above problems and the object of the present invention is to provide a method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device capable of forming a high purity TiN layer without performing a MOCVD process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device capable of preventing deterioration of TiN layer by impurities and plasma treatment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Still another object of the present invention is to provide an apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer applying the above-mentioned method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In order to accomplish the above objects, the present invention comprises the steps of: forming an interlayer insulating layer having a contact hole on a semiconductor substrate; forming a Ti layer in the contact hole and on the interlayer insulating layer; and transforming an upper part of the Ti layer into a TiN layer by reacting the Ti layer with nitrogen radicals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the nitrogen radical is formed by performing high frequency microwave treatment to nitrogen gas. The frequency of microwave is in the range of 0.5 GHz to 4 GHz. The flow rate of nitrogen gas is in the range of 100 sccm to 10000 sccm. And, the TiN layer is formed at a temperature of normal to 500&deg; C. and the pressure of 10 mTorr to 10 Torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to the present invention includes: a reaction chamber; a heating unit arranged in the reaction chamber for supporting and heating a semiconductor substrate; a microwave generating unit for generating microwave; a nitrogen gas supplying unit for supplying nitrogen gas; a nitrogen radical generating unit for treating the nitrogen gas by the microwave to generate nitrogen radicals; and a nitrogen radical injecting unit arranged opposite to the heating unit in the reaction chamber with a predetermined distance for injecting the nitrogen radicals into the semiconductor substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Preferable, the microwave generating unit generates microwave in the range of 0.5 GHz to 4 GHz. The nitrogen gas supplying unit supplies nitrogen gas in the range of 100 sccm to 10000 sccm. The reaction chamber is maintained at a temperature of normal to 500&deg; C. and the pressure of 10 mTorr to 10 Torr. And, the nitrogen radical generating unit is arranged within 50 cm from the reaction chamber.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view showing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to a conventional art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference> are cross-sectional views showing a method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to the conventional art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are cross-sectional views showing a method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a drawing showing an outline of apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The objects and features of the invention may be understood with reference to the following detailed description of an illustrative embodiment of the invention, taken together with the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are cross-sectional views showing a method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to the present invention and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a drawing showing an outline of apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> heating unit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is provided on the lower part of the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> for supporting and heating a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to a predetermined temperature. A microwave generating unit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is arranged on the outside of reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to generate high frequency microwave. A nitrogen gas supplying unit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> supplies nitrogen gas to the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> through a nitrogen radical generating unit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> which is arranged on the outside of the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> for treating the nitrogen gas by the microwave to generate nitrogen radical. A nitrogen injecting unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is arranged opposite to the heating unit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> on the upper part thereof in the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> with a predetermined distance for injecting the nitrogen radical downward to the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through nozzle units <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The microwave generating unit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> generates microwave in the range of 0.5 GHz to 4 GHz and the nitrogen gas supplying unit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> supplies nitrogen gas in the range of 100 sccm to 10000 sccm. The reaction chamber is maintained at a temperature of normal to 500&deg; C. and a pressure of 10 mTorr to 10 Torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The nitrogen radical generating unit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is arranged within <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> cm from the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to use most of nitrogen radicals for the formation of TiN layer without returning to the original state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device by using the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> will be described in more detail with reference to drawings of FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, first, an interlayer insulating layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, such as oxide layer, is deposited to have a sufficient thickness on a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a predetermined contact region. Although it is not shown in the drawing, diffusion regions such as source and drain regions of transistor are formed on the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with a lower structure such as a gate electrode and a bit line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, the interlayer insulating layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> on the contact region of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is completely removed in accordance with a photolithography process to expose the contact region, thereby forming a contact hole <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Then, the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is arranged on the heating unit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> in the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Subsequently, a Ti layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is deposited on the lower part and the side of contact hole <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and on the surface of interlayer insulating layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> thicker than the Ti layer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in accordance with a general sputtering process, collimator sputtering process, IMP process or LTS process in order to improve step coverage. This is because a part of the Ti layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is to be used in the formation of TiN layer <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> by reacting the radical with the Ti of Ti layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> nitrogen gas supplying unit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> supplies nitrogen gas in the range of 100 sccm to 10000 sccm to a nitrogen radical generating unit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> through gas supplying line and a microwave generating unit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> generates microwave in the range of 0.5 GHz to 4 GHz to the nitrogen radical generating unit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Therefore, nitrogen gas is exposed to the microwave in the nitrogen radical generating unit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, thereby generating nitrogen radical. Then, the nitrogen radical is supplied to a nitrogen radical injecting unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> of the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Here, the nitrogen radical generating unit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is arranged within 50 cm from the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to use most nitrogen radicals in the formation of TiN layer <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> without returning to the original state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the nitrogen radical is injected downwardly from the nitrogen radical injecting unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through nozzle units <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. Therefore, Ti of the Ti layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> reacts with the nitrogen radical to form a TiN layer <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> on the Ti layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in the contact hole <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and outside thereof, thereby completing the barrier layer. Here, the reaction chamber <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is maintained at a temperature of normal to 500&deg; C. and a pressure of 10 mTorr to 10 Torr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, a tungsten layer is filled only in the contact hole and then, a metal layer, such as aluminum layer, is formed on the barrier layer outside of the tungsten layer and the contact hole. Finally, a photolithography is performed to complete a metal wiring pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As described above, according to the present invention, it is possible to obtain a high purity TiN layer by forming a contact hole on an interlayer insulating layer of semiconductor substrate, depositing a Ti layer on the interlayer insulating layer in the contact hole and outside thereof and then, performing microwave treatment to nitrogen gas to generate nitrogen radicals and finally reacting these nitrogen radicals with the Ti layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Therefore, according to the present invention, it is not required to perform MOCVD process, thereby solving the problems of conventional TiN layer formed by MOCVD process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Although the preferred embodiments of the invention have been disclosed for illustrative purposes, those skilled in the art will appreciate that various modifications, additions and substitutions are possible, without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention as disclosed in the accompanying claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming an interlayer insulating layer having a contact hole on a semiconductor substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a Ti layer on the contact hole and on the interlayer insulating layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>reacting the Ti layer with nitrogen radical to transform an upper part of the Ti layer into a TiN layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nitrogen radical is formed by performing high frequency microwave treatment to nitrogen gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the frequency of the microwave is in the range of 0.5 GHz to 4 GHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nitrogen gas is supplied at the flow rate of 100 sccm to 10000 sccm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the TiN layer is formed at a temperature of normal to 500&deg; C. and a pressure of 10 mTorr to 10 Torr. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device comprising: 
<claim-text>a reaction chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a heating unit arranged in the reaction chamber for supporting and heating a semiconductor substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a microwave generating unit for generating microwave; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a nitrogen radical generating unit for generating nitrogen radicals by treating nitrogen gas with the microwave; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a nitrogen radical injecting unit arranged opposite to the heating unit in the reaction chamber with a predetermined distance for injecting the nitrogen radicals to the semiconductor substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the microwave generating unit generates microwave in the range of 0.5 GHz to 4 GHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nitrogen gas supplying unit supplies nitrogen gas in the range of 100 sccm to 10000 sccm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus for manufacturing a barrier layer of semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reaction chamber is maintained at a temperature of normal to 500&deg; C. and a pressure of 10 mTorr to 10 Torr.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2,5,6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003719A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003719A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003719A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003719A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003719A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
