<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000503A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000503A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000503A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000503A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000503A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000503A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000503A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000503A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000503A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000503A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000503</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10184922</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-198537</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F02M001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>123</class>
<subclass>514000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Fuel supply apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hideto</given-name>
<family-name>Takahashi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kariya-city</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Larry S. Nixon, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>NIXON &amp; VANDERHYE P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>8th Floor</address-1>
<address-2>1100 North Glebe Rd.</address-2>
<city>Arlington</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22201-4714</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A fuel supply apparatus maintains a level of fuel within a sub tank and, even if the fuel within the sub tank becomes low in volume, maintaining fuel coverage on a fuel filter is possible. A cylindrical member is formed integrally with the cover and has, at its inner bottom surface, opposite a jet pump, a fuel receiving portion for receiving fuel introduced from an introducing pipe. Above the fuel receiving portion is formed a slit-shaped opening portion which opens toward the fuel filter. The fuel fed from the jet pump passes through the introducing pipe, along the inner bottom surface, and then strikes the fuel receiving portion. The fuel then crosses over a partition wall through the opening portion located above the fuel receiving portion, and changes its direction to flow laterally to reach the top of the suction filter. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is based upon, and claims the benefit of priority of, prior Japanese Patent Application 2001-198537 filed on Jun. 29, 2001, the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a fuel supply apparatus that draws in and discharges fuel from a jet pump to a sub tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Generally, there is known a fuel supply apparatus having a fuel pump which is housed in a sub tank that is located within a fuel tank, in which, even if a liquid level of fuel contained in the fuel tank is lowered, a level of fuel in the sub tank is maintained at a level so that the fuel can be drawn in by a fuel pump. A fuel supply apparatus of the type mentioned above operates such that when return fuel, i.e. fuel returned from an engine or the like, is fed to a jet pump, and fuel within the fuel tank is thereby drawn upward by a suction pressure produced when the fuel is injected from a jet nozzle of the jet pump, that is lower than atmospheric pressure. Then, a jet stream of the drawn fuel, together with the fuel within the fuel tank, are delivered into the sub tank. By delivering the fuel within the fuel tank into the sub tank through the jet pump, the level of the fuel within the sub tank is kept higher than the level of the fuel within the fuel tank. Consequently, even if the fuel remaining in the fuel tank becomes smaller in volume, the fuel pump is properly able to draw in and discharge the fuel within the sub tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Depending on a placement location or other conditions, the fuel tank may need to be made lower in profile (height). Using a low-profile fuel tank necessitates using a low-profile sub tank which is placed within the fuel tank. The shallow sub tank requires a larger bottom surface area to secure a sufficient capacity. The larger the bottom surface area of the sub tank, the larger an area of a suction filter that extends over the inner bottom portion of the sub tank. The suction filter serves to remove foreign substances entrained in the fuel when the fuel pump draws in fuel within the sub tank. If a vehicle corners or travels on steeply inclined ground with a low volume of fuel within the sub tank, a part of the suction filter may not be exposed to the fuel within the sub tank, resulting in the surface of the suction filter from running out of a liquid. This causes the fuel pump to draw in fuel and air through the suction filter. As a result, the suctioning capability and pressure-applying capability of the fuel pump are deteriorated, leading to a decrease in fuel discharge amount. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, an object of the present invention is to provide a fuel supply apparatus which is designed so that the level of the fuel within the sub tank is maintained at an appropriate level and so that running out of a liquid film on the filter is prevented even when the fuel within the sub tank is small in quantity. That is, the filter will be submerged in liquid fuel at all times, even when the volume in the tank is low in volume. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In a fuel supply apparatus according to a first aspect of the present invention, a fuel flow changing member serves to change a direction of fuel delivered from a jet pump that flows along an inner bottom surface from an upward direction into a lateral direction. This decreases the momentum of the fuel flow delivered from the jet pump to the sub tank. Since the fuel is prevented from flowing out of the sub tank, the level of the fuel within the sub tank can be maintained at an appropriate level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the fuel flowing upwards from the inner bottom surface changes its direction to flow sideways so as to reach the upper side of the filter. Thus, even if the fuel within the sub tank becomes smaller in volume, the filter is splashed with fuel from above. This prevents the surface of the filter from not being exposed to fuel at all times. Consequently, even if the fuel within the sub tank becomes smaller in volume, the fuel pump is properly able to draw in and discharge fuel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing construction description, the flow of fuel delivered from the jet pump into the sub tank may strike a fuel receiving portion, and may then be let out from an opening portion via an introducing portion. This facilitates conversion of the fuel flow direction. Moreover, by using a tubular member, the fuel flow changing member having the fuel receiving portion, the introducing portion, and the opening portion formed therein can be constructed with ease. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing construction, a partition wall may serve to prevent the fuel from flowing into the sub tank and traveling in a direction other than a direction toward the fuel flow changing member. This will permit the fuel to flow solely toward the fuel flow changing member. Consequently, fuel is efficiently splashed on the filter. Further, fuel may be permitted to cross over the partition wall so as to flow easily toward the upper side of the filter. Thus, with a simple structure, the surface of the filter can be splashed with fuel and thereby remain covered with fuel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing constitution, first and second slant faces may be placed apart from each other. This allows the fuel having struck the second slant face after flowing along the first slant face to be widely scattered in the direction of the filter. Consequently, the surface of the filter not exposed to the fuel can be uniformly wetted or covered by the fuel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Further areas of applicability of the present invention will become apparent from the detailed description provided hereinafter. It should be understood that the detailed description and specific examples, while indicating the preferred embodiment of the invention, are intended for purposes of illustration only and are not intended to limit the scope of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention will become more fully understood from the detailed description and the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a front view showing a fuel supply apparatus according to a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top taken in the direction of arrow II of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, illustrating a construction in which only a cylindrical member is sectioned at the position of an opening, and a sub tank is left uncovered; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along the line III-III of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view showing the fuel supply apparatus according to a second embodiment of the present invention, as viewed at the same plane of section as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view showing the fuel supply apparatus according to a third embodiment of the present invention, as viewed at the same plane of section as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along the line VI-VI of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Hereinafter, with reference to the accompanying drawings, preferred embodiments of the present invention will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> (First Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> show a fuel supply apparatus in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention. The fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> which is attached to an upper wall of a fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> made of resin or other material. The other components constituting the fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are accommodated in the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and a sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are each made of resin or other material and coupled to a column support <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> made of metal. The column support <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has one end inserted into a bottomed tubular portion (not shown) formed in the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and has its other end inserted into a tubular portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of a stay <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> supported by a tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is made movable with respect to the column support <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the longitudinal direction of the column support <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A coil spring <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> loads the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> with a force that tends to move it in a direction away from the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, that is, move it toward a bottom of the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. In this way, the bottom portion of the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is kept pressed against the inner bottom surface of the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in a state where the fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is attached to the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. With such a construction, even if a resin-made fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is expanded or contracted due to a change in its internal pressure resulting from a temperature change, or a change in the amount of fuel, the bottom portion of the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is constantly kept pressed against the inner bottom surface of the fuel tank by an urging force exerted by the coil spring <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further comprises a discharge pipe <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, a return pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and an electric connector <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> that are formed integrally with one another by using resin or other bonding material. The discharge pipe <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the return pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and the electric connector <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> may alternatively be provided as separate components and individually attached to the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The discharge pipe <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> serves to discharge fuel discharged from a fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> housed in the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to the outside of the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The discharge pipe <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is connected to the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> by a corrugated tube <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> which passes through a hole <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed in a cover <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The return pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> serves to return excessive fuel fed from the engine side into the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, and is connected to a jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> by a corrugated tube <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The electric connector <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> serves to supply a driving current to the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and to output signals detected in a level gage (not shown). The electric connector <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, an electric portion of the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and the level gage are connected to one another by a lead wire <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is provided with the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the cover <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the cover <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are coupled to each other by means of snap fit or other suitable fitting means. The sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is not sealed, and the cover <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has an opening on a part of its upper portion. An introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> serves to introduce fuel fed from the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> into the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has a check valve member <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> attached to the fuel outlet thereof. The check valve member <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> prevents fuel from flowing from the interior of the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> back toward the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Moreover, the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> has a partition wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> formed integrally therewith for separating a suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> from fuel flowing from the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> into the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The partition wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is so shaped that its height becomes lower gradually from the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> through the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, to a cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> acting as a fuel flow changing member, which extends from the cover <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, through an inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, toward the periphery of the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>is formed integrally with the cover <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> so as to extend perpendicularly to the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>The cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is partially covered with the cover <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and has, at its inner-bottom-surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>portion opposite the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, a fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> extending toward the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>for receiving fuel introduced from the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Above the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is formed a slit-shaped opening portion <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> opened toward the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, which is formed continuously with the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is formed of a resin pipe with its lower edge cut away. Between a lower end surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is provided a slight gap. The lower end surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is located below a central position <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> indicated by a dash-and-dot line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is arranged horizontally within the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and draws in the fuel within the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> from the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> through a fuel suction pipe <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is placed on the inner bottom portion of the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> so as to extend over the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>The placement position of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> deviates from a flow direction of the fuel coming from the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> emits, through a jet nozzle <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, return fuel having been returned from the return pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> through the corrugated tube <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> draws in the fuel within the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> by exploiting a suction pressure produced by a jet of the fuel that is lower than an atmospheric pressure, and then allows the fuel to pass through the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, along the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, so as to be delivered into the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Next, the working of the fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> will be described. When the engine is driven to operate and a driving current is supplied from the electric connector <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> draws in fuel within the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> through the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and then, after removal of foreign substances by the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, discharges the fuel through the discharge pipe <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> toward the engine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The fuel having been returned from the engine side to the corrugated tube <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> through the return pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> passes through the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and is thereafter jetted into the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Thereupon, a suction pressure is produced and the fuel within the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is drawn up. By the injection pressure of the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, the fuel within the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is delivered from the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, along the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and into the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Since the fuel flowing from the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> into the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are separated from each other by the partition wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, the fuel flows along the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and toward the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> A portion of the fuel directed to the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> passes through the region between the lower end surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>so as to be let out over the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as viewed from the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. That is, upon introduction of fuel into the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for the first time after a vehicle is assembled, the fuel passes through the region between the lower end surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>so as to reach the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Since the central position <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is located above the lower end surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>the remaining fuel to be delivered from the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> strikes the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> causing the fuel flow to lose its momentum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> At this time the fuel, having lost its momentum as a result of the collision with the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, is directed upward within the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. However, the fuel cannot flow upwards to reach the upper part of the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Then, the fuel is directed, via an introducing portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> located above the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, to the opening portion <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, the fuel crosses over the partition wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and changes its direction to travel sideways so as to reach the upper side of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to be let out from the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Since the upper part of the opening portion <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is located above the upper end of the partition wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, it is possible to ensure that the fuel discharged from the opening portion <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> crosses over the partition wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> so as to be splashed on the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Since the fuel fed from the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is delivered through the opening portion <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> of the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> into the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the level of the fuel within the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is raised with respect to the exterior of the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and is maintained at a predetermined height. Consequently, even if no fuel remains around the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> as a result of the vehicle&apos;s cornering or running on steeply inclined ground under the condition in which the level of the fuel within the fuel tank is lowered, the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is able to draw in the fuel within the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> without causing improper fuel suctioning, thereby making it possible to continuously supply fuel to the engine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Even if the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is made smaller in depth, the fuel fed from the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is permitted to strike the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, causing the fuel flow to lose its momentum. Consequently, the fuel is prevented from crossing over the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and flowing out of the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> through the hole <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Moreover, when a part of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is exposed due to a shortage of fuel within the tank case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, fuel is splashed on the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> through the opening portion <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, and thereby the surface of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is kept wet (the outer surface is kept wet with fuel). Since the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is designed not to draw in air together with fuel through the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is able to draw in and discharge a desired amount of fuel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> (Second Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a second embodiment of the present invention. In the second embodiment, a cylindrical member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, provided as a fuel flow changing member, is so designed that a fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and an opening portion <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> are not formed continuously with each other. An upper part of the opening portion <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> is located above the upper end of the partition wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The fuel, having struck the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, is directed through an introducing portion <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> located above the fuel receiving portion <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, to the opening portion <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, the second embodiment is substantially identical to the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> (Third Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference> show a third embodiment of the present invention. A sub tank <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is provided with a tank case <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and a cover <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. The tank case <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> has a first slant face <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which is so formed as to extend in a direction in which fuel flows from the introducing pipe <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> along an inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the tank case <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and obliquely upwards from the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The cover <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> has a second slant face <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> which is formed at a position to which the fuel flowing obliquely upwards from the inner bottom surface <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>a along the first slant surface <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is directed. The second slant face <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> serves to change the direction of the flow of the fuel so that the fuel travels sideways so as to reach the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The first and second slant faces <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> each constitute a part of the fuel flow changing member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Since the first and second slant faces <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> are located away from each other, in a state where the fuel within the tank case <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> is small in quantity, the fuel traveling obliquely upwards by the guide of the first slant face <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> strikes the second slant face <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The fuel having struck the second slant face <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is splashed and scattered toward the upper side of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, thereby allowing the surface of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> exposed from the fuel within the tank case <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> to be thoroughly wetted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In the plurality of embodiments described thus far, the flow direction of the fuel delivered from the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> into the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> changed by the fuel flow changing member from an upward direction to a lateral direction. Thus, the fuel directed from the jet pump <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> into the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is prevented from leaking out of the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, thereby making it possible to secure a sufficient amount of fuel in the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Moreover, if the fuel within the sub tank <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> becomes smaller in volume, the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is not exposed to the fuel. In this case, the surface of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is wetted by the fuel flowing sideways toward the upper side of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, thereby creating a liquid fuel film on the surface of the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Thus, even if the fuel within the sub tank becomes small in volume, the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> never draws in air through the suction filter <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Consequently, it is possible to draw in and discharge the required amount of fuel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The description of the invention is merely exemplary in nature and, thus, variations that do not depart from the gist of the invention are intended to be within the scope of the invention. Such variations are not to be regarded as a departure from the spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A fuel supply apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a sub tank housed in a fuel tank; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a jet pump for drawing fuel contained in the fuel tank by suction produced when fuel is injected from a jet nozzle, and for delivering the fuel into the sub tank along an inner bottom surface of the sub tank; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fuel pump housed in the sub tank, for drawing in and discharging the fuel contained in the sub tank; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter disposed on the inner bottom portion of the sub tank, for removing foreign substances in the fuel within the sub tank that are drawn in by the fuel pump; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fuel flow changing member for changing a direction of the fuel delivered from the jet pump and flowing along the inner bottom surface so that the fuel is directed away from the inner bottom surface, and for changing a direction of the fuel flowing away from the inner bottom surface so that the fuel is directed parallel to the inner bottom surface to reach a portion of the filter farthest from the inner bottom surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein the fuel flow changing member is a tubular member with an opening at its end closest to the inner bottom surface, the tubular member being arranged substantially perpendicular to the inner bottom surface, the tubular member including: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fuel receiving portion provided at its end closest to the inner bottom surface and opposite the jet pump so as to extend toward the inner bottom surface, upon which fuel delivered from the jet pump impinges; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an opening portion provided above the fuel receiving portion, for allowing the fuel, which has been changed in its direction to flow upwards by impinging upon the fuel receiving portion, then be directed from the tubular member in a lateral direction so as to reach the top side of the filter; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an introducing portion for transferring fuel from the fuel receiving portion to the opening portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a partition wall for separating fuel delivered into the sub tank by the jet pump from the filter and guiding the fuel to the fuel flow changing member, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the opening portion continues along the cylindrical member above an upper end of the partition wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein the fuel flow changing member includes: 
<claim-text>a first slant face extending, in a direction which fuel delivered from the jet pump flows, obliquely upwards from the inner bottom surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second slant face for changing a direction of the fuel, which has been changed in its direction by the first slant face to flow obliquely upwards, so that the fuel is directed laterally so as to reach the upper side of the filter. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a partition wall for separating fuel delivered into the sub tank by the jet pump from the filter and guiding the fuel to the fuel flow changing member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a partition wall for separating fuel delivered into the sub tank by the jet pump from the filter and guiding the fuel to the fuel flow changing member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a partition wall for separating fuel delivered into the sub tank by the jet pump from the filter and guiding the fuel to the fuel flow changing member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000503A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000503A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000503A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000503A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000503A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
