<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004865A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004865A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004865A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004865A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004865A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004865A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004865A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004865A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004865A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004865A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004865</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09897328</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F017/60</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>705</class>
<subclass>038000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>705</class>
<subclass>042000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Loan examination method and loan examination system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Haruhiko</given-name>
<family-name>Kinoshita</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KATTEN MUCHIN ZAVIS ROSENMAN</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>575 MADISON AVENUE</address-1>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10022-2585</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Information on business activities of an enterprise to be examined is accumulated on an ASP server from a terminal of the enterprise through a network such as the Internet. An examiner such as a financial institution evaluates the activities of the enterprise based on the information on business activities of the enterprise accumulated on the ASP server to examine the enterprise. The examination typically is an examination for determining whether a new loan can be offered to the enterprise. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a scheme of an examination for lending or loaning money to an enterprise, and more particularly to a system and a method preferably applied to an examination business or the like in which a financial institution previously determines whether it can offer loan or financing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> When a financial institution finances an enterprise or settles a loan to the enterprise, it performs an examination in advance for determining whether it may offer the loan. In the loan examination, whether the loan can be offered is determined on the basis of information obtained from, for example, (1) inquiries from the financial institution to a company to be examined or an examinee and responses from the examinee to the inquiries, (2) data such as the financial statements already issued by the examinee, (3) exchanges of information on debts of the examinee between the financial institution and another financial institution, (4) assets of the examinee serving as collateral, and (5) visits of the financial institution to the examinee. The information is provided over a computer network, in the form of documents, by telephone, through direct hearings or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> When the financial institution determines whether it can offer the loan requested by the examinee, it can refer only to (1) information generally released by the examinee, (2) information on the examinee substantially known to the financial industry, and (3) information provided for the financial institution by the examinee, of the aforementioned information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a scheme for a conventional loan examination. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> collects information by using financial accounting report <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> such as a financial statement of examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> already released by examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, putting directly questions to examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> on a visit thereto and the like to determine whether financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can finance examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In addition, financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may visit business partner <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> without notifying examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the visit to check business situations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, financial accounting report <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is produced by examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> on its own with the help of an auditor, accountant or audit corporation, and released to the outside after receipt of certification by the auditor or accountant in terms of accuracy and validity. Since financial accounting report <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is produced and released at each term end, examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> produces such a financial accounting report once a year or twice a year, that is, once in the first half and once in the second half of a year, or four times in a year, that is, every three months, depending on company accounting systems varying from one country to another. A financial statement for stock investors is an example of data readily obtained by financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> as specific data of financial accounting report <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a specific procedure of the conventional loan examination. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> company attempting to obtain financing, that is, examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> makes a request for new loan to financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> such as a bank as required in business at step A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Upon receipt of the request for loan, financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> inquires of examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> which made the request about its actual conditions of management and asset status at step A<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. At step A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> presents an already released financial accounting report of examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, for example reports on securities, to financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. At step A<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> responds to the inquiries at step A<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by holding an interview with a member of staff of financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, directly presenting data, or making a call. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In some cases, at step A<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> makes contact with business partner <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to inquire about uncertainties of the information acquired at steps A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and A<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for confirmation and verification of the information. At step A<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, business partner <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> responds only to some items of the inquiries from financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to which it wishes to respond. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Finally, at step A<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, financial institution <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> determines whether it can offer the loan to examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> by using the information obtained at step A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, A<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and A<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and public information, and notifies examinee <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the determination result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the conventional loan examination method, however, a problem exists in that the information which the financial institution can referred to at the loan examination is limited to the information generally released by the examinee, the information on the examinee substantially known to the financial industry, and the information provided by the examinee for the financial institution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The financial institution which desires a more accurate loan examination wishes to obtain variable information in order to analyze the examinee from many aspects referring to business activities during a certain period, expected orders in the next term and the like, although it is difficult to thoroughly carry out that wish. In addition, there is only a poor method for checking whether the contents of the responses of the examinee to the inquiries of the financial institution are true or not. Furthermore, in general, the examinee which is to apply for financing to the financial institution may hide weak points in the actual conditions of management of the company and exaggeratedly explain its strengths. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Since the conventional loan examination method also has a problem of being time-consuming due to the need of manpower to collect the necessary information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The understanding of accurate and latest conditions of management of the examinee in the financial institution is required for realizing a more accurate finance examination by the financial institution. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the present invention to provide a method which allows a financial institution to promptly perform a loan examination and enables improved accuracy of the loan examination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide a system which allows a financial institution to promptly perform a loan examination and enables improved accuracy of the loan examination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In the present invention which achieves the aforementioned objects, information on business activities of an enterprise is collected on an ASP (application service provider) server from a terminal apparatus provided in the enterprise through a network such as the Internet. An examiner such as a financial institution evaluates the activities of the enterprise based on the information accumulated on the ASP server to examine the enterprise. The examination typically is an examination for determining whether financing can be offered to the company. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects, features, and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following description referring to the accompanying drawings which illustrate examples of preferred embodiments of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic view for explaining a method of a conventional loan examination; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow diagram illustrating a specific procedure of the conventional loan examination; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a configuration of a loan examination system according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flow diagram illustrating operations of the system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS: </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the present invention, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is placed in a financial institution, terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is placed in an enterprise which wishes to obtain a loan, ASP (Application Service Provider) server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is operated by the financial institution or an entity holding a commission from the finance institution, and terminals <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, and ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> are interconnected through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The Internet, for example, is preferably used as network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> An enterprise which wishes to obtain a loan is referred to as &ldquo;an examinee.&rdquo; Such examinees include corporations such as limited companies or corporations, unlimited companies or corporations, general partnerships, associations, medical corporations, eleemosynary corporations such as incorporated schools, and public corporations, and one-man businesses, depending on definitions in corporation laws, civil codes, and commercial laws in various countries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment, information on business activities of an enterprise which wishes to obtain a loan is transmitted from terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> placed in the enterprise to ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and accumulated on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The accumulated information on business activities is transmitted to terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of an entity who is to evaluate the enterprise, for example an entity which is to offer loans, in response to a request from the entity. The entity which evaluates the enterprise determines actions for the enterprise by evaluating the activities of the enterprise. When a loan examination is performed, the entity which evaluates the enterprise performs the loan examination based on the evaluation to determine whether the entity can offer the loan to the enterprise. One terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee may be provided for the examinee, or a plurality of terminals <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may be provided for one examinee depending on the scale or the like of the examinee. Specifically, terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee may be provided for each office of the examinee, or each of departments such as a finance department, accounts department, sales department, and manufacturing department of the examinee. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In the present invention, ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is preferably operated by the entity which evaluates the enterprise. The following description is made assuming that a financial institution itself sets up and operates ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is not open to third parties except the enterprise and the entity which evaluates the enterprise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A procedure of a loan examination based on the present invention includes the steps of: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> recording information on business activities of the examinee on the ASP server from the terminal placed in the examinee; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> appending, updating, deleting, viewing the information on business activities recorded on the ASP server by the terminal of the examinee; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> transmitting a request for loan from the terminal of the examinee to the terminal of the financial institution; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> acquiring the information on business activities of the examinee stored on the ASP server from the terminal of the financial institution; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> determining whether the loan can be offered to the examinee based on the information on business activities of the examinee stored on the ASP server and notifying the terminal of the examinee of the determination result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> A company typically creates a database for managing finance, accounting, marketing, manufacturing and the like of the company. In recent years, the operation of the database for managing finance, accounting, marketing, manufacturing and the like is often committed to an external ASP as part of outsourcing of peripheral activities in the company. Thus, in the present embodiment, a financial institution and the like sets up and operates the ASP server to undertake the database management of finance, accounts, marketing, manufacturing and the like of the examinee as well as perform a loan examination based on information on business activities of the examinee accumulated on the ASP server. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As a result, the financial institution uses the latest information on various business activities of the examinee stored on the ASP server which would not be acquired conventionally as reference information, for example, to determine whether the financial institution settles loan to the company without releasing the information to third parties, thereby achieving improved accuracy of the loan examination. The information on business activities sent to the ASP server from the examinee includes, as an example, information on finance, accounts, marketing, manufacturing and the like of the examinee. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Description is hereinafter made for a loan examination system of the embodiment in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution includes request section <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, information receipt section <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, request receipt section <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, and sending section <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. Request section <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> has the function of making a request to ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> operated by the financial institution through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> for information on business activities of the examinee stored on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Information receipt section <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> has the function of receiving contents sent from ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Request receipt section <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> has the function of receiving a request for new loan sent from terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Sending section <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> has the function of sending the determination result of whether the requested loan can be offered or not to terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution further includes display <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> such as a CRT (cathode ray tube) or liquid crystal display (LCD) and input device <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> such as a keyboard or mouse. The information on business activities received from ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and the information on the request for new loan from the examinee are displayed on display <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. Request section <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> requests ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to send the information on business activities of the examinee through operations of input device <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> While each of request section <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, information receipt section <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, request receipt section <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, and sending section <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> may be formed of hardware, the processing thereof is typically realized by a program executed on a computer constituting terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution. In this case, the functions of terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution herein described are realized by reading the program from a recording medium having the program recorded thereon such as a magnetic recording medium, optical disc, or semiconductor memory onto the computer constituting terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution before execution of the program, or by downloading the program from a server or the like to the computer constituting terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution through the network before execution of the program on the computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee includes data update section <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>, request sending section <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, and determination acquiring section <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>. Data update section <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> is provided for causing ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to accumulate information on general business activities such as finance, accounting, sales, manufacturing and the like of the examinee through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, and has the functions of instructing ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to add, update, or delete the information on business activities of the examinee stored on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and viewing the information on business activities of the examinee stored on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Request sending section <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> has the function of sending a request for new loan to terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Determination acquiring section <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> has the function of acquiring the determination result of whether loan can be offered to the company sent from terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee further includes display <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> such as a CRT or liquid crystal display and input device <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight> such as a keyboard or mouse. When data update section <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> adds, updates, deletes, or views the information on business activities stored on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, the information on business activities is displayed on display <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. The determination result of whether loan can be offered to the company from terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution is also displayed on display <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. Input for adding, updating, deleting or viewing the information on business activities on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> by data update section <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> is made through input device <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight>. Request sending section <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> sends a request for new loan to terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution through operations of input device <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> While each of data update section <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>, request sending section <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, and determination acquiring section <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> may be formed of hardware, the processing thereof is typically realized by a program executed on a computer constituting terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee. In this case, the functions of terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee herein described are realized by reading the program from a recording medium having the program recorded thereon such as a magnetic recording medium, optical disc, or semiconductor memory onto the computer constituting terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee before execution of the program, or by downloading the program from a server or the like to the computer constituting terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee through the network before execution of the program on the computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> operated by the financial institution includes storage section <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> for storing information on business activities of each examinee, data update section <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>, and data sending section <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>. Data update section <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> has the functions of storing information on general business activities sent from terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee into storage section <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>, changing information on business activities stored in storage section <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>, or providing information on business activities for terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee, in accordance with instructions (for storage, change, or view) from terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee. While storage section <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> has information on business activities of a plurality of examinees stored therein, one of the examinees must be prohibited from accessing information on business activities of another examinee. For this reason, data update section <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> also performs access control such that terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of an examinee can access only information on its own business activities. Data sending section <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> has the function of sending, in response to a request from terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution, requested information on general business activities of the examinee to terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The processing in ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is typically performed by a program executed on a server computer. Storage section <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> is realized as a mass storage unit provided on the server computer. Data update section <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and data sending section <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> are realized by a program which performs processing therefor. The functions of ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> herein described are realized by reading the program from a recording medium having the program recorded thereon such as a magnetic recording medium, optical disc, or semiconductor memory onto the server computer constituting ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> before execution of the program, or by downloading the program from a server or the like to the server computer constituting ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> through the network before execution of the program on the computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Next, the procedure of the loan examination according to the embodiment is described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The following description is made assuming that network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is the Internet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> At step B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, employees in departments such as a finance department, accounts department, sales department, and manufacturing department of the examinee record, as their jobs, information on general business activities in the past on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> operated by the financial institution through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> by using terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee placed in the respective departments. At this point, each employee in each department performs the recording as a task on an EDP (Electronic Data Processing) environment of his or her own company without particular consciousness of the location or operator of ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Each employee in each department of the examinee adds information on current general business activities to ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> one by one as his or her job at the proper time of update by using terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee placed in each department. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> At step B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, each employee in each department of the examinee updates, deletes, or views information already stored on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> as required in business of each department. At this point, each employee in each department performs the update, deletion, or view of the information as a task on an EDP environment of his or her own company without particular consciousness of the location or operator of ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Assume herein that a motivation for requesting new loan occurs in the examinee. In response thereto, at step B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a person authorized to apply for loan in the examinee sends a request for new loan to terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> from terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> At step B<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, upon receipt of the request for a new loan, a person in charge in the financial institution views the information on general business activities such as finance, accounting, sales, and manufacturing of the examinee stored on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> through network <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> from terminal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the financial institution to perform a loan examination. At this point, data usable for the loan examination by the financial institution can include not only information scheduled to be included in a financial accounting report but also a wide variety of information on business activities such as finance, accounting, sales, and marketing. It is thus possible to use predicted performance of the company in the future such as sales schedules from the next term onward as a factor in the determination in the loan examination. At step B<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the person in charge in the financial institution performs a further loan examination by considering information on the examinee obtained in a manner other than through ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> such as known information to make a final determination of whether the loan can be offered, and notifies terminal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the examinee of the determination result of whether the loan can be offered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As described above, according to the embodiment, the information on various business activities of the examinee, which could not be acquired conventionally by the financial institution, is stored on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The financial institution does not release the information on various business activities stored on ASP server <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to the public but exclusively uses the information as reference information for determining whether it can offer the loan to the examinee. It is thus possible to realize improved accuracy of the loan examination in the financial institution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> According to the system, the financial institution can directly acquire grouped and correct information on the examinee in a desired form and at a desired time. Thus, the number of man-hours of employees is reduced in the financial institution and the examinee involved in the loan examination to allow a reduction in time taken for the examination as compared with the conventional examination method when the same level of accuracy of the loan examination as the conventional method is maintained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In addition, the examinee capable of presenting the information on business activities to the financial institution by using this system is thought to be regarded in the market as a company with no fraud, high clearness, and high credibility of a financial accounting report. Thus, it is expected that stocks, bonds and the like of the examinee are more highly regarded in the market. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> While the aforementioned embodiment has been described with an example of a company being financed, a target for loan is not limited to such a company, and the system is applicable to various enterprises. The present invention is also applicable to a system for management diagnosis such as management analysis of an enterprise. In other words, the present invention is not limited to the configuration of the aforementioned embodiment, and it goes without saying that various changes and modifications which may be made by those skilled in the art within the range of the present invention defined by the appended claims are included. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An examination method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>storing information on business activities of an enterprise on an ASP (Application Service Provider) server from a terminal of said enterprise through a network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing said information on business activities of said enterprise accumulated on said ASP server for an examiner; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>evaluating activities of said enterprise based on said information on business activities provided for said examiner. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The examination method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said examination is an examination for determining whether a loan can be offered to said enterprise. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An examination method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>transmitting information on business activities of an enterprise from a terminal of said enterprise to an ASP (Application Service Provider) server through a network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>accumulating said information on business activities of said enterprise on said ASP server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting said information on business activities of said enterprise accumulated on said ASP server to a terminal of an examiner based on a request from said examiner, said examiner being to perform an examination of said enterprise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting said information on business activities of said enterprise on said terminal of said examiner, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said information on business activities of said enterprise accumulated on said ASP server is not open to a third party except said enterprise and said examiner, and said examiner evaluates activities of said enterprise based on said information on business activities transmitted to said terminal of said examiner to perform an examination of said enterprise. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The examination method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said ASP server is operated by said examiner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The examination method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said examination is an examination for determining whether a loan can be offered to said enterprise. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A loan examination method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>recording information on business activities of an examinee on an ASP (Application Service Provider) server operated by a financial institution from a terminal of said examinee, said examinee being a company, corporation or enterprise to be examined; </claim-text>
<claim-text>performing at least one of addition, update, deletion, and view of said information on business activities recorded on said ASP server from said terminal of said examinee; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting a request for loan from said terminal of said examinee to a terminal of said financial institution; </claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring said information on business activities of said examinee stored on said ASP server through said terminal of said financial institution; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether said loan can be offered to said examinee based on said information on business activities of said examinee stored on said ASP server to notify said terminal of said examinee of the determination result. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A loan examination method, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>recording information on general business activities regarding at least one of finance, accounting, sales, and manufacturing of an examinee on an ASP (Application Service Provider) server operated by a financial institution from a terminal of said examinee, said examinee being a company, corporation or enterprise to be examined; </claim-text>
<claim-text>performing addition, update, deletion, or view of said information on business activities on said ASP server from said terminal of said examinee in accordance with progress of actual business activities; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting a request for new loan from said terminal of said examinee to a terminal of said financial institution; </claim-text>
<claim-text>closely investigating said information on general business activities regarding at least one of finance, accounting, sales, and manufacturing of said examinee stored on said ASP server from said terminal of said financial institution; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether said loan can be offered to said examinee based on information obtained by said close investigation to notify said terminal of said examinee of the determination result. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An ASP (Application Service Provider) server operated by an examiner who is to perform an examination of an enterprise, said ASP server comprising: 
<claim-text>means for receiving information on business activities of said enterprise to be examined transmitted from a terminal of said enterprise through a network; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for accumulating said received information on business activities; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for transmitting said accumulated information on business activities of said enterprise to a terminal of said examiner through said network based on a request transmitted from said terminal of said examiner through said network, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said information on business activities of said enterprise accumulated on said ASP server is not open to a third party except said enterprise and said examiner. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A loan examination system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a communication network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a terminal of a financial institution connected to said communication network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a terminal of an examinee connected to said communication network, said examinee being a company, corporation or enterprise to be examined; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an ASP (Application Service Provider) server connected to said communication network and operated by said financial institution; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said terminal of said financial institution including: 
<claim-text>means for making a request to said ASP server for predetermined information on business activities of said examinee stored on said ASP server to receive said information on business activities; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for receiving a request for loan from said terminal of said examinee; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for returning a result of a loan examination to said terminal of said examinee, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said terminal of said examinee including: 
<claim-text>means for recording said predetermined information on business activities of said examinee on said ASP server, updating said predetermined information on business activities of said examinee recorded on said ASP server, deleting said predetermined information on business activities of said examinee recorded on said ASP server, and viewing said information on business activities of said examinee from said ASP server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for transmitting the request for loan to said terminal of said financial institution; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for receiving the result of the loan examination from said terminal of financial institution, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said ASP server including: 
<claim-text>means for receiving said information on business activities of said examinee transmitted from said terminal of said examinee, providing said information on business activities of said examinee for said terminal of said examinee based on a request from said terminal of said examinee, and performing record, update, or deletion of said information on business activities of said examinee based on an instruction from said terminal of said examinee; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for accumulating said received information on business activities; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for providing, based on a request from said terminal of said financial institution, requested information on business activities of said examinee for said terminal of said financial institution. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A loan examination system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a communication network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a terminal of a financial institution connected to said communication network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a terminal of an examinee connected to said communication network, said examinee being a company, corporation or enterprise to be examined; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an ASP (Application Service Provider) server connected to said communication network and operated by said financial institution; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said terminal of said financial institution including: 
<claim-text>means for viewing information on general business activities regarding at least one of finance, accounting, sales, and manufacturing of said examinee stored on said ASP server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for receiving a request for new loan from said terminal of said examinee; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for returning a result of a loan examination to said terminal of said examinee, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said terminal of said examinee including: 
<claim-text>means for recording information on general business activities regarding at least one of finance, accounting, sales, and manufacturing of said examinee on said ASP server, updating on said ASP server said information on general business activities recorded on said ASP server, deleting on said ASP server said information on general business activities recorded on said ASP server, and viewing from said ASP server said information on general business activities recorded on said ASP server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for transmitting the request for new loan to said terminal of said financial institution; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for receiving the result of the loan examination from said terminal of said financial institution, </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said ASP server including: 
<claim-text>means for storing said information on general business activities of said examinee transmitted from said terminal of said examinee; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for performing record, update, or deletion of said information on general business activities of said examinee in said storing means based on an instruction from said terminal of said examinee, and reading said information on general business activities of said examinee from said storing means based on a request from said terminal of said examinee to transmit said read information to said terminal of said examinee; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for reading said information on general business activities of said examinee requested from said terminal of said financial institution from said storing means to transmit said read information to said terminal of said financial institution. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A recording medium readable by a computer connected to an ASP (Application Service Provider) server and a terminal of an examinee through a network, said examinee being a company, corporation or enterprise to be examined, said recording medium having a program recorded thereon causing said computer to perform the processing of: 
<claim-text>viewing predetermined information on business activities of said examinee stored on said ASP server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a request for loan from said terminal of said examinee; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>returning a result of a loan examination to said terminal of said examinee. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A recording medium readable by a computer connected to a terminal of a financial institution and an ASP (Application Service Provider) server through a network, said recording medium having a program recorded thereon causing said computer to perform the processing of: 
<claim-text>recording predetermined information on business activities of an examinee on said ASP server, said examinee being a company, corporation or enterprise to be examined; </claim-text>
<claim-text>updating said predetermined information on business activities of said examinee recorded on said ASP server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>deleting said predetermined information on business activities of said examinee recorded on said ASP server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>viewing said information on business activities of said examinee from said ASP server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting a request for loan to said terminal of said financial institution; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a result of a loan examination from said terminal of said financial institution. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A recording medium readable by a computer connected to a terminal of a financial institution and a terminal of an examinee through a network, said examinee being a company, corporation or enterprise to be examined, said recording medium recording a program recorded thereon for performing the processing of: 
<claim-text>receiving information on business activities of said examinee transmitted from said terminal of said examinee to accumulate said received information on a storage device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>reading and transmitting from said storage device said information on business activities of said examinee requested from said terminal of said financial institution or said terminal of said examinee; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>performing record, update, or deletion of said information on business activities of said examinee in said storage device based on an instruction from said terminal of said examinee.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004865A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004865A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004865A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004865A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004865A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
