<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003609A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003609A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003609</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10143568</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020513</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/66</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G01R031/26</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>014000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>017000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Ultra-fast nucleic acid sequencing device and a method for making and using the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10143568</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020513</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09653543</doc-number>
<document-date>20000831</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6413792</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60199130</doc-number>
<document-date>20000424</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60217681</doc-number>
<document-date>20000712</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jon</given-name>
<middle-name>Robert</middle-name>
<family-name>Sauer</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Superior</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bart</given-name>
<middle-name>Jozef</middle-name>
<family-name>Van Zeghbroeek</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boulder</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Roylance, Abrams, Berdo &amp; Goodman, L.L.P.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 600</address-1>
<address-2>1300 19th Street</address-2>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20036</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system and method employing at least one semiconductor device having at least one detecting region which can include, for example, a recess or opening therein, for detecting a charge representative of a component of a polymer, such as a nucleic acid strand, proximate to the detecting region, and a method for manufacturing such a semiconductor device. The system and method can thus be used for sequencing individual nucleotides or bases of ribonucleic acid (RNA) or deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA). The semiconductor device includes at least two doped regions, such as two n-type regions implanted in a p-type semiconductor layer or two p-type regions implanted in an n-type semiconductor layer. The detecting region permits a current to pass between the two doped regions in response to the presence of the component of the polymer, such as a base of a DNA or RNA strand. The current has characteristics representative of the component of the polymer, such as characteristics representative of the detected base of the DNA or RNA strand. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/653,543, filed on Aug. 31, 2000, the entire contents thereof being incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Related subject matter is disclosed in a provisional U.S. Patent Application of Jon R. Sauer et al. entitled &ldquo;Ultra-Fast, Semiconductor-Based Gene Sequencing&rdquo;, Serial No. 60/199,130, filed Apr. 24, 2000, and of a provisional U.S. Patent Application of Bart Van Zeghbroeck et al. entitled &ldquo;Charge Sensing and Amplification Device for DNA Sequencing&rdquo;, Serial No. 60/217,681, filed Jul. 12, 2000, the entire contents of both of said provisional applications being incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a system and method employing a semiconductor device having a detecting region for identifying the individual mers of long-chain polymers, such as carbohydrates and proteins, as well as individual bases of deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) or ribonucleic acid (RNA), and a method for making the semiconductor device. More particularly, the present invention relates to a system and method employing a semiconductor device, similar to a field-effect transistor device, capable of identifying the bases of a DNA/RNA strand to thus enable sequencing of the strand to be performed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> DNA consists of two very long, helical polynucleotide chains coiled around a common axis. The two strands of the double helix run in opposite directions. The two strands are held together by hydrogen bonds between pairs of bases, consisting of adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). Adenine is always paired with thymine, and guanine is always paired with cytosine. Hence, one strand of a double helix is the complement of the other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Genetic information is encoded in the precise sequence of bases along a DNA strand. In normal cells, genetic information is passed from DNA to RNA. Most RNA molecules are single stranded but many contain extensive double helical regions that arise from the folding of the chain into hairpin-like structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Mapping the DNA sequence is part of a new era of genetic-based medicine embodied by the Human Genome Project. Through the efforts of this project, one day doctors will be able to tailor treatment to individuals based upon their genetic composition, and possibly even correct genetic flaws before birth. However, to accomplish this task it will be necessary to sequence each individual&apos;s DNA. Although the human genome sequence variation is approximately 0.1%, this small variation is critical to understanding a person&apos;s predisposition to various ailments. In the near future, it is conceivable that medicine will be &ldquo;DNA personalized&rdquo;, and a physician will order sequence information just as readily as a cholesterol test is ordered today. Thus, to allow such advances to be in used in everyday life, a faster and more economical method of DNA sequencing is needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> One method of performing DNA sequencing is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,653,939, the entire content of which is incorporated herein by reference. This method employs a monolithic array of test sites formed on a substrate, such as a semiconductor substrate. Each test site includes probes which are adapted to bond with a predetermined target molecular structure. The bonding of a molecular structure to the probe at a test site changes the electrical, mechanical and optical properties of the test site. Therefore, when a signal is applied to the test sites, the electrical, mechanical, or optical properties of each test site can be measured to determine which probes have bonded with their respective target molecular structure. However, this method is disadvantageous because the array of test sites is complicated to manufacture, and requires the use of multiple probes for detecting different types of target molecular structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Another method of sequencing is known as gel electrophoresis. In this technology, the DNA is stripped down to a single strand and exposed to a chemical that destroys one of the four nucleotides, for example A, thus producing a strand that has a random distribution of DNA fragments ending in A and labeled at the opposite end. The same procedure is repeated for the other three remaining bases. The DNA fragments are separated by gel electrophoresis according to length. The lengths show the distances from the labeled end to the known bases, and if there are no gaps in coverage, the original DNA strand fragment sequence is determined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> This method of DNA sequencing has many drawbacks associated with it. This technique only allows readings of approximately 500 bases, since a DNA strand containing more bases would &ldquo;ball&rdquo; up and not be able to be read properly. Also, as strand length increases, the resolution in the length determination decreases rapidly, which also limits analysis of strands to a length of 500 bases. In addition, gel electrophoresis is very slow and not a workable solution for the task of sequencing the genomes of complex organisms. Furthermore, the preparation before and analysis following electrophoresis is inherently expensive and time consuming. Therefore, a need exists for a faster, consistent and more economical means for DNA sequencing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Another approach for sequencing DNA is described in U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,795,782 and 6,015,714, the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference. In this technique, two pools of liquid are separated by a biological membrane with an alpha hemolysin pore. As the DNA traverses the membrane, an ionic current through the pore is blocked. Experiments have shown that the length of time during which the ionic current through the pore is blocked is proportional to the length of the DNA fragment. In addition, the amount of blockage and the velocity depend upon which bases are in the narrowest portion of the pore. Thus, there is the potential to determine the base sequence from these phenomena. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Among the problems with this technique are that individual nucleotides cannot, as yet, be distinguished. Also, the spatial orientation of the individual nucleotides is difficult to discern. Further, the electrodes measuring the charge flow are a considerable distance from the pore, which adversely affects the accuracy of the measurements. This is largely because of the inherent capacitance of the current-sensing electrodes and the large statistical variation in sensing the small amounts of current. Furthermore, the inherent shot noise and other noise sources distort the signal, incurring additional error. Therefore, a need exists for a more sensitive detection system which discriminates among the bases as they pass through the sequencer. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a system and method for accurately and effectively identifying individual bases of DNA or RNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a system and method employing a semiconductor device for sequencing individual bases of DNA or RNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide a method for manufacturing a semiconductor-based DNA or RNA sequencing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a system and method for accurately and effectively identifying the individual mers of long-chain polymers, such as carbohydrates or proteins, as well as measuring the lengths of the long-chain polymers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Still another object of the present invention is to provide a system and method employing a semiconductor-based device having a opening therein, for accurately and effectively identifying bases of DNA or RNA by measuring charge at a location where the DNA or RNA molecules traverse the opening in the sequencer, to thus eliminate or at least minimize the effects of shot noise and other noise sources associated with the random movement of the DNA or RNA molecules through the opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> These and other objects of the invention are substantially achieved by providing a system for detecting at least one polymer, comprising at least one semiconductor device having at least one detecting region which is adapted to detect a charge representative of a component of the polymer proximate to the detecting region. The component can include a base in a nucleic acid strand, so that the detecting region is adapted to detect the charge which is representative of the base in the nucleic acid strand. The detecting region is further adapted to generate a signal representative of the detected charge. Also, the detecting region can include a region of the semiconductor device defining a recess in the semiconductor device, or an opening in the semiconductor device having a cross-section sufficient to enable the polymer to enter the opening, so that the detecting region detects the charge of the component in the opening. Furthermore, the semiconductor device preferably further includes at least two doped regions, and the detecting region can pass a current between the two doped regions in response to a presence of the component proximate to the detecting region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects of the invention are also substantially achieved by providing a method for detecting at least one polymer, comprising the steps of positioning a portion of the polymer proximate to a detecting region of at least one semiconductor device, and detecting at the detecting region a charge representative of a component of the polymer proximate to the detecting region. The component can include a base in a nucleic acid strand, so that the detecting step detects a charge representative of the base. The method further comprises the step of generating at the detecting region a signal representative of the detected charge. The detecting region can include a region of the semiconductor device defining a recess in the semiconductor device, or an opening in the semiconductor device having a cross-section sufficient to enable the polymer to enter the opening, so that the detecting step detects the charge of the component in the recess or opening. Furthermore, the semiconductor device can further include at least two doped regions, so that the method can further include the step of passing a current between the two doped regions in response to a presence of the component proximate to the detecting region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects of the invention are further substantially achieved by providing a method for manufacturing a device for detecting a polymer, comprising the steps of providing a semiconductor structure comprising at least one semiconductor layer, and creating a detecting region in the semiconductor structure, such that the detecting region is adapted to detect a charge representative of a component of the polymer proximate to the detecting region. The component can include a base in a nucleic acid strand, and the detecting region can be created to detect a charge representative of the base in the nucleic acid strand. The method can further include the step of creating a recess in the semiconductor structure, or creating an opening in the semiconductor structure having a cross-section sufficient to enable a portion of the polymer to pass therethrough, and being positioned in relation to the detecting region such that the detecting region is adapted to detect the charge representative of the component in the recess or opening. The method can further include the step of forming an insulating layer on a wall of the semiconductor layer having the opening to decrease the cross-section of the opening. Furthermore, the method can include the step of creating at least two doped regions in the semiconductor layer which are positioned with respect to the detecting region such that the detecting region is adapted to pass a current between the doped regions in response to the component of the polymer proximate to the detecting region. The doped regions can be separated by a portion of the semiconductor layer having a different doping, and can be created as a stack of doped regions, each having a first doping and being separated by a layer having a second doping. The doped regions can include either a p-type or an n-type doping. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> These and other objects, advantages and novel features of the invention will be more readily appreciated from the following detailed description when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a system for performing DNA or RNA sequencing comprising a DNA or RNA sequencer constructed in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of the DNA or RNA sequencer shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a graph showing an example of the waveform representing the current detected by a current detector in the system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> as the adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C) bases of a DNA or RNA sequence pass through the DNA or RNA sequencer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate from which a DNA or RNA sequencer as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is fabricated in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the SOI substrate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> having shallow and deep n-type regions formed in the silicon layer, and a portion of the substrate etched away; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the SOI substrate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> in which a portion of the insulator has been etched away and another shallow n-type region has been formed in the silicon layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the SOI substrate having an opening etched therethrough; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of the SOI substrate as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the SOI substrate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> having an oxidation layer formed on the silicon layer and on the walls forming the opening therein; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of the SOI substrate as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates a detailed cross-sectional view of the SOI substrate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> having an oxidation layer formed on the silicon layer and on the walls forming the opening therein; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of the SOI substrate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> illustrates a detailed cross-sectional view of an exemplary configuration of the opening in SOI substrate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of the opening shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the SOI substrate as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> having holes etched in the oxidation layer and metal contacts formed over the holes to contact the shallow and deep n-type regions, respectively; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the DNA or RNA sequencer shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> having been fabricated in accordance with the manufacturing steps shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a DNA or RNA sequencer having multiple detectors formed by multiple n-type regions according to another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of a DNA or RNA sequencer according to another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of a DNA or RNA sequencer according to a further embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> illustrates a cross-sectional view of a DNA or RNA sequencer according to a further embodiment of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of the DNA or RNA sequencer shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> illustrate a system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for detecting the presence of a polymer, such as DNA or RNA, a protein or carbohydrate, or a long chain polymer such as petroleum, and, more preferably, for identifying the individual mers of the polymer or long chain polymer, as well as the length of the polymer or long chain polymer. The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is preferably adaptable for performing sequencing of nucleic acids, such as DNA or RNA sequencing, according to an embodiment of the present invention. Accordingly, for purposes of this description, the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> will be discussed in relation to nucleic acid sequencing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> which, as described in more detail below, is a semiconductor device. Specifically, the nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> resembles a field-effect transistor, such as a MOSFET, in that it includes two doped regions, a drain region <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and a source region <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. However, unlike a MOSFET, the nucleic acid sequencing device does not include a gate region for reasons discussed below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is disposed in a container <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> that includes a liquid <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> such as water, gel, or any other suitable solution. It is important to note that the solution <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can be an insulating medium, such as oil, or any other suitable insulating medium. In addition, the container <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> does not need to include a medium such as a liquid. Rather, the container <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can be sealed and evacuated to create a vacuum in which nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is disposed. Also, although <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows only a single nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in the container <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> for exemplary purposes, the container can include multiple nucleic acid sequencing devices <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> for performing multiple DNA sequencing measurements in parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The liquid <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> or other medium or vacuum in container <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> includes the nucleic acid strands or portions of nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> to be sequenced by nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. As further shown, voltage source <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, such as a direct current voltage source, is coupled in series with a current meter <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> by leads <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> across drain and source regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, respectively. In this example, the positive lead of voltage source <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is coupled to the drain region <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> while the negative lead of voltage source <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is coupled via the current meter <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to source region <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The voltage potential applied across drain and source regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> creates a gradient across drain and source regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, which draws the nucleic acid strands into opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of the nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. That is, the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> move through the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> because of the local gradient. Alternatively or in addition, the liquid can include an ionic solution. In this event, the local gradient causes the ions in the solution to flow through the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, which assists the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, such as DNA or RNA, to move through the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Additional electrodes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> positioned in the medium <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and connected to additional voltage sources <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> would further facilitate the movement of the nucleic acid strands towards the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. In other words, the external electrodes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> are used to apply an electric field within the medium <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. This field causes all of the charged particles, including the nucleic acid strand <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, to flow either toward the hole <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> or away from the hole <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Thus electrodes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> are used as a means to steer the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> into or out of the hole <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. In order to connect voltage sources <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> to the nucleic acid sequencer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, metal contacts <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> are coupled to the n-type doped region <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, described in more detail below. The electrodes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> could also provide a high frequency voltage which is superimposed on the DC voltage by an alternating voltage source <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. This high frequency voltage, which can have a frequency in the radio frequency range, such as the megahertz range (e.g., 10 MHz), causes the nucleic acid strand <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and ions to oscillate. This oscillation makes passage of the nucleic acid strand <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> through the hole <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> smoother, in a manner similar to shaking a salt shaker to enable the salt grains to pass through the openings in the shaker. Alternatively, a device <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>, such as an acoustic wave generator, can be disposed in the liquid <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> or at any other suitable location, and is controlled to send sonic vibrations through the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to provide a similar mechanical shaking function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> As can be appreciated by one skilled in the art, the nucleic acid strands each include different combinations of bases A, C, G and T, which each contain a particular magnitude and polarity of ionic charge. The charge gradient between drain and source regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, or otherwise across the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, will thus cause the charged nucleic acid strands to traverse the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, another voltage source (not shown) can be used to create a difference in voltage potential between the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and the liquid. Also, a pressure differential can be applied across the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> to control the flow of the DNA independent from the voltage applied between the source and drain <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In addition, the DNA sequencer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can attract the nucleic acid strands to the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> by applying a positive voltage to the medium <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> relative to the voltage source <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the nucleic acid strands in the medium <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> can be pushed in and out of the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and be analyzed multiple times by reversing the polarity across drain and source regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As described in more detail below, the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is configured to have a diameter within the nanometer range, for example, within the range of about 1 nm to about 10 nm. Therefore, only one DNA strand can pass through opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> at any given time. As a DNA strand passes through opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, the sequence of bases induce image charges which form a channel <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> between the drain and source regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> that extends vertically along the walls of the device defining opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. As a voltage is applied between the source <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> and drain <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> by means of the voltage source <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, these image charges in the channel flow from source to drain, resulting in a current flow which can be detected by the current meter <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the bases induce a charge variation in channel <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight>, leading to a current variation as detected by current meter <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Any variation of the ion flow through the opening due to the presence of the DNA strand would also cause a variation to the image charge in the channel <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> and results in a current variation as detected by current meter <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Each different type of bases A, C, G, and T induces a current having a particular magnitude and waveform representative of the particular charge associated with its respective type of bases. In other words, an A type base will induce a current in a channel between the drain and source regions of the nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> having a magnitude and waveform indicative of the A type base. Similarly, the C, T and G bases will each induce a current having a particular magnitude and waveform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> An example of a waveform of the detected current is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, which symbolically illustrates the shape, magnitude, and time resolution of the expected signals generated by the presence of the A, C, G and T bases. The magnitude of current is typically in the microampere (&mgr;A) range, which is a multiplication factor of 10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>greater than the ion current flowing through the opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, which is in the picoampere range. A calculation of the electrostatic potential of the individual bases shows the complementary distribution of charges that lead to the hydrogen bonding. For example, the T-A and C-G pairs have similar distributions when paired viewed from the outside, but, when unpaired, as would be the case when analyzing single-stranded DNA, the surfaces where the hydrogen bonding occurs are distinctive. The larger A and G bases are roughly complementary (positive and negative reversed) on the hydrogen bonding surface with similar behavior for the smaller T and C bases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, as the DNA strand passes through opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, the sequence of bases in the strand can be detected and thus ascertained by interpreting the waveform and magnitude of the induced current detected by current meter <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> therefore enables DNA sequencing to be performed in a very accurate and efficient manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The preferred method of fabricating a nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> will now be described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the fabrication process begins with a wafer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, such as a silicon-on-insulator (SOI) substrate comprising a silicon substrate <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, a silicon dioxide (SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) layer <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, and a thin layer of p-type silicon <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. In this example, the silicon substrate <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> has a thickness within the range of about 300 &mgr;m to about 600 &mgr;m, the silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> has a thickness within the range of about 200 to 6400 nm, and the p-type silicon layer <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> has a thickness of about 1 &mgr;m or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> doped n-type region <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is created in the p-type silicon layer <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> by ion implantation, and annealing or diffusion of an n-type dopant, such as arsenic, phosphorous or the like. As illustrated, the n-type region <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is a shallow region which does not pass entirely through p-type silicon <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. A deep n-type region <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is also created in the p-type silicon <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The deep n-type region <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> passes all the way through the p-type silicon <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to silicon dioxide <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and is created by known methods, such as diffusion, or ion implantation and annealing of an n-type material which can be identical or similar to the n-type material used to create n-type region <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. As further illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the silicon substrate <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is etched along its (111) plane by known etching methods, such as etching in potassium hydroxide (KOH) or the like. As illustrated, the etching process etches away a central portion of silicon substrate <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> down to the silicon dioxide <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> to create an opening <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> in the silicon substrate <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the portion of the silicon dioxide <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> exposed in opening <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is etched away by conventional etching methods, such as etching in hydrofluoric acid, reactive etching or the like. Another shallow n-type region <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is created in the area of the p-type silicon <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> exposed at opening <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> by known methods, such implantation or diffusion of an n-type material identical or similar to those used to create n-type regions <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>) is then formed through the n-type region <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, p-type silicon <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and bottom n-type region <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> as shown, for example, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference> by reactive ion etching using Freon (CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>), optical lithography, electron-beam lithography or any other fine-line lithography, which results in an opening having a diameter of about 10 nm. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the diameter of the opening can be further decreased by oxidizing the silicon, thus forming a silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> over the p-type silicon layer <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and the walls forming opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. As shown in detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference>, the resulting oxide has a volume larger than the silicon consumed during the oxidation process, which further narrows the diameter of opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. It is desirable if the diameter of opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> can be as small as 1 nm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Although for illustration purposes <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> show opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> as being a cylindrically-shaped opening, it is preferable for opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> to have a funnel shape as shown, for example, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</cross-reference>. This funnel-shaped opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is created by performing V-groove etching of the (100) p-type silicon layer <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> using potassium hydroxide (KOH), which results in V-shaped grooves formed along the (111) planes <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> of the p-type silicon <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. The V-shaped or funnel-shaped opening, as shown explicitly in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, facilitates movement of a DNA strand through opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, and minimizes the possibility that the DNA strand will become balled up upon itself and thus have difficulty passing through opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Oxidation and V-groove etching can be combined to yield even smaller openings. Additionally, anodic oxidation can be used instead of thermal oxidation, as described above. Anodic oxidation has the additional advantage of allowing for monitoring of the hole size during oxidation so that the process can be stopped when the optimum hole size is achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, holes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> are etched into the silicon dioxide <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> to expose n-type region <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and n-type region <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Metal contacts <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> are then deposited onto silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> and into holes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to contact the respective n-type regions <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. An insulator <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is then deposited over metal contacts <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, thus resulting in device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As further shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> portion of insulator <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> can be removed so that leads <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> can be connected to the n-type regions <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, which thus form the drain regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and source <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, respectively. An additional insulator <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> is deposited over insulator <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> to seal the openings through which leads <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> extend to contact n-type regions <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The completed device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can then be operated to perform the DNA sequencing as discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Additional embodiments of the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can also be fabricated. For example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a nucleic acid sequencing device according to another embodiment of the present invention. In this embodiment, the steps described above with regard to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 through 16</cross-reference> are performed to form the n-type regions which ultimately form the drain and source regions. However, in this embodiment, the n-type region <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> shown, for example, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, is formed as four separate n-type regions, <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> in a p-type silicon layer similar to p-type silicon layer <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> described above. A silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> covers the p-type silicon layer into which n-type regions <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> have been created. Holes <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> are etched into silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> so that metal contacts <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> that are deposited on silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> can contact n-type regions <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. By detecting current flowing between the four drain regions formed by n-type regions <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and the source region (not shown), the spatial orientation of the bases on the DNA strand passing through opening <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> can be detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a cross section of a nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> according to another embodiment of the present invention. Similar to nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> includes a silicon substrate <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, a silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>, an n-type region <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> implanted in p-type silicon <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>, and a second n-type region <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> implanted in p-type silicon <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>. Nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> further has an opening <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> passing therethrough. The opening can be cylindrical, or can be a V-shaped or funnel-shaped opening as described above. A silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> covers p-type silicon layer <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>, n-type region <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and n-type region <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> as shown, and decreases the diameter of opening <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> in the manner described above. An opening is etched into silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> to allow a lead <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> to be attached to n-type region <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Another lead <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> is also attached to an exposed portion of n-type region <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, so that a voltage source <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> can apply a potential across the drain region <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> formed by n-type region <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and source region <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> formed n-type region <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. The nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> can thus be used to detect the bases of a DNA strand <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> in a manner described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> illustrates a DNA sequencing system <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> according to another embodiment of the present invention. System <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> includes a multi-layer nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> which, in this example, comprises three MOSFET-type devices stacked on top of each other. That is, device <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> includes a silicon substrate <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> similar to silicon substrate <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> described above. A silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> is present on silicon substrate <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>. The device <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> further includes an n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>, a p-type silicon dioxide region <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight>, an n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight>, a p-type silicon dioxide region <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, an n-type doped region silicon region <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, a p-type silicon dioxide region <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and an n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>. Regions <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> are stacked on top of each other as shown explicitly in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>. However, as can be appreciated by one skilled in the art, the polarity of the layers can be reversed for this embodiment, and for any of the other embodiments discussed herein. That is, the device <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> can comprise a p-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>, an n-type silicon dioxide region <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight>, a p-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight>, and so on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Additionally, a thin silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> is formed over the layers as illustrated, and is also formed on the walls forming opening <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to decrease the diameter of opening <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> in a manner described above with regard to opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Also, opening <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> can be cylindrically shaped, a V-shaped groove or a funnel-shaped groove as described above. Holes are formed in silicon dioxide layer <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> so that leads <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> can be attached to regions <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> to couple voltage source <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and current meters <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> to device <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> as will now be described. Voltage sources <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and current meters <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> are similar to voltage source <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and current meter <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, respectively, as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Specifically, leads <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> couple voltage source <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and current meter <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> in series to n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>. Therefore, voltage source <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> applies a voltage across regions <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> which are separated by p-type silicon dioxide region <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. Leads <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> also couple voltage source <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> and current meter <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> to n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> and n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> as shown. Furthermore, leads <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> couple voltage source <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and current meter <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> to n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> and n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> as shown. Accordingly, as can be appreciated from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>, n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> and n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> act as the drain and source regions, respectively, of one MOSFET, n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> act as drain and source regions, respectively, of a second MOSFET, and n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and n-type doped silicon region <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> act as drain and source regions, respectively, of a third MOSFET. These three MOSFET type devices can measure the current induced by the bases of a DNA strand passing through opening <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, and thus take multiple measurements of these bases to improve accuracy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> It is also noted that a nucleic acid sequencing device above can be configured to sense the bases of a nucleic acid strand without it being necessary for the DNA strand to pass through an opening in the devices, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 20 and 21</cross-reference>. That is, using the techniques described above, a nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>, similar to nucleic acid sequencing device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, can be fabricated having its drain and source regions proximate to a surface. It is noted that like components shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 20</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are identified with like reference numbers. However, in place of an opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, one or more grooves <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> can optionally be formed in the surface extending from the drain region to the source region. Alternatively, no grooves are formed in the surface, but rather, the detection area for detecting nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> is present between the drain and source regions. Techniques similar to those discussed above, such as the application of voltage potentials, by means of voltage sources <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, and creation of a pressure differential in the container <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can be used to move the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> in a horizontal direction along the surface of the device over the grooves <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>. The bases in the nucleic acid strands create an image charge channel <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> between the drain and source regions which allows current to flow between the drain and source regions. The current induced in the nucleic acid sequencing device by the bases can be measured in a manner similar to that described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Again, it is noted that the device <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> differs from the other embodiments represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 17</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> in that the channel <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> containing the image charge is horizontal rather than vertical. The structure no longer contains a hole <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> as in the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 17</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, but rather this embodiment contains a charge sensitive region just above channel <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the external electrodes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> are used to apply an electric field which steers the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> towards or away from the charge sensitive region. That is, the motion of the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> is controlled by applying a voltage to the external electrodes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> relative to the voltage applied to the doped regions <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Additional electrodes (not shown) can be added to move the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> perpendicular to the plane shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The charge sensitive region of the device is located just above the channel <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and between the two doped regions <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Identification of individual bases requires that the distance between the two doped regions is on the order of a single base and that the motion of the nucleic acid strand <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> is such that each base is successively placed above the charge sensitive region. This horizontal configuration enables more parallel as well as sequential analysis of the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and does not require the fabrication of a small opening. Additional surface processing, such as the formation of grooves <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> as discussed above that channel the nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> can be used to further enhance this approach. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The horizontal embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 19 and 20</cross-reference> is also of interest to detect the presence of a large number of nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. For instance, using an electrophoresis gel as the medium, one starts by placing nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> of different length between the electrodes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. A negative voltage is applied to the electrodes <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>, relative to the doped regions <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The nucleic acid strands <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> will then move towards the charge sensitive region. The smaller strands will move faster and the larger strands will move slower. The smaller strands will therefore arrive first at the charge sensitive region, followed by the larger ones. The charge accumulated in the charge sensitive region and therefore also the image charge in the channel <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> therefore increases &ldquo;staircase-like&rdquo; with time. This results in a staircase-like increase or decrease of the current measured by current meter <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> While this operation does not yield the identification of the individual bases of a single DNA/RNA strands, it does provide a measurement of the length of strands equivalent to the one obtained by an electrophoresis measurement. The advantage over standard electrophoresis is that a real-time measurement of the position of the DNA/RNA strands is obtained. In addition, the dimensions can be reduced dramatically since micron-sized devices can readily be made, while standard electrophoresis uses mm if not cm-sized drift regions. This size reduction leads to faster measurements requiring less DNA/RNA strands, while also reducing the cost of a single charge sensing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Although only several exemplary embodiments of the present invention have been described in detail above, those skilled in the art will readily appreciate that many modifications are possible in the exemplary embodiments without materially departing from the novel teachings and advantages of this invention. Accordingly, all such modifications are intended to be included within the scope of this invention as defined in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A system for detecting at least one polymer, comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one semiconductor device having at least one detecting region, adapted to detect a charge representative of a component of said polymer proximate to said detecting region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said component includes a base in a nucleic acid strand; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said detecting region is adapted to detect said charge representative of said base in said nucleic acid strand. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said detecting region is further adapted to generate a signal representative of said detected charge. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said detecting region includes a region of said semiconductor device defining an opening in said semiconductor device having a cross-section sufficient to enable said polymer to enter said opening, such that said detecting region is adapted to detect said charge of said component in said opening. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an excitation device, adapted to generate movement in said semiconductor device to facilitate movement of said polymer through said opening. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said detecting region includes a region of said semiconductor device defining a recess in said semiconductor device, such that said detecting region is adapted to detect said charge of said component in said recess. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said semiconductor device includes a plurality of said detecting regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>each said detecting region is adapted to detect a charge representative of a component of said at least one polymer proximate thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said semiconductor device further includes at least two doped regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said detecting region is adapted to pass a current between said two doped regions in response to a presence of said component proximate to said detecting region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said semiconductor device includes a plurality of doped regions, and a respective detecting region associated with each respective pair of said doped regions, such that each said respective detecting region is adapted, in response to a presence of a component proximate thereto, to pass a respective current between its said respective pair of doped regions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of said semiconductor devices. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a detector, adapted to detect a signal generated by said detecting region in response to said component proximate thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method for detecting at least one polymer, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>positioning a portion of said polymer proximate to a detecting region of at least one semiconductor device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at said detecting region, detecting a charge representative of a component of said polymer proximate to said detecting region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said component includes a base in a nucleic acid strand; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said detecting step detects said charge representative of said base in said nucleic acid strand. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>generating at said detecting region a signal representative of said detected charge. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said detecting region includes a region of said semiconductor device defining an opening in said semiconductor device having a cross-section sufficient to enable said polymer to enter said opening; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said detecting step detects said charge of said component in said opening. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>generating movement in said semiconductor device to facilitate movement of said polymer through said opening. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said detecting region includes a region of said semiconductor device defining a recess in said semiconductor device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said detecting step detects said charge of said component in said recess. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said semiconductor device includes a plurality of said detecting regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said detecting step includes the step of detecting, at each said detecting region, a charge representative of a component of said at least one polymer proximate thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said semiconductor device further includes at least two doped regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said method further includes the step of passing a current between said two doped regions in response to a presence of said component proximate to said detecting region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said semiconductor device includes a plurality of doped regions, and a respective detecting region associated with each respective pair of said doped regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said method further includes the step of passing, at each said respective detecting region in response to a presence of a component proximate thereto, a respective current between its said respective pair of doped regions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said positioning step positions a respective portion of each of a plurality of said polymers proximate to a respective detecting region of a respective semiconductor device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said detecting step detects, at each said respective detecting region, a charge representative of a component of said respective polymer proximate to said respective detecting region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>detecting a signal generated by said detecting region in response to said component proximate thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method for manufacturing a device for detecting a polymer, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a semiconductor structure comprising at least one semiconductor layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>creating a detecting region in said semiconductor structure, said detecting region being adapted to detect a charge representative of a component of said polymer proximate to said detecting region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said component includes a base in a nucleic acid strand; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said creating step creates said detecting region which is adapted to detect said charge representative of said base in said nucleic acid strand. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>creating an opening in said semiconductor structure, said opening having a cross-section sufficient to enable a portion of said polymer to pass therethrough, and being positioned in relation to said detecting region such that said detecting region is adapted to detect said charge representative of said component in said opening. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said opening creating step includes the step of: 
<claim-text>forming an insulating layer on a wall of said semiconductor layer forming said opening to decrease said cross-section of said opening. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>creating a recess in said semiconductor structure, positioned in relation to said detecting region such that said detecting region is adapted to detect said charge representative of said component in said recess. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>creating at least two doped regions in said semiconductor layer, said doped regions being positioned with respect to said detecting region such that said detecting region is adapted to pass a current between said doped regions in response to said component of said polymer proximate thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said doped region creating step creates said doped regions having a first doping such that said doped regions are separated by a portion of said semiconductor layer having a second doping. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said doped region creating step creates said doped regions as a stack of doped regions, each having a first doping and being separated by a layer having a second doping. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>each of said doped regions includes a p-type doping. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>each of said doped regions includes an n-type doping.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003609A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
