<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003768A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003768A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003768A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003768A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003768A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003768A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003768A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003768A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003768A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003768A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003768A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003768A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003768</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09885985</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010618</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/31</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>778000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>CVD PLASMA ASSISTED LOWER DIELECTRIC CONSTANT SICOH FILM</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Seon-Mee</given-name>
<family-name>Cho</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<middle-name>Wai-Man</middle-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chi-I</given-name>
<family-name>Lang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dian</given-name>
<family-name>Sugiarto</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chen-An</given-name>
<family-name>Chen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Li-Qun</given-name>
<family-name>Xia</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shankar</given-name>
<family-name>Venkataraman</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ellie</given-name>
<family-name>Yieh</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Applied Materials, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>APPLIED MATERIALS, INC.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2881 SCOTT BLVD. M/S 2061</address-1>
<city>SANTA CLARA</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95050</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A low dielectric constant film having silicon-carbon bonds and dielectric constant of about 3.0 or less, preferably about 2.5 or less, is provided. The low dielectric constant film is deposited by reacting a cyclic organosilicon compound and an aliphatic organosilicon compound with an oxidizing gas while applying RF power. The carbon content of the deposited film is between about 10 and about 30 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms, and is preferably between about 10 and about 20 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to the fabrication of integrated circuits. More particularly, the invention relates to a process for depositing dielectric layers on a substrate and the structures formed by the dielectric layer. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Semiconductor device geometries have dramatically decreased in size since such devices were first introduced several decades ago. Since then, integrated circuits have generally followed the two year/half-size rule (often called Moore&apos;s Law), which means that the number of devices that will fit on a chip doubles every two years. Today&apos;s fabrication plants are routinely producing devices having 0.13 &mgr;m and even 0.1 &mgr;m feature sizes, and tomorrow&apos;s plants soon will be producing devices having even smaller geometries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In order to further reduce the size of devices on integrated circuits, it has become necessary to use conductive materials having low resistivity and to use insulators having low dielectric constants (k&lt;4.0) to reduce the capacitive coupling between adjacent metal lines. One such low k material is spin-on glass, such as un-doped silicon glass (USG) or fluorine-doped silicon glass (FSG), which can be deposited as a gap fill layer in a semiconductor manufacturing process. Other examples of low k materials include silicon dioxide and polytetrafluoroethylene which are all commercially available. However, the continued reduction in device geometries has generated a demand for films having even lower k values. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Rose et al. (U.S. Pat. No. 6,068,884) discloses a method of depositing an insulator wherein a cyclic organosilicon compound, octamethylcylcotetrasiloxane (OMCTS), is partially fragmented to form both cyclic and chain structures in the deposited film. However, partially fragmenting cyclic precursors is difficult to control. Therefore, there is a need for a controllable process for making low dielectric constant materials that would improve the speed and efficiency of devices on integrated circuits. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a method for depositing a low dielectric constant film having a dielectric constant of about 3.0 or less, preferably about 2.5 or less. In one aspect, a cyclic organosilicon compound and an aliphatic organosilicon compound are reacted with an oxidizing gas at conditions sufficient to deposit a low dielectric constant film on the semiconductor substrate. The cyclic organosilicon compound comprises at least one silicon-carbon bond. The aliphatic organosilicon compound comprises a silicon-hydrogen bond or a silicon-oxygen bond. A sufficient amount of the aliphatic organosilicon compound is added to the cyclic organosilicon compound to provide a dielectric constant at least 5% lower than a dielectric constant obtained by omitting the aliphatic organosilicon compound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, a method for depositing a low dielectric constant film comprises flowing a cyclic organosilicon compound and an aliphatic organosilicon compound into a reaction zone at a volume ratio between about 1:4 and about 4:1, and reacting the compounds with an oxidizing gas while applying RF power to deposit a film having a dielectric constant of about 3 or less, preferably about 2.5 or less. The cyclic organosilicon compound comprises at least three silicon atoms and from one to two alkyl groups bonded to each silicon atom. The aliphatic organosilicon compound comprises at least one hydrogen or at least one alkoxy group bonded to at least one silicon atom. In another aspect, both the cyclic organosilicon compound and the aliphatic organosilicon compound comprise at least one silicon-hydrogen bond.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> So that the manner in which the above recited features, advantages and objects of the present invention are attained and can be understood in detail, a more particular description of the invention, briefly summarized above, may be had by reference to the embodiments thereof which are illustrated in the appended drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is to be noted, however, that the description and appended drawings illustrate only typical embodiments of this invention and are therefore not to be considered limiting of its scope, for the invention may admit to other equally effective embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagram of an exemplary CVD reactor configured for use according to embodiments described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow chart of a process control computer program product used in conjunction with the exemplary CVD reactor of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view showing a damascene structure comprising a low dielectric constant film as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>C are cross sectional views showing one embodiment of a damascene deposition sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view showing a dual damascene structure comprising two low dielectric constant films as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>E are cross sectional views showing one embodiment of a dual damascene deposition sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a relationship between dielectric constant and ratio of gases.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The present invention includes a significant and unexpected reduction in dielectric constants for films comprising silicon, oxygen, and carbon by blending both aliphatic organosilicon compounds and cyclic organosilicon compounds with an oxidizing gas at conditions sufficient to form a low dielectric constant film. The low dielectric constant film has a dielectric constant of about 3.0 or less, preferably about 2.5 or less. The films contain silicon-carbon bonds and the carbon content of the deposited film is between about 10 and about 30 atomic percent (excluding hydrogen atoms), preferably between about 10 and about 20 atomic percent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Cyclic organosilicon compounds typically have a ring comprising three or more silicon atoms and the ring may further comprise one or more oxygen atoms. Commercially available cyclic organosilicon compounds include rings having alternating silicon and oxygen atoms with one or two alkyl groups bonded to the silicon atoms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Aliphatic organosilicon compounds have linear or branched structures comprising one or more atoms and one or more silicon carbon atoms, and the structure may further comprise oxygen. Commercially available aliphatic organosilicon compounds include organosilanes that do not contain oxygen between silicon atoms and organosiloxanes which contain oxygen between two or more silicon atoms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The carbon content of the deposited films refers to atomic analysis of the film structure which typically does not contain significant amounts of non-bonded hydrocarbons. The carbon contents are represented by the percent of carbon atoms in the deposited film, excluding hydrogen atoms which are difficult to quantify. For example, a film having an average of one silicon atom, one oxygen atom, one carbon atom and two hydrogen atoms has a carbon content of 20 atomic percent (one carbon atom per five total atoms), or a carbon content of 33 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms (one carbon atom per three total atoms). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Organosilicon compounds contain carbon atoms in organic groups. Low dielectric constant films are prepared from organosilicon compounds that have one or more carbon atoms attached to silicon wherein the carbon is not readily removed by oxidation at suitable processing conditions. Organic groups may include alkyl, alkenyl, cyclohexenyl, and aryl groups in addition to functional derivatives thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Cyclic organosilicon compounds include, for example, one or more of the following compounds: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> 1,3,5-trisilano-2,4,6-trimethylene, &mdash;(&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;(cyclic) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> 2,4,6,8-tetramethylcyclotetrasiloxane (TMCTS) &mdash;(&mdash;SiHCH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>&mdash;(cyclic) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane (OMCTS), &mdash;(&mdash;Si(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>&mdash;(cyclic) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> 2,4,6,8,10-pentamethylcyclopentasiloxane, &mdash;(&mdash;SiHCH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>&mdash;(cyclic) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> 1,3,5,7-tetrasilano-2,6-dioxy-4,8-dimethylene, &mdash;(&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;(cyclic) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> hexamethylcyclotrisiloxane &mdash;(&mdash;Si(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;(cyclic) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Aliphatic organosilicon compounds include for example, one or more of the following compounds:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="119PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>methylsilane,</entry>
<entry>CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>dimethylsilane,</entry>
<entry>(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>trimethylsilane,</entry>
<entry>(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>dimethyldimethoxysilane,</entry>
<entry>(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;Si&mdash;(OCH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>ethylsilane,</entry>
<entry>CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>disilanomethane,</entry>
<entry>SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>bis(methylsilano)methane,</entry>
<entry>CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1,2-disilanoethane,</entry>
<entry>SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1,2-bis(methylsilano)ethane,</entry>
<entry>CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2,2-disilanopropane,</entry>
<entry>SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;C(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1,3-dimethyldisiloxane,</entry>
<entry>CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1,1,3,3-tetramethyldisiloxane,</entry>
<entry>(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH&mdash;O&mdash;SiH&mdash;(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>hexamethyldisiloxane (HMDS),</entry>
<entry>(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;Si&mdash;O&mdash;Si&mdash;(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1,3-bis(silanomethylene)</entry>
<entry>(SiH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>disiloxane,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>bis(1-methyldisiloxanyl)</entry>
<entry>(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>methane,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2,2-bis(1-methyldisiloxanyl)</entry>
<entry>(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;O&mdash;SiH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;C(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>propane,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>hexamethoxydisiloxane</entry>
<entry>(CH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>O)<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;Si&mdash;O&mdash;Si&mdash;(OCH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(HMDOS)</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, a cyclic organosilicon compounds and an aliphatic organosilicon compound are reacted with an oxidizing gas in amounts sufficient to deposit a low dielectric constant film on a semiconductor substrate, wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound comprises at least one silicon-carbon bond. The aliphatic organosilicon compound contains a silicon-hydrogen bond or a silicon-oxygen bond, preferably a silicon-hydrogen bond. For example, the cyclic organosilicon compound may be 2,4,6,8-tetramethylcyclotetrasiloxane or octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane and the aliphatic organosilicon compound may be trimethylsilane or 1,1,3,3-tetramethyidisiloxane. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, both the cyclic organosilicon compound and the aliphatic organosilicon compound contain a silicon-hydrogen bond. For example, 2,4,6,8-tetramethylcyclotetrasiloxane and trimethylsilane or 1,1,3,3-tetramethyidisiloxane are blended and oxidized while applying RF power. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Although a post cure is not necessary, the low dielectric constant film may be annealed to reduce the moisture content, such as after exposure to ambient air. For example, the film may be subjected to a temperature between about 100&deg; C. and about 400&deg; C. for between about 1 minute and about 60 minutes, preferably about 30 minutes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Oxygen and oxygen containing compounds may be dissociated to increase reactivity and achieve the desired carbon content in the deposited film. For example, organosilicon compounds not containing oxygen may be oxidized by reaction with oxygen (O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), ozone (O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>), nitrous oxide (N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O), carbon monoxide (CO), carbon dioxide (CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), water (H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O), or combinations thereof, preferably oxygen. When ozone is used as an oxidizing gas, an ozone generator converts from 6% to 20%, typically about 15%, by weight of the oxygen in a source gas to ozone, with the remainder typically being oxygen. However, the ozone concentration may be increased or decreased based upon the amount of ozone desired and the type of ozone generating equipment used. Disassociation of oxygen or the oxygen containing compounds may occur in a microwave chamber prior to entering the deposition chamber to reduce excessive dissociation of the silicon containing compounds. Preferably, radio frequency (RF) power is applied to the reaction zone to increase dissociation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Deposition of the low dielectric constant film can be continuous or discontinuous. Although deposition preferably occurs in a single deposition chamber, the film can be deposited sequentially in two or more deposition chambers. During deposition, the substrate is maintained at a temperature between about &minus;20&deg; C. and about 400&deg; C., and preferably is maintained at a temperature between about 170&deg; C. and about 450&deg; C. RF power may be cycled or pulsed to reduce heating of the substrate and promote greater porosity in the deposited film. For a plasma enhanced deposition, the low dielectric constant film is deposited using a power density ranging between about 0.03 W/cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and about 3.2 W/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, which is a RF power level of between about 10 W and about 2000 W for a 200 mm substrate. Preferably, the RF power level is between about 300 W and about 1700 W. The RF power is provided at a frequency between about 0.01 MHz and 300 MHz. The RF power may be provided continuously or in short duration cycles wherein the power is on at the stated levels for cycles less than about 200 Hz and the on cycles total between about 10% and about 50% of the total duty cycle. The deposition process of the low dielectric constant film is performed in a substrate processing system described in more detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Exemplary CVD Reactor </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a vertical, cross-section view of a parallel plate chemical vapor deposition processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a high vacuum region <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> contains a gas distribution manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> having perforated holes for dispersing process gases there-through to a substrate (not shown). The substrate rests on a substrate support plate or susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is mounted on a support stem <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> which connects the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to a lift motor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The lift motor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> raises and lowers the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> between a processing position and a lower, substrate-loading position so that the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (and the substrate supported on the upper surface of susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) can be controllably moved between a lower loading/off-loading position and an upper processing position which is closely adjacent to the manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. When the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the substrate are in the upper processing position <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, they are surrounded by an insulator <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> During processing, gases introduced to the manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are uniformly distributed radially across the surface of the substrate. A vacuum pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> having a throttle valve controls the exhaust rate of gases from the chamber through a manifold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Deposition and carrier gases flow through gas lines <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> into a mixing system <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and then to the manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Generally, each process gas supply line <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> includes (i) safety shut-off valves (not shown) that can be used to automatically or manually shut off the flow of process gas into the chamber, and (ii) mass flow controllers (also not shown) to measure the flow of gas through the gas supply lines <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. When toxic gases are used in the process, several safety shut-off valves are positioned on each gas supply line <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in conventional configurations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The deposition process performed in the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be either a thermal process or a plasma enhanced process. In a plasma process, a controlled plasma is typically formed adjacent the substrate by RF energy applied to the gas distribution manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> using a RF power supply <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, RF power can be provided to the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> or RF power can be provided to different components at different frequencies. The RF power supply <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can supply either single or mixed frequency RF power to enhance the decomposition of reactive species introduced into the high vacuum region <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A mixed frequency RF power supply typically supplies power at a high RF frequency (RF1) of 13.56 MHz to the distribution manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and at a low RF frequency (RF2) of 360 KHz to the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> When additional dissociation of the oxidizing gas is desired, an optional microwave chamber <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> can be used to input from between about 0 Watts and about 6000 Watts to the oxidizing gas prior to the gas entering the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The additional microwave power can avoid excessive dissociation of the organosilicon compounds prior to reaction with the oxidizing gas. A gas distribution plate (not shown) having separate passages for the organosilicon compound and the oxidizing gas is preferred when microwave power is added to the oxidizing gas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Typically, any or all of the chamber lining, distribution manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and various other reactor hardware is made out of material such as aluminum or anodized aluminum. An example of such a CVD reactor is described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,000,113, entitled A Thermal CVD/PECVD Reactor and Use for Thermal Chemical Vapor Deposition of Silicon Dioxide and In-situ Multi-step Planarized Process, issued to Wang et al. and assigned to Applied Materials, Inc., the assignee of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> A system controller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> controls the motor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the gas mixing system <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and the RF power supply <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> which are connected therewith by control lines <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The system controller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> controls the activities of the CVD reactor and typically includes a hard disk drive, a floppy disk drive, and a card rack. The card rack contains a single board computer (SBC), analog and digital input/output boards, interface boards, and stepper motor controller boards. The system controller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> conforms to the Versa Modular Europeans (VME) standard which defines board, card cage, and connector dimensions and types. The VME standard also defines the bus structure having a 16-bit data bus and 24-bit address bus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the system controller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> operates under the control of a computer program <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> stored on the hard disk drive <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The computer program dictates the timing, mixture of gases, RF power levels, susceptor position, and other parameters of a particular process. The computer program code can be written in any conventional computer readable programming language such as, for example, 68000 assembly language, C, C&plus;&plus;, or Pascal. Suitable program code is entered into a single file, or multiple files, using a conventional text editor, and stored or embodied in a computer usable medium, such as a memory system of the computer. If the entered code text is in a high level language, the code is compiled, and the resultant compiler code is then linked with an object code of precompiled windows library routines. To execute the linked compiled object code, the system user invokes the object code, causing the computer system to load the code in memory, from which the CPU reads and executes the code to perform the tasks identified in the program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an illustrative block diagram of the hierarchical control structure of the computer program <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. A user enters a process set number and process chamber number into a process selector subroutine <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> in response to menus or screens displayed on the CRT monitor by using the light pen interface. The process sets are predetermined sets of process parameters necessary to carry out specified processes, and are identified by predefined set numbers. The process selector subroutine <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> (i) selects a desired process chamber on a cluster tool such as an Centura&reg; platform (available from Applied Materials, Inc.), and (ii) selects a desired set of process parameters needed to operate the process chamber for performing the desired process. The process parameters for performing a specific process are provided to the user in the form of a recipe and relate to process conditions such as, for example, process gas composition, flow rates, temperature, pressure, plasma conditions such as RF bias power levels and magnetic field power levels, cooling gas pressure, and chamber wall temperature. The parameters specified by the recipe are entered utilizing the light pen/CRT monitor interface. The signals for monitoring the process are provided by the analog input and digital input boards of the system controller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the signals for controlling the process are output to the analog output and digital output boards of the system controller <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A process sequencer subroutine <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> comprises program code for accepting the identified process chamber and set of process parameters from the process selector subroutine <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, and for controlling operation of the various process chambers. Multiple users can enter process set numbers and process chamber numbers, or a user can enter multiple process chamber numbers, so the sequencer subroutine <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> operates to schedule the selected processes in the desired sequence. Preferably the sequencer subroutine <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> includes computer readable program code to perform the steps of (i) monitoring the operation of the process chambers to determine if the chambers are being used, (ii) determining what processes are being carried out in the chambers being used, and (iii) executing the desired process based on availability of a process chamber and type of process to be carried out. Conventional methods of monitoring the process chambers can be used, such as polling. When scheduling a process execute, the sequencer subroutine <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> can be designed to take into consideration the present condition of the process chamber being used in comparison with the desired process conditions for a selected process, or the &ldquo;age&rdquo; of each particular user entered request, or any other relevant factor a system programmer desires to include for determining the scheduling priorities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Once the sequencer subroutine <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> determines which process chamber and process set combination is going to be executed next, the sequencer subroutine <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> causes execution of the process set by passing the particular process set parameters to a chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> which controls multiple processing tasks in a process chamber according to the process set determined by the sequencer subroutine <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight>. For example, the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> includes program code for controlling CVD process operations in the process chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> also controls execution of various chamber component subroutines which control operation of the chamber component necessary to carry out the selected process set. Examples of chamber component subroutines are susceptor control subroutine <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>, process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight>, pressure control subroutine <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight>, heater control subroutine <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight>, and plasma control subroutine <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight>. Those having ordinary skill in the art would readily recognize that other chamber control subroutines can be included depending on what processes are desired to be performed in a processing chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In operation, the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> selectively schedules or calls the process component subroutines in accordance with the particular process set being executed. The chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> schedules the process component subroutines similarly to how the sequencer subroutine <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> schedules which process chamber and process set is to be executed next. Typically, the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> includes steps of monitoring the various chamber components, determining which components needs to be operated based on the process parameters for the process set to be executed, and causing execution of a chamber component subroutine responsive to the monitoring and determining steps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Operation of particular chamber component subroutines will now be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The susceptor control positioning subroutine <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> comprises program code for controlling chamber components that are used to load the substrate onto the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and optionally to lift the substrate to a desired height in the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to control the spacing between the substrate and the gas distribution manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. When a substrate is loaded into the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is lowered to receive the substrate, and thereafter, the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is raised to the desired height in the chamber to maintain the substrate at a first distance or spacing from the gas distribution manifold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> during the CVD process. In operation, the susceptor control subroutine <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> controls movement of the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in response to process set parameters that are transferred from the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> has program code for controlling process gas compositions and flow rates. The process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> controls the open/close position of the safety shut-off valves, and also ramps up/down the mass flow controllers to obtain the desired gas flow rate. The process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> is invoked by the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>, as are all chamber components subroutines, and receives from the chamber manager subroutine process parameters related to the desired gas flow rates. Typically, the process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> operates by opening the gas supply lines, and repeatedly (i) reading the necessary mass flow controllers, (ii) comparing the readings to the desired flow rates received from the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>, and (iii) adjusting the flow rates of the gas supply lines as necessary. Furthermore, the process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> includes steps for monitoring the gas flow rates for unsafe rates, and activating the safety shut-off valves when an unsafe condition is detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In some processes, an inert gas such as helium or argon is put into the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to stabilize the pressure in the chamber before reactive process gases are introduced. For these processes, the process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> is programmed to include steps for flowing the inert gas into the chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for an amount of time necessary to stabilize the pressure in the chamber, and then the steps described above would be carried out. Additionally, when a process gas is to be vaporized from a liquid precursor, the process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> would be written to include steps for bubbling a delivery gas such as helium through the liquid precursor in a bubbler assembly. For this type of process, the process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> regulates the flow of the delivery gas, the pressure in the bubbler, and the bubbler temperature in order to obtain the desired process gas flow rates. As discussed above, the desired process gas flow rates are transferred to the process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> as process parameters. Furthermore, the process gas control subroutine <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> includes steps for obtaining the necessary delivery gas flow rate, bubbler pressure, and bubbler temperature for the desired process gas flow rate by accessing a stored table containing the necessary values for a given process gas flow rate. Once the necessary values are obtained, the delivery gas flow rate, bubbler pressure and bubbler temperature are monitored, compared to the necessary values and adjusted accordingly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The pressure control subroutine <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> comprises program code for controlling the pressure in the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by regulating the size of the opening of the throttle valve in the exhaust pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The size of the opening of the throttle valve is set to control the chamber pressure to the desired level in relation to the total process gas flow, size of the process chamber, and pumping set point pressure for the exhaust pump <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. When the pressure control subroutine <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> is invoked, the desired, or target pressure level is received as a parameter from the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>. The pressure control subroutine <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> operates to measure the pressure in the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by reading one or more conventional pressure manometers connected to the chamber, compare the measure value(s) to the target pressure, obtain PID (proportional, integral, and differential) values from a stored pressure table corresponding to the target pressure, and adjust the throttle valve according to the PID values obtained from the pressure table. Alternatively, the pressure control subroutine <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> can be written to open or close the throttle valve to a particular opening size to regulate the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the desired pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The heater control subroutine <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> comprises program code for controlling the temperature of the heat modules or radiated heat that is used to heat the susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The heater control subroutine <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> is also invoked by the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> and receives a target, or set point, temperature parameter. The heater control subroutine <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> measures the temperature by measuring voltage output of a thermocouple located in a susceptor <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, compares the measured temperature to the set point temperature, and increases or decreases current applied to the heat module to obtain the set point temperature. The temperature is obtained from the measured voltage by looking up the corresponding temperature in a stored conversion table, or by calculating the temperature using a fourth order polynomial. The heater control subroutine <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> gradually controls a ramp up/down of current applied to the heat module. The gradual ramp up/down increases the life and reliability of the heat module. Additionally, a built-in-fail-safe mode can be included to detect process safety compliance, and can shut down operation of the heat module if the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not properly set up. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The plasma control subroutine <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight> comprises program code for setting the RF bias voltage power level applied to the process electrodes in the processing chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and optionally, to set the level of the magnetic field generated in the reactor. Similar to the previously described chamber component subroutines, the plasma control subroutine <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight> is invoked by the chamber manager subroutine <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The pretreatment and method for forming a pretreated layer of the present invention is not limited to any specific apparatus or to any specific plasma excitation method. The above CVD system description is mainly for illustrative purposes, and other CVD equipment such as electrode cyclotron resonance (ECR) plasma CVD devices, induction-coupled RF high density plasma CVD devices, or the like may be employed. Additionally, variations of the above described system such as variations in susceptor design, heater design, location of RF power connections and others are possible. For example, the substrate could be supported and heated by a resistively heated susceptor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Deposition of a Low Dielectric Constant Film </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a damascene structure having a low dielectric constant film of the present invention deposited thereon. The low dielectric constant film is deposited as a dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> on a dielectric liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. A cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is deposited on the dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. The cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> acts as an etch stop during further substrate processing or alternatively, as a liner layer. The cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, and dielectric liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> are pattern etched to define the openings of interconnects <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> such as lines that expose underlying conducive features <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. A conductive liner/barrier layer <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is deposited within the interconnects <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>, and a conductive material <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is deposited thereon to fill the interconnects <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>. The substrate is typically planarized, as shown, after deposition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>C are cross sectional views of a substrate <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> having the steps of the invention formed thereon. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A, a</cross-reference> dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> of the low dielectric constant film formed from two or more organosilicon compounds as described in subsequent examples is deposited on the liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> to a thickness between about 5,000 &angst; to about 10,000 &angst; , depending on the size of the structure to be fabricated. The liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may be a silicon carbide layer, for example, from the PECVD of an alkylsilane compound using a plasma of an inert gas. The silicon carbide layer may be doped with oxygen or nitrogen. The liner/barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may alternatively comprise another material, such as silicon nitride, which minimizes oxidation and/or diffusion of conductive materials, such as copper, which may comprise conductive features <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> previously formed in the substrate <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, which can be a silicon carbide layer have a low dielectric constant, is then deposited on the dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> by reaction of the trimethylsilane to a thickness of about 200 &angst; to about 1000 &angst; using RF power in the range between about 10 and about 1000 watts for a 200 mm substrate. The silicon carbide material may be doped with oxygen or nitrogen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, the cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, the dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, and the liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> are then pattern etched to define the interconnects <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> and to expose the conductive feature <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> in substrate <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, the dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, and the liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> are pattern etched using conventional photolithography and etch processes for silicon carbide films. Any photo resist or other material used to pattern the cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is removed using an oxygen strip or other suitable process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Following etching of the deposited material and removal of photo resist materials, exposed portions of the cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, the dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, and the liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may be treated with a reactive pre-clean process to remove contaminants, particulate matter, residues, and oxides that may have formed on the exposed portions of the interconnects <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> and on the surface of the substrate. The reactive pre-clean process comprises exposing the substrate to a plasma, preferably comprising hydrogen, argon, helium, nitrogen, or mixtures thereof, at a power density between of 0.03 watts/cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and about 3.2 watts/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, or at a power level between about 10 watts and 1000 for a 200 millimeter substrate. The processing chamber is maintained at a pressure of about 20 Torr or less and at a substrate temperature of about 450&deg; C. or less during the reactive clean process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>C, after the cap layer <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, the dielectric layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, and the liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> have been etched to define the interconnects <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> and the photo resist has been removed, the interconnects <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> are filled with a conductive material <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. The structure is preferably formed with a conductive material such as aluminum, copper, tungsten, or combinations thereof. Presently, the trend is to use copper to form the smaller features due to the low resistivity of copper (1.7 &OHgr;-cm compared to 3.1 &OHgr;-cm for aluminum). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the conductive barrier layer <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is first deposited conformably in the interconnects <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> to prevent copper migration into the surrounding silicon and/or dielectric material. Barrier layers include titanium, titanium nitride, tantalum, tantalum nitride, and combinations thereof among other conventional barrier layer materials. Thereafter, copper <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is deposited using chemical vapor deposition, physical vapor deposition, electroplating, or combinations thereof, to form the conductive structure. Once the structure has been filled with copper or other conductive material, the surface is planarized using chemical mechanical polishing to produce the finished damascene structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> A dual damascene structure which includes two low dielectric constant films and two silicon carbide cap layers or doped silicon carbide cap layers deposited thereon is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. A conductive feature <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is formed in a substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. The first low dielectric constant film is deposited as a first dielectric layer <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> on a liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>, for example, silicon carbide. A first silicon carbide cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> is deposited on the first dielectric layer <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. The silicon carbide cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> reduces the dielectric constant of the low dielectric constant film and is pattern etched to define the openings of vertical interconnects such as contacts/vias. For the dual damascene application, a second dielectric layer <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> comprising the second low dielectric constant film is deposited over the patterned silicon carbide cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>. The second silicon carbide cap layer <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> is deposited on the second dielectric layer <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> and pattern etched to define horizontal interconnects such as lines. An etch process is performed to define the horizontal interconnects down to the first silicon carbide layer <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> which functions as an etch stop, and to define the vertical interconnects and expose the conductive feature <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> in substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> prior to filling the interconnects with a conductive material <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> A preferred method for making the dual damascene structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is sequentially depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>E, which are cross sectional views of a substrate having the steps of the invention formed thereon. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A, an initial first dielectric layer 510 of the low dielectric constant film is deposited on the liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> to a thickness between about 5,000 &angst; and about 10,000 &angst;, depending on the size of the structure to be fabricated. The liner layer <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> may be a silicon carbide layer which may be doped with oxygen or nitrogen. The liner/barrier layer <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> may alternatively comprise another material, such as silicon nitride, which minimizes oxidation and/or diffusion of conductive materials, such as copper, which may comprise conductive features <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> previously formed in the substrate <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>B, the first cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>, which includes a silicon carbide layer or doped silicon carbide layer is then deposited on the first dielectric layer to a thickness between about 200 and about 1000 &angst; using RF power in the range between about 10 and about 1000 watts for a 200 mm substrate. The first cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> is then pattern etched to define the contact/via openings <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> and to expose first dielectric layer <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> in the areas where the contacts/vias are to be formed as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</cross-reference>. Preferably, the first cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> is pattern etched using conventional photolithography and etch processes for silicon carbide films. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> After the first cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> has been etched to pattern the contacts/vias <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> and the photo resist has been removed, a second dielectric layer <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> is deposited over the first cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> to a thickness between about 5,000 &angst; and about 10,000 &angst; as described for the first dielectric layer <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6D</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> A second cap layer <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight>, which includes a silicon carbide layer or doped silicon carbide layer is then deposited on the second dielectric layer <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> to a thickness of about 200 to about 1000 &angst;. The silicon carbide material may be doped with oxygen or nitrogen. The second cap layer <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> is then patterned to define lines <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6E</cross-reference>. The lines <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> and contacts/vias <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> are then etched using reactive ion etching or other anisotropic etching techniques to define the metallization structure (i.e., the openings for the lines and contact/via) and expose the conductive feature <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6F</cross-reference>. Any photo resist or other material used to pattern and etch the second cap layer <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> is removed using an oxygen strip or other suitable process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Following etching of the deposited material and removal of photo resist materials, exposed portions of the second cap layer <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight>, the second dielectric layer <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>, the first cap layer <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>, the first dielectric layer <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, and the liner or barrier layer <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> may be treated with a reactive pre-clean process, as described above, to remove contaminants, particulate matter, residues, and oxides that may have formed on the exposed portions of the contact/via openings <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>, the line openings <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>, and the conductive feature <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The metallization structure is then formed with a conductive material such as aluminum, copper, tungsten or combinations thereof. Presently, the trend is to use copper to form the smaller features due to the low resistivity of copper (1.7 &OHgr;-cm compared to 5.1 &OHgr;-cm for aluminum). Preferably, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6G, a</cross-reference> conductive barrier layer <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> is first deposited conformably in the metallization pattern to prevent copper migration into the surrounding silicon and/or dielectric material. Barrier layers include titanium, titanium nitride, tantalum, tantalum nitride, and combinations thereof among other conventional barrier layer materials. Thereafter, copper <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> is deposited using either chemical vapor deposition, physical vapor deposition, electroplating, or combinations thereof to form the conductive structure. Once the structure has been filled with copper or other metal, the surface is planarized using chemical mechanical polishing as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The following examples illustrate the low dielectric films of the present invention. The films were deposited using a chemical vapor deposition chamber. In particular, the films were deposited using a &ldquo;CENTURA DxZ&rdquo; system. The system is fabricated and sold by Applied Materials, Inc. of Santa Clara, Calif. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> A low dielectric constant film was deposited on a substrate from the following reactive gases at a chamber pressure of 9 Torr and temperature of 350&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane (OMCTS), at 136 sccm (1800 mg/min); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Trimethylsilane (TMS), at 50 sccm; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Oxygen, at 50 sccm; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Helium, at 500 sccm </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The substrate was positioned 500 mm from the gas distribution showerhead. A power level of 1300 W at a frequency of 13.56 MHz was applied to the showerhead for plasma enhanced deposition of the film. The film was deposited at a rate of about 12,438 A/min, and had a dielectric constant (k) of about 2.65 measured at 0.1 MHz. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> A low dielectric constant film was deposited on a substrate from the following reactive gases at a chamber pressure of 9 Torr and temperature of 350&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane (OMCTS), at 136 sccm (1800 mg/min); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Trimethylsilane (TMS), at 150 sccm; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Oxygen, at 50 sccm; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Helium, at 500 sccm </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The substrate was positioned 500 mm from the gas distribution showerhead. A power level of 1300 W at a frequency of 13.56 MHz was applied to the showerhead for plasma enhanced deposition of the film. The film was deposited at a rate of about 9,940 A/min, and had a dielectric constant (k) of about 2.60 measured at 0.1 MHz. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 3 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> A low dielectric constant film was deposited on a substrate from the following reactive gases at a chamber pressure of 9 Torr and temperature of 350&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane (OMCTS), at 136 sccm (1800 mg/min); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Trimethylsilane (TMS), at 450 sccm; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Oxygen, at 50 sccm; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Helium, at 500 sccm </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The substrate was positioned 500 mm from the gas distribution showerhead. A power level of 1300 W at a frequency of 13.56 MHz was applied to the showerhead for plasma enhanced deposition of the film. The film was deposited at a rate of about 8,110 A/min, and had a dielectric constant (k) of about 2.56 measured at 0.1 MHz. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 4 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> A low dielectric constant film was deposited on a substrate from the following reactive gases at a chamber pressure of 9 Torr and temperature of 350&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane (OMCTS), at 136 sccm (1800 mg/min); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Trimethylsilane (TMS), at 350 sccm; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Oxygen, at 50 sccm; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Helium, at 500 sccm </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The substrate was positioned 500 mm from the gas distribution showerhead. A power level of 1300 W at a frequency of 13.56 MHz was applied to the showerhead for plasma enhanced deposition of the film. The film was deposited at a rate of about 7,495 A/min, and had a dielectric constant (k) of about 2.69 measured at 0.1 MHz. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 5 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> A low dielectric constant film was deposited on a substrate from the following reactive gases at a chamber pressure of 14 Torr and temperature of 350&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane (OMCTS), at 113 sccm (1500 mg/min); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Trimethylsilane (TMS), at 300 sccm; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Oxygen, at 300 sccm; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Helium, at 500 sccm </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> A power level of 800 W at a frequency of 13.56 MHz was applied to the showerhead for plasma enhanced deposition of the film. The deposited film had a dielectric constant (k) between about 2.45 and about 2.58 measured at 0.1 MHz. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Comparison Example 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> A low dielectric constant film was deposited on a substrate from the following reactive gases at a chamber pressure of 9 Torr and temperature of 350&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane (OMCTS), at 113 sccm (1500 mg/min); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Oxygen, at 300 sccm; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Helium, at 500 sccm </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> A power level of 800 W at a frequency of 13.56 MHz was applied to the showerhead for plasma enhanced deposition of the film. The deposited film had a dielectric constant (k) of about 2.68 measured at 0.1 MHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates the effect of varying the flow rate of TMS in Examples 1-5 described above. It was surprisingly found that the deposition rate and the dielectric constant decreased as the flow rate of TMS increased between about 50 sccm and less than about 350 sccm. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the dielectric constant increased at about 350 sccm of TMS, while the deposition rate decreased. The low dielectric constants were achieved with a ratio of cyclic organosilicon compound to aliphatic organosilicon compound ranging from about 1:4 to about 4:1. As illustrated with the comparative example 1 and shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the addition of a sufficient amount of the aliphatic organosilicon compound and oxygen to the cyclic organosilicon compound provided a dielectric constant at least 5% lower than a dielectric constant obtained by omitting the aliphatic organosilicon compound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> While the foregoing is directed to preferred embodiments of the present invention, other and further embodiments of the invention may be devised without departing from the basic scope thereof, and the scope thereof is determined by the claims which follow. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for depositing a low dielectric constant film on a semiconductor substrate, comprising reacting a cyclic organosilicon compound and an aliphatic organosilicon compound with an oxidizing gas at conditions sufficient to deposit a low dielectric constant film on the semiconductor substrate, wherein the low dielectric constant film comprises silicon-carbon bonds and a dielectric constant that is at least 5% less than a dielectric constant obtained by omitting the aliphatic organosilicon compound. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the low dielectric constant film has a carbon content from about 5 to about 30 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the low dielectric constant film has a carbon content from about 5 to about 20 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conditions comprise a power density ranging from about 0.3 W/cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to about 3.2 W/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conditions comprise a substrate temperature from about 170&deg; C. to about 450&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the dielectric constant is about 2.5 or less. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the aliphatic organosilicon compound comprises one or more alkoxy groups. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidizing gas is oxygen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound is 2,4,6,8-tetramethylcyclotetrasiloxane or octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane and the aliphatic organosilicon compound is trimethylsilane or 1,1 ,3,3-tetramethyidisiloxane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound comprises a silicon-hydrogen bond. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound is selected from the group consisting of 2,4,6,8-tetramethylcyclotetrasiloxane and octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane, and the aliphatic organosilicon compound is selected from the group consisting of methylsilane, dimethylsilane, trimethylsilane, 1,3-dimethyidisiloxane, dimethyidimethoxysiloxane, 1,1,3,3-tetramethyldisiloxane, and hexamethyldisiloxane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the low dielectric constant film is annealed at a substrate temperature from about 200&deg; C. to about 450&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method for depositing a low dielectric constant film on a semiconductor substrate, comprising reacting a cyclic organosilicon compound and an aliphatic organosilicon compound with an oxidizing gas at conditions sufficient to deposit a low dielectric constant film on the semiconductor substrate, wherein both the cyclic organosilicon compound and the aliphatic organosilicon compound comprise a silicon-hydrogen bond, and wherein the low dielectric constant film comprises silicon-carbon bonds and a dielectric constant that is at least 5% less than a dielectric constant obtained by omitting the aliphatic organosilicon compound. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound is octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane and the aliphatic organosilicon compound is trimethylsilane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conditions comprise a substrate temperature from about 170&deg; C. to about 450&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the dielectric film has a carbon content from about 5 to about 30 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the dielectric film has a carbon content from about 5 to about 20 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound is 2,4,6,8-tetramethylcyclotetrasiloxane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the aliphatic organosilicon compound is dimethydimethoxysiloxane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the aliphatic organosilicon compound is trimethylsilane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method for depositing a low dielectric constant film, comprising; 
<claim-text>flowing a cyclic organosilicon compound and an aliphatic organosilicon compound into a reaction zone as a volume ratio of between about 1:4 and about 4:1; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>reacting the cyclic organosilicon compound and the aliphatic organosilicon compound with an oxidizing gas while applying RF power to deposit a film having a dielectric constant of about 3 or less; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound comprises at least three silicon atoms and from one to two alkyl groups bonded to each silicon atom; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the aliphatic organosilicon compound comprises at least one silicon-hydrogen bond or at least one silicon-oxygen bond. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the low dielectric constant film has a carbon content from about 5 to 30 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conditions comprise a power density ranging from about 0.3 W/cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to about 3.2 W/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conditions comprise a substrate temperature from about 170&deg; C. to about 450&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the aliphatic organosilicon compound is trimethylsilane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidizing gas is oxygen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound is 2,4,6,8-tetramethylcyclotetrasiloxane or octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane and the aliphatic organosilicon compound is trimethylsilane or 1,1,3,3-tetramethyldisiloxane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cyclic organosilicon compound is selected from the group consisting of 2,4,6,8-tetramethylcyclotetrasiloxane and octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane, and the aliphatic organosilicon compound is selected from the group consisting of methylsilane, dimethylsilane, trimethylsilane, 1,3-dimethyldisiloxane, dimethyldimethoxysiloxane, 1,1,3,3-tetramethyldisiloxane, and hexamethyldisiloxane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the low dielectric constant film is annealed at a substrate temperature from about 200&deg; C. to about 450&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the low dielectric constant film has a carbon content from about 5 to about 20 atomic percent excluding hydrogen atoms.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003768A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003768A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003768A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003768A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003768A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003768A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
