<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000558A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000558A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000558</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10004794</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011207</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>01 2 37574.8</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010423</filing-date>
<country-code>CN</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>01 2 37609.4</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010425</filing-date>
<country-code>CN</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A45B001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A45B011/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A45B017/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A45B023/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A45B025/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A45B025/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A45B025/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>E04H015/40</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>015100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>020300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>022000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>135</class>
<subclass>127000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Automatic multiple-folding umbrella</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lung-Chiao</given-name>
<family-name>Chou</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ROSENBERG, KLEIN &amp; LEE</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>3458 ELLICOTT CENTER DRIVE-SUITE 101</address-1>
<city>ELLICOTT CITY</city>
<state>MD</state>
<postalcode>21043</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention provides a ratio mechanism of an automatic multiple-folding umbrella, cooperating to cooperating to the opening mechanism, and main stick assembly and said handle control mechanism; wherein said terminal pulley of said ratio mechanism has a pulley for threading said inner stay wire over so that one end of said inner stay wire is fixed on said pulley assembly, and the another end is threaded through said pulley on said terminal pulley base, and the pulley of said pulley assembly, then passing through said terminal pulley base to be fixed on said locking head; said main stick is composed of four stick segments. Due to building up said switch, repeat press down said button can bring into being automatic opening and closing umbrella function. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention is relative to an automatic multiple-folding umbrella in the umbrella field, and especially to a ratio mechanism of automatic opening umbrella. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> So far, in the umbrella industrial, the new products are brought to light weeding the old continuously, so that the automatic multiple-folding umbrellas are changed almost every day. According to the automatic multiple-folding umbrella we can find in the market, it typically is comprised of an opening mechanism and a main stick assembly, ratio mechanism and a handle control mechanism, wherein said main stick assembly includes a traction spring and three nested stick segments, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; said ratio mechanism <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; is comprised of an outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> an inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, a pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>&prime;, a terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime;, a locking head <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; and a sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;, therein one end <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>&prime; of said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; is fixed on the low strut nest (un-drawn in drawings), and the another end <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>&prime; is fixed on the top end <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>&prime; of said pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>&prime;, and one end <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>&prime; of said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; threading over the pulley <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>&prime; of said pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>&prime; is fixed on the top end of said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime; with one end, and the another end <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>&prime; is led through said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime; to be fixed on said locking head <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime;; said parts like said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, said pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>&prime; and said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime; are mounted into the hollow inside of said sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;, wherein said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime; is located on the bottom end of said sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, by the ratio relation between said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; and said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; . . . 2:1 proportion of folding said three stick segments, when opening the umbrella, said sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; is rapidly ejected by said traction spring to stretch out said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> about two stick-segment length, meanwhile said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; is just drew in one stick-segment length; contrarily, it is a closing umbrella operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> According to above description, said ratio mechanism just adapts to the three stick-segment automatic umbrella, but not to four stick-segment one because the ratio relation between said inner and outer stay wires cannot bring to pass. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS AND SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The key object of the present invention is to provide a ratio mechanism suiting to open and close a four stick-segment automatic umbrella. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> For archiving above-mentioned object, the present invention provides a ratio mechanism for opening and closing a multiple-folding umbrella, cooperating to the opening mechanism, comprised of upper and low strut nests and strut fids, and main stick assembly and said handle control mechanism; said ratio mechanism is comprised of an outer stay wire, an inner stay wire, a pulley assembly, a terminal pulley base, a locking head and a sleeve, wherein one end of said outer stay wire is fixed on one end of said pulley assembly, and the another end is fixed on said low strut nest of said opening mechanism; and said inner stay wire, said pulley assembly and said terminal pulley base are mounted into the hollow inside of said sleeve, therein said terminal pulley base is located on the bottom end of said sleeve; the feature of the present invention is that said terminal pulley of said ratio mechanism has a pulley for threading said inner stay wire over so that one end of said inner stay wire is fixed on said pulley assembly, and the another end is threaded through said pulley on said terminal pulley base, and the pulley of said pulley assembly, then passing through said terminal pulley base to be fixed on said locking head; said main stick is composed of four stick segments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Said handle control mechanism of said ratio mechanism for opening and closing umbrella automatically is comprised of a handle base, a button component and a handle shell, wherein said handle base has a base hole at the center axially for holding said main stick in, a flange at the topside and an adjacent case at the bottom side of said flange for containing said button, a restoring strip and a lever hung on at the openings on the both open sides by a dowel pin separately, and a spring located on the bottom side of said restoring strip, and a slot for containing a cramp below next said restoring strip, said cramp connected with a spring with one end located on said handle base cooperating to a stopper, and touching against said lever with another end; said button assembly is comprised of a button and a switch connected together with a dowel pin, and a spring located between said button and said switch, wherein said switch has a central hollow space for containing a portion of said main stick and the low strut nest of said opening mechanism, said button covers on said restoring strip and said switch, and mounted at said case of said handle base; said low strut nest of said opening mechanism has a snap slot coordinating to said switch; said handle shell is a shell nesting over said handle base with a U-shape slot for holding said button. Said cramp is a flat frame with a lug extending inward; said switch has a tilt coordinating to said low strut nest of said opening mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In said ratio mechanism of automatic opening and closing umbrella, said low strut nest of said opening mechanism has a track-way at the outside wall holding on a restoring spring covered on top end by a sliding disk. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Applying above-mentioned structure, due to adding a pulley on said terminal pulley base in said ratio mechanism of the present invention, said inner wire threads through two pulleys sequentially in said sleeve so as to come into being <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>:<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> ratio relation between said inner stay wire and said outer stay wire to make a four stick-segment automatic umbrella come true, additionally due to increasing the movement of said traction spring, the power of opening umbrella is increased too; on the other hand, due to setting upon said switch of handle control mechanism, cooperating to said button backing up with said restoring spring, press down said button with finger to make switch release said low strut nest to bring into being automatic opening umbrella function; by said restoring spring, said switch is contacted with said lever, when pressing down said button again, make said cramp release the locked locking head to bring into being automatic closing umbrella finction. Therefore, by repeating to press down said button, the present invention carries out automatic opening and closing umbrella functions conveniently and simply. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the prior art (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the prior art (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing the combination of the ratio mechanism of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an enlarged solid view showing the terminal pulley base of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an exploded view showing the handle control mechanism of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-section view showing closing state of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross-section view showing opening state of the present invention (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-section view showing opening state of the present invention (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cross-section view showing closing state of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a part solid view showing the main stick assembly of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an exploded view showing the opening mechanism of another embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the present invention cooperates to an opening mechanism B, a main stick assembly C and a handle control mechanism D, wherein said opening mechanism B is comprised of an upper strut nest B <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and proper number of strut fids (undrawn in drawings). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> in following, a ratio mechanism provided in the present invention, as the same as the conventional products, is comprised of an outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, an inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a locking head <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and a sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, wherein one end <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> of said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is fixed on the top end <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> of said pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the another end <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is fixed on the low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of said opening mechanism B (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>), co-referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the key feature of the present invention is that said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is attached on the topside with a pulley <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>, and has a through-hole <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> at the bottom portion for passing through said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>; said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is fixed on said pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> with one end <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, the another end <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is threaded downward over said pulley <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> of said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, then upward through said pulley <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> of said pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, next downward again to pass through said through-hole <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to be fixed on said locking head <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>; these parts like said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, said pulley assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are located into the inside of said sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is retained on the bottom end of said sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Said main stick assembly C is comprised of a traction spring <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and four nested stick segments (referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, said handle control mechanism D is typically comprised of a handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a button <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and a handle shell <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Said handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> has a base hole <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> at the center axially for holding said main stick C in, a flange <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> at the topside and an adjacent case <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> at the bottom side of said flange <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for containing said button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, a restoring strip <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and a lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> hung on at the openings on the both open sides by a dowel pin X separately, and a spring <highlight><bold>341</bold></highlight> located on the bottom side of said restoring strip <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and a slot <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> for containing a cramp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> below next said restoring strip <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, said cramp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is a flat frame with a lug <highlight><bold>361</bold></highlight> extending inward, and is connected to a spring <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> located on said handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> with one end cooperating to a stopper <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, and touching against said lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> with another end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Said button assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is comprised of a button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and a switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> connected together with a dowel pin X, and a spring <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> located between said button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for restoring, wherein said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has a central hollow space <highlight><bold>421</bold></highlight> for containing a portion of said main stick C and the low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of said opening mechanism B, said button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> covers on said restoring strip <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and mounted at said case <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of said handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>; said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of said opening mechanism B has a snap slot B<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> coordinating to said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>); for good looking, said upper strut nest B <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> extends a shield B <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> upward to cover an exposed pulley (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>); said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has a tilt <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> coordinating to said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of said opening mechanism B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Said handle shell <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is a shell nesting over said handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> with a U-shape slot <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> for holding said button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In combination, referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, firstly locate said restoring spring <highlight><bold>341</bold></highlight>, said restoring strip <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and said lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> on said handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in pivoting joint with said dowel pins X separately and sequentially; next place said button assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in said handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>; then secure said main stick assembly C on said handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> with said dowel pin X, meanwhile slide said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of said opening mechanism B downward into said base hole <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of said handle base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> until it is locked by said tilt <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> of said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> catching into said snap slot B<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, additionally, said locking head <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of said ratio mechanism A is locked by said lug <highlight><bold>361</bold></highlight> of said cramp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Because said traction spring <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> on said main stick assembly C is in compressed state, under the elastic restoring force, said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> tends to jump up so as to make said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> touch against said flange <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> tightly, at the same time, said restoring spring <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> of said button assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is in compressed state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> When the present invention is used in opening umbrella, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, press down said button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to push said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to move rightward simultaneously so as to release said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, by restoring up said traction spring <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> along main stick <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of said main stick assembly C, said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is pushed upward to open the umbrella; said four stick segments <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are in extending state, because said locking head <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is locked by said cramp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of said handle control mechanism D, as said sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is driven to make an upward movement by said traction spring <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> threading over two pulleys <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> is dragged out from said terminal pulley base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> about three stick-segment length, meanwhile said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is drawn into said sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> one stick-segment length to come into being <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>:<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> ratio relation between said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to meet the necessary of four stick-fold umbrella. At this time, the restoring spring <highlight><bold>341</bold></highlight> of said handle control mechanism D is in compressed state, under the restoring force, said restoring spring <highlight><bold>341</bold></highlight> pushes said restoring strip <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> turning an angle so that said button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is moved to the original position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> When the present invention is used in closing umbrella, in this time said button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> has resumed into the original state, but because said restoring spring <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> has released so that said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is pushed to touch against said lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> by said restoring spring <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>; as closing the umbrella, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, press down said button <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to push said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> rightward, further to turn said lever <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> an angle so that said cramp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is moved leftward to withdraw said lug <highlight><bold>361</bold></highlight> from said locked locking head <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to free it, said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is stretched out rapidly from said ratio mechanism A, the umbrella is closed under the restoring force of said restoring spring in said opening mechanism B, then by the advantage of the hand force of the user, slide said handle control mechanism D downward to make said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of said opening mechanism B take in place so as to lock said snap slot B<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> on said tilt <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> of said switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to finish the closing process, then co-referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> again, said four stick segments <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are in folding state, said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is stretched out from said main stick <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> one stick-segment length along the outer side wall under the drive of said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of said opening mechanism B, but said inner stay wire <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> threading over two pulleys <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> just is stretched one stick-segment length to the inside of said sleeve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Due to applying said <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>:<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> ratio relation in the present invention, the movement of said traction spring is increased, so that the power of opening umbrella is enlarged too. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, said low strut nest B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of said opening mechanism B has a track-way B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> at the outside wall holding on a restoring spring B<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> covered on top end by a sliding disk B<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> fastened with the outer end of said stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of said ratio mechanism A. Because said outer stay wire <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can drive said sliding disk B<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to slide on the track-way B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> with one end <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, by the advantage of the length of said track-way B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the ratio relation of said ratio mechanism A can be increased such as more than <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>:<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, said handle control mechanism D in the present invention can adapt itself to a three stick-segment or a five stick-segment automatic umbrella. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A ratio mechanism of an automatic multiple-folding umbrella, cooperating to cooperating to the opening mechanism, comprised of upper and low strut nests and strut fids, and main stick assembly and said handle control mechanism; said ratio mechanism is comprised of an outer stay wire, an inner stay wire, a pulley assembly, a terminal pulley base, a locking head and a sleeve, wherein one end of said outer stay wire is fixed on one end of said pulley assembly, and the another end is fixed on said low strut nest of said opening mechanism; and said inner stay wire, said pulley assembly and said terminal pulley base are mounted into the hollow inside of said sleeve, therein said terminal pulley base is located on the bottom end of said sleeve; the feature of the present invention is that said terminal pulley of said ratio mechanism has a pulley for threading said inner stay wire over so that one end of said inner stay wire is fixed on said pulley assembly, and the another end is threaded through said pulley on said terminal pulley base, and the pulley of said pulley assembly, then passing through said terminal pulley base to be fixed on said locking head; said main stick is composed of four stick segments. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A ratio mechanism of an automatic multiple-folding umbrella as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said handle control mechanism is comprised of a handle base, a button component and a handle shell, wherein said handle base has a base hole at the center axially for holding said main stick in, a flange at the topside and an adjacent case at the bottom side of said flange for containing said button, a restoring strip and a lever hung on at the openings on the both open sides by a dowel pin separately, and a spring located on the bottom side of said restoring strip, and a slot for containing a cramp below next said restoring strip, said cramp connected with a spring with one end located on said handle base cooperating to a stopper, and touching against said lever with another end; said button assembly is comprised of a button and a switch connected together with a dowel pin, and a spring located between said button and said switch, wherein said switch has a central hollow space for containing a portion of said main stick and the low strut nest of said opening mechanism, said button covers on said restoring strip and said switch, and mounted at said case of said handle base; said low strut nest of said opening mechanism has a snap slot coordinating to said switch; said handle shell is a shell nesting over said handle base with a Ushape slot for holding said button. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A ratio mechanism of an automatic multiple-folding umbrella as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, said cramp is a flat frame with a lug extending inward at the inside. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A ratio mechanism of an automatic multiple-folding umbrella as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said switch has a tilt coordinating to said low strut nest of said opening mechanism. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A ratio mechanism of an automatic multiple-folding umbrella as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said low strut nest of said opening mechanism has a track-way at the outside wall holding on a restoring spring covered on top end by a sliding disk fastened with the outer end of said stay wire of said ratio mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030000558A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
