<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000721A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000721A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000721A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000721A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000721A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000721A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000721A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000721A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000721A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000721A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000721</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10180166</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020626</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05K007/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>174</class>
<subclass>050000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Thermal management system and method for electronics system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301224</doc-number>
<document-date>20010627</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Scott</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Garner</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lititz</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Samuel W. Apicelli</name-1>
<name-2>Duane Morris LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 1003</address-1>
<city>Harrisburg</city>
<state>PA</state>
<postalcode>17108-1003</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A thermal energy management system is provided having a heat spreading device that is operatively engaged with at least one semiconductor chip and a thermal bus operatively engaged with the heat spreading device so as to transport thermal energy from the heat spreading device to a heat sink. The heat spreading device includes a heat pipe and the thermal bus includes a loop thermosyphon. A second thermal bus may be operatively engaged with the first thermal bus so as to transport thermal energy from the first thermal bus to a heat sink. The second thermal bus may also include a loop thermosyphon. A method of managing thermal energy in an electronic system is also provided that includes spreading thermal energy generated by one or more devices over a surface that is relatively larger than the devices, thermally coupling an evaporator portion of a loop thermosyphon to the surface, and thermally coupling a condensing portion of the loop thermosyphon to a thermal energy sink, e.g., a second loop thermosyphon, convection fin, or cold plate. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority from copending Provisional Patent Application Serial No. 60/301,224, filed Jun. 27, 2001, and entitled Loop Thermosyphons And Their Applications To High Density.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to the management of thermal energy generated by electronic systems, and more particularly to a packaging scheme for efficiently and cost effectively routing and controlling the thermal energy generated by various components of an electronic system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The electronics industry, following Moore&apos;s Law, has seemed to be able to defy the laws of economics by providing ever increasing computing power at less cost. However, the industry has not been able to suspend the laws of physics inasmuch as high computing performance has been accompanied by increased heat generation. Board level heat dissipation has advanced to a point that several years ago was only seen at the system level. The trend toward ever increasing heat dissipation in microprocessor and amplifier based systems, such as are housed in telecommunication and server port cabinets, is becoming increasingly critical to the electronics industry. In the foreseeable future, finding effective thermal solutions will become a major constraint for the reduction of system cost and time-to-market, two governing factors between success and failure in commercial electronics sales. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The problems caused by the increasing heat dissipation are further compounded by the industry trend toward system miniaturization&mdash;one of the main methodologies of the electronics industry to satisfy the increasing market demand for faster, smaller, lighter and cheaper electronic devices. The result of this miniaturization is increasing heat fluxes. For example, metal oxide semiconductor-controlled thyristors may generate heat fluxes from 100 to 200W/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, some high voltage power electronics for military applications may generate heat fluxes of 300W/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, while some laser diode applications require removal of 500W/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. Also, non-uniform heat flux distribution in electronics may result in peak heat fluxes in excess of five times the average heat flux over the entire semiconductor chip surface (&tilde;30W/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Thus, as clock speeds for integrated circuits increase, package temperatures will be required to correspondingly decrease to achieve lower junction temperatures. However, increasing package temperatures will result from the increase in heat dissipation in the package from higher clock speed devices. This increase in temperature will cascade throughout the interior of the structure that encloses or houses such circuits, (e.g. a typical telecommunications or server port cabinets, or the like) as the number of high power semiconductor components positioned within the housing increases. The difference between these physical aspects (i.e., the difference between the interior cabinet temperature and the package temperature) of the electronic system defines a &ldquo;thermal budget&rdquo; that is available for the design of the cooling devices/systems needed to manage the heat fluxes generated by the various electronic devices in the system. As these two conflicting parameters converge, the available thermal budget shrinks. When the thermal budget approaches zero, refrigeration systems become necessary to provide the requisite cooling of the electronic system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is well known to those skilled in the art that thermal resistances (often referred to as &ldquo;delta-T&rdquo;) for typical thermal systems at the semiconductor junction-to-package, package-to-sink and sink-to-air levels have been trending up over the past decade. The lack of understanding of micro-scale heat transfer physics, the requirement of matching the coefficients of thermal expansion (C.T.E.&apos;S) of a semiconductor chip and the thermal energy spreading materials, and the potential adverse effect on conventional packaging practices of integrating heat transfer mechanisms into packages, have largely limited the choice of cooling/spreading techniques at the semiconductor chip and semiconductor package levels to heat conduction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Extensive efforts in the areas of heat sink optimization (including the use of heat pipes) and interface materials development in the past have resulted in the significant reduction of sink-to-air and package-to-sink thermal resistances. However, the reduction of these two thermal resistances has now begun to approach the physical and thermodynamic limitations of the materials. On the other hand, the junction-to-package thermal resistance (delta-T) has increased recently, due to the increasing magnitude and non-uniformity (localization) of the heat generation and dissipation from the semiconductor package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Successful cooling technologies must deal with thermal issues at the device, device cluster, printed wiring board, subassembly, and cabinet or rack levels, all of which are within the original equipment manufacturer&apos;s (OEM&apos;s) products. Many times, the problem is further complicated by the fact that the thermal solution is an &ldquo;after thought&rdquo; for the OEM. A new equipment design may utilize the latest software or implement the fastest new semiconductor technology, but the thermal management architecture is generally relegated to the &ldquo;later phases&rdquo; of the new product design. The thermal management issues associated with a designed electronic system are often solved by the expedient of a secondary cooling or refrigeration system that is arranged in tandem with the electronics system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> There are several negatives associated with the use of tandem cooling or refrigeration systems. The additional electrical power required by such systems not only increases the cost to operate the electronic equipment, but also causes an adverse environmental impact in the form of pollution (from power generation processes) and noise. Reliability issues are also of considerable concern with refrigeration systems. In addition, such add-on thermal management solutions can make after market servicing very difficult and expensive. There is a need for a thermal management system that can be easily disassembled from the underlying electronic system, in the field, to facilitate servicing of the components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> There is a compound challenge in the art to provide a thermal management architecture that satisfactorily accumulates and transfers variable amounts of thermal energy, generated by a wide variety of electronic components arranged together in an enclosed space, while avoiding or minimizing the use of non-passive, tandem cooling or refrigeration systems for cooling. As a consequence, there is also a need in the art for a cost effective, integral thermal management architecture for high power electronic systems and that is easily removed during servicing. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a thermal energy management system comprising a heat spreading device that is operatively engaged with at least one semiconductor chip. A thermal bus is operatively engaged with the heat spreading device so as to transport thermal energy from the heat spreading device to a heat sink. In one preferred embodiment, the heat spreading device comprises a heat pipe and a thermal bus is provided that comprises a loop thermosyphon. In another embodiment of the invention, a second thermal bus is operatively engaged with the first thermal bus so as to transport thermal energy from the first thermal bus to a heat sink. The second thermal bus may also comprise a loop thermosyphon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A method of managing thermal energy in an electronic system is provided that includes spreading thermal energy generated by one or more devices over a surface that is relatively larger than the devices, thermally coupling an evaporator portion of a loop thermosyphon to the surface, and thermally coupling a condensing portion of the loop thermosyphon to a thermal energy sink, e.g., a second loop thermosyphon, convection fin, or cold plate.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> These and other features and advantages of the present invention will be more fully disclosed in, or rendered obvious by, the following detailed description of the preferred embodiment of the invention, which is to be considered together with the accompanying drawings wherein like numbers refer to like parts and further wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view, partially in phantom, of a typical electronics system including a thermal management system formed in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a typical electronics subsystem incorporating the thermal management system of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective, broken-away view of a portion of the electronics subsystem shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view, as taken along line <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, of a thermal bus, evaporator plate, heat pipe, and heat generating electronic component; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view, as taken along line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, of a thermal bus to thermal bus interface.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> This description of preferred embodiments is intended to be read in connection with the accompanying drawings, which are to be considered part of the entire written description of this invention. The drawing figures are not necessarily to scale and certain features of the invention may be shown exaggerated in scale or in somewhat schematic form in the interest of clarity and conciseness. In the description, relative terms such as &ldquo;horizontal,&rdquo; &ldquo;vertical,&rdquo; &ldquo;up,&rdquo; &ldquo;down,&rdquo; &ldquo;top&rdquo; and &ldquo;bottom&rdquo; as well as derivatives thereof (e.g., &ldquo;horizontally,&rdquo; &ldquo;downwardly,&rdquo; &ldquo;upwardly,&rdquo; etc.) should be construed to refer to the orientation as then described or as shown in the drawing figure under discussion. These relative terms are for convenience of description and normally are not intended to require a particular orientation. Terms including &ldquo;inwardly&rdquo; versus &ldquo;outwardly,&rdquo; &ldquo;longitudinal&rdquo; versus &ldquo;lateral&rdquo; and the like are to be interpreted relative to one another or relative to an axis of elongation, or an axis or center of rotation, as appropriate. Terms concerning attachments, coupling and the like, such as &ldquo;connected&rdquo; and &ldquo;interconnected,&rdquo; refer to a relationship wherein structures are secured or attached to one another either directly or indirectly through intervening structures, as well as both movable or rigid attachments or relationships, unless expressly described otherwise. The term &ldquo;operatively connected&rdquo; is such an attachment, coupling or connection that allows the pertinent structures to operate as intended by virtue of that relationship. In the claims, means-plus-function clauses are intended to cover the structures described, suggested, or rendered obvious by the written description or drawings for performing the recited function, including not only structural equivalents but also equivalent structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the present invention provides a thermal energy management system <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> that may be implemented in a functioning system of electronic components and/or subsystems e.g., a 1-U server <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Thermal energy management system <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> generally comprises a hierarchical scheme of thermal management components that are operatively engaged with individual heat generating components or groups of such components that form server <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Advantageously, the thermal management components are substantially only thermally driven, i.e., passive heat transfer devices that have no moving parts and require no external power for their operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, thermal energy management system <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> comprises a planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> arranged in thermal communication with a thermal bus <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for transporting thermal energy away from individual heat generating devices <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> as well as, clusters of such devices within the electronic system. More particularly, planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is sized and shaped so as to spread the thermal energy generated by at least one semiconductor device <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> that is arranged in intimate thermal engagement with planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> within server <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Often, one or more semiconductor devices <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> e.g., microprocessors, voltage regulators, power supplies, etc., are mounted within the same region of the electronics system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprises a vapor chamber <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> that is defined between a top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and a bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, and extends transversely and longitudinally throughout planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> comprise substantially uniform thickness sheets of a thermally conductive material, and are spaced-apart by about 2.0 (mm) to about 4.0 (mm) so as to form the void space within heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> that defines vapor chamber <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> preferably comprises a substantially planer inner surface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is also substantially planar, and comprises an integrally formed layer of wicking material, or wick <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, sintered copper powder or felt metal wick structure, having an average thickness of about 0.5 mm to 2.0 mm is positioned over substantially all of the inner surface of bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> so as to form wick <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. Of course, other wick materials, such as, aluminum-silicon-carbide or copper-silicon-carbide may be used with equal effect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Vapor chamber <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is created by the attachment of top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, along their common edges which are then hermetically sealed at their joining interface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A two-phase vaporizable liquid (e.g., ammonia or freon not shown) resides within vapor chamber <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and serves as the working fluid for planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is formed by drawing a partial vacuum within vapor chamber <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and injecting the working fluid just prior to final hermetic sealing of the common edges of top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. For example, planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (including top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) may be made of copper or copper-silicon-carbide with water, ammonia, or freon generally chosen as the two-phase vaporizable liquid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, thermal bus <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> comprises a loop-thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> that is thermally engaged with planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> so as to bus thermal energy from planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to a thermal energy sink or heat sink <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, e.g., a cold plate or convection cooled fin stack. In the context of the present invention, terms such as &ldquo;bus, buses, or busing&rdquo; mean to transport or otherwise transfer thermal energy in a directed manner from one location to another location, e.g., from a high heat flux portion to a lower heat flux portion of a rack/chassis assembly <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> that structurally supports a plurality of servers <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> comprises a closed tube <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> that is formed from a substantially uniform thickness, thermally conductive material (e.g., copper, aluminum, or the like) having a continuous internal passageway <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. At least an evaporator portion <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of tube <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes an integrally formed wicking layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of sintered copper powder or metal felt, having an average thickness of about 0.5 mm to 2.0 mm. Wicking layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is continuously disposed over substantially all of the inner surface of tube <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> at evaporator portion <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. A condensing portion <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of tube <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is positioned in spaced away relation to evaporator portion <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, and often arranged in intimate thermal contact with a wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of a support chassis <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of server <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is maintained in position within server <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> by means of simple fasteners, e.g., screws and brackets, so that it may be disassembled from the underlying electronic system and components so that they may be serviced without need for time consuming and error prone reassembly of the system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> A two-phase vaporizable liquid (e.g., ammonia, water, freon or the like, not shown) resides within passageway <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> of loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and serves as the working fluid. Loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> may be formed by drawing a partial vacuum within tube <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and injecting the working fluid just prior to final hermetic sealing of the tube. Condensing portion <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of tube <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may or may not include an integrally formed wicking layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The evaporator portions <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of one or more additional loop-thermosyphons <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> may be located on the outer surface <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> of wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> so as to (i) receive thermal energy from condensing portion <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of loop-thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, via thermal conduction through wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, and (ii) bus that thermal energy to other lower heat flux regions of a rack/chassis assembly <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is also maintained in position within on chassis <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> by means of simple fasteners, e.g., screws and brackets, so that it may be quickly disassembled from the underlying electronic system and chassis for servicing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Evaporator plates <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> provide a physical and thermal interface between top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and evaporator portion <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of loop-thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and between wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and evaporator portion <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of loop-thermosyphon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. More particularly, evaporator plate <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is formed from a substantially uniform thickness sheet of a thermally conductive material, and is preferably substantially planar. It is sized and shaped to cover a portion of top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of planar heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, or the portion of wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> adjacent to evaporator portions <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of loop-thermosyphon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The outer surface of bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> may be either permanently bonded to heat generating devices <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, or a thermal grease or other heat transfer material may be disposed at the thermal interface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> between evaporator <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and heat generating devices <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. At least two grooves <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> are formed in a top surface <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of evaporator plate <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> so as to receive and cradle evaporator portion <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of loop-thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, or evaporator portion <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of loop-thermosyphon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. A thermal grease or other heat transfer material may be diposed at the thermal busing interface <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> between evaporator portion <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of loop-thermosyphon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and condensing portion <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. A mechanical locking mechanism <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> may also be employed to help force evaporator plate <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> into intimate thermal engagement and communication with wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> so as to enhance heat transfer across this thermo-mechanical interface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In one example, thermal management system and method <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the present invention was used for cooling four McKinley processors in a 1-U rack mount system. Four McKinley processors <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and four associated power supplies <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in a 1-U rack mount system with forty-two systems per rack. Each processor generates one hundred and thirty watts of thermal energy, each power supply generates forty-five watts, each central processing unit generates one hundred and seventy-five watts, so that each server yields about seven hundred watts of thermal energy, with a total power output for the rack equal to about twenty-nine thousand four hundred watts. The allowable thermal resistance is based upon a T<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>max equal to about eighty-five degrees centigrade. Assuming an allowable ambient temperature of thirty-five degrees centigrade, the rate of power generation from the overall system, that is allowable to remain within specifications, is about 0.38 watts per degree centigrade. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the thermal busing path from server <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to heat sink <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> starts at first thermal interface <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> between the case or package containing the first McKinley processor <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). In this embodiment of the invention, heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> extends across both the McKinley processor <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and its associated power supply pod <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> so as to spread thermal energy over an area larger than the area of at least one of these heat generating components, i.e., heat pipe heat spreader <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> preferably comprises a larger area than processor <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and its associated power supply pod <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Heat is transferred across first thermal interface <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> to bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, through vapor chamber <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, to top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is often permanently attached to at least processor <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> by e.g., solder or brazing, such that first thermal interface <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> permanently attaches processor <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to the outer surface of bottom wall <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A second thermal interface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is provided between the bottom surface of evaporator <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and the outer surface of top wall <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A thermal grease or other heat transfer material may be disposed at thermal interface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. This arrangement of heat pipes <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and evaporator plates <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is duplicated across all four McKinley processors <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and associated power supplies <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the 1-U rack mount system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Evaporator portion <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of flexible loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is then assembled to each evaporator plate <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> via placing tube <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> into grooves <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> on top surfaces <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. Flexible loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is maintained in place on evaporators <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> by means of simple fasteners that are easily removed for servicing. The heat transferred from heat pipes <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> actually creates a series of multiple evaporator portions <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> along the length of flexible loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. This interface between heat pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and flexible loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is thus a detachable thermal joint so as to allow for the replacement of processor <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and power supply module <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Flexible loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> transfers all the heat generated by the four McKinley processors <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and four associated power supplies <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to side wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of the 1-U server <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which provides lower thermal flux region for condenser portion <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of flexible loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Since server chassis&apos; <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> need to be removable, a third thermal interface <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> is provided between wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and an evaporator plate <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> that is cradling evaporator portion <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). This interface is often enhanced by use of a cam-type mechanical locking mechanism <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> that aids in forcing evaporator plate <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> into intimate thermal engagement and communication with wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> so as to enhance heat transfer across this thermo-mechanical interface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In this way, loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> transfers the heat to the top of rack <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> where it can be dissipated to a large air-cooled heat sink <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, or coupled to a re-circulated water or refrigeration cooled heat sink. For clarity of illustration, the details of the condenser integration are not shown in the various figures, however, a simple tube-in-fin type heat exchanger could easily be integrated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In this example, the use of thermal management system and method <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> yielded an overall system temperature rise is 21.6 degrees C., which corresponds to a thermal resistance of 0.166 degrees C./watt based on the 130 watts processor power. Assuming a 50 degrees C. allowable case to ambient temperature rise leaves 28.4 degrees C. available to dissipate the transferred heat from the condenser of loop thermosyphon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to the ambient air. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Advantages of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Numerous advantages are obtained by employing the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> More specifically, a thermal energy management system comprising a hierarchical scheme of thermal management components that are operatively engaged with individual components or groups of components that form an electronic system is provided which avoids all of the aforementioned problems associated with prior art systems for managing thermal energy generated by electronic systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In addition, a thermal energy management system is provided that incorporates discrete heat spreading technologies at the semiconductor device and semiconductor device package that enables the package temperature to increase without overheating at the junction level while incorporating a thermal bus for transporting or otherwise transferring thermal energy in a directed manner from one location to another location, e.g., from the high heat flux portion of a semiconductor to a lower heat flux portion of an external heat sink. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Also, a thermal energy management system is provided that is easily disassembled from the underlying electronic system and components so that they may be serviced without need for time consuming and error prone reassembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that the present invention is by no means limited only to the particular constructions herein disclosed and shown in the drawings, but also comprises any modifications or equivalents within the scope of the claims </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system comprising: 
<claim-text>a heat spreading device that is operatively engaged with at least one heat generating component; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a thermal bus that is operatively engaged with said heat spreading device so as to transport thermal energy from said heat spreading device to a heat sink. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said heat spreading device comprises a heat pipe and said thermal bus comprises a loop thermosyphon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> including a second thermal bus that is operatively engaged with said first thermal bus so as to transport thermal energy from said first thermal bus to a heat sink. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said second thermal bus comprises a loop thermosyphon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said heat spreading device comprises a planar heat pipe arranged in thermal communication with said thermal bus so as to transport thermal energy away from said at least one heat generating component wherein said planar heat pipe is sized and shaped so as to spread thermal energy over an area larger than the area of said at least one heat generating component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said heat spreading device comprises a planar heat pipe including a vapor chamber that is defined between a top wall formed from a substantially uniform thickness sheet of a thermally conductive material and a bottom wall comprises a substantially uniform thickness sheet of a thermally conductive material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said top wall and said bottom wall are spaced-apart by about 2.0 (mm) to about 4.0 (mm) so as to form a void space within said heat pipe that defines a vapor chamber, and further wherein said top wall comprises a substantially planer inner surface and said bottom wall comprises a substantially planar surface having an integrally formed wick. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said wick comprises is formed from a material selected from the group consisting of sintered copper powder, aluminum-silicon-carbide, or copper-silicon-carbide, and metal felt having an average thickness of about 0.5 mm to 2.0 mm and that is positioned over substantially all of said inner surface of said bottom wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said thermal bus comprises at least one loop-thermosyphon that is thermally engaged with said heat spreading device so as to bus thermal energy to a thermal energy sink. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said thermal bus comprises a loop thermosyphon formed from a closed tube having a continuous internal passageway and at least an evaporator portion including an integrally formed wicking layer disposed on the surface of said tube that defines said internal passageway adjacent to said evaporator portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said wicking layer comprises sintered copper powder having an average thickness of about 0.5 mm to 2.0 mm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said loop thermosyphon comprises a condensing portion positioned in spaced away relation to an evaporator portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a portion of said thermal bus is arranged in intimate thermal contact with a wall of a support chassis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said thermal bus is maintained in position by a simple fastening system so that it may be disassembled from an underlying electronic system and components. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a second thermal bus positioned adjacent to a condensing portion of said thermal bus. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said second thermal bus comprises an evaporator portion located on an outer surface of a wall of a chassis that supports said at least one heat generating component so as to (i) receive thermal energy from a condensing portion of said thermal bus, and (ii) bus said thermal energy to a lower heat flux region of said chassis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system comprising: 
<claim-text>a heat pipe heat spreader that is thermally engaged with at least one heat generating component; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an evaporator plate positioned between a portion of said heat pipe heat spreader and an evaporation portion of a loop thermosyphon so as to transport thermal energy from said heat pipe heat spreader to a heat sink. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said evaporator plate provides a physical and thermal interface between a top wall of said heat pipe heat spreader and said evaporator portion of said loop-thermosyphon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said evaporator plate is formed from a substantially uniform thickness sheet of a thermally conductive material that is sized and shaped to cover a portion of said top wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one groove is formed in a top surface of said evaporator plate so as to receive and cradle said evaporator portion of said loop-thermosyphon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system comprising: 
<claim-text>a heat pipe heat spreader that is operatively engaged with at least one heat generating component; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an evaporator plate positioned between a portion of said heat pipe heat spreader and an evaporation portion of a first loop thermosyphon so as to transport thermal energy from said heat pipe heat spreader to a heat sink; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second evaporator plate positioned between a condensing portion of said first loop thermosyphon and an evaporator portion of a second loop thermosyphon. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a wall of a chassis that supports said at least one heat generating component is located between said second evaporator plate and said condensing portion of said first loop thermosyphon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A thermal energy management system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a locking mechanism for forcing said second evaporator plate into intimate thermal engagement and communication with said wall <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A method of managing thermal energy in an electronic system comprising: 
<claim-text>spreading thermal energy generated by one or more devices over a surface that is relatively larger than said devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>thermally coupling an evaporator portion of a loop thermosyphon to said surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>thermally coupling a condensing portion of said loop thermosyphon to a thermal energy sink. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A method of managing thermal energy in an electronic system comprising: 
<claim-text>spreading thermal energy generated by one or more devices over a surface that is relatively larger than said devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>thermally coupling an evaporator portion of a loop thermosyphon to said surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>thermally coupling a condensing portion of said loop thermosyphon to an evaporator portion of a second loop thermosyphon.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000721A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000721A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000721A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000721A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000721A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
