<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002770A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002770A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002770A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002770A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002770A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002770A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002770</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10158250</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020530</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B006/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>014000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Flip-chip package integrating optical and electrical devices and coupling to a waveguide on a board</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10158250</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020530</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09892921</doc-number>
<document-date>20010626</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kishore</given-name>
<middle-name>K.</middle-name>
<family-name>Chakravorty</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Johanna</given-name>
<family-name>Swan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Scottsdale</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Brandon</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Barnett</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Beaverton</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Joseph</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Ahadian</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Carlsbad</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Thomas</given-name>
<middle-name>P.</middle-name>
<family-name>Thomas</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Beaverton</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ian</given-name>
<family-name>Young</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Pillsbury Winthrop LLP</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Group</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 2800</address-1>
<address-2>725 South Figueroa Street</address-2>
<city>Los Angeles</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90017-5406</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A package allowing both electrical and optical coupling between one or more integrated circuits and a printed circuit board (PCB) has optical waveguide structures in addition to electrical connections. An optically active device is flip-chip bonded directly to an integrated circuit using solder bump technology. The optically active device has a lens attached to it to facillitate optical coupling to the optical waveguide. The integrated circuit is flip-chip bonded to a BGA package. The BGA package is bonded to the PCB using solder reflow technology. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/892,921, filed Jun. 26, 2001, titled &ldquo;Packaging and Assembly Method for Optical Coupling,&rdquo; Attorney Docket No. 042390.P10500 </paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Technical Field </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the invention generally relates to mounting optical and electrical devices to a substrate while coupling to an optical waveguide integrated on a printed circuit board. More particularly, the present invention relates to using conventional flip-chip packaging to integrate optical and electrical devices to a printed circuit board while simultaneously coupling the optical devices to an optical waveguide by utilizing an integrated microlens array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Discussion of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Electrical systems often use a number of integrated circuits that are mounted on a printed circuit board. Each integrated circuit includes a number of leads that extend from the packaging of the circuit. The leads of the various integrated circuits are interconnected to allow signals to be passed between the integrated circuits such that the system performs some function. For example, a personal computer includes a wide variety of integrated circuits, e.g., a microprocessor and memory chips, that are interconnected on one or more printed circuit boards in the computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Printed circuit boards are used to bring together separately fabricated integrated circuits. However, the use of printed circuit boards creates some problems that are not so easily overcome. A printed circuit board includes metal traces to transmit an electrical signal between the various integrated circuits. As the number of components on a printed circuit board increases, the number of metal traces needed to connect the components also increases. This fact decreases the spacing between the metal traces, which can lead to capacitance problems between the metal traces and space constraints due to the limited area available on the printed circuit board for metal traces. It is desirable to reduce the amount of physical space required by such printed circuit boards. Also, it is desirable to reduce the physical length of electrical interconnections between devices because of concerns with signal loss or dissipation and interference with and by other integrated circuitry devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As the density of electronic integrated circuits increases, the limiting factor for circuit speed increasingly becomes propagation delay due to capacitance associated with circuit interconnection. At relatively low clock speeds, the capacitive loading is not a significant factor. As newer applications push clock speeds into the one hundred megahertz range and beyond, capacitive loading becomes a limiting factor for circuit performance by limiting circuit speed and increasing circuit cross talk. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A continuing challenge in the semiconductor industry is to find new, innovative, and efficient ways of forming electrical connections with and between circuit devices that are fabricated on the same, and on different, wafers or dies. Relatedly, continuing challenges are posed to find and/or improve upon the packaging techniques utilized to package integrated circuitry devices. As device dimensions continue to shrink, these challenges become even more important. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> One approach utilizes optical interconnection to transmit optical signals between components, particularly components located on remote regions of a board. The optical signals are composed of modulated light beams that carry data between components. An optical emitter, such as a laser, is mounted on one region of the board and emits the optical signal. The optical signals are diffracted by holographic elements into a optical waveguide. The optical signals then propagate from one point to another through the optical waveguide before being diffracted out of the optical waveguide by holographic elements and focused upon opto-electronic receivers on the surface of an integrated circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> However, the interface between the component, i.e., the emitter or detector, and the optical waveguide is difficult to fabricate. In this approach, holographic routing elements have to be precisely aligned with the opto-electronic receivers of the integrated circuits. The opto-electronic transmitters then have to be precisely aligned relative to the holographic routing elements in order for the modulated light beams emitted by the sources to be directed by the holographic routing element to the proper opto-electronic receivers. Achieving the required precision of alignment makes assembly into a package extremely challenging. The kinds of tolerances required are normally associated with semiconductor device fabrication processes rather than with package assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another limitation of the prior art is the lack of flexibility in the assembly of printed circuit boards. Because the optical emitters, holographic elements, waveguides, and optical detectors must be mounted during assembly of the printed circuit board, there is no flexibility in adding any of these elements or adjusting their position once the printed circuit board has been fabricated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> For reasons stated above, and for other reasons which will become apparent to those in the art upon reading and understanding the present specification, there is a need in the art for an improved technique for interconnecting individual integrated circuits in an electronic system. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a package suitable for implementing embodiments of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of an alternative package suitable for implementing embodiments of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a flow chart for a method of optically interconnecting integrated circuits according to an embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the invention addresses the limitations of the prior art by providing a structure wherein optically active devices, i.e., opto-electronic transmitters and opto-electronic receivers, are individually manufactured, and optimized for performance and reliability. The optically active devices are then mounted on a PCB and aligned to a waveguide formed on the PCB. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The opto-electronic transmitters and receivers <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, for example, are first flip-chip bonded to integrated circuits <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> such as drivers, transimpedance amplifiers, microprocessors, etc. The integrated circuits <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are then flip-chip bonded to substrates <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, which are incorporated into Ball Grid Array (BGA) <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> or Land Grid Array (LGA) packages. Flip-chip bonding, otherwise known as controlled collapsed chip connection technology or solder bump technology, involves solder bumps on the chip that are reflowed to make connection to terminal pads on the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The BGA <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> package (including the integrated circuit and the optically active device) is then bonded directly to a printed ciruit board (PCB) <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in such a way as to position the optically active devices <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in close proximity to optical waveguides <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> deposited on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The optically active devices <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> align with coupling elements <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> e.g. (holographic elements or 45 degree facets) incorporated into the optical waveguides <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, thus forming an optical interconnect structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> An alternative BGA package <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> suitable for implementing embodiments of the present invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. A driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is flip-bonded on a first surface of the BGA package substrate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, and a bottom emitting or sensing optically active device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is flip-bonded on a second surface of the BGA package substrate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, and the BGA package <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> is bonded to a printed circuit board (PCB) <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> using solder reflow technology. The example system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> also has a waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> to direct the light from the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> through the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The present invention overcomes a significant limitation of the prior art in that precise alignment between opto-electronic devices <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the optical waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is not required. In the prior art, the optical waveguides are directly deposited over the electro-optic devices using standard semiconductor fabrication techniques. To electricaly connect the various chips, the substrate has very fine feature sizes that are compatible with the input/output pitch of the various chips. The configuaration ensured an intimate contact between the opto-electronic devices and the optical waveguides and consequently good optical coupling is achieved. However, this technology can not provide a cost effective solution because it is not compatible with integrating waveguides on a conventional printed circuit board. Printed circuit boards typically have gross feature sizes (&gt;3 mils linewidth). In addition, the prior art is not compatible with current Central Processing Unit (CPU) motherboard fabrication and assembly processes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The present invention allows alignment requirements to be relaxed by using a lens to collimate the divergent light beam from the opto-electronic transmitter <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, or to focus a diffracted beam from the optical waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> onto a photodiode contained within the opto-electronic reciever <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The lens is directly attached to the optically active devices <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The lens allows the divergent light beam to be readily coupled to the optical waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> deposited in the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> without regard to the separation and original divergence of the opto-electronic transmitter <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In the prefered embodiment of the present invention the opto-electronic transmitter <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is a Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Laser (VCSEL) with an attached lens. The optical emission of the VCSEL is from the top surface of the chip. VCSEL&apos;s have a circularly semetric, nonastigmatic beam. In a custom VCSEL assembly used in a sensing application, for example, a VCSEL is mounted chip-on-board in a TO style package, with an injection-molded plastic lens aligned to the VCSEL to collimate the optical output, as well as a pair of silicon detectors and some passive elements. In an alternative embodiment of the present invention the opto-electronic transmitter <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is an array of Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers (array of VCSEL&apos;s) with a microlens array attached. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The move to higher data rates and smaller packaging requires examination of the electrical characteristics of both the VCSEL and packaging. In a typical fiberoptic transceiver, the elements to be considered are the output impedance of the laser driver, the circuit, and traces used to carry the signal to the laser package and finally, the laser chip itself. To determine the electrical characteristics of the VCSEL, S parameter measurements may be taken with a network analyzer. Once the electrical characteristics of the VCSEL chip are known, various packaging options may be investigated, and the output stages of laser drivers and circuit board parameters may be optimized to deliver high quality electrical signals to the VCSEL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> To optimize the VCSEL performance, typical packaging rules apply: minimize both the inductance and the capacitance of the packaging by keeping the leads to the TO package as short as possible. Also minimize the distance between the laser driver and the TO package to reduce any impedance mismatched reflections, and optimize the output stage of the laser driver to drive the VCSEL TO package. For operation at data rates above a few giga-bits per second (Gb/s), the total impedance is completely dominated by the electrical parasitics of the TO package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> At higher speeds, i.e., 10 Gb/s, it may be necessary to connect the VCSEL directly to the laser driver integrated circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> using a ribbon bond wire. In the prefered embodiment of the invention, the use of the bond wire is eliminated by flip-chip bonding the VCSEL chip directly to the laser driver integrated circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The combination optically active device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>/integrated circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is tested prior to mounting to the substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of the BGA package. Any number of integrated circuits <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may also be mounted to the substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by any suitable means; however, in a preferred embodiment, flip-chip or solder bump technology is used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Ball Grid Array (BGA) package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is suitable for any integrated circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> that may previously have been put in a plastic type package. The BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is composed of three basic parts: a bare chip (shown as the driver or transimpedance amp integrated circuit <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>), a BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, and an interconnection matrix (not shown). Depending on the package style, the bare chip may be affixed to the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> either face-up or face-down. The interconnection matrix then connects the bare chip to the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> using wire-bond, tape-automated-bonding (TAB), or direct attach flip-chip bonding. The BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, similar to a miniature multi-layer PCB with small traces and microscopic through-hole vias, conveys the signals to the underlying printed circuit board <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> through an array of solder-bump attachment pads <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> on its bottom surface. A metal cover or plastic encapsulation is then used to seal the package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> BGA packages <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are inherently low-profile. The package includes the chip, some interconnections, a thin substrate, and a plastic encapsulant. No big pins, and no lead frames are included. The low profile and small size means that the total loop area, from a signal on the chip, through the interconnection matrix onto the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and back into the chip through the power/ground pins is very small, as little as &frac12; to &frac13; the size of the same loop on a typical package of equivalent pincount. This smaller loop area means less radiated noise, and less crosstalk between pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> has relatively large, easy-to-work-with solder bumps <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, much bigger than the ones used for flip-chip bonding. By way of contrast, flip-chip techniques, which use solder-balls <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, placed directly on the face of a silicon die, require solder bumps with much smaller dimensions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Because the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is an inherently thin package, it has reasonably good cooling properties. With the die mounted face-up, most of the heat flows down and out through the ball-grid array. In packages that mount the die face-down, the back side of the die is in intimate contact with the top of the package, an ideal arrangement for heatsinking. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of an opto-electronic system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> suitable for implementing embodiments of the present invention. The example system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes packaging that provides pitch transformation from fine pitch to coarse pitch. The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a bottom emitting optically active device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> (or a bottom detecting optically active device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>) that is flip-chip bonded on a driver <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The driver <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is flip-chip bonded on a ball grid array (BGA) package substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, and the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is solder reflowed to a printed circuit board (PCB) <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> that includes a waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The active face (emitting or detecting surface) of optically active devices, such as the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, is on the side opposite of the electrical traces (the interconnect surface). Example bottom emitting or detecting optically active devices <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> emits (or detects) light when activated. The device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is surface normal and may be a Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers (VCSEL), an array of Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers, a light emitting diode (LED), a photodetector, an optical modulator, or similar optically active device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. A lens or microlens array is attached to the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to collimate the divergent optical beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, an optical via <highlight><bold>157</bold></highlight> is made in the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> for the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the light emitted by the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Light from (or to) the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> passes through the optical via <highlight><bold>157</bold></highlight>. This may also be in the form of a clearance in the substrate to accomadate the VCSEL chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is any integrated circuit suitable for applying an electrical signal to the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to activate the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Implementation of the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is well known. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> may be any known flip-chip Ball Grid Array package. The BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in one embodiment is an organic laminate substrate that uses epoxy resin dielectric materials or bismaleimide triazine (BT) materials, and copper conductors or traces. In another embodiment, the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is a multi-layer ceramic substrate based on aluminum oxide (Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> typically has an insulating layer made of epoxy glass. The PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> also has an electric circuit with various conducting strips or traces that connect to each other based on the particular PCB application. The PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be a multi-layer PCB with several insulating layers and conducting layers, with each conducting layer having its own traces. Printed circuit boards suitable for implementing the present invention are well known. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> According to the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the optically active device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is flip-chip bonded on the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> using well known solder bump technology. For example, the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has two solder bumps <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, which are very tiny and spaced very close together. The device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may have more than two solder bumps. If the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> were to be mounted directly on the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> would have to have very fine features to accommodate the tiny and closely spaced solder bumps <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. This requirement may cause the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to be more complex and the manufacturing process for the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> would be costly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> accommodates existing PCB manufacturing by mounting the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> using the tiny solder balls <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and mounting the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is flip-chip bonded to the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> using solder balls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, whose pitch may be, illustratively, 1.27 millimeters, such that the pitch is compatible with conventional PCB technology and does not require high-density substrates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> includes bumps <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, which electrically connect the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to traces on the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The bumps <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> may be made of solder or other type of metal(s) that melt and create a bond (e.g., lead-tin compositions (PbSn), tin-silver (SnAg) compositions, nickel (Ni) compositions). In the embodiment in which the bumps <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are made of solder, the solder melts during reflow and the surface tension of the molten solder centers the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> correctly over the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In some instances, it may be desirable to direct light from the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> on the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has an optical waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> for this purpose. The waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> contains coupling elements <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and the waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> may be laminated on the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The coupling elements may include holographic gratings made of dichromated gelatin film, photosensitive polymer film, gratings etched photolithographically into the waveguides or waveguides faceted at 45 degrees. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> For fine alignment of the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the solder balls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> are subject to high temperature, which causes the solder balls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> to melt. When the solder balls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> melt, the surface tension pulls the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> into alignment with the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Surface tension is the attraction that the molecules at the surface of a drop of melted solder have for each other. The attraction the solder molecules have for each other is greater than the attraction the solder molecules have for the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> so that the solder does not spread. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> When the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is placed over the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the solder balls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> rest over pad areas <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>, respectively, on the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Thus, the solder ball-to-pad contact determines the vertical separation of the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. This feature ensures that solder balls and pad areas will remain in an intimate (i.e., high coupling efficiency) optical contact after assembly of the package <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> also provides fine alignment of the BGA package <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> with the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The solder balls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> rest on the pads <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>, respectively, and self-align within the pads <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> during solder reflow. In this embodiment, the solder balls <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> set the height of the package <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in the &ldquo;z&rdquo; dimension and have no constraints in the &ldquo;x&rdquo; dimension or the &ldquo;y&rdquo; dimension. The final tolerance may be determined by the placement accuracy of the flat pads <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The resulting fine alignment provided by solder reflow techniques ensures the light emitted by the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is properly aligned with the coupling elements <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> of the waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> on the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. After bonding, the aligned package <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> positions the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> correctly over the coupling elements <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> of the waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The solder metallurgy for the joint(s) between the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> has a higher melting temperature than the solder metallurgy for the joint(s) between the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. For example, well-known 63Pb/37Sn solder melts at 187 degrees Centigrade. This use of solder is done to ensure that joint(s) between the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> maintains its integrity when the driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is flip-chip bonded to the BGA substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the solder bumps on the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may be the same material as the solder bumps on the device <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the solder on the board has a lower melting point than the solder bumps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The arrows <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> illustrate the direction light travels from the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, to the waveguide structure <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, and to a receiving optically active device (not shown). The reverse is true for light arriving at the receiving optically active device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of an alternative BGA package <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> suitable for implementing embodiments of the present invention. A driver or transimpedance amplifier chip <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is flip-bonded on a first surface of the BGA package substrate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, and a bottom emitting or sensing optically active device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is flip-bonded on a second surface of the BGA package substrate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, and the BGA package <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> is bonded to a printed circuit board (PCB) <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> using solder reflow technology. The example system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> also has a waveguide <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> to direct the light from the device <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> through the PCB <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a flow chart for a method of optically interconnecting integrated circuits according to an embodiment of the present invention. Optical waveguides <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are formed having a first coupling element and a second coupling element onto a printed circuit board. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Opto-electronic transmitters and receivers are electrically coupled <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> to integrated circuits, the integrated circuits being bonded to substrates, the substrates being bonded to the printed circuit board, the opto-electronic transmitters and receivers being aligned correspondingly with the first coupling element and the second coupling element of the plurality of optical waveguides. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Electrical signals from the integrated circuits modulate <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> light emissions of the opto-electronic transmitter. The microlens array attached to the opto-electronic transmitter collimates <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> divergent light emissions to form collimated light emissions and directs the collimated light emissions toward the first coupling element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The collimated light emissions propagates <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> from the first coupling element through the optical waveguide to the second coupling element. The second coupling element directs the light emissions <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> toward the corresponding microlens array attached to the opto-electronic receiver. Finally, the opto-electronic receiver transduces <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight> the modulated light emissions into electrical signals for the integrated circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> While the description above refers to particular embodiments of the present invention, it will be understood that many modifications may be made without departing from the spirit thereof. The accompanying claims are intended to cover such modifications as would fall within the true scope and spirit of the present invention. The presently disclosed embodiments are therefore to be considered in all respects as illustrative and not restrictive, the scope of the invention being indicated by the appended claims, rather than the foregoing description, and all changes that come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are therefore intended to be embraced therein. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An opto-electronic package, comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optically active device flip-chip bonded to the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an integrated circuit bonded to the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the optically active device is flip-chip bonded to the the substrate using solder bumps. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the substrate is selected from the group consisting of a Ball Grid Array substrate, an organic laminate substrate, and a multi-layer ceramic substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the optically active device is selected from the group consisting of a vertical cavity surface emitting laser (VCSEL), a vertical cavity surface emitting laser (VCSEL) with an attached lens, an array of vertical cavity surface emitting lasers with an attached microlens array, a light emitting diode (LED) with an attached lens, a photodetector with an attached lens, and an optical modulator with an attached lens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the integrated circuit is selected from the group consisting of an optical device driver, a transimpedance amplifier, a microprocessor, a microprocessor chip set, a networking integrated circuit, and a memory. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a printed circuit board (PCB) bonded to the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the PCB includes a waveguide to propagate light to or from the optically active device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the waveguide includes a holographic element to diffract light to or from the optically active device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the waveguide includes a sloped facet to reflect light to or from the optically active device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the printed circuit board (PCB) is flip-chip bonded to the substrate using solder reflow technology, where solder reflow surface tension pulls the substrate into alignment with the PCB. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An opto-electronic package, comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optically active device with an attached optical element flip-chip bonded to an integrated circuit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the integrated circuit bonded to the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate is selected from the group consisting of a Ball Grid Array substrate, an organic laminate substrate, and a multi-layer ceramic substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optically active device with an attached optical element is selected from the group consisting of a vertical cavity surface emitting laser (VCSEL) with an attached lens, an array of vertical cavity surface emitting lasers with an attached microlens array, a light emitting diode (LED) with an attached lens, a photodetector with an attached lens, and an optical modulator with an attached lens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optically active device with an attached optical element is flip-chip bonded to the integrated circuit using solder bumps. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the integrated circuit is selected from the group consisting of an optical device driver, a transimpedance amplifier, a microprocessor, a microprocessor chip set, a networking integrated circuit, and a memory. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a printed circuit board (PCB) bonded to the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the PCB includes a waveguide to propagate light to or from the optically active device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the waveguide includes a holographic element to diffract light to or from the optically active device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the waveguide includes a sloped facet to reflect light to or from the optically active device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the printed circuit board (PCB) is flip-chip bonded to the substrate using solder reflow technology, where solder reflow surface tension pulls the substrate into alignment with the PCB. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method of optically interconnecting integrated circuits, comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a plurality of optical waveguides having a first coupling element and a second coupling element onto a printed circuit board; </claim-text>
<claim-text>electrically coupling opto-electronic transmitters and receivers to integrated circuits, said integrated circuits being bonded to substrates, said substrates being bonded to the printed circuit board, the opto-electronic transmitters and receivers being aligned correspondingly with the first coupling element and the second coupling element of the plurality of optical waveguides; </claim-text>
<claim-text>modulating light emissions of the opto-electronic transmitters with electrical signals from the integrated circuits to form divergent modulated light emissions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>emitting divergent modulated light emissions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>collimating divergent modulated light emissions of the opto-electronic transmitters using attached lens to form collimated modulated light and directing the collimated modulated light toward the first coupling element; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving, by the first coupling element, the collimated modulated light and forming propagating modulated light; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transporting the propagating modulated light from the first coupling element through the optical waveguides to the second coupling element; </claim-text>
<claim-text>directing the propagating modulated light from the second coupling element toward the corresponding lens attached to the opto-electronic receivers to form modulated light emissions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>transducing, by the opto-electronic receivers, the modulated light emissions into electrical signals for the integrated circuits. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein electrically coupling the opto-electronic transmitters and receivers to the integrated circuits includes using flip-chip bonded solder bump connection technology. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An opto-electronic system to optically interconnect integrated circuits, comprising: 
<claim-text>an opto-electronic transmitter having an emitting surface and an interconnect surface, the interconnect surface being bonded to a first integrated circuit, the opto-electronic transmitter emitting a divergent modulated light beam from the emitting surface through an attached first lens to form a collimated modulated light beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first substrate including a first surface bonded to the first integrated circuit, and a second surface bonded to a printed circuit board; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical waveguide in close proximity to the first lens attached to the opto-electronic transmitter, wherein the optical waveguide is formed on the printed circuit board, contains a first coupling element to receive the collimated modulated light beam emitted by the opto-electronic transmitter to form propagating modulated light and to re-direct the propagating modulated light through the optical waveguide, and a second coupling element to re-direct the propagating modulated light out of the optical waveguide to a second lens attached to an opto-electronic receiver and in close proximity with the second coupling element; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second integrated circuit bonded to the opto-electronic receiver; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second substrate including a first surface bonded to the second integrated circuit, and a second surface bonded to the printed circuit board. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first surface of the first substrate is bonded to a second surface of the first integrated circuit and the opto-electronic transmitter is bonded to the second surface of the first integrated circuit, and the second surface of the first substrate is bonded to the printed circuit using flip-chip bonded solder bump connection technology. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first surface of the second substrate is bonded to a second surface of the second integrated circuit and the opto-electronic receiver is bonded to the second surface of the second integrated circuit, and the second surface of the second substrate is bonded to the printed circuit using flip-chip bonded solder bump connection technology. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the opto-electronic transmitter is a Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Laser (VCSEL). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the opto-electronic transmitter is an array of Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers (VCSEL). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the opto-electronic receiver is a photodiode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second substrates are contained within Ball Grid Array (BGA) packages or Land Grid Array (LGA) packages. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one or more integrated circuits are bonded to the first and second substrates, and electrically coupled to the opto-electronic transmitter and opto-electronic receiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second coupling elements include sloped facets or holographic elements formed in the optical waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the holographic elements are formed in the optical waveguide such that holographic elements diffract the modulated light into or out of the optical waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. An opto-electronic system to optically interconnect integrated circuits, comprising: 
<claim-text>an opto-electronic transmitter having an emitting surface and an interconnect surface, the interconnect surface being bonded to a second surface of a first substrate, the opto-electronic transmitter emitting a divergent modulated light beam from the emitting surface through an attached first lens to form a collimated modulated light beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first substrate including a first surface bonded to a first integrated circuit, and the second surface bonded to a printed circuit board; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical waveguide in close proximity to the first lens attached to the opto-electronic transmitter, wherein the optical waveguide is formed on the printed circuit board, contains a first coupling element to receive the collimated modulated light beam emitted by the opto-electronic transmitter to form propagating modulated light and to re-direct the propagating modulated light through the optical waveguide, and a second coupling element to re-direct the propagating modulated light out of the optical waveguide to a second lens attached to an opto-electronic receiver and in close proximity with the second coupling element; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second surface of a second substrate bonded to the opto-electronic receiver; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second substrate including a first surface bonded to the second integrated circuit, and the second surface bonded to the printed circuit board. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first surface of the first substrate is bonded to the first integrated circuit and the second surface of the first substrate is bonded to the opto-electronic transmitter, and the second surface of the first substrate is bonded to the printed circuit using flip-chip bonded solder bump connection technology. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first surface of the second substrate is bonded to the second integrated circuit and the second surface of the second substrate is bonded to the opto-electronic receiver, and the second surface of the second substrate is bonded to the printed circuit board, using flip-chip bonded solder bump connection technology. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the opto-electronic transmitter is a Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Laser (VCSEL). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the opto-electronic transmitter is an array of Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers (VCSEL). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the opto-electronic receiver is a photodiode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second substrates are contained within Ball Grid Array (BGA) packages or Land Grid Array (LGA) packages. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one or more integrated circuits are bonded to the first and second substrates, and electrically coupled to the opto-electronic transmitter and opto-electronic receiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second coupling elements include sloped facets or holographic elements formed in the optical waveguide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The opto-electronic system according to claim <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, wherein the holographic elements are formed in the optical waveguide such that holographic elements diffract the modulated light into or out of the optical waveguide.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002770A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002770A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002770A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
