<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001196A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001196A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001196</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10186153</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-37420</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/8238</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/76</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/788</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>315000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>314000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>321000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>263000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>264000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>201000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Non-volatile memory device and method of fabricating the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jung-Dal</given-name>
<family-name>Choi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyunggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jong-Woo</given-name>
<family-name>Park</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Seong-Soon</given-name>
<family-name>Cho</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyunggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chang-Hyun</given-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyunggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Hwasung-City</city>
<country>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MARGER JOHNSON &amp; MCCOLLOM PC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1030 SW MORRISON STREET</address-1>
<city>PORTLAND</city>
<state>OR</state>
<postalcode>97205</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A non-volatile memory device includes a tunnel oxide layer, a charge storage layer, a blocking insulating layer, and a gate electrode that are sequentially stacked, as well as an impurity diffusion layer in an active region at both sides of the gate electrode. The gate electrode crosses active regions between device isolation layers formed in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate, and an edge of the charge storage layer is extended to have a protruding part that protrudes from the gate electrode. In order to form a charge storage layer having a protruding part, a stack insulating layer including first to third insulating layers is formed in an active region between the device isolation layers formed in the substrate. A plurality of gate electrodes crossing the active region are formed on the stack insulating layer, and a sidewall spacer is formed on both sidewalls of the gate electrode. Using the sidewall spacer and the gate electrode, the stack insulating layer is etched to form a charge storage layer that protrudes from the sidewall of the gate electrode. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application relies for priority upon Korean Patent Application No. 2001-37420, filed on Jun. 28, 2001, the contents of which are herein incorporated by this reference in their entirety. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to a method of fabricating a semiconductor device. More specifically, the present invention is directed to a floating trap-type non-volatile memory device that stores data in a charge storage layer including one insulating layer by injecting charges, and to a method of fabricating the same. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Non-volatile memory devices continuously hold data even when an external power is turned off. As the integration density of memory devices increases, there is a need for reducing the area and vertical height of a memory cell. Since a conventional floating gate type non-volatile memory device has a floating gate, it is restrictive to reduce a vertical height of a memory cell. For that reason, a floating trap-type non-volatile memory device has been attractive as a candidate to overcome the above disadvantage in that charges can be stored in at least one insulating layer without a floating gate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top plan view of a conventional floating trap-type non-volatile memory device. A device isolation layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is formed in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate to define an active region <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A plurality of gate electrodes <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> cross the active region, and a charge storage layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is intervened between the gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the active region <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is formed on a sidewall of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> are cross-sectional flow diagrams showing the steps of fabricating a conventional non-volatile memory device, taken along a line I-I&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> device isolation layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is formed in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate to define active regions <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A stack insulating layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and a gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are formed on a semiconductor substrate where the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is formed. Generally, the stack insulating layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> includes first, second, and third insulating layers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which are conventionally made of thin thermal oxide, silicon nitride, and CVD oxide, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the stack insulating layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are sequentially patterned to form a plurality of gate electrodes <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> crossing the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a charge storage layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and a blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are sequentially stacked between the gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the active region <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In case sidewalls of the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are damaged by an etch, a defect density increases with increased trap density around edges of the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. As a result, it is likely to generate a trap-assisted leakage current to the gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through the high-density trap. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> thermal oxidation process is carried out for the semiconductor substrate in order to alleviate the damage of the sidewalls of the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. As a result, a capping insulating layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is formed on a sidewall and a top surface of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, using the gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the capping insulating layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> as an ion implanting mask, impurities are implanted into the semiconductor substrate to form an impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is then formed on sidewalls of the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and the capping insulating layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> that are sequentially stacked. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, oxygen atoms are diffused through an interface between the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> during the thermal oxidation process. At this time, an edge of the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> becomes thick (i.e., a bird&apos;s beak phenomenon occurs) because it is oxidized by the diffused oxygen atoms. This leads to a drop in device operational speed. Furthermore, a trap density becomes high at the relatively thicker edge of the tunneling oxide layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> thereby increasing trap-assisted leakage current through the edge. As the bird&apos;s beak phenomenon causes a thickness variation of a tunnel oxide layer to be high in a cell array, device characteristics become non-uniform. The more a gate line width decreases, the more the thickness of the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> increases. Therefore, what is needed is a non-volatile memory device with a structure to overcome device operational characteristic defects that result from a tunnel oxide layer of high trap density and from bird&apos;s beak phenomenon. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A feature of the present invention is to provide a non-volatile memory device having a conformal tunnel oxide layer without a bird&apos;s beak phenomenon, and to provide a method of fabricating the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another feature of the present invention is to provide a non-volatile memory device that can minimize the influence of trap-assisted tunneling, and to provide a method of fabricating the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the present invention, a non-volatile memory device includes a charge storage layer and a gate electrode. The gate electrode crosses an active region between device isolation layers formed in a semiconductor substrate. The charge storage layer intervenes between the gate electrode and the active region. An edge of the charge storage layer extends to form a protruding part that protrudes from a sidewall of the gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the present invention, the charge storage layer is isolated by the device isolation layer or is successive under the gate electrode. A blocking insulating layer intervenes between the gate electrode and the charge storage layer, and a tunnel oxide layer intervenes between the charge storage layer and the active region. The non-volatile memory device further includes a first sidewall spacer on both sidewalls of the gate electrode. The width of the charge storage layer is preferably approximately equal to the sum of a width of the gate electrode and widths of the first sidewall spacers. Further, the nonvolatile memory device may include a second sidewall spacer that covers a sidewall of the charge storage layer and the first sidewall spacer. A gate capping insulating layer may intervene between the sidewall of the gate electrode and the sidewall spacer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The non-volatile memory device has a cell array region and a peripheral circuit region. A first transistor including a wordline and a stack insulating layer is formed on an active region. The stack insulating layer comprises a tunnel oxide layer, a charge storage layer, and a blocking insulating layer and a first transistor. A second transistor including at least a gate insulating layer and a gate electrode is formed in the peripheral region. The first sidewall spacer may be formed on each sidewall of the gate electrodes in the first and second transistors. Further, a second sidewall spacer may be formed on the first sidewall spacer that is formed on each sidewall of the wordline and the gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, a method of fabricating a nonvolatile memory device is provided. A stack insulating layer is formed on an active region of a semiconductor substrate. The stack insulating layer comprises at least first, second, and third insulating layers that are sequentially stacked. A plurality of gate electrodes crossing the active region are formed on a semiconductor substrate including the stack insulating layer. The stack insulating layer is patterned to form a tunnel oxide layer, a charge storage layer, and a blocking insulating layer that are sequentially stacked between the gate electrode and the active region. The tunneling oxide layer, the charge storage layer, and the blocking insulating layer correspond to the first, second, and third insulating layers, respectively. An edge of the charge storage layer has a protruding part that protrudes from a sidewall of the gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Specifically, the device isolation layer may be formed using a conventional trench isolation technology. In this case, the stack insulating layer is formed on an overall surface of a semiconductor substrate where the device isolation layer is formed. A gate conductive layer is formed on the stack insulating layer, and then is patterned to form a gate electrode crossing the active region. Alternatively, the device isolation layer may be formed using a self-aligned trench isolation technology. In this case, a stack insulating layer and a lower gate conductive layer are sequentially formed on an active region between the device isolation layers. An upper gate conductive layer is formed on an overall surface of a semiconductor substrate where the device isolation layer is formed. Thereafter, the upper and lower gate conductive layers are sequentially patterned to form the active region crossing the active region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the present invention, a first sidewall spacer is formed on a sidewall of the gate electrode so as to form the protruding part of the charge storage layer. Using the first sidewall spacer and the gate electrode as an etch mask, at least the third and second insulating layers are etched to form a blocking insulating layer protruding from the sidewall of the gate electrode and a charge storage layer. Alternatively, prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer, the third insulating layer exposed to both sides of the gate electrode may be removed. In this case, the charge storage layer has a protruding part that protrudes from the sidewall of the gate electrode, and the first sidewall spacer covers the sidewall of the gate electrode and an upper portion of the protruding part. Further, a second sidewall spacer may be formed to cover sidewalls of the charge storage layer and the first sidewall spacer.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top plan view of a conventional non-volatile memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> are cross-sectional flow diagrams showing the steps of fabricating the conventional non-volatile memory device, taken along a line I-I&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a top plan view of a non-volatile memory device according to first and second embodiments of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the non-volatile memory device according to the first embodiment, taken along a line II-II&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> are cross-sectional flow diagrams showing the steps of fabricating the non-volatile memory device according to the first embodiment, taken along the line II-II&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> are cross-sectional flow diagrams showing the steps of fabricating the non-volatile memory device according to the second embodiment, taken along the line II-II&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a top plan view of a non-volatile memory device according to third and fourth embodiments of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a non-volatile memory device according to the third embodiment, taken along a line III-III&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> are cross-sectional flow diagrams showing the steps of fabricating the non-volatile memory device according to the third embodiment, taken along the line III-III&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a structure according to the fourth embodiment, taken along the line III-III&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The present invention will now be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which preferred embodiments of the invention are shown. The invention may, however, be embodied in different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the invention to those skilled in the art. In the drawings, the thickness of layers and regions are exaggerated for clarity. It will also be understood that when a layer is referred to as being &ldquo;on&rdquo; another layer or substrate, it can be directly on the other layer or substrate, or intervening layers may also be present. Like numbers refer to like elements throughout. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a top plan view illustrating a non-volatile memory device according to first and second embodiments of the present invention, in which a region &ldquo;a&rdquo; is a cell array region and a region &ldquo;b&rdquo; is a peripheral circuit region. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating the non-volatile memory device according to the first embodiment, taken along a line II-II&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is formed in a predetermined region of a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> defines a plurality of first active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;, and a second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. A plurality of wordlines <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> crossing over the first active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> are formed in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;. A stack insulating layer intervenes between the wordlines <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the first active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, and includes a tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, a charge storage layer <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, and a blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> that are sequentially stacked. It is preferable that the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, and the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> are made of thermal oxide, silicon nitride, and CVD oxide, respectively. Also, the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> overlap with the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to cross over the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. A sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is covered with a first sidewall spacer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, a gate capping oxide layer <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> may intervene between the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. A width of the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> is larger than that of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> at least, so that the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> has a protruding part <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> protruding from a sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Therefore, although a high electric field is applied between the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the first active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> by a program voltage or an erase voltage, an electric field applied to the protruding part <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> is relatively weak. This causes a conspicuous decrease in a leakage current flowing through a blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and a tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> that are located over and under the protruding part <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight>, respectively. As a result, a soft program characteristic or a data retention characteristic can be improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> covers not only the sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> but also a top of the protruding part <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> . The second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> may cover an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> and a sidewall of the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. A first impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is formed in the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> between the wordlines <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Therefore, a first cell transistor is formed at an intersection of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. In this case, the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> under the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> has a uniform thickness. That is, a thick tunnel oxide layer caused by a bird&apos;s beak phenomenon is not formed at least under an edge of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Thus, a plurality of first transistors in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; have the equivalent threshold voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> A gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> crossing over the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> is formed in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. The first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> covers the gate insulating layer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> between the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, and a sidewall of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The second sidewall spacer may cover an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. A gate capping layer <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> may intervene between the fist sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. A dual-structured impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> is formed in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The dual-structured impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> includes a second impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> and a third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> that correspond to a lightly doped impurity diffusion layer and a heavily doped impurity diffusion layer, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> are cross-sectional flow diagrams showing the steps of fabricating a non-volatile memory device according to a first embodiment of the present invention, taken along a line II-II&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8, a</cross-reference> device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is formed in a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to define a first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and a second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> in a cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; and a peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;, respectively. A stacking insulating layer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and a gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are sequentially formed in a cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; of a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> where the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is formed. At the same time, a gate insulating layer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and a gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are sequentially formed in a peripheral region &ldquo;b&rdquo; of the semiconductor substrate where the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is formed. Preferably, the stack insulating layer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is formed by sequentially stacking first, second, and third insulating layers <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the first insulating layer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is made of thermal oxide. Preferably, the first insulating layer has a thickness of approximately 15 &angst;-35 &angst; in order to lower a program and erase voltages. In this embodiment, it is preferable that the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> has a thickness of approximately 40 &angst;-100 &angst;, and the third insulating layer <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> has a thickness of approximately 40 &angst;-120 &angst;. The gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be made of polysilicon, or polycide that is formed by sequentially stacking polysilicon and metal silicide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is patterned to form a plurality of wordlines <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> crossing the first active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;, and to form a gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> at least on the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. The third insulating layer <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> exposed between the wordlines <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is overetched or attacked by plasma while etching the gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Therefore, a defect site may be created in the third insulating layer around an edge of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, a trap-to-trap tunneling may occur through the defect site. Charges stored in a later-formed charge storage layer are then discharged to a gate electrode, having an undesirable influence on device operations. Preferably, in order to overcome the above disadvantages, a thermal oxidation process is performed for a semiconductor substrate where the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> are formed. Thus, the damage of the third insulating layer <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> can be alleviated. As a result, a gate capping oxide layer <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> is formed on sidewalls and top surfaces of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, impurities are implanted into the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> between the wordlines <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to form a first impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Also, impurities are implanted into the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to form a second impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the first and second impurity diffusion layers <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be formed at the same time or prior to formation of the gate capping oxide layer <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, a spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is conformally formed on an entire surface of the resultant structure in which the first and second impurity diffusion layers <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> are formed. Preferably, the spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is made of silicon nitride or oxide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is anisotropically etched to form a first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> on sidewalls of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. If the spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is made of oxide, the third insulating layer <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is also etched during the anisotropic etch to expose the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. If the spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is made of silicon nitride, the third insulating layer <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is etched using the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> as an etch mask following formation of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Using the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> as an etch mask, at least the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is then etched to form at least second and third insulating layer patterns <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> between the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. Edges of the second and the third insulating layer patterns <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> are extended to form a protruding part <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> that protrudes from both sides of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The second insulating layer patterns <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> correspond to a charge storage layer, and the third insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> intervened between the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> corresponds to a blocking insulating layer. The first insulating layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> under the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> corresponds to a tunnel oxide layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Following formation of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, impurities are implanted into the second active region exposed to both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo; to form a third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, a dual-structured impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> is formed in the second active region at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> may be formed before or after formation of the second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Following formation of the third and the second insulating layer patterns <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, a second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) may further be formed in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; and the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. In the cell array region &ldquo;b&rdquo;, the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> covers sidewalls of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, the third insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, and the second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. In the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;, the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> covers the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. If the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> is further formed, the third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> may be formed in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> exposed to both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> following formation of the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the first and second impurity diffusion layers <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be formed following the formation of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, and the third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> may be formed following the formation of the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> As a result, a width of the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> is equal to the sum of the width of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the widths of the sidewall spacers <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. In other words, the nonvolatile memory device of the invention has a protruding part that is formed by extending an edge of the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> to protrude from a sidewall of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Therefore, even if defect sites are created in insulating layers over/under the protruding part, device operation characteristics are scarcely influenced by the defect sites compared with a prior art. Because an edge of the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> also protrudes from the gate electrode <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> wherein a bird&apos;s beak phenomenon may occur in subsequent annealing processes, the non-volatile memory device of the invention has an excellent data retention characteristic compared with the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> are cross-sectional flow diagrams for explaining the steps of fabricating a non-volatile memory device according to a second embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, steps until formation of a gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>) in the second embodiment are identical to those in the first embodiment, as described in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the third insulating layer <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>) are sequentially patterned to form a wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and a third insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; and to form a gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. The third insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> corresponds to a blocking insulating layer. Furthermore, a thermal oxidation process is carried out for the semiconductor substrate to form a gate capping oxide layer <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>&prime; on a sidewall and a top surface of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;, impurities are implanted into a first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> between the wordlines <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to form a first impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. In the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;, impurities are implanted into a second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> exposed to both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to form a second impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. A spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is conformally formed on an entire surface of a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> where the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> are formed. The spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is made of silicon nitride or oxide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, the spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is anisotropically etched to form a first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> on sidewalls of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. If the spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is made of silicon nitride, the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is also etched to form the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> and a second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> with a protruding part <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>protruding from the sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> while anisotropically etching the spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> If the spacer insulating layer <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is made of oxide, it is anisotropically etched to form a first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> on the sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Using the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> as an etch mask, the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is then etched to form a second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> with a protruding part <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> a protruding from the sidewall of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> corresponds to a charge storage layer. Following formation of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, impurities are implanted into the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to form a third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. As a result, a dual-structured impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> is formed in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> may be formed after or before formation of the second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Following formation of the second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, a second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) may further be formed in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; and the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. In the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;, the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> covers the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> and the sidewalls of the third and second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. In the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;, the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> covers the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. In this case, the third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> may be formed in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> following formation of the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the first and second impurity diffusion layers <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be formed following formation of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, and the third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> may be formed following the formation of the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in the drawings, constructions of the non-volatile memory devices according to the first and second embodiments are very similar to each other. A difference therebetween is that the third insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is self-aligned to the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, and thus a width of the third insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is identical to a width of the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> covers a sidewall of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, a sidewall of the third insulating layer <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and a top surface of the protruding part <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a top plan view illustrating a non-volatile memory device according to third and fourth embodiments of the present invention, in which reference numerals &ldquo;a&rdquo; and &ldquo;b&rdquo; denote a cell array region and a peripheral circuit region, respectively. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a non-volatile memory device according to a third embodiment of the present invention, taken along a line III-III&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16, a</cross-reference> device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>&prime; is formed in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to define a plurality of first active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;, and to define a second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. A plurality of wordlines <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> crossing over the first active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; and the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>&prime; are formed in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;. A stack insulating layer intervenes between the wordlines <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and the first active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime;, and includes a tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, a charge storage layer <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>, and a blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> that are sequentially stacked. It is preferable that the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>, and the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> are made of thermal oxide, silicon nitride, and CVD oxide, respectively. A sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> is covered with a first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, a gate capping oxide layer <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> may intervene between the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. Since the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> and the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> have larger widths than the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>, they have a protruding part <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> that protrudes from the sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. Therefore, although a high electric field is applied between the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; by a program voltage or an erase voltage, an electric field applied to the protruding part <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> is weak. As a result, a leakage current flowing through the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> and the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> each being formed over and under the protruding part <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> is considerably reduced to improve a soft program characteristic or a data retention characteristic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> covers not only the sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> but also a top surface of the protruding part <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, a second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>) may cover an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>, a sidewall of the blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight>, and a sidewall of the charge storage layer. A first impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is formed in the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; between the wordlines <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. Therefore, a first cell transistor is formed at an intersection of the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime;. In this case, the tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> under the wordline <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> has a uniform thickness. That is, a thick tunnel oxide layer caused by a bird&apos;s beak phenomenon is not formed at least under an edge of the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. Thus, a plurality of first transistors in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; have the equivalent threshold voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;, a gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> is formed to cross over the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. A gate insulating layer <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> intervenes between the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> and the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. A sidewall of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> is covered with the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> may be covered with a second sidewall spacer, as described above. The gate capping oxide layer <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> may intervene between the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>. Dual-structured impurity diffusion layers <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> are formed in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>. The dual-structure impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> includes second and third impurity diffusion layers <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>. As a result, the impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> corresponds to an LDD-type source/drain region, and the second impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> and the third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> correspond to a lightly doped diffusion layer and a heavily doped impurity diffusion layers, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> A difference between the first and third embodiments is that the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>&prime; is formed using a self-aligned shallow trench technology (S. A. STI). Accordingly, the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> includes an upper wordline <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> crossing the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; and a lower wordline <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> intervened between the upper wordline <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime;. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> may include a lower gate electrode <highlight><bold>281</bold></highlight> and an upper gate electrode <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> are cross-sectional flow diagrams for explaining the steps of fabricating the non-volatile memory device according to the third embodiment of the present invention, taken along a line III-III&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17, a</cross-reference> stack insulating layer <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> is formed on a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. After the stack insulating layer <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> formed in a peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo; is removed and a gate insulating layer <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> is formed, a lower gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight> and a hard mask layer are formed on an entire surface of the substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The hard mask layer, the lower gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight>, the stack insulating layer <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>, and the substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; and the hard mask layer, the lower gate electrode <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight>, and the substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are sequentially patterned to form a trench in a predetermined area of the substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the first insulating layer <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> is formed to a thickness of 15 &angst;-35 &angst; in order to make a tunneling of charges even in low program and erase voltages. As above-mentioned in the first embodiment, the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> is preferably made of silicon nitride to a thickness of 40 &angst;-100 &angst;, and the third insulating layer <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> is preferably made of CVD oxide to a thickness of 40 &angst;-120 &angst;. Thereafter, the trench area is filled with an insulating layer to form a device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>&prime;, and the hard mask layer is removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, the upper gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is formed on an entire surface of a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> where the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>&prime; is formed. The upper gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is preferably made of polysilicon, or polycide that is formed by sequentially stacking polysilicon and metal silicide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>, the upper gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and the lower gate conductive layer <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight> are sequentially patterned to form a plurality of wordlines <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> crossing the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;, and to form a gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> crossing the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. In the same manner as the first embodiment, a first impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is formed in the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; between the wordlines <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>, and a second impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> is formed in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>. A first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> is formed on sidewalls of a wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and a gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>. The wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> includes lower and upper wordlines <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> that are sequentially stacked, and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> includes lower and upper gate electrodes <highlight><bold>281</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>. Using the sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; as an etch mask, at least the third and second insulating layers <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> are etched to form third and second insulating layer patterns <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> between the gate electrode <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and each of the active regions <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> An edge of the second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> is extended to have a protruding part <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> that protrudes from a sidewall of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. The second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> corresponds to a charge storage layer, and the third insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> intervened between the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and the second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> corresponds to a blocking insulating layer. The first insulating layer <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> intervened between the second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> and the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; corresponds to a tunnel oxide layer. Following formation of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>, impurities are implanted into the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo; to form a third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>. Thus, a dual-structured impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> is formed in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; on either side (both sides) of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>. The third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> may be formed before or after formation of the second insulating layer pattern <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, a second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> may be formed in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; and the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. The second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> covers not only sidewalls of the third and second insulating layer patterns <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; but also the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. In this case, the first and second impurity diffusion layers <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> may be formed following formation of the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. Also, the third impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> may be formed in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; on either side (both sides) of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> following formation of the second sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view illustrating a non-volatile memory device according to a modified version of the second embodiment, taken along a line III-III&prime; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>, in a fourth embodiment of the invention, a device isolation layer is formed using a self-aligned shall trench technology (S. A. STI), like the third embodiment. Steps until formation of the gate conductive layer are identical to those in the foregoing modified version of the first embodiment. Subsequent steps are performed in the same manner as the second embodiment, forming a wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> crossing a first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; in a cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo; of a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and a gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> extended to an upper part of the device isolation layer <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>&prime; in the second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. A gate capping oxide layer <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>&prime; may further be formed on sidewalls and top surfaces of wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>. A tunnel oxide layer <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, a charge storage layer <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>, and a blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are sequentially stacked on the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; between device isolation layers <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and are intervened between the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime;. The blocking insulating layer <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is self-aligned to the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>, so that their widths are identical to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> A sidewall of the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> has a protruding part <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> a that protrudes from a sidewall of the gate electrode. A first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> is formed on the sidewall of the wordline <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and the protruding part <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> a of the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;, and on the sidewall of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight> in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. Furthermore, the second spacer <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> may be formed to cover the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> and a sidewall of the charge storage layer <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> in the cell array region &ldquo;a&rdquo;, and the first sidewall spacer <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> in the peripheral circuit region &ldquo;b&rdquo;. A first impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is formed in the first active region <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>&prime; between the wordlines <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>, and a dual-structured impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> is formed in a second active region <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>&prime; on either side (both sides) of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>283</bold></highlight>. The dual-structured impurity diffusion layer <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> includes second and third impurity diffusion layers <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, an edge of a charge storage layer is extended to have a protruding part that protrudes from a sidewall of a gate electrode. With a high defect density, edges of a blocking insulating layer and a tunnel oxide layer also protrude from the sidewall of the gate electrode, which results in a conspicuous decrease in a leakage current flowing through defect sites in the edges of the blocking insulating layer and the tunnel oxide layer. Thus, a data retention characteristic can be improved in comparison with the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the invention makes it possible to lessen deterioration of repeated operation cycle characteristics, and to form a tunnel oxide layer without a bird&apos;s beak under the gate electrode. Thus, the threshold voltage distribution range of memory cells can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art will readily implement the steps necessary to provide the structures and the methods disclosed herein, and will understand that the process parameters, materials, dimensions, and sequence of steps are given by way of example only and can be varied to achieve the desired structure as well as modifications that are within the scope of the invention. Variations and modifications of the embodiments disclosed herein may be made based on the description set forth herein, without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as set forth in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A non-volatile memory device comprising: 
<claim-text>an active region defined in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate electrode crossing over the active region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tunnel oxide layer, a charge storage layer, and a blocking insulating layer which are sequentially stacked between the gate electrode and at least the active region, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the charge storage layer has a protruding part which protrudes from a sidewall of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tunnel oxide layer and the blocking insulating layer are made of silicon oxide, and the charge storage layer is made of silicon nitride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the blocking insulating layer is self-aligned to the gate electrode to have the same width as a width of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a first sidewall spacer which covers the sidewall of the gate electrode and a sidewall of the blocking insulating layer, and is positioned on the protruding part of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a width of the charge storage layer is equal to the sum of the width of the gate electrode and widths of the first sidewall spacers covering both sidewalls of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a gate capping oxide layer intervened between the first sidewall spacer and the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second sidewall spacer which covers an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer and a sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the blocking insulating layer has a protruding part which protrudes from the sidewall of the gate electrode, and has the same width as the width of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a first sidewall spacer which covers the sidewall of the gate electrode, and is positioned on the protruding part of the blocking insulating layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the width of the charge storage layer is equal to the sum of the width of the gate electrode and widths of the first sidewall spacers covering the both sidewalls of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a gate capping oxide layer intervened between the gate electrode and the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second sidewall spacer covering an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer, the sidewall of the blocking insulating layer, and the sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A non-volatile memory device comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of parallel device isolation layers formed in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate to define at least one active region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate electrode crossing the active region and the device isolation layers adjacent to both sides of the active region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tunnel oxide layer, a charge storage layer, and a blocking insulating layer which are sequentially stacked between the gate electrode and at least the active region, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the charge storage layer is extended in parallel with the device isolation layer to have a protruding part which protrudes from a sidewall of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gate electrode includes: 
<claim-text>an upper gate electrode crossing the active region and the device isolation layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower gate electrode intervened between the upper gate electrode and the active region, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the tunnel oxide layer, the charge storage layer, the blocking insulating layer, and the lower gate electrode are sequentially stacked on the active region between the adjacent device isolation layers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer are extended in parallel with the gate electrode to cross cover the active region and the device isolation layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the blocking insulating layer is self-aligned to the gate electrode to have the same width as a width of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a first sidewall spacer which covers a sidewall of the gate electrode and a sidewall of the blocking insulating layer, and is located on the protruding part of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a capping oxide layer intervened between the first sidewall spacer and the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second sidewall spacer covering an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer and a sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the blocking insulating layer has a protruding part which protrudes from the sidewall of the gate electrode, and has the same width as a width of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a first sidewall spacer which covers the sidewall of the gate electrode, and is located on the protruding part of the blocking insulating layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a gate capping oxide layer intervened between the gate electrode and the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second sidewall spacer covering an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer, a sidewall of the blocking insulating layer, and a sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A non-volatile memory device with a cell array region and a peripheral circuit region, comprising: 
<claim-text>device isolation layers formed in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate to define a first active region and a second active region in the cell array region and the peripheral circuit regions, respectively; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate electrode crossing the second active region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate insulating layer intervened between the second active region and the gate electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of wordlines crossing the first active region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a stack insulating layer intervened between the wordlines and at least the first active region, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the stack insulating layer includes a tunnel oxide layer, a charge storage layer, and a blocking insulating layer which are sequentially stacked; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least the charge storage layer is extended across the wordlines to have a protruding part at both sides of the wordlines. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the wordlines includes: 
<claim-text>an upper wordline crossing over the first active region and the device isolation layers adjacent to both sides of the first active region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower wordline intervened between the first active region and the upper wordline, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the stack insulating layer and the lower wordline are sequentially stacked on the first active region between the device isolation layers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein gate electrode includes: 
<claim-text>an upper gate electrode crossing over the second active region and the device isolation layer adjacent thereto; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower gate electrode intervened between the upper gate electrode and the second active region, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the gate electrode and the lower gate electrode are sequentially stacked on the second active region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer are extended in parallel with the wordline to cross over the active region and the device isolation layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the blocking insulating layer is self-aligned to the overlying wordline to have the same width as a width of the wordline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a first sidewall spacer which covers a sidewall of the wordline and a sidewall of the blocking insulating layer, and is located on the protruding part of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second sidewall spacer covering an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer and the sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the blocking insulating layer has a protruding part which protrudes from the sidewall of the wordline, and has the same width as a width of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a first sidewall spacer which covers the sidewall of the wordline, and is located on the protruding part of the blocking insulating layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second sidewall spacer covering an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer, a sidewall of the blocking insulating layer, and a sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The non-volatile memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a source/drain region which is formed in the second active region at both sides of the gate electrode, and has a LDD (lightly doped drain) structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A method of fabricating a non-volatile memory device, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a stack insulating layer on a semiconductor substrate by sequentially stacking first, second and third insulating layers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate electrode crossing over the stack insulating layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a charge storage layer and a blocking insulating layer which are sequentially stacked between the gate electrode and the first insulating layer by patterning the third and second insulating layers, wherein at least the second insulating layer is patterned so that the charge storage layer has a protruding part which protrudes from a sidewall of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and third insulating layers are made of silicon oxide, and the second insulating layer is made of silicon nitride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>etching the third insulating layer by using the gate electrode as an etch mask to form a blocking insulating layer which is self-aligned to the gate electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first sidewall spacer on the sidewall of the gate electrode and a sidewall of the blocking insulating layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching the second insulating layer by using the gate electrode and the first sidewall spacer as an etch mask to form a charge storage layer whose width is larger than a width of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a steps of forming a gate capping oxide layer at least on the sidewall of the gate electrode prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a second sidewall spacer on an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer and the sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a first sidewall spacer on the sidewall of the gate electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially etching third and second insulating layers by using the gate electrode and the first sidewall spacer to form a blocking insulating layer having a protruding part under the first sidewall spacer and a charge storage layer which is self-aligned to the blocking insulating layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a gate capping oxide layer at least on the sidewall of the gate electrode prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a second sidewall spacer on the outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer, the sidewall of the blocking insulating layer, and the sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A method of fabricating a non-volatile memory device, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a device isolation layer and a stack insulating layer, wherein the device isolation layer is formed in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate to define an active region, and the stack insulating layer includes first, second and third insulating layers which are sequentially stacked at least on the active region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate electrode crossing the active region on the stack insulating layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a charge storage layer and a blocking insulating layer which are sequentially stacked between the first insulating layer and the gate electrode by patterning the third to second insulating layers, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least the second insulating layer is patterned so that the charge storage layer has a protruding part which protrudes from the sidewall of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and third insulating layers are made of silicon oxide, and the second insulating layer is made of silicon nitride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the device isolation layer, the stack insulating layer, and the gate electrode includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>sequentially forming a first insulating layer, a second insulating layer, a third insulating layer, and a lower gate conductive layer on an entire surface of the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially patterning the lower gate conductive layer, the third insulating layer, the second insulating layer, and the first insulating layer to form a trench region which defines an active region in a predetermined area of the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a device isolation layer to fill the trench area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a lower gate conductive layer on an entire surface of a resultant structure including the device isolation layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially patterning the upper gate conductive layer and the patterned lower gate conductive layer to form a lower gate electrode intervened between the gate electrode and the active region as well as an upper gate electrode crossing over the active region and the device isolation layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the device isolation layer, the stack insulating layer, and the gate electrode includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a device isolation layer to define an active region in a predetermined area of the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially forming first to third insulating layers and a gate conductive layer on an entire surface of a resultant structure including the device isolation layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning the gate conductive layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>etching the third insulating layer by using the gate electrode as an etch mask to form a blocking insulating layer which is self-aligned to the gate electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first sidewall spacer on the sidewall of the gate electrode and the sidewall of the blocking insulating layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching the second insulating layer by using the gate electrode and the first sidewall spacer as an etch mask to form a charge storage layer whose width is larger than a width of the gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a gate capping oxide layer at least on the sidewall of the gate electrode prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a second sidewall spacer on the outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer and the sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a first sidewall spacer on the sidewall of the gate electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially etching the third and second insulating layers by using the gate electrode and the first sidewall spacer as an etch mask to form a blocking insulating layer having a protruding part under the first sidewall spacer and a charge storage layer which is self-aligned to the blocking insulating layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a gate capping oxide layer at least on the sidewall of the gate electrode prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a second sidewall spacer on the outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer, the sidewall of the blocking insulating layer, and the sidewall of the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. A method of fabricating a non-volatile memory device with a cell array region and a peripheral circuit region, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming not only a device isolation layer in a predetermined area of a semiconductor substrate to define a first active region and a second active region in the cell array region and the peripheral circuit region, respectively, but also a stack insulating layer including first, second and third insulating layers which are sequentially stacked on the first active region, and a gate insulating layer stacked on the second active region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a plurality of wordlines crossing over the stack insulating layer, and a gate electrode crossing over the gate insulating layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning at least the third and second insulating layers to form a charge storage layer and a blocking insulating layer which are sequentially stacked between the first insulating layer and the wordlines, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least the second insulating layer is patterned so that the charge storage layer has a protruding part which protrudes from a sidewall of the wordlines. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and third insulating layers are made of silicon oxide, and the second insulating layer is made of silicon nitride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the device isolation layer, the stack insulating layer, the gate insulating layer, the wordlines, and the gate electrode includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>selectively forming the stack insulating layer on the substrate in the cell array region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>selectively forming a gate insulating layer on the substrate in the peripheral circuit region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a lower gate conductive layer under a resultant structure including the gate insulating layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially patterning the lower conductive layer, the stack insulating layer, the gate insulating layer, and the substrate to form a trench area which defines a first active region and a second active region in the cell array region and the peripheral circuit region, respectively; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a device isolation layer to fill the trench area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an upper gate conductive layer on an entire surface of a resultant structure including the device isolation layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a plurality of wordlines crossing over the upper gate conductive layer, and a gate electrode crossing over the second active region, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of the wordlines includes an upper wordline crossing over the first active region, and a lower wordline intervened between the upper wordline and the first active region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the gate electrode includes an upper gate electrode crossing over the second active region, and a lower gate electrode intervened between the upper gate electrode and the second active region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the device isolation layer, the stack insulating layer, the gate insulating layer, the wordlines, and the gate electrode includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a device isolation layer in a predetermined area of the substrate to define a first active region and a second active region in the cell array region and the peripheral circuit region, respectively; </claim-text>
<claim-text>selectively forming first, second and third insulating layers in the cell array region of a resultant structure including the device isolation layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a gate insulating layer on the second active region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a conductive layer on an entire surface of a resultant structure including the first to third insulating layers and the gate insulating layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning the conductive layer to form wordlines crossing the first active region and a gate electrode crossing the second active region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>etching the third insulating layer by using the wordlines as an etch mask to form blocking insulating layers which are self-aligned to the wordlines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first sidewall spacer on sidewalls of the wordlines, sidewalls of the blocking insulating layers, and the sidewall of the gate electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching the second insulating layer by using the wordlines and the first sidewall spacer as an etch mask to form a charge storage layer whose width is larger than a width of the wordline. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 57</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a gate capping oxide layer on surfaces of the wordlines and a surface of the gate electrode prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 57</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the second active region by using the gate electrode and the first sidewall spacer as an ion implanting mask to form a heavily doped source/drain region, before or after forming the charge storage layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 59</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the first and second active regions by using the wordlines and the gate electrode as an ion implanting mask, before or after forming the blocking insulating layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 57</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a second sidewall spacer on the outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer and the sidewall of the charge storage layer in the cell array region, and on an outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer in the peripheral circuit region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 61</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the second active region by using the gate electrode, the first sidewall spacer, and the second sidewall spacer as an ion implanting mask to form a heavily doped source/drain region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the first and second active regions by using the wordlines and the gate electrode as an ion implanting mask to form a lightly doped source/drain region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the first and second active regions by using the wordlines, the gate electrode, and the first sidewall spacer as an ion implanting mask to form a lightly doped source/drain region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of forming the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer includes the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a first sidewall spacer on the sidewalls of the wordlines and the sidewall of the gate electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sequentially etching the third and second insulating layers by using the gate electrode, the first sidewall spacer, and the first sidewall spacer as an etch mask to form a blocking insulating layer having a protruding part under the first sidewall spacer and a charge storage layer that is self-aligned to the blocking insulating layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 65</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of a gate capping oxide layer on the surface of the gate electrode and the surfaces of the wordlines prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00067">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 65</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the second active region by using the wordlines, the gate electrode, and the first sidewall spacer as an ion implanting mask to form a heavily doped source/drain region, following formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00068">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 67</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the first and second active regions by using the wordlines and the gate electrode as an ion implanting mask to form a lightly doped source/drain region, prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00069">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 65</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of forming a second sidewall spacer on the outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer, the sidewall of the charge storage layer, and the sidewall of the blocking insulating layer in the cell array region, and on the outer sidewall of the first sidewall spacer in the peripheral circuit region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00070">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 69</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the second active region by using the gate electrode, the first sidewall spacer, and the second sidewall spacer as an ion implanting mask to form a heavily doped source/drain region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00071">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The method of claim of claim <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the first and second active regions by using the wordlines and the gate electrode as an ion implanting mask to form a lightly doped source/drain region, prior to formation of the first sidewall spacer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00072">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The method of claim <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, further comprising a step of implanting impurities into the first and second active regions by using the wordlines, the gate electrode, and the first sidewall spacer as an ion implanting mask to form a light doped source/drain region, before or after forming the charge storage layer and the blocking insulating layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>11</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030001196A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
