<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002832A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002832A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002832A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002832A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002832A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002832A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002832</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09766563</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010119</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B006/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>F21V008/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>120000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>901000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>362</class>
<subclass>554000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Optical display apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09766563</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20010119</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09569811</doc-number>
<document-date>20000512</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6418267</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09569811</doc-number>
<document-date>20000512</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09482290</doc-number>
<document-date>20000113</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6304703</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Brian</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lowry</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Emlenton</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>PEPPER HAMILTON LLP</name-1>
<name-2>Attn: James M. Singer</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>50th Floor</address-1>
<address-2>500 Grant Street</address-2>
<city>Pittsburgh</city>
<state>PA</state>
<postalcode>15219</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A multiple optical fiber display module may be used in a Large Screen Display system. The multiple optical fiber display module includes at least two modular optical fiber display elements. Each modular display element further includes an optical fiber display tile, an optical fiber array, and an input matrix. The modular display module also includes a mounting frame for demountably attaching the input matrix of each modular optical fiber display tile to a single micro-display. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CLAIM OF PRIORITY AND RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority to, and is a continuation-in-part of, U.S. Utility patent application Ser. No. 09/569,811, entitled &ldquo;Micro-Display Driven Tiled Electro-Optic Display Apparatus,&rdquo; filed May 12, 2000, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety, and which is a continuation-in-part of U.S. Utility patent application Ser. No. 09/482,290, entitled &ldquo;Tiled Fiber Optic Display Apparatus,&rdquo; filed Jan. 12, 2000 which is also incorporated herein by reference in its entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This application relates to the provisional application of Brian C. Lowry and Jerald F. Lowry, entitled &ldquo;Contoured Screen Display,&rdquo; filed on the even date herewith, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Large screen display (&ldquo;LSD&rdquo;) technology enables the dynamic display of interactive and non-interactive content to large audiences. Applications of LSD technology are diverse and include public venues such as sports stadia, airports, and shopping malls. The wide range of applications drives a large and diverse market. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> With the development and deployment of LSD technology comes the opportunity for further refinement and improvement of the apparatus and business methods that support the technology. Significant enhancements made to state-of-the-art LSD apparatus and business methods will likely generate a substantial increase in market share. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In an electro-optical LSD system having multiple modular optical fiber display tiles connected to a single micro-display, maintenance of the system becomes an issue. In particular, if one of the modular optical fiber display tiles becomes damaged, all modular optical fiber display tiles connected to the same micro-display must be replaced. Thus, there is a need for a way to connect multiple modular optical fiber display tiles to a single micro-display such that the modular optical fiber display tiles are individually replaceable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The reliability of an electro-optical LSD system having a particular number of micro-display driven modular optical fiber display tiles is a function of the total number of micro-displays used. As the total number of micro-displays increases, system reliability decreases. For a given number of modular optical fiber display tiles, using a single micro-display to drive multiple modular optical fiber display tiles would therefore increase system reliability. Thus, there is also a need for a way to increase the reliability of an electro-optical LSD system having micro-display driven modular optical fiber display tiles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Electro-optical LSD systems having micro-display driven modular optical fiber display tiles may suffer from non-uniform color balance across the LSD surface. This results from non-uniform color balance between modular optical fiber display tiles, which is in turn a result of non-uniform color temperatures among the light sources, which provide illumination to the micro-displays, which drive the modular optical fiber display tiles. Thus, there is a need for a way to assure uniform color balance across substantially all or all modular optical fiber display tiles in an electro-optical LSD system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The current technology also does not provide a means for contouring an LSD surface comprised of multiple modular display tiles driven from a single micro-display. Thus, there is also a need for a way to provide a means for contouring an LSD surface comprised of multiple modular display tiles driven from a single micro-display. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention, the invention features a multiple optical fiber display tile module for use in an LSD system. The multiple optical fiber display tile module includes at least two modular optical fiber display tiles. Each modular display tile further includes an optical fiber display tile, an optical fiber array, and an input matrix. The modular display tile also includes a mounting frame for demountably attaching the input matrix of each modular optical fiber display tile to a single micro-display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another embodiment, the invention features a micro-lens array interposed between the micro-display and each input matrix. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another embodiment, the invention features an illumination source attached to and illuminating the micro-display.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic representation of a single modular optical fiber display tile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic representation of multiple modular optical fiber display tiles driven from a single micro-display.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to an apparatus having a single micro-display or Spatial Light Modulator (&ldquo;SLM&rdquo;) interconnected to multiple modular optical fiber display tiles for use in an Large Screen Display (&ldquo;LSD&rdquo;) system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> modular optical fiber display element <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes an optical fiber display tile <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, mechanically and optically connected to an optical fiber array <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and an input matrix <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> comprising the ends of the fibers in the array <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. A method for manufacturing and using modular optical fiber display elements <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is fully shown and described in pending U.S. Utility patent applications Ser. No. 09/569,811 entitled &ldquo;Micro-Display Driven Tiled Electro-Optic Display Apparatus&rdquo; and No. 09/718,745 entitled &ldquo;A Large Screen Fiber Optic Display With High Fiber Density and Method for its Rapid Assembly,&rdquo; both of which are commonly owned and assigned, and are herein incorporated by reference in their entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, multiple optical fiber display tile module <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes multiple optical fiber display tiles such as <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, a mounting frame <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>, an illumination source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> such as a halogen lamp, a micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, and a micro-lens array <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Mounting frame <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> further includes a first end <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and a second end <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>. Illumination source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> further includes an electrical power interconnect <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> for connecting to an electrical power source (not shown). Micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> further includes a video signal interconnect <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> for connecting to a video signal source (not shown), for the purpose of relaying the video signal to micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Illumination source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is demountably attached to the inside surface of mounting frame <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> at first end <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>. Micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is positioned and attached within mounting frame <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> relative to illumination source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> such that illumination source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> directs light through micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> toward micro-lens array <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Micro-lens array <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is positioned and attached within mounting frame <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> relative to micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> such that light directed toward it by micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is focused toward and into input matrix <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the micro-lens array includes a number of lenses equal to the number of fibers. Each lens directs light to a corresponding fiber. Micro-lens array <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is optional, however, and in an embodiment without a micro-lens array the light may be projected directly from the micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> to the input matrix <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. Each input matrix <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, of each modular optical fiber display tile <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> inserts into second end <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> of mounting frame <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. Optionally, mechanical contact of the matrix <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> may be made with micro-lens array <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Mounting frame <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> is designed to align each input matrix such as <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> with micro-lens array <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> via a sliding connection. The size of micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> dictates the size of each input matrix such as <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. For example, if micro-display <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> measures approximately 1 inch by 1 inch, then multiple optical fiber display tile module <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may include four optical fiber display tile modules <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> each having an input matrix <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> measuring approximately 0.50 inch by 0.50 inch. The above measurements are only intended to be exemplary. Preferably, for example, the micro-display has a size ranging from a 0.15 inch diagonal measurement to an 8-inch diagonal measurement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The advantages of this invention include one or more of the following. One advantage is that it enables the construction of a contoured electro-optical LSD display surface comprised of multiple optical display tile modules, each module driven from a single micro-display. A second advantage is that it allows the connection of multiple modular optical fiber display tiles to a single micro-display such that the individual optical fiber display tiles are individually replaceable. A third advantage is that it reduces the cost of replacing a damaged modular optical fiber display tile. A fourth advantage is that it increases the reliability of an LSD system comprised of multiple optical fiber display tile modules, each module driven by a single micro-display. A fifth advantage is that it assures more uniform color balance across the entire display of electro-optical LSD systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that the invention is not limited in its application to the details of construction and to the arrangements of the components set forth herein the following or illustrated in the drawings. The invention is capable of other embodiments and of being practiced and carried out in various ways. Also, it is to be understood that the phraseology and terminology employed herein, as well as the abstract included below, are for the purpose of description and should not be regarded as limiting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> As such, those skilled in the art will appreciate that the conception upon which this disclosure is based may readily be utilized as a basis for the designing of other structures, methods and systems for carrying out the several purposes of the present invention. Further, since numerous modifications and variations will readily occur to those skilled in the art, it is not desired to limit the invention to the exact construction and operation illustrated and described, and accordingly, all suitable modifications and equivalents may be resorted to, falling within the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">The invention claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A display tile module for a large screen display, comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) a plurality of optical fiber display tiles; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a plurality of optical fiber arrays, each array comprising a plurality of optical fibers, the arrays positioned so that each array is physically and optically connected to one of the display tiles; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a mounting frame having a first end and a second end, the first end and second end positioned substantially parallel to each other; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) an illumination source positioned between the first end and the second end of the mounting frame, the illumination source having a front and a rear, the illumination source being operable to project light from the front; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) a micro-display positioned within the mounting frame to receive the light projected from the illumination source and project light away from the illumination source; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) a plurality of input matrices positioned within the mounting frame to receive the light projected by the micro-display, each input matrix physically and optically attached to one of the optical fiber arrays.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002832A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002832A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002832A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
