<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001021A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001021A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001021A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001021A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001021A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001021A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001021</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09681929</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G05D023/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>236</class>
<subclass>047000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>236</class>
<subclass>051000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Methods and control unit for temperature controlled devices</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>George</given-name>
<family-name>Mazereeuw</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Freckleton</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JOHN S. BEULICK</name-1>
<name-2>C/O ARMSTRONG TEASDALE, LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>ONE METROPOLITAN SQUARE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 2600</address-2>
<city>ST LOUIS</city>
<state>MO</state>
<postalcode>63102-2740</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method for operating a temperature controlled device includes detecting a human presence status and controlling a temperature of the temperature controlled device based upon the detected status. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to temperature controlled devices and, more particularly, to controlling a temperature of a temperature controlled device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> At least some temperature controlled devices are refrigerant type cooling devices that include a compressor to compress a refrigerant and an evaporator that evaporates the refrigerant. During an evaporation process, the refrigerant expands and a temperature of the refrigerant lowers such that heat is absorbed providing a cooling of a main compartment of the cooling device. The evaporated refrigerant is then compressed by the compressor and then condensed into a liquid state by a condenser. The liquid refrigerant is then supplied to the evaporator completing the cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Cooling devices require energy for operation. To conserve energy, cooling devices are often maintained at one temperature during business hours and maintained at a second temperature higher than the first temperature during non-business hours to conserve energy. For example, a cooling device may be set to operate at 3&deg; Celsius (C.) during business hours and set to operate at 10&deg; C. during non-business hours. Accordingly, less energy is utilized to maintain the cooling device at 10C.&deg; than when the cooling device is set at 3&deg; C. One technique to vary the cooling device&apos;s temperature involves manually adjusting a thermostat during a business day. Manual adjustments relay on the performance of employees and as such may be unreliable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, a method for operating a temperature controlled device is provided. The method includes detecting a human presence status and controlling a temperature of the temperature controlled device based upon the detected status. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, a method for fabricating a temperature controlled device includes providing a human presence detector and coupling the human presence detector to the temperature controlled device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In a further aspect, a method for fabricating a control unit for a temperature controlled device includes providing a control unit and coupling a human detector to the control unit such that the control unit controls the temperature controlled device based on a human presence status. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, a control unit for control of a temperature controlled device includes a human detector.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an exemplary embodiment of a cooling device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front view of a control unit according to one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of the cooling device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an alternative embodiment of a control system.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an exemplary embodiment of a cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including a control unit (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). In one embodiment, cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a commercial refrigerator such as a Gamko model number GR 038600RS420 commercially available from Gamko Holding, AL Etten Leur, Holland. In another embodiment, cooling device is a stand alone cooling cabinet such as a GR-05013XSS420 stand alone cooling cabinet commercially available from Gamko Holding, AL Etten Leur, Holland. In another embodiment, cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a commercial bottle cooling cabinet such as Gamko Maxiglass cabinet model numbers MXB-20/150 and 20/250 commercially available from Gamko Holding, AL Etten-Leur, Holland. In a further embodiment, cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a commercial freezer such as Gamko model numbers GF-100600RS420 and GF-12513XSS420 also commercially available from Gamko Holding, AL Etten-Leur, Holland. Alternatively, cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a residential refrigerator or refrigerator/freezer unit such as a GE Profile Arctic Top Freezer/Refrigerator model number PTS22LBMWW commercially available from General Electric Company, General Electric Appliances, Louisville, Ky. In an exemplary embodiment, cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a known compressor (not shown), a known condenser (not shown), and a known evaporator (not shown). Cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> utilizes a refrigerant (not shown) to cool a main storage compartment <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> wherein cooled or frozen products are stored. In one embodiment, the refrigerant is either Ammonia or Freon. In another embodiment, the refrigerant is neither Ammonia nor Freon. Cooling devices <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> include, but are not limited to refrigerators, freezers, refrigerator/freezers, chillers, ice builders or ice makers, refrigerated cabinets, cold storage cells, walk in coolers and freezers, and other refrigerant type cooling units including units utilizing all refrigerants. Therefore, as used herein, &ldquo;cooling device&rdquo; refers to refrigerant type cooling units which have a compartment for storing cooled or frozen products. It is contemplated that the benefits of the invention accrue to heating devices such as commercial cooking appliances including commercial ovens, heating bins, and deep fat fryers, and domestic appliances such as residential ovens and cooktops. As used herein, &ldquo;heating devices&rdquo; refers to thermostatically controlled heating apparatuses other than furnaces. Additionally, it is contemplated that the benefits of the invention accrue to all temperature controlled devices and, accordingly, as used herein &ldquo;temperature controlled devices&rdquo; refers to all cooling devices and all heating devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front view of an exemplary embodiment of a control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes a human detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes human detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> coupled to a known control device such as a model TC-110 control unit commercially available from Elstat Electronics LTD, Lancashire, England. Control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also includes a temperature indication lens <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a mode indicator <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of function buttons <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a motion detector. In another embodiment, detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is an infrared detector. In a further embodiment detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a vibration detector. Control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is coupled to cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and controls a temperature within compartment <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is programmable to set a temperature of compartment <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> using signals from detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which indicate a human presence status. When detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> detects a presence of a human then the status is &ldquo;human present&rdquo; and cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is controlled at a first temperature. When detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> does not detect the presence of a human, then the status is &ldquo;human absent&rdquo; which is transmitted to control device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is controlled at a second temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> During operation, a retailer uses at least one cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to offer cooled products for sale. To lower or avoid energy consumption, control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is programmed to operate at a first temperature that is colder than a second temperature. For example, control unit is programmed to operate at a first temperature of approximately 3&deg; C. (Celsius) and a second temperature of approximately 10&deg; C. During business hours, detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> detects customers and/or employees passing by detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and because a &ldquo;human present&rdquo; signal is provided to control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the cooled product is maintained at approximately the first temperature. During non-business hours, employees and/or customers are no longer present, and because a &ldquo;human absent&rdquo; signal is provided to control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the cooled product is maintained approximately at the second temperature. Because it is typically less costly to maintain a higher temperature than a lower temperature within cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, lower energy costs are associated using control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> than without using control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Since the temperature is automatically adjusted based upon a human presence, and not in reliance on an employee making manual adjustments to the temperature, inherent risks of human error and forgetfulness are reduced. In one embodiment, detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is integral with control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In another embodiment, detector is not integral with control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) including control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), and illustrating a detection area <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> that is proximate cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. When a human is present within detection area <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is controlled at the first temperature as described above. Detection area <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes a length <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, length <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is adjustable by a retailer. In an exemplary embodiment, a time delay is programmed into control unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, such that cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is controlled at the first temperature for a specified period of time regardless of a human absent status. The delay is programmed based upon the retailer&apos;s traffic patterns. If a retailer is typically very busy during business hours, then a relatively short time delay of 10 minutes is programmed. If a retailer typically has extended non-busy periods during business hours, then a relatively long time delay of one hour is programmed. The time delay programmed reduces a number of on/off cycles for a cooling system (not shown) of cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In some cooling applications, the retailer or other owner of cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> does not desire any cooling during non business hours, and, during a status of &ldquo;human absent&rdquo;, a second temperature is not specified, and rather, the cooling system or cooling device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shut off when a &ldquo;human absent&rdquo; status is detected by detector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A time delay is also utilized to reduce cycling and the time delay is adjustable by the owner of cooling device to suit the owner&apos;s particular traffic patterns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an alternative embodiment of a control system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> including a control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> that is operationally coupled to a cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. A remote human detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is operationally coupled to control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is electronically coupled to control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. In another embodiment, remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is in wireless communication with control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Remote detector <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> detects a presence of humans in a detection area <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> that is distant from cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is programmed to set a temperature within a compartment (not shown) based upon signals from remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> representing a human presence status in detection area <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. When remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> detects a human, the status is &ldquo;human present&rdquo; and cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is controlled at a first temperature. When remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> does not detect the presence of a human in detection area <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> then the status is &ldquo;human absent&rdquo; and cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is controlled at a second temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> During operation, at least one cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> contains cooled products. Control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is programmed such that a first temperature is colder than a second temperature. For example, the first temperature is approximately 3&deg; C. and the second temperature is approximately 10&deg; C. During business hours, remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> detects customers and/or employees in detection area <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, and because a &ldquo;human presence&rdquo; signal is provided to control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the cooled product is maintained at approximately the first temperature. During non-business hours, remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> detects an absence of customers and/or employees, and because a &ldquo;human absent&rdquo; signal is provided to control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the cooled product is maintained at the second temperature. Because it is typically less costly to maintain a higher temperature than a lower temperature in cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, lower energy costs are associated using control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> than without using control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. Since the temperature is automatically adjusted based upon a human presence in detection area <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and not on an employee making manual adjustments to the temperature, inherent risks of human error and forgetfulness are reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> When a human is present in detection area <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is controlled at the first temperature as explained above. In an exemplary embodiment, a delay time is programmed into at least one of control unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and remote detector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> such that cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is controlled at the first temperature for a specified period of time regardless of a human absent status. The delay time is programmed based upon a retailer&apos;s traffic patterns. If a retailer is typically very busy during business hours, then a relatively short time delay of ten minutes is programmed. If a retailer typically has extended non-busy periods during business hours then a relatively long time delay of one hour is programmed. The programmed time delay reduces the number of on/off cycles for a cooling system (not shown) of cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. In some cooling applications, the retailer or other owner of cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> does not desire any cooling during non business hours, and, during a status of human absent, a second temperature is not specified, and rather, the cooling system or cooling device <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is shut off when a &ldquo;human absent&rdquo; status is detected by remote detector <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. A time delay is also utilized to reduce cycling and the time delay is programmed according to the owners particular traffic patterns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in terms of a controlling the temperature of a cooling device in a retail environment, it is contemplated that the benefits of the invention accrue to cooling devices not in a retail environment and to heating devices. For example, restaurant heating devices such as a grill and a deep fat fryer are typically operated at a first temperature during business hours and a second temperature during non-business hours. More specifically, a deep fat fryer is typically operated at a particular temperature during business hours and turned off during non-business hours. The fryer is typically turned on and off manually by an employee of the restaurant. However, if the employee forgets to turn off the fryer during non-business hours then the fryer consumes more energy than if the fryer was turned off. Additionally, a heating device inadvertently left on may pose a fire hazard. Accordingly, utilizing a human detector such as human detectors <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> to control the temperature of a heating device lowers energy consumption and facilitates a reduction in fires. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in terms of various specific embodiments, those skilled in the art will recognize that the invention can be practiced with modification within the spirit and scope of the claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for operating a temperature controlled device, said method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>detecting a human presence status; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling a temperature of the temperature controlled device based upon the detected status. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of detecting a human presence status comprises the step of detecting a human presence status utilizing at least one of a motion detector, an infrared sensor, and a vibration sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of detecting a human presence status comprises the step of detecting a human presence utilizing a motion detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of detecting a human presence status comprises the step of detecting a human presence status in an area proximate to the temperature controlled device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of detecting a human presence comprises the step of detecting a human presence in an area distant to the temperature controlled device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of controlling a temperature comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>specifying a first temperature of the temperature controlled device comprising a cooling device when the detected status is human present; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>specifying a second temperature of the temperature controlled device when the detected status is human absent, the second temperature higher than the first temperature. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of controlling a temperature comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>specifying a first temperature of the temperature controlled device comprising a cooling device when the detected status is human present; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>specifying a second temperature of the temperature controlled device after detecting a human absent status for a predetermined period of time, the second temperature higher than the first temperature. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of controlling a temperature comprises the step of turning off the temperature controlled device when the detected status is human absent. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of controlling a temperature comprises the step of turning off the temperature controlled device after detecting a human absent status for a predetermined period of time. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of controlling a temperature comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>specifying a temperature of the temperature controlled device when the detected status is human present; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>turning off the temperature controlled device when the detected status is human absent. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of controlling a temperature comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>specifying a temperature of the temperature controlled device when the detected status is human present; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>turning off the temperature controlled device after detecting a human absent status for a predetermined period of time. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of controlling a temperature comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>specifying a first temperature of the temperature controlled device comprising a heating device when the detected status is human present; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>specifying a second temperature of the temperature controlled device when the detected status is human absent, the second temperature lower than the first temperature. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of controlling a temperature comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>specifying a first temperature of the temperature controlled device comprising a heating device when the detected status is human present; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>turning off the temperature controlled device after detecting a human absent status for a predetermined period of time. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method for fabricating a temperature controlled device, said method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a human presence detector; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling the human presence detector to the temperature controlled device such that the temperature controlled device is controlled based on a human presence status. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of providing a human presence detector comprises the step of providing at least one of a motion detector, an infrared sensor, and a vibration sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of coupling the human presence detector comprises coupling the human presence detector to the temperature controlled device comprising a cooling device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of coupling the human presence detector comprises coupling the human presence detector to the temperature controlled device comprising a heating device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A method for fabricating a control unit for a temperature controlled device, said method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a control unit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling a human detector to the control unit such that the control unit controls the temperature controlled device based on a human presence status. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A control unit for control of a temperature controlled device, said control unit comprising a human detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said human detector comprises at least one of a motion detector, an infrared sensor, and a vibration sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said control unit configured to control the temperature controlled device based on a human presence status. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said control unit further configured to: 
<claim-text>control the temperature controlled device at a first temperature when said human detector detects a human present status; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>control the temperature controlled device at a second temperature when said human detector detects a human absent status. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said second temperature higher than said first temperature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said second temperature lower than said first temperature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said detector configured to detect a human presence status in an area proximate said control unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said detector configured to detect a human presence status in an area distant said control unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said control unit further configured to: 
<claim-text>control the temperature controlled device at a first temperature when said human detector detects a human present status; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>control the temperature controlled device at a second temperature after said human detector detects a human absent status for a predetermined period of time. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said control unit further configured to: 
<claim-text>control the temperature controlled device at a first temperature when said human detector detects a human present status; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>turn off the temperature controlled device when said human detector detects a human absent status. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A control unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said control unit further configured to: 
<claim-text>control the temperature controlled device at a first temperature when said human detector detects a human present status; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>turn off the temperature controlled device after said human detector detects a human absent status for a predetermined period of time.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001021A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001021A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001021A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
