<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001482A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001482A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001482A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001482A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001482A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001482A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001482A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001482A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001482</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10187724</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-39303</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01J029/80</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>313</class>
<subclass>404000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>313</class>
<subclass>407000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Color selection apparatus for color cathode ray tube</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jae-Ho</given-name>
<family-name>Jeong</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Busan-city</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Myung-Sup</given-name>
<family-name>Seo</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Busan-city</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sang-Shin</given-name>
<family-name>Choi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Suwon-city</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jae-Woo</given-name>
<family-name>Kim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Busan-city</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CHRISTIE, PARKER &amp; HALE, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 7068</address-1>
<city>PASADENA</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>91109-7068</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A color selection apparatus for a cathode ray tube. A mask frame having a pair of supporting members is disposed in parallel and spaced away from each other. A pair of elastic members is disposed between and coupled to the supporting members. A tensioned mask is coupled to the supporting members and is provided with a plurality of beam-passing apertures. A spring assembly includes a hook having a frame fixing part fixed on the mask frame and a spring fixing part and a spring fixed to the spring fixing part. The hook has a cut-away portion defined by cutting a portion of the frame fixing part. The cut-away portion forms a welding portion for welding the hook to the mask frame. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of Korean Application No. 2001-39303, filed on Jul. 2, 2001 in the Korean Patent Office, the entire disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a color selection apparatus for a color cathode ray tube (CRT), and more particularly, to a color selection apparatus for a CRT with a tension mask. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Generally, a CRT is designed to realize an image by electron-beams emitted from an electron gun and scanning a phosphor screen deposited with red R, green G and blue B phosphors. The CRT typically includes a panel with a phosphor screen at its inner surface, an electron gun for emitting electron beams, a neck portion for receiving the electron gun, a funnel for connecting the panel to the neck portion, and a color selection apparatus mounted on an inner surface of the panel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The color selection apparatus is disposed facing the phosphor screen to let the electron beams emitted from the electron gun land on the corresponding phosphors. The color selection apparatus includes a shadow mask functioning as an electrode, a mask frame for supporting the shadow mask, and a spring assembly for fixing the mask frame on the panel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The shadow mask is formed by drawing AK steel or INVAR steel after a plurality of beam-passing apertures are formed on the steel through a photolithography process. Since the shadow mask is very thin when compared with its large area and hundreds of thousands of apertures are formed on such a thin plate, its strength is very low. Therefore, the shadow mask may be easily depressed by outer shock or domed toward the phosphor screen by the thermal expansion caused by electron beams emitted from the electron gun. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> When the shadow mask is depressed or domed, the location of the beam-passing apertures is shifted. This may deteriorate the color purity as the shadow mask cannot precisely select the color. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> To develop a shadow mask suitable for the trend toward the large-sized and flattened CRT while solving the above described problems, Japanese laid-open patent No. H7-230760 discloses a tensioned mask that is fixed on the frame in a state where tension is applied thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> That is, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, tensioned mask <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> provided with a plurality of beam-passing apertures <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is tensioned in a vertical direction (in a direction of a Y-axis in the drawing) and welded on supporting members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> that are connected to each other by a pair of elastic members <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Supporting members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and elastic members <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> define mask frame <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> supporting tensioned mask <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Spring assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> for mounting mask frame <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> on an inner surface of the panel is mounted on each sidewall of supporting members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and elastic members <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Spring assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> includes hook <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> having one end welded on supporting member <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> or elastic member <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and spring <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> having a first end fixed on hook <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and a second end coupled on a stud pin (not shown) buried on an inner surface of the panel through coupling hole <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Hook <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> includes a high thermal expansion member and a low thermal expansion member that are joined to each other lengthwise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Tensioned mask <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and mask frame <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> that are integrally welded goes to a heat-treatment process including a darkening process. The darkening process is for forming a dark layer on tensioned mask <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> by injecting a mixture gas of air and propane into a darkening furnace having a temperature of about 610&tilde;620&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> However, when mask frame <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is subjected to a variable heat-treatment process and the process varies less than desired, tensioned mask <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may undergo elastic deformation due to the loss of its tensile force. The CRT&apos;s display quality can then become deteriorated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> To solve this problem, reinforcing member <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> having a thermal expansion coefficient higher than elastic members <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is welded on a lower portion of elastic members <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, a reinforcing member having a thermal expansion coefficient lower than elastic members <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is welded on an upper portion of elastic members <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Reinforcing member <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is deformed during the heat-treatment process so that tensioned mask <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is applied with a retraction force in a the curved arrow directions of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, thereby suppressing the elastic deformation of tensioned mask <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In addition, reinforcing member <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, hook <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and tensioned mask <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> sequentially go through the welding process in this order by a resistance welding at two or three welding points <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Here, the resistance welding is performed by applying a current of 6,000&tilde;7,000 amperes in a short time in a state where members to be welded to each other are overlapped and applied with a predetermined pressure, thereby welding the members to each other by melting the members using a heat resistance generated by a contact resistance between the members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> However, when welding the reinforcing member and the hook to the mask frame, the welding does not occur simultaneously but occurs in a predetermined time sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, due to the high heat generated during the welding of the first welding point, the members (reinforcing member, mask frame and etc.) to be welded increase in temperature. As a result, the contact area of the welding electrode is enlarged during the welding of the second and third welding points, thereby forming oxide layer which deteriorates the electric conduction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the welding force at the second and third welding points is lower than that at the first welding point, deteriorating the welding reliability. When a sample frame is used for checking the welding force to improve the welding reliability, the costs are increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, since the high current of 6,000&tilde;7,000 amperes is used for the resistance welding, the mask frame is magnetized at a magnetic flux density of about 60&tilde;70 gausses after the welding process is finished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, a degaussing process for reducing the magnetic flux density inevitably needs to be performed for the magnetized mask frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the present invention has been made in an effort to solve the above-described problems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention a color selection apparatus is provided that is reduced in its magnetic flux density, and avoids the need for performing a sampling test, thereby allowing naked eye inspection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A color selection apparatus for a cathode ray tube is provided. A mask frame having a pair of supporting members is disposed in parallel and spaced away from each other. A pair of elastic members is disposed between and coupled to the supporting members. A tensioned mask is coupled to the supporting members and is provided with a plurality of beam-passing apertures. A spring assembly includes a hook having a frame fixing part fixed on the mask frame and a spring fixing part and a spring fixed to the spring fixing part, wherein the hook having a cut-away portion is defined by cutting a portion of the frame fixing part, the cut-away portion forming a welding portion for welding the hook to the mask frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The cut-away portion may be formed by cutting a middle portion of one end of the frame fixing part. The welding portion is formed in the vicinity of a surface of the cut-away portion in parallel with the one end of the frame fixing part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the cut-away portion may be formed by cutting both sides of one end of the frame fixing part. The welding portion is formed in the vicinity of a surface of the cut-way portion in parallel with the one end of the frame fixing part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the cut-away portion may be formed by forming plural apertures on the frame fixing part. The apertures are formed in a circular-shape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The hook and the mask frame may be welded to each other by a welding process using a current less than 500 amperes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The hook and the mask frame may also be welded to each other by a tungsten inert gas welding process using a current of about 300&tilde;400 amperes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The spring and the hook may be welded to each other by a tungsten inert gas welding process using a current of about 300&tilde;400 amperes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The color selection apparatus may further include a reinforcing member for preventing the tensioned mask from being thermally deformed during a heat-treatment process including a darkening process, the reinforcing member being fixed on one of upper and lower portions of the elastic member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The reinforcing member and the elastic member are welded to each other by a tungsten inert gas (TIG) welding process using a current of about 300&tilde;400 amperes.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings illustrate an embodiment of the invention, and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a color selection apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a spring assembly according to a modified example of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a spring assembly according to another modified example of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a conventional color selection apparatus for a CRT.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a color selection apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention is employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As shown in the drawing, the inventive color selection apparatus includes tensioned mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> functioning as a color selection electrode, mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for supporting tensioned mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of spring assemblies <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for fixing mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> on a panel for a cathode ray tube. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Tensioned mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is formed by drawing AK steel or INVAR steel after a plurality of beam-passing apertures is formed on the steel through a photolithography process. Tensioned mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> provided with the plurality of beam-passing apertures <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is tensioned in a vertical direction (in a direction of a Y-axis in the drawing) and fixed on mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes a pair of supporting members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> arranged in a direction of an X-axis in parallel and facing the longitudinal sides of tensioned mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a pair of U-shaped elastic members <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for maintaining a space between supporting members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> at a predetermined distance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Spring assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for mounting mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> on an inner surface of the panel is mounted on each sidewall of supporting members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and elastic members <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Spring assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> having frame fixing part fixed on mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and spring fixing part B and spring <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> having a first end fixed on spring fixing part B of hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and a second end coupled on a stud pin (not shown) buried on an inner surface of the panel through coupling hole <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Each of the elastic members <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed of a U-shaped bar, and reinforcing member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is welded on elastic member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> so as to prevent tensioned mask <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> from being thermally deformed during the heat-treatment process including a darkening process </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is provided at its one end of frame fixing part A with central cut-away part <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>defined by cutting a middle portion of the end. In this case, welding portion <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for welding hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to the mask frame is defined in the vicinity of an end wall of central cut-away part <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in parallel with the end of frame fixing part A. The welding process is preferably performed in a TIG (tungsten inert gas) welding process using a welding current less than 500 amperes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The spring <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is welded at its two circular welding portions <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to spring fixing part B of hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Reinforcing member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is welded at its three circular welding portions <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to a lower part of elastic member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. At this point, since reinforcing member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is fixed on the lower part of elastic member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, reinforcing member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> should be selected from a material having a thermal expansion coefficient less than that of elastic member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in a high temperature range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The reinforcing member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may be fixed on the upper part of elastic member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In this case, reinforcing member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> should be selected from a material having a thermal expansion coefficient higher than that of elastic member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in a high temperature range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As described above, the TIG welding process for welding spring <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and reinforcing member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and elastic member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> uses heat generated by an arc electric discharge to melt the members and join them. The current used for the TIG welding process is about 300&tilde;400 amperes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The current of about 300&tilde;400 amperes used for the welding process prevents mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from being magnetized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In addition, welding portions <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> by the TIG welding process makes it possible for a user to inspect the welding quality through his/her naked eyes, thereby avoiding the sampling inspection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, portion C of frame fixing part A, which is not cut-away, from welding portion <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to the end of frame fixing part A, functions as a shock absorbing member when outer impact is applied to hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a modified example of the hook. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> A hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; of this example is provided with cut-away part <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;<highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>defined by cutting-way both side ends of frame fixing part A. In this case, a welding portion at which hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; welded is to mask frame <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be defined in the vicinity of the end walls defined by cut-away part <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;<highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>parallel with the end of frame fixing part A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, cut-way part of hook <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&Prime; may be formed of plural circular apertures <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&Prime;<highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed on frame fixing part A. At this point, welding portion <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is defined in the vicinity of the inner circumferences of apertures <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&Prime;<highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As described above, by using the TIG welding process using less than 500 amperes, particularly 300&tilde;400 amperes, for welding the members such as the hook, the mask frame, and the reinforcing member, the magnetization of the mask frame by the welding current can be prevented, making it possible to avoid the degaussing process. Actually, it is noted that the magnetic flux density of the mask frame of the present invention is less than 10 gausses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In addition, since the welding portion is designed to be inspected by the naked eye, there is no need for a sampling inspection, thereby reducing the manufacturing costs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> While this invention has been described in connection with certain embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the disclosed embodiments, but, on the contrary, is intended to cover various modifications and equivalent arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A color selection apparatus for a cathode ray tube, comprising: 
<claim-text>a mask frame having a pair of supporting members disposed in parallel and spaced away from each other and a pair of elastic members disposed between and coupled to the supporting members; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tensioned mask coupled to the supporting members and provided with a plurality of beam-passing apertures; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a spring assembly including a hook and a spring, the hook having a frame fixing part and a spring fixing part, the spring being fixed to the spring fixing part, the frame fixing part having a cut-away welding portion for welding the hook to the mask frame. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cut-away welding portion is a cut-away middle portion of one end of the frame fixing part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cut-away welding portion is formed in the vicinity of and in parallel with the one end of the frame fixing part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cut-away welding portion are cut-aways of both corners of one end of the frame fixing part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cut-away welding portion is in parallel with the one end of the frame fixing part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cut-away welding portion is a plurality of welding apertures on the frame fixing part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of welding apertures are circular-shape apertures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the hook and the mask frame are welded to each other by a welding process using a current less than 500 amperes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the hook and the mask frame are welded to each other by a tungsten inert gas welding process using a current of about 300&tilde;400 amperes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spring and the hook are welded to each other by a tungsten inert gas welding process using a current of about 300&tilde;400 amperes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a reinforcing member being fixed on one of upper and lower portions of the elastic member for preventing the tensioned mask from being thermally deformed during a heat-treatment process including a darkening process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The color selection apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reinforcing member and the elastic member are welded to each other by a tungsten inert gas welding process using a current of about 300&tilde;400 amperes.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001482A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001482A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001482A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001482A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
