<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003811A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003811A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003811</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09981310</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011016</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01R009/22</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>439</class>
<subclass>718000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>MODULAR LUG BLOCK ASSEMBLY</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09981310</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20011016</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09892901</doc-number>
<document-date>20010627</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<family-name>Chadbourne</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Merrimack</city>
<state>NH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HARRINGTON &amp; SMITH, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>4 RESEARCH DRIVE</address-1>
<city>SHELTON</city>
<state>CT</state>
<postalcode>06484-6212</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An electrical power connection block housing including a first housing piece and a second housing piece. The first housing piece forms at least a portion of a first exterior side of the block housing. An interior side of the first housing piece has a first slot shaped bus bar mounting area. The second housing piece is connected to the first housing piece. The second housing piece has a portion with a first side located directly opposite the interior side of the first housing piece and a second slot shaped bus bar mounting area on the first side of the second housing piece. The first and second housing pieces form a first bus bar receiving area with the first and second bus bar mounting areas located generally opposite each other on opposite sides of the receiving area for capturing a bus bar therebetween. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This is a continuation-in-part of copending application Ser. No. 09/892,901 filed Jun. 27, 2001 which is herby incorporated by reference in its entirety.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to electrical connectors and, more particularly, to an electrical connection block assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Brief Description of Prior Developments </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Power stud blocks are generally known in the art. For example, Marathon Special Products sells 600 Volt power stud blocks under the catalog numbers 1422122 and 1423122. Power stud blocks are generally used for AC or DC power distribution, such as for a DC circuit in a telecom application. Power stud blocks can be provided in two pole or three poll configurations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> There is a desire to provide an electrical power connection block which is smaller in size than conventional electrical power connection blocks. There is also a desire to provide an electrical power connection block which has modular components to allow multiple different types of connection blocks to be manufactured with use of common components. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> An electrical power connection block housing comprising a container and a cover. The container comprises multiple housing pieces connected to form at least two electrical connector receiving areas. Each connector receiving area has end apertures through opposite ends of the container at joints between the housing pieces. A first one of the connector receiving areas comprises two of the end apertures in a first one of the opposite ends and one of the end apertures in a second one of the opposite ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An electrical power connection block housing comprising a container and a cover connected to a top side of the container. The container comprises multiple housing pieces connected to form at least two connector receiving areas. The container has a first conductor pass-through aperture in an end wall open to a top open side of the container. The has a downwardly extending end side with a second conductor pass-through aperture aligned with the first conductor pass-through aperture. The end side of the cover has slits extending outward from the second conductor pass-through aperture forming cantilevered deflectable fingers extending up to the second conductor pass-through aperture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> An electrical power connector block housing comprising a first housing piece having a first interlock connection section; and a second housing piece having a first side with a second interlock connection section directly interconnected with the first interlock connection section and forming an electrical connector receiving area therebetween with conductor pass-through apertures at end joints between the first and second housing pieces at the end walls of the first and second housing pieces. The first and second interlock connection sections comprise mating projections and recesses. Leading edges of at least some of the projections of the second housing piece comprise a non-vertical surface located opposite a matching non-vertical surface in one of the recesses of the first housing piece such that a distance along a projection and recess joint between the non-vertical surfaces is longer than a height of the projection and recess joint.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The foregoing aspects and other features of the present invention are explained in the following description, taken in connection with the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top, front and right side perspective view of an electrical connection block assembly shown connected to electrical conductors and located on another member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top, front and right side perspective view of the assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> without the electrical conductors and with the cover located in an exploded position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of some of the components of the assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an exploded bottom, front and left side perspective view of some of the components of the assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an exploded bottom, rear and right side perspective view of the components of the assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view of the first interlock connection section of the first housing piece; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an exploded top, left side and front side perspective view of the housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective view of one of the bus bars used in the assembly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of an alternate embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternate embodiment of the bus bar shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a perspective view of another alternate embodiment of the bus bar shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a perspective view of another alternate embodiment of the electrical power connection block housing incorporating features of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the opposite end of the block housing shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of an electrical power connection block assembly comprising the electrical power connection block housing shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of the cover of the electrical power connection block shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is an end elevational view of the cover shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is an exploded end elevational view of the container housing pieces shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is an enlarged partial cross sectional view of a projection and recess joint between two of the housing pieces shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is shown a perspective view of an electrical power connection block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> shown attached to electrical conductors A, B, C and D and located on top of a mounting member E. Although the present invention will be described with reference to the embodiments shown in the drawings, it should be understood that the present invention can be embodied in many alternate forms of embodiments. In addition, any suitable size, shape or type of elements or materials could be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> generally comprises a housing <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and electrical bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>(see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; also referred to as bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). The housing <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> generally comprises a container <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a cover <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. However, in an alternate embodiment, the cover might not be provided. In the embodiment shown, the block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a two pole block assembly. However, as described below, features of the present invention can be incorporated into a three or more poll block assembly. In the embodiment shown, the block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is for a DC power distribution circuit. However, in an alternate embodiment, the present invention could be used as an AC power distribution circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Conductors A and C are connected to each other inside the block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and are connected to supply electricity from a battery. Conductors B and D are connected to each other inside the block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and are connected as a return to the battery. However, the conductors A-D could be connected to any suitable components. In addition, more or less than four conductors could be connected by the block assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The mounting member E could be any suitable type of component, such as a metal sheet member. The mounting member E comprises holes F therethrough. Fasteners (not shown) such as screws can be used to fixedly attach the block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the mounting member E by being screwed into the holes F and being located in the fastener receiving areas <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the container <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. However, In alternate embodiments, any suitable type of system for mounting the block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to another component could be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Referring also to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the container <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> generally comprises three housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. However, in alternate embodiments, the container <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> could be comprised of more or less than three housing pieces. The first and third housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are substantially mirror images of each other except at their bottom sections as will be described in further detail below. The first and third housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> form the outer sides of the container <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The first housing piece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> forms a left side. The third housing piece <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> forms a right side. The terms &ldquo;right&rdquo;, &ldquo;left&rdquo;, &ldquo;top&rdquo;, &ldquo;bottom&rdquo;, &ldquo;front&rdquo; and &ldquo;rear&rdquo; are used herein for reference only. The second housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is sandwiched between the first and third housing pieces. Thus, the second housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> forms a middle piece of the container <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The first housing piece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> generally comprises a bottom section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a side section <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, a front section <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and a rear section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The bottom section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> comprises a first interlock connection section <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. As seen best in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the first interlock connection section <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> comprises a side edge of the bottom section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> having two pairs of bottom slots <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, top slots <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and cover sections <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. However, more or less than two pairs could be provided. In addition, the first interlock connection section could have any suitable type of size or shape. For example, rather than molding the cover section <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> over the top slot, a piece of non-integrally-molded flat insulating material can be placed over the top slot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown, the top slots <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are located over the bottom slots <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The bottom slots <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extend into the side edge a further distance than the top slots <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The top and bottom slots are connected to each other, but the top and bottom slots or partially horizontally offset from each other in each pair. The cover sections <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are located over the top slots <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. In an alternate embodiment the cover sections <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> might not be provided. Front and rear ends of the bottom section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> also comprise slots <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The side section <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> has an interior facing side which comprises a bus bar mounting area. In the embodiment shown, the bus bar mounting area generally comprises a first projection <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a second projection <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The first projection <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has a general C shape and extends inward from the interior side. The second projection has a general reversed C shape and extends inward from the interior side. In the embodiment shown, the first and second projections are partially vertically offset from each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The C shape and reversed C shape each form a slot <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> which are vertically offset from each other. The slots <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> form receiving areas for one of the side edges of one of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as will be described in further detail below. In alternate embodiments, the bus bar mounting areas could have any suitable type of shape. For example, the bus bar mounting area might not comprise projections, but instead could comprise recessed slots. Alternatively, the projections could have any suitable type of shape, so long as the bus bar mounting area is adapted to receive a side edge of the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An exterior side of the first housing piece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> at the side section <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> comprises the fastener mounting areas <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The front section <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> comprises a recess <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The rear section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> comprises a recess <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The top side of the side section <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, front section <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and rear section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> form part of a cover mounting lip <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3, 5</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the second housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> generally comprises a bottom section <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, a middle section <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, a front section <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and a rear section <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The bottom section <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> comprises a second interlock connection section <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and a third interlock connection section <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The third interlock connection section <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is substantially identical to the first interlock connection section <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. However, in alternate embodiments, the first and third interlock connection sections could have different sizes or shapes. As seen best in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the third interlock connection section <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> comprises a side edge of the bottom section <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> having two pairs of bottom slots <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, top slots <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and cover sections <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. However, more or less than two pairs could be provided. In addition, the third interlock connection section could have any suitable type of size or shape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The second interlock connection section <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> comprises a side edge of the bottom section <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> having two pairs of bottom projections <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, top projections <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and, recesses <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> between the pairs. However, more or less than two pairs could be provided. In addition, the second interlock connection section could have any suitable type of size or shape. In the embodiment shown, the top projections <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> are located over the bottom projections <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The bottom projections <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> extend outward at the side edge a further distance than the top projections <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The top and bottom projections are partially horizontally offset from each other in each pair. The second interlock connection section <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is sized and shaped to mate with the first interlock connection section <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The middle section <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> has a side which faces the first housing piece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> which comprises a bus bar mounting area. In the embodiment shown, the bus bar mounting area generally comprises a first projection <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and a second projection <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The first projection <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> has a reversed general C shape and extends from the side. The second projection has a general C shape and extending from the side. In the embodiment shown, the first and second projections are partially vertically offset from each other. The C shape and reversed C shape form slots <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which are vertically offset from each other. The slots <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> form receiving areas for one of the side edges of one of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> as will be described in further detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As seen best in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the middle section <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> also has an opposite side which comprises a bus bar mounting area and which faces the third housing piece <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment shown, the bus bar mounting area on the opposite side generally comprises a first projection <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and a second projection <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The first projection <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> has a general C shape and extends outward from the side. The second projection has a general reversed C shape and extends outward from the side. In the embodiment shown, the first and second projections are partially vertically offset from each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The C shape and reversed C shape each form a slot <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> which are vertically offset from each other. The slots <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> form receiving areas for one of the side edges of one of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> as will be described in further detail below. In alternate embodiments, the bus bar mounting areas could have any suitable type of shape. For example, the bus bar mounting area might not comprise projections, but instead could comprise recessed slots. Alternatively, the projections could have any suitable type of shape, so long as the bus bar mounting area is adapted to receive a side edge of the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The lateral sides of the front and rear ends of the bottom section <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> also comprises slots and projections. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The front section <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> comprises two recesses <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The rear section <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> comprises two recesses <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The top side of the front section <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and rear section <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> form part of the cover mounting lip <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The middle section <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> has fastener holes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> into its top side. As seen with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, when the second housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to the first housing piece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the recesses <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>form an aperture <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> which allows the conductor D to pass through the housing <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Likewise, the recesses <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>form an aperture <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> which allows the conductor B to pass through the housing <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The third housing piece <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> generally comprises a bottom section <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a side section <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, a front section <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and a rear section <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The bottom section <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> comprises a fourth interlock connection section <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The fourth interlock connection section <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is substantially identical to the second interlock connection section <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. However, in alternate embodiments, the second and fourth interlock connection sections could have different sizes and shapes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As seen best in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the fourth interlock connection section comprises a side edge of the bottom section <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> having two pairs of bottom projections <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, top projections <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and, recesses <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> between the pairs. However, more or less than two pairs could be provided. In addition, the fourth interlock connection section could have any suitable type of size or shape. In the embodiment shown, the top projections <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> are located over the bottom projections <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The bottom projections <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> extend outward at the side edge a further distance than the top projections <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The top and bottom projections are partially horizontally offset from each other in each pair. The fourth interlock connection section <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is sized and shaped to mate with the third interlock connection section <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The side section <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> has an interior facing side which comprises a bus bar mounting area. The bus bar mounting area on the side section <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is substantially identical to the bus bar mounting area on the side of the middle section <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of the middle housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which faces the first housing piece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. However, in alternate embodiments, the two bus bar mounting areas could have different sizes and shapes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown, the bus bar mounting area in the side section <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> generally comprises a first projection <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and a second projection <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The first projection <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> has a general C shape and extends inward from the interior side. The second projection <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> has a general reversed C shape and extends inward from the interior side. In the embodiment shown, the first and second projections are partially vertically offset from each other. The C shape and reversed C shape each form a slot <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> which are vertically offset from each other. The slots <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> form receiving areas for one of the side edges of one of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> as will be described in further detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In alternate embodiments, the bus bar mounting area on the side section <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> could have any suitable type of shape. For example, the bus bar mounting area might not comprise projections, but instead could comprise recessed slots. Alternatively, the projections could have any suitable type of shape, so long as the bus bar mounting area is adapted to receive a side edge of the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An exterior side of the third housing piece <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> at the side section <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> comprises the fastener mounting areas <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The front section <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> comprises a recess <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The rear section <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> comprises a recess <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The top side of the side section <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, front section <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and rear section <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> form part of the cover mounting lip <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. As seen with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, when the second housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to the third housing piece <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the recesses <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> form an aperture <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> which allows the conductor C to pass through the housing <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Likewise, the recesses <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> form an aperture <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> which allows the conductor A to pass through the housing <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are adapted to be assembled to each other as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The first interlock connection section <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the second interlock connection section <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> matingly interlock with each other. Likewise, the third interlock connection section <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and the fourth interlock connection section <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> matingly interlock with each other. This forms the container <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The cover <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be placed on the container lip <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and fasteners <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) can fixedly attach the cover <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to the center section <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of the middle piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. However, the cover <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> might not be provided. The housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are preferably retained with each other by fasteners (not shown) located in the fastener receiving areas <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and attached to the member E. However, in alternate embodiments, any suitable means could be provided for fixedly retaining the housing pieces with each other separate from the member E, such as the cover <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Before the housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are attached to the member E, the conductors A-D or preferably attached to connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>which, in turn, are fixedly attached to the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>generally comprise a first section <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and a second section <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. The first section <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is adapted to be crimped or compressed onto one of the conductors A-D. The second section <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> as holes therethrough for mounting on posts of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. However, in alternate embodiments, the block assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> could be used with conductors having any suitable type or shape of connectors thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Referring also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, each bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> generally comprises a first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, a second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, and a connecting section <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. In alternate embodiments, the bus bars could be different from each other. The first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> comprises fastening posts <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. The second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> comprises fastening posts <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. The fastening posts <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> extend in an opposite direction from the fastening posts <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. Although the embodiment shown shows two fastening posts for each of the first and second sections <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, each section might comprise more or less than two fastening posts. In addition, rather than fastening posts, the bus bar could comprise any suitable means for fixedly and stationarily attaching the connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> One alternate embodiment of the bus bar is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. In this alternate embodiment, the bus bar <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> comprises a flat block of stock material with two sets <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> of fastener mounting holes <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. The fastener holes have enlarged counter-bored sections <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> which are adapted to receive a head of a fastener, such as a stud or screw, for clearance. Each set <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> has its counter-bored sections <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> on opposite sides of the bus bar. Another alternate embodiment of the bus bar is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. In this embodiment the bus bar <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> has tapped or threaded holes <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>. This allows the use of screws or bolts instead of nuts on studs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown, the first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is vertically offset from the second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. The connecting section <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> connects the first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> with the second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and connecting section <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> form a general Z shape. However, in alternate embodiments, the sections could form the bus bar in any suitable type of shape. For example, the first and second sections <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> might not be vertically offset from each other. The first and second sections could have notches on their respective top and bottom sides. Alternatively, the first and second sections could have raised sections on their respective top and bottom sides for receiving the second sections <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. For such alternatives embodiments, the slots in each of the bus bar mounting areas might not be vertically offset from each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The second sections <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> of the connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are mounted on the posts <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and the nuts <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> are attached to the posts <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> to fixedly and stationarily attach the connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. As seen best in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, the connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are located on top sides of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and extend towards the rear ends of the bus bars. The connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are located on bottom sides of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and extend towards the front ends of the bus bars. These connections could be made in a factory the housing pieces being mounted on the piece of equipment E with screws in cavities <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Conductors A and B could be installed during equipment installation when the electrical power is connected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> With the conductors A-D attached to the connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, and the connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> attached to the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are placed between the housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are then assembled to each other. During assembly, side edges of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are received in the slots of the bus bar mounting areas in the housing pieces. The two slots <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are located directly opposite each other. The two slots <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> are located directly opposite each other. The two slots <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are located directly opposite each other. The two slots <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> are located directly opposite each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> A right side edge of the right bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is located in the bus bar receiving area of the third housing piece <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the right side edge of the first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is located in the slot <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, the right side edge of the second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> is located in the slot <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, and the right side edge of the connecting section <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is located between the two projections <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. A left side edge of the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is located in the right side bus bar receiving area of the second housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the left side edge of the first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is located in the slot <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, the left side edge of the second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> is located in the slot <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, and the left side edge of the connecting section <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is located between the two projections <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. This stationarily traps the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>between the housing pieces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> at a predetermined fixed location. The top and bottom sides of the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>are spaced a predetermined distance from the top and bottom sides of the housing <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to provide a predetermined air clearance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> A left side edge of the left bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is located in the bus bar receiving area of the first housing piece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the left side edge of the first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is located in the slot <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, the left side edge of the second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> is located in the slot <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and the left side edge of the connecting section <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is located between the two projections <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A right side edge of the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is located in the left side bus bar receiving area of the second housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the right side edge of the first section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is located in the slot <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, the right side edge of the second section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> is located in the slot <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, and the right side edge of the connecting section <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is located between the two projections <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. This stationarily traps the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>between the housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at a predetermined fixed location. More specifically, the top and bottom sides of the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are spaced a predetermined distance from the top and bottom sides of the housing <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to provide a predetermined air clearance. The top connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>can also be removed from the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> without removing the bus bars from their connection with the housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> One of the features of the present invention is the use of both lateral sides of the bus bars to mount and entrap the bus bars between the housing pieces. Entrapping the bus bars in a suspended matter enables both sides of the bus bar to be used. This results in a much smaller electrical power connection block. This can take up less space on the member E. This invention can allow a method of making a factory connection at an OEM that enables the end user to make the power connection with a reliable lug terminal. The two pole lug block body described above consists of merely three molded plastic component housing pieces that interlock with each other trapping the two bus bars suspended in between them. The present invention uses the lateral sides of the bus bars as mounting ears for the bus bars. This can reduce the overall size of the connection block. If a three poll installation is required, then an additional center block <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and bus bar can be used side by side with the other components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Another one of the features of the present invention is in regard to the interlocking and keying nature of the interlock connection sections <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. As noted above, the projections <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> have different lateral lengths. Likewise, the recesses <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> have different lateral lengths. Thus, when the housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are connected to each other even if the housing pieces are not precisely flush against each other the overlapping nature of the housing pieces prevent air gaps at the seams between the top side of the bottom sections and the bottom sides of the bottom sections. This prevents a possible incorrect air clearance and oversurface clearance between the bus bars and the member E. However, in alternate embodiments, any suitable type of overlapping of the housing pieces at their connection could be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Another feature of the present invention is in regard to the modular design of the housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The housing pieces are easily assembled without any special tools. The keying nature of the interlock connection sections <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> prevent the housing pieces from being incorrectly assembled relative to each other. Referring also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, an alternate embodiment of the electrical power connection block is shown. The embodiment shown is for a three poll connection. Thus, the connection block <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> comprises three electrical bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>and connection block housing <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the connection block housing <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> generally comprises a first housing piece <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, a second housing piece <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, a third housing piece <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and a fourth housing piece <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. The first housing piece <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> is identical to the first housing piece <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the embodiment shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The fourth housing piece <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is identical to the third housing piece <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the embodiment shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The second housing piece <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and the third housing piece <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> are identical to each other. The second and third housing pieces <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> are identical to the second housing piece <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the embodiment shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Thus, three housing piece components can be used to form a housing container for either a two pole situation, as in the embodiment shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, or a three poll situation as in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. This can reduce manufacturing costs and inventory costs. For the three poll situation, a person assembling the housing components merely adds a second one of the middle housing pieces and an additional bus bar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> an alternate embodiment of the electrical power connection block housing will be described. The electrical power connection block housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is used to form an electrical power connection block assembly (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>) comprising the electrical bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the electrical connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight>However, in alternate embodiments, the assembly could comprise additional or alternative components. For example, any suitable type of bus bars or electrical connectors could be provided, such as the bus bars shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, for example. In addition, the assembly could be provided as a three poll configuration similar to that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The electrical power connection block housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> generally comprises a container <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and a cover <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. The container <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> generally comprises three housing pieces <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. The three housing pieces <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> are substantially the same as the three housing pieces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> except for the differences noted below. The three housing pieces form two electrical connector receiving areas. Each connector receiving area has end apertures through opposite ends of the container at joints between the housing pieces. Two of the end apertures in a first end of the container have top sides which are open at a top open side of the container. The top sides of these two end apertures are closed by portions of the cover <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. Similar to the embodiment shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, each bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is sandwiched between two of the housing pieces, each of the two housing pieces comprising slots which receive opposite lateral sides of the bus bars. However, in alternate embodiments, any suitable means for mounting the bus bars in the housing could be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The projections <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> of the first interlock connection section <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> of the first housing piece <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> comprises a leading edge with a non-vertical angled surface <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. The recesses <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> of the second interlock connection section <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> of the second housing piece <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> comprises a non-vertical angled surface <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> which is located opposite the angled surface <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. The projections <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> of the third interlock connection section <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> of the second housing piece <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> comprise a leading edge with a non-vertical angled surface <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>. The recesses <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> of the fourth interlock connection section <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> of the third housing piece <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> comprises a non-vertical angled surface <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> which is located opposite the angled surface <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Referring particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, an enlarged cross sectional view of the surfaces <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is shown when the housing pieces are assembled to each other. A same view would be seen with regard to the surfaces <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. The surfaces <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> are adapted to mate with each other at a joint <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. However, it is possible that the surfaces <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> might not contact each other along the entire length of the connection between the housing pieces. Thus, an air gap may exist between the surfaces <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> at the joint <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. Because the surfaces <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> are angled, the length L of the joint <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> is longer than the height H of the joint <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. The increased distance or length of the joint <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> provides an increased resistance to passage of electricity through the joint <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> to the mounting member which the assembly is subsequently mounted to. This increased resistance to passage of electricity is created by an increased length air clearance between the electrical components inside the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and members located outside the housing. Minimizing the height H of the joint <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> also enables the overall height of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to be minimized. Thus, the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> can have a lower profile which is beneficial if the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is located in an enclosure to allow cables inside the enclosure to be located over the top of the cover <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. It is a desirable feature of the present invention to minimize the overall size of the connector block assembly. In alternate embodiments, the surfaces <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the surfaces <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> could comprise any suitable type of shape to increase the length or distance through the projection and recess joints between the top sides and bottom sides of the interlock connection sections. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The container <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> also comprises an additional conductor pass-through aperture <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. The aperture <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> is formed at the end joint of the mating first and second housing pieces <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. Thus, the first electrical connector receiving area formed by the first and second housing pieces <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> comprises three conductor pass-through apertures <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>; two of the pass-through apertures <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> (on the return side) extending through the same end wall. The third aperture <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> into the first electrical connector receiving area allows a bonding conductor (not shown) to pass through the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and be connected to the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>The second electrical connector receiving area formed by the second and third housing pieces <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> comprises two conductor pass-through apertures <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Referring particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15 and 16</cross-reference>, the cover <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> comprises a downwardly extending end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment shown, the end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> is angled at an acute angle relative to a main section <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> of the cover <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> is angled relative to the main section <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> at an angle of about <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> degrees. However, in alternate embodiments, any suitable angle could be provided. In another alternate embodiment, the side end <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> could be curved. The end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> comprises two conductor pass-through apertures <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The apertures <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> are aligned with the conductor pass-through apertures formed at the top open end of the container <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. This alignment forms the apertures <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>. The end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> comprises slits <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> extending outward from the apertures <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment shown, the slits <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> are arranged in a general semicircular pattern. However, in alternate embodiments, any suitable pattern could be provided. The slits <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> are angled relative to each other at an angle of about 12 degrees. However, in alternate embodiments, any suitable angle could be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The slits form cantilevered deflectable fingers <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> in the end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> which extend up to the apertures <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> also comprises projections <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> which extend into the conductor pass-through apertures formed at the top open end of the container <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. However, the projections <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> might not be provided. Alternatively, any suitable type or shape of projections could be provided. In another alternate embodiment, any suitable means for closing a gap between the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and conductors passing through apertures into the housing could be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The use of the cover <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> allows the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to be used with relatively small conductors passing through the apertures <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> with a greatly reduced risk that a user could accidentally insert a finger through one of the apertures <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and accidentally touch one of the bus bars <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> or connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The angle of the end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> insurers that when the cover <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is connected to the container <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, the fingers <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> will all deflect outward in a same direction. This insures predictability to movement of the fingers <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and insurers a minimal gap between the fingers. If the end side <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> was not angled at an acute angle, the fingers <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> might deflect in opposite directions. The angle of the end side, thus, promotes proper behavior of the deflection of the fingers in an outward direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Referring particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and electrical connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>on the battery side of the assembly is substantially the same as the embodiment shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. However, the return side of the assembly comprises an additional electrical connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight>The first connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is connected to the mounting posts <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of the first connection section <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> as in the first embodiment. However, the third connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and a fifth connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>are both connected to the mounting posts <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> of the second connection section <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. The third and fifth connectors <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>are stacked with each other and fixedly mounted to the mounting posts <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. The fifth connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>extends in an opposite direction from the third connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>The fifth connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>extends in a same direction as the first connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>However, the fifth connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>is vertically offset from the first connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>because the two connectors are mounted to opposite sides of the bus bar <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>The conductors which are connected to the first connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the fifth connector <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>can extend out of the same connector receiving area at a same end of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> through the two apertures <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> It should be understood that the foregoing description is only illustrative of the invention. Various alternatives and modifications can be devised by those skilled in the art without departing from the invention. Accordingly, the present invention is intended to embrace all such alternatives, modifications and variances which fall within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing comprising: 
<claim-text>a container comprising multiple housing pieces connected to form at least two electrical connector receiving areas, each connector receiving area having end apertures through opposite ends of the container at joints between the housing pieces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover connected to the container, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a first one of the connector receiving areas comprises two of the end apertures in a first one of the opposite ends and one of the end apertures in a second one of the opposite ends. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a first one of the end apertures in the first opposite end has a top side open at a top open side of the container, and wherein the top side of the first end aperture is closed by a portion of the cover. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cover comprises a downwardly extending end side with an aperture aligned with the first end aperture to form a conductor pass-through aperture. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the end side of the cover comprises slits extending outward from the aperture in the end side which form cantilevered deflectable fingers extending up to the conductor pass-through aperture. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the downwardly extending end side is angled at an acute angle relative to a main section of the cover. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a first one of the housing pieces comprises a first interlock connection section and a second one of the housing pieces comprises a first side with a second interlock connection section directly interconnected with the first interlock connection section, wherein the first and second interlock connection sections comprise a mating projection and recess, and wherein a leading edge of the projection comprises an angled surface located opposite an angled surface in the recess such that a distance along a projection and recess joint between the angled surfaces is longer than a height of the projection and recess joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the downwardly extending end side of the cover comprises projections which extend into at least two of the end apertures in the first opposite end of the container. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>an electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 1;</dependent-claim-reference> and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an electrical bus bar sandwiched between two of the housing pieces, each of the two housing pieces comprising slots which receive opposite lateral sides of the bus bar. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electrical bus bar comprises a first section with at least one first fastening post extending in a first direction and a second section with at least one second fastening post extending in an opposite second direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first section is at least partially vertically offset from the second section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a first electrical connector connected to the first section and extending towards the first opposite end of the container, a second electrical connector connected to the second section and extending towards a second one of the opposite ends of the container, and a third electrical connector connected to the second section and extending towards the first opposite end of the container. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second and third electrical connectors are both mounted on the second fastening post. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing comprising: 
<claim-text>a container comprising multiple housing pieces connected to form at least two connector receiving areas, the container having a first conductor pass-through aperture in an end wall open to a top open side of the container; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover connected to the top side of the container, the cover having a downwardly extending end side with a second conductor pass-through aperture aligned with the first conductor pass-through aperture, the end side of the cover having slits extending outward from the second conductor pass-through aperture forming cantilevered deflectable fingers extending up to the second conductor pass-through aperture. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the downwardly extending end side is angled at an acute angle relative to a main section of the cover. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the downwardly extending end side of the cover comprises a projection which extends into the first conductor pass-through aperture of the container. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the container comprises a separate second conductor pass-through aperture in the end wall located below the first conductor pass-through, and wherein both the first and second conductor pass-throughs extend into a same one of the connector receiving areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the container comprises a separate third conductor pass-through aperture in an opposite end wall extending into the same connector receiving area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connection block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a first one of the housing pieces comprises a first interlock connection section and a second one of the housing pieces comprises a first side with a second interlock connection section directly interconnected with the first interlock connection section, wherein the first and second interlock connection sections comprise a mating projection and recess, and wherein a leading edge of the projection comprises an angled surface located opposite an angled surface in the recess such that a distance along a projection and recess joint between the angled surfaces is longer than a height of the projection and recess joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connector block housing comprising: 
<claim-text>a first housing piece having a first interlock connection section; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second housing piece having a first side with a second interlock connection section directly interconnected with the first interlock connection section and forming an electrical connector receiving area therebetween with conductor pass-through apertures at end joints between the first and second housing pieces at the end walls of the first and second housing pieces, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and second interlock connection sections comprise mating projections and recesses, and wherein leading edges of at least some of the projections of the second housing piece comprise a non-vertical surface located opposite a matching non-vertical surface in one of the recesses of the first housing piece such that a distance along a projection and recess joint between the non-vertical surfaces is longer than a height of the projection and recess joint. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An electrical power connector block housing as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a cover connected to a top side of the first and second housing pieces, the cover having a downwardly extending end side with a second conductor pass-through aperture aligned with a first one of the conductor pass-through apertures formed at the end joint, the end side of the cover having slits extending outward from the second conductor pass-through aperture forming cantilevered deflectable fingers extending up to the second conductor pass-through aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030003811A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
