<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000616A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000616A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000616A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000616A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000616</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10149042</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020603</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>9928630.4</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19991204</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B60C011/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B60C009/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>152</class>
<subclass>209500</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>152</class>
<subclass>209110</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>152</class>
<subclass>532000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Motor-cycle radial tyre</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>Robert</middle-name>
<family-name>Watkins</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Sutton Coldfield</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gary</given-name>
<middle-name>Terence</middle-name>
<family-name>Barrett</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Sutton Coldfield</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>David L King</name-1>
<name-2>The Goodyear Tire &amp; Rubber Company</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Patent &amp; Trademark Department 823</address-1>
<address-2>1144 East Market Street</address-2>
<city>Akron</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>44316-0001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/GB00/04582</doc-number>
<document-date>20001201</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A motor-cycle tire (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) comprising a ground contacting tread (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) reinforced between its edges (<highlight><bold>3,4</bold></highlight>) by a breaker assembly and having in its normally inflated fitted condition a camber value C/L of between 0.5 and 0.7, a reinforcing carcass ply (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) extending radially inside the breaker assembly and between two bead regions (<highlight><bold>10,11</bold></highlight>) and wrapped in each bead region around an annular bead core (<highlight><bold>12,13</bold></highlight>) from the axial inside to the outside to form carcass ply turn-ups (<highlight><bold>15,16</bold></highlight>) and between the tread edges (<highlight><bold>3,4</bold></highlight>) and bead regions (<highlight><bold>10,11</bold></highlight>), tire sidewalls (<highlight><bold>8,9</bold></highlight>) wherein the breaker assembly comprises two breaker plies (<highlight><bold>5,7</bold></highlight>) comprising reinforcing cords oppositely inclined with respect to the circumferential direction of the tire characterized in that the tread comprises two different rubber compounds, the first rubber compound extending in a continuous first layer between the tread edges (<highlight><bold>3,4</bold></highlight>) and the second rubber compound being disposed in a second layer radially outwardly of the layer of the first rubber compound to form the tread running surface in the central portion of the tread. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to radial motor-cycle tires and in particular but not exclusively to high performance or race motor-cycle tires. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Such tires utilize very wide treads which in transverse cross-section are sharply curved to provide good contact with the road surface when the motor-cycle is steeply banked in cornering. Maintenance of a consistent ground contact area or &lsquo;tire footprint&rsquo; under all conditions is a major problem in determining general vehicle handling. Of particular importance in race motor-cycle tires of radial construction is the provision of high cornering power with the good stability to maximise cornering speeds under race conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Present radial motor-cycle race tires have short sidewalls which extend to the tread edges radially and axially outwardly from the tire beads. The beads provide engagement to the wheelrim on tapered bead seats. The sidewalls are reinforced by radial carcass plies which when tensioned by the inflation pressure act together with sidewall geometry to provide location of the curved tread regions to withstand cornering forces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The sharply curved tread region of the tire is specially reinforced by a reinforcing breaker to give the required structural rigidity to allow for banking over of the motorcycle when cornering whilst giving sufficient flexibility to allow localised tread flattening in the ground contact patch for good road grip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Also in the art EP-A-774 367 proposes the use of two different tread compounds for a motorcycle race tire where one side of the tread is provided with high grip compound and the other side with a harder compound. The construction is prepared for race circuits where the majority of bends are in the same direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Also Japanese Patent Publication 61-211106 discloses a motorcycle tire with a tread formed with three separate compound zones each of which is at full tread thickness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Such tires however, do not provide fully optimum performance with regard to tread durability. It therefore an object of the present invention is to improve the properties of such tires. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Accordingly the present invention provides a motorcycle tire having the features set out in claim 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> By camber value is meant the ratio C/L between the radial distance C from the centre to the edge of the tire tread and the axial distance L between the centre and edge of the tread.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Further aspects of the present invention will become apparent from the description of the following embodiments in conjunction with the attached diagrammatic drawing in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows in cross-section a 170/60 R17 radial motor-cycle tire intended for high speed racing.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The tire <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> comprises a pair of sidewalls <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> terminating in bead regions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Each bead region is reinforced by an inextensible annular bead core <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Extending between each bead region is a tire carcass reinforcement ply <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> which is anchored in each bead region by being turned around the respective bead core <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> laterally from the inside to the -outside to form a ply turn-up <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The carcass reinforcement ply <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> comprises a single ply of tire fabric laid with nylon cords substantially radially. Each bead region <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> further comprises a hard rubber apex member <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> which is anchored to each respective bead core <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and extends taperingly radially outwardly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The carcass ply fabric of the present tire may also comprise polyester, rayon or aramid cords. Further whilst a single ply carcass of cords at substantially <highlight><bold>900</bold></highlight> may be particularly advantageous in the case of tires for the rear wheel of the motorcycle, for the front wheel a tire with two plies of cords crossed at an angle of 70&deg;-88&deg; may be advantageous. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The tire <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a camber value of 0.6 and comprises a convex tread region <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, having tread edges <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, reinforced by a breaker assembly. The width TW of the tread is 220 mm measured along the outer surface. The breaker assembly comprises two breaker plies <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> each of which comprises Kevlar (Registered Trade Mark) aramid cord tire fabric each of 2/165 TEX. The cords in each of the breaker plies <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are oppositely inclined to each other at an angle of 25&deg; to the circumferential direction of the tire. The radially inner breaker ply <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> has a width Bi of 200 mm and is narrower than the radially outer breaker ply <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> which has a width Bo of 220 mm. The breaker plies may also comprise steel cords. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> As evident from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> the tread of the tire comprises two distinct layers of rubber. The first rubber layer RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> extends continuously between the tread edges <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In the central tread portion a second rubber layer RL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is disposed radially outward of the first rubber layer RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and centred on the tire circumferential centreline C/L. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The tread ground contacting surface comprises in the centre the rubber compound of the second rubber layer and to either side in the lateral regions a different rubber compound of the first rubber layer RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The portion of the first rubber layer RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> extending radially inward of the second rubber layer has a thickness of 2 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> At the boundary between the first and second rubber layer is disposed an interfacial fabric layer which comprises in this embodiment a rubberised cut fabric ply. This ply comprises nylon cords disposed in mutually parallel configuration and at an angle of between 18&deg;-30&deg; preferably 25&deg; to the tire circumferential direction. In accordance with the invention the interfacial fabric may comprise other textile materials common in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The second layer of rubber RL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a width S which is 40% of the tread width TW. According to the invention this width may be in the range of 30%-50%. If the second rubber layer width exceeds 50% of the tread width then the second rubber compound extends too far into the lateral regions of the tread and the cornering performance of the tire deteriorates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The compound properties of the rubber of the first layer RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are such that the material provides good grip on cornering whilst those of the rubber of the second layer RL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are to give low temperature generation in straight running. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Preferably the properties of the rubber layer of RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are characterised by a hardness value at 100&deg; C. of between 40-49 Shore &lsquo;A&rsquo; and a tensile modulus at 100&deg; C. and 300% extension of less than 5.0 MPa. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In contrast the properties of the second rubber layer RL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are preferably a hardness value at <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>&deg; C. of not less than 50 Shore &lsquo;A&rsquo; and a tensile modulus at 100&deg; C. and 300% extension of not less than 5.0 MPa. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Example formulations of rubber compounds suitable for the invention are shown in Table 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The formulation A is a compound suitable for the softer first rubber layer RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> whilst compound B is suitable for the harder second rubber layer RL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The polymer type can be emulsion or solution polymerised styrene butadiene (SBR) and may contain 20-50% styrene, preferably 25-45%. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The reinforcing filler may be either carbon black as shown or silica or a blend of both. The total amount of filler present may be from 15 to 160 parts by weight per hundred parts by weight of styrene-butadiene rubber. Preferably the filler is present in an amount from 30 to 120 parts of the rubber. If silica is used, then this may be in conjunction with a coupling agent, preferably a silane coupling agent, e.g. bis 1,3-triethoxy-silyl propyl tetrasulphide. Silica may have a surface area 60-300 m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/g, preferably 80-250 m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/g and is preferably precipitated silica. The coupling agent may be used in the amount from 2-18.5% by weight of silica filler, preferably 5-12% by weight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The carbon black may be a high surface area carbon black of SAF or ISAF type, having a surface area 80-300 m<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/g and be present at 15 to 160 and preferably 30 to 120 parts by weight per 100 parts by weight of styrene-butadiene rubber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The oil in the composition is preferably an aromatic oil and may be present from 10 to 180 parts by weight per hundred rubber, preferably 15 to 120. Suitable aromatic oils are well known to a man skilled in the art. Preferably they have a specific gravity from 0.95-1.0. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The rubber compounds may contain conventional additives, e.g. accelerators, activators, extenders and anti-degradants as desired. The vulcanisation agent is preferably sulphur or a sulphur-containing compound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The resultant tires have been found to have good precision under the slower speed involved in cornering and due to the lower temperature generation in the second rubber compound the tire also has improved durability at high speed running. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Whilst the presence of the interfacial fabric is preferred most of the advantages of the present invention can be obtained if it is omitted.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="119PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="77PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>A</entry>
<entry>B</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="77PT" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Solution SBR</entry>
<entry>145</entry>
<entry>145</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Carbon black</entry>
<entry>90</entry>
<entry>109</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Aromatic oil</entry>
<entry>44</entry>
<entry>44</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Zinc oxide</entry>
<entry>4.0</entry>
<entry>4.0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Stearic acid</entry>
<entry>1.3</entry>
<entry>1.3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Anti-degradants</entry>
<entry>4.0</entry>
<entry>4.0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Processing aid</entry>
<entry>3.0</entry>
<entry>3.0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Accelerator</entry>
<entry>2.6</entry>
<entry>3.3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Sulphur</entry>
<entry>1.5</entry>
<entry>1.9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A motor-cycle tire (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) comprising a ground contacting tread (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) reinforced between its edges (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) by a breaker assembly and having in its normally inflated fitted condition a camber value C/L of between 0.5 and 0.7, a reinforcing carcass ply (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) extending radially inside the breaker assembly and between two bead regions (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) and wrapped in each bead region around an annular bead core (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) from the axial inside to the outside to form carcass ply turn-ups (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) and between the tread edges (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and bead regions (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>), tire sidewalls (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) wherein the breaker assembly comprises two breaker plies (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) comprising reinforcing cords oppositely inclined with respect to the circumferential direction of the tire characterised in that the tread comprises two different rubber compounds, a first rubber compound extending in a continuous first layer between the tread edges (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and a second rubber compound disposed in a second layer radially outwardly of the layer of the first rubber compound to form the tread running surface in the central portion of the tread, centred on the tire axial centreline, having a width (S) of between 30% and 50% of the tread width (TW), the widths being measured along the arc of the tread surface, and on an interfacial fabric layer disposed at the boundary between the first and second rubber layers, the cords of the fabric layer are laid parallel to each other and disposed at an angle of 18&deg;-30&deg; to the tread circumferential direction and radial thickness of the second layer of rubber is between 50% and 80% of the total radial thickness of the tread. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A tire according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised in that the interfacial fabric layer comprises nylon cords. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A tire according to any of claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, characterised in that the radial thickness (t) of the portion of first rubber layer radially inward of the second layer is not less than 2 mm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A tire according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">3</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised in that the hardness of the rubber of the first rubber layer (RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) at 100&deg; C. lies in range 40-49 Shore &lsquo;A&rsquo;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A tire according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">4</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised in that the first rubber layer (RL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) has a tensile modulus at 300% extension at 100&deg; C. of less than 5.0 MPa. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A tire according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">5</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised in that the rubber of the second rubber layer (RL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) has a hardness at 100&deg; C. of not less than 500 Shore &lsquo;A&rsquo;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A tire according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, characterised in that the rubber of the second rubber layer (RL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) has a tensile modulus at 300% extension at 100&deg; C. of not less than 5.0 MPa.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000616A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000616A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
