<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001113A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001113A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001113A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001113A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001113A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001113A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001113A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001113A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001113A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001113A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001113A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001113A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001113A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001113A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001113</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10183780</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020625</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61L002/10</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>250</class>
<subclass>50400R</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Device to disinfect air or surfaces with radiation and method therefor</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301903</doc-number>
<document-date>20010629</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Witham</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ventura</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<family-name>Arance</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Valencia</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Ultra Violate, a California Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CISLO &amp; THOMAS, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>233 WILSHIRE BLVD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 900</address-2>
<city>SANTA MONICA</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90401-1211</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Interlocking, modular anti-microbial Radiation fixtures mount on a custom rack or bracket, which are used to irradiate an air stream and/or surfaces within an HVAC (heating, ventilating, air conditioning) system. The individual units are adapted for modular integration and slidable mounting on a rack, bracket or fixture which allows for ease of installation. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This patent application is related to U.S. Provisional Patent Application Serial No. 60/301903 filed Jun. 29, 2001 for DEVICE TO DISINFECT AIR OR SURFACES WITH UV LIGHT AND METHOD THEREFOR, which application is incorporated herein by this reference thereto.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">COPYRIGHT AUTHORIZATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A portion of the disclosure of this patent document contains material which is subject to copyright protection. The copyright owner has no objection to the facsimile reproduction by any one of the patent disclosure as it appears in the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office patent files or records, but otherwise reserves all copyright rights whatsoever. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to anti-microbial radiation fixtures within HVAC equipment. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to modular, anti-microbial radiation fixtures that may be positioned in tandem to provide adequate radiation coverage of large areas as may be found in heating, ventilating and air conditioning systems. Previous approaches have entailed using hard wired fixtures, with the necessity for many wires and cable running throughout the installation, or complex and expensive connection methods. The fixtures are generally mounted on a support structure within the equipment. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> This invention consists of interlocking, modular anti-microbial radiation fixtures that mount on a custom rack or bracket, which in turn are used to irradiate an air stream and/or surfaces within an HVAC (heating, ventilating, air conditioning) system such as filter elements, air conditioning coils, drip pans and duct wall surfaces, thereby reducing the formation of molds and fungus on those surfaces. The operating fixtures may also reduce fungi, bacteria and virus in a moving air stream within which they are used. The invention may utilize inexpensive electrical connections in combination with a simple mechanical locking method. Each module engages mechanically and electrically with the next one and the desired coupled component is in turn slid into position on a rack support or bracket with final connection to power being in the form of a cable which plugs into the last unit of the set. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the present invention to provide interlocking, modular anti-microbial radiation fixtures that mount on a custom rack or bracket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide a means of having modular fixtures that are positioned in tandem and which may be combined to adequately cover a large variety of applications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is still another important object of the invention to provide a modular anti-microbial radiation fixture that may be connected in tandem fashion with a like fixture so as to provide an assembled fixture for a variety of end uses and applications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> It is still another important, specific object of the invention to provide radiation fixture modules that are integrateable to form a specific designed fixture in cooperation with a bracket or rack wherein the assembled device may have a wide application of uses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> These and other objects and advantages of the present invention will be apparent from a review of the following specification and accompanying figures.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.: A typical fixture of this invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>.: A detail showing one end plug and mechanical latch for inter-connecting the units both mechanically and electrically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>.: An enlarged detail showing the opposite end connection from that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> and depicting slots for track mounting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>.: A detail showing two of the modular units inter-connected end to end or in tandem. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>.: A typical fixture mounted on a typical track or mounting bracket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>.: Provision for an interlock switch which prohibits operation unless the unit is mounted on the appropriate track. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT(S) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The detailed description set forth below in connection with the appended figures is intended as a description of presently-preferred embodiments of the invention and is not intended to represent the only forms in which the present invention may be constructed and/or utilized. The description sets forth the functions and the sequence of steps for constructing and operating the invention in connection with the illustrated embodiments. However, it is to be understood that the same or equivalent functions and sequences may be accomplished by different embodiments that are also intended to be encompassed within the spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> This invention consists of modular, anti-microbial radiation fixtures and support structures upon which to mount them. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The modular fixtures each share a common design and many details, but differ in length and electrical conponentry to accommodate lamps of various outputs. Modules may be combined to adequately cover a large variety of applications. The modules incorporate integral slots that match the configuration of the rack or bracket. Each module is slid onto the rack or bracket while the next or successive module is slid onto the rack and a connection is made to the previous module with a mating connector and retaining latch. As each module is positioned and connected, the assembly is pushed further down the rack or bracket. When the final module is in place, a power supply is connected to the last exposed module receptacle. The power cable is then connected to the power supply. The power supply can be a flexible utility cord or a conduit box to accept permanent hard wiring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Referring to the figures, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a typical fixture of the invention from a side perspective. Radiation bulb <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be an ultraviolet light, or any other radiation-emitting device selected for a particular anti-microbial application. Receptacle <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is typically configured to receive a conventional 2-prong connector, but may be of any configuration known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Socket <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is depicted here as a 3-prong inlet, however any conventional electrical connection can be used. Locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>comprises a longitudal member with a downward bias, and includes a vertical protrusion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for locking engagement with an appropriately configured slot. Locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>extends through tang cavity <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an enlarged detail of the plug side of an embodiment of this invention. Here, the electrical connection <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is depicted as a recessed plug, although any conventional electrical connection can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts two modular units in tandem engagement. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, vertical protrusion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>lockingly engages slot <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e, </italic></highlight>and lip <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>(not visible) rests on the surface adjacent to slot <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>in flush contact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the anti-microbial radiation system of the present invention, includes at least one support track <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, the support track having a generally concave cross-section <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and including outer edge protrusions <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> that extend laterally to form wings for slideable engagement with a lateral groove <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The support track <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> may be formed from a wood, metal, composite or polymeric material, and is configured to support or suspend the system from a surface, such as a wall, ceiling or floor. The track <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> may be attached to the desired surface by conventional means, such as bolts, nails, wires, adhesives, or any other suitable method. Frame <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> includes a first end <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>with a first face <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that includes a modular socket <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>and a second end <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>with a second face <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that includes a modular plug <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The faces <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>define lateral grooves <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> for slideably receiving lateral wings <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> for suspending the system, and the ends also include slots <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e, </italic></highlight>best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, and locking tangs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>best shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, for engagement with slots <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight>Locking tangs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>include vertical protrusions <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>and locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is biased so that vertical protrusions <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>snap into engagement with slots <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>in a secure manner, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Locking tangs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are attached to frame <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> by anchoring structure <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Anchoring structure <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is depicted as including plurality of apertures for receiving fastening devices, such as bolts, but can comprise any conventional anchoring method known to those skilled in the art. Ultraviolet light <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is removeably attached to a frame in a conventional manner, although the system can accommodate any radiation-emitting device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates an embodiment of the invention that includes an interlock switch <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. When the invention is connected in tandem with another module, locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>rests below cavity <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>due to its downward bias. When support track <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is engaged within lateral grooves <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>, track <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> forces locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>upward into cavity <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>When locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is forced upward, it depresses interlock switch <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, which closes the circuit that provides power from electrical connection <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>to radiation device <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>which may be an ultraviolet light. When track <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is not properly engaged, locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>remains in its natural downward bias, interlock switch <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> remains extended, and the circuit is open, which prevents operation of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In operation, light <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is removeably attached to receptacle <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>and frame <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is placed in sliding relationship with track <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> by grooves <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. Subsequent frames are connected with tracks in a similar manner, and the separate fixtures are interconnected by inserting a plug <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>into a corresponding socket <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>in addition to engaging locking tangs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with slots <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight>An external power source may then be connected to an exposed electrical coupling, such as modular socket <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>to energize the system. Locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>depresses interlock switch <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, which closes the circuit and allows locking tang <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to flow to the light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> While the present invention has been described with regards to particular embodiments, it is recognized that additional variations of the present invention may be devised without departing from the inventive concept. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An anti-microbial radiation system, comprising mechanical and electrical coupling end portions whereby a plurality of modular fixtures may be interconnected. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The anti-microbial radiation system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> including a track which receives the modular fixtures in sliding relationship therewith, and wherein one modular fixture is mechanically and electrically connected to successively placed modular fixtures which are in sliding relationship to said track, whereby a selected number of modular units may be interposed in a space to be exposed to radiation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The anti-microbial radiation system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said end portions include two vertical surfaces, said vertical surfaces each including an opening that defines a channel for receiving a track. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The anti-microbial radiation system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each modular fixture includes at least one horizontal surface, said horizontal surface including at least one integral slot, and at least one mechanical coupling configured for locking engagement with said integral slot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The anti-microbial radiation system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electrical couplings are disposed upon the vertical faces. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The anti-microbial radiation system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electrical couplings comprise a socket, and a plug. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The anti-microbial radiation system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the mechanical coupling comprises a longitudinal member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The anti-microbial radiation system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the longitudinal member includes a protrusion extending vertically from a horizontal surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The anti-microbial radiation system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the channel is defined by a portion of the vertical face extending below the at least one horizontal surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An anti-microbial light system, comprising: 
<claim-text>At least one support track, said support track having a generally concave cross-section, and including outer edge protrusions that extend laterally to form wings for slideable engagement with a lateral groove, at least one frame, said frame including a first end, with a first face including a modular socket, and a second end, with a second face including a modular plug, said faces defining lateral grooves for slideably receiving lateral wings for suspending the system, and said ends including slots, and locking tangs for engagement with said slots, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one ultra-violet light, each light being removably attached to a frame. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of providing radiation devices in hard to reach places comprising the steps of creating interconnected modules for association with a bracket or rack wherein a selected number of modules are placed in sliding relationship with said rack or bracket and the number of modules interconnected to provide satisfactory treatment of the surface or area to be treated by radiation.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001113A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001113A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001113A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001113A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001113A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001113A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001113A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
