<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002475A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002475A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002475A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002475A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002475A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002475A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002475A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002475A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002475</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09132851</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>19980812</filing-date>
<continued-prosecution-application>This is a publication of a continued prosecution application (CPA) filed under 37 CFR 1.53(d).</continued-prosecution-application>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>97202504.3</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19970813</filing-date>
<country-code>EP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04L012/66</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>370</class>
<subclass>352000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>COMMUNICATION NETWORK</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>FRANK P.</given-name>
<family-name>DERKS</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>HILVERSUM</city>
<country-code>NL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CORPORATE PATENT COUNSEL</name-1>
<name-2>U S PHILIPS CORPORATION</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>580 WHITE PLAINS ROAD</address-1>
<city>TARRYTOWN</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10591</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In a communication network, a terminal (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) is arranged for communication with a terminal (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>) via a packet switched network (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>). To do so, the terminal (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) is connected via a gateway (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) to the packet switched network, and the terminal (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>) is connected via the gateway (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) to the packet switched network, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">According to the present invention, the gateway (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) is arranged for receiving the information of a second terminal to be connected without answering the call of the first terminal. This has the advantage that no calling costs are incurred for transferring the information of the terminal to be called. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0003" lvl="0">Preferably the gateway (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) waits with answering the call of the first terminal (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) until the second terminal (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>) has answered the call. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a system comprising a terminal coupled via a dial-up network to a gateway, the terminal comprises means for dialing the gateway and providing an identification of a second terminal connectable to said gateway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> To enable communication between existing telephony systems and emerging IP-based telephony &lsquo;devices&rdquo; (E.g. an Internet Telephony software package running on a PC) as well as the communication between existing telephony systems inter-connected via IP-based networks, so-called Telephony Gateways (hereafter called gateway(s)) are used. These gateways connect to an IP-based network (such as the public Internet and private Intranets) on one side and a telephone network (E.g. PSTN/ISDN/GSM) on the other side and provide the necessary conversion functions to transmit and receive voice-band and control data on either network. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Because of the differences in addressing structure on both sides of the gateway and because of the nature of some of the telephone networks, connections initiated from the telephone network side are usually set up by a two-step dialing process. First, a gateway is called and this gateway answers the call to obtain an identification of the second terminal, which can be constituted by additional addressing information for either an IP-based telephony device (E.g. an IP-address) or addressing information for the combination of a remote gateway and a remote (normal) telephone terminal. Second, the gateway uses this addressing information to attempt to set up a call to the &lsquo;remote&rsquo; telephony device, which can either be an IP-based telephony device or a regular telephony device connected (directly or indirectly) to a remote gateway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The problem with this approach is that a call is answered by the gateway, to obtain numbering information, before it is known whether the actual destination will answer the call. The caller will thus pay the bill for a call that may never exist and always pay for a duration that is longer than the actual call, when it takes place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a communication network according to the preamble in which the above problem is solved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> For achieving said object the communication network according to the invention is characterized in that the gateway is arranged for receiving the identification of the second terminal without answering the call. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> When the gateway is arranged for receiving the identification of the second terminal before answering a call, no calling costs are incurred for transferring the identification of the second terminal. This can e.g. be done by using the signaling possibilities of ISDN. On ISDN interfaces complying with the ITU-T Q.931 Recommendation, calls are initiated by the transmission of a &lsquo;setup&rdquo; message from the calling to the called party (from the calling user to the network to be precise). Such a &lsquo;setup&rsquo; message contains mandatory information elements and may contain optional information elements. The &lsquo;called party number&rsquo;, &lsquo;called party subaddress&rsquo; and &lsquo;keypad facility&rdquo; information elements are three of these optional information elements. They (may) contain, when present, numbering and addressing information about the called terminal. It is observed that it is also possible to use ISDN interfaces which are derived from the Q.931 Recommendation, such as EURO-ISDN. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of a communication network according to the invention is characterized in that the gateway is arranged for establishing communication with the second node, and in that the gateway is arranged for answering the call of the terminal after the second terminal has been contacted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In this way it is obtained that the caller does not incur calling cost until the destination really answers the call, and that the behavior of the destination telephony device, as seen from the caller in the telephone network, is identical to the behavior of a destination telephony device that is located in and reached through the telephone network.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The invention will now be explained with reference to the drawing figures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a communication network according to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an alternative arrangement of the communication network according to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a block diagram of a gateway according to the invention.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In the communication network according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> node <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises a gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to which a telephone terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> can be connected via a telephone switch which is here a PABX <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. It is however possible that the telephone switch is a switch in the public telephone network. The gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is connected to a telephone network <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via a link <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which is routed via the PABX <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is also connected to the packet switched network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which can be the public Internet. Alternatively the connection of the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to the packet switched network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can be a dial up connection or a leased line <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> routed via the PABX <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to the telephone network <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as is indicated by the dotted line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The connection <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> between the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can be a telephone line which is connected via the PABX <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, but it is also possible that the functions of the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are included in a single device, such as a personal computer or a telephone terminal specially arranged for Internet telephony. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> When the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is connected to the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> via the PABX <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> initiates a call by going off hook and dialing a number corresponding to the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> accepts the call and the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> provides the (IP) address of the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the terminal <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to be called to the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. If only one terminal is connected to the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to be called, which is the case when the gateway function is integrated in a PC or in a special internet phone device, only the internet address of the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is given. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> does not answer the call initiated by terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, but that it only reads the numbering/addressing information in the &lsquo;called party number&rsquo;, &ldquo;called party subaddress&rdquo; and/or &lsquo;keypad facility&rsquo; information elements which could be included in an ISDN set up message. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, it is also possible that the address information of the terminal to be called is stored in the PABX, and that a normal telephone number is assigned to said terminal. If said number is called, the PABX retrieves the complete address information and tries to contact the terminal via the packet switched network before answering the call of the calling terminal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> After having received the address of the terminal <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to be called from the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> attempts to contact the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in the node <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. If this attempt is successful, the addressing information of the terminal <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is passed via the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which tries to set up a connection with the terminal <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> via the link <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. When the terminal <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> accepts the connection, this is signalled by the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, after which a connection between the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the terminal <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is established. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> If the attempt of the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to contact the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> via the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> fails, it is assumed that the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is not connected to the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In that case, the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> calls the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> directly via the PSTN using a telephone number stored locally, in order to request that the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> connects to the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. After the request has been transmitted, the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> directly terminates the connection with the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, in order to minimize the connection costs. Alternatively the request to connect to the internet can be included in an ISDN set up message which will be passed by the PSTN to the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> before a call is established. The latter possibility has the advantage that no connection costs are incurred at all. In response to this request, the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> connects to the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In general this will be done via a dial up connection over the PSTN <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via the link <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> It is observed that it is also possible to pass the address of the calling terminal/gateway combination to the gateway during the request to connect to the packet switched network. This has the advantage that the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> directly can call the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> after it has connected to the packet switched network <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. It is thereby prevented that the calling gateway has to wait a before contacting the called gateway over the packet switched network until it is ensured that the called gateway has connected to the packet switched network. Because this waiting time is not known, the calling gateway has to wait longer than is necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> If the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is connected to the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> via a dial up connection over the telephone network <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> when the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> should be called directly, the call to the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is terminated and the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is called. After having transmitted the request to connect to the internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> connects again to the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and again tries to contact the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for establishing a call between the terminals <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. If the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> has a fixed connection <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the Internet or when is has more than one line available to the PSTN <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, it can stay connected to the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> when calling the gateway <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> directly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In the network according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is present between the PSTN network <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. If the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> wants to contact the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in order to contact a terminal <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> via the Internet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. it dials the phone number of the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to make a connection. In the present proposal the gateway does not answer calls to obtain information about the actual destination of the call, but uses the numbering/addressing information in the &lsquo;called party number&rsquo;, &ldquo;called party subaddress&rdquo; and/or &lsquo;keypad facility&rsquo; information elements. The gateway uses this numbering information to set up a call to the destination terminal <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The destination telephony device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the combination of a destination gateway and a (directly or indirectly) connected normal telephony device have a means of identifying and indicating that the telephony device is in the alerting state. The gateway sends an &lsquo;alerting&rdquo; message to the caller or network when it is informed that the IP-based telephony device or the normal telephony device behind a gateway is in the alerting state. The caller has a means of supplying the required addressing/numbering information and place that information in the &lsquo;called party number&rsquo;, &lsquo;called Party subaddress&rsquo; information elements&apos; and/or &lsquo;keypad facility&rsquo; information elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A first advantage of this way of setting up a call is that the caller does not incur calling cost until the destination really answers the call. A second advantage is that the behaviour of the destination telephony device, as seen from the caller at the terminal <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is identical to the behaviour of a destination telephony device that is reached directly through the telephone network. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> comprises an interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for interfacing to the PABX <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or to a local exchange of the PSTN. The interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to a plurality of telephone lines <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. It is also possible that the interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to the PABX or the PSTN via an E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (Europe) or T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (US, Japan) line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected via a protocol converter <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to an Internet interface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The protocol converter <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is arranged for converting the speech signal and the associated control signals received from the interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> into signals which can be transmitted via the Internet. Furthermore the protocol converter <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is arranged for converting the signals received from the Internet into signals which can be transmitted via the telephone interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The conversion of the signals from the interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to signals to be transmitted over the Internet interface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> involves speech compression and packetizing the compressed speech signals into packets for transmission over the Internet. If the interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to an analog telephone network, the protocol converter <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> also performs analog to digital conversion. The conversion of the signals from the interface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to the signals for the interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> involves depacketizing the packets received from the interface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> into a signal stream, and decompressing the signal stream into a digital speech signal. If the interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to an analog telephone network, the digital speech signal is also converted to an analog signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The internet interface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> can be fixedly connected to the Internet, but it is also possible that the Internet interface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is connected to the telephone interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, in order to connect to the Internet via a dial up connection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is also connected to a control signal receiver <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> which is arranged for receiving the control signals associated with a connection to the telephone network. If the interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to an analog telephone network, the control signal receiver <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> comprises a tone detector for detecting various signalling tones received from the telephone network and converting them into a corresponding control message. If the telephone interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to an ISDN telephone network, the control signal receiver <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is arranged for extracting several control messages from the control signals received from the telephone network. Examples of such control messages can e.g. be addressing information carried in an ISDN set up message as explained above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The control signals at the output of the control signal receiver <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are passed to a controller <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> which interprets the control signals and takes appropriate actions by sending control signals to a dialler/control signal transmitter <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, to the protocol converter <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and to the internet interface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> If the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> receives via the interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> a set up message including the address information of a terminal to be called via the internet, the control signal receiver <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> extracts the address information from the set up message and passes it to the controller <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The controller <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> requests the internet interface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to set up a (virtual) connection between said internet interface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the gateway identified with the internet address carried by the set up message. After the connection has been set up, optionally a terminal identification signal is transmitted over the connection in order to address one out of more terminals connected to the remote gateway. The remote gateway signals the status of the remote terminal (alerting, in use, off hook) via the Internet interface to the controller <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. If the remote terminal goes off hook, the controller <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> instructs the dial/control interface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to accept the telephone call corresponding to the previously received set up message. Furthermore the protocol converter <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is instructed to pass the converted signals from the telephone interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to the Internet interface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> for transmission to the remote gateway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> If the called terminal does not answer the call, the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> does not answer the call of the calling terminal. This way of dealing with the incoming call has the advantage that no calling costs are incurred before the remote terminal actually answers the call. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> If the attempt to contact the remote gateway fails, the controller <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> instructs the dial/control interface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to dial the telephone number of the remote gateway in order to request that the remote gateway connects to the Internet. Subsequently the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> tries again to connect to the remote gateway via the Internet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> If the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> does not have a fixed connection to the internet, it should connect to the internet via a dial up connection. In that case, the control signal receiver <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is arranged for receiving a message from a remote gateway requesting the gateway <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to connect to the internet. In response to said request the controller instructs the dial/control interface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to establish a dial up connection to the Internet. </paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Communication system comprising a terminal coupled via a dial-up network to a gateway, the terminal comprises means for dialing the gateway and providing an identification of a second terminal connectable to said gateway, characterized in that the gateway is arranged for receiving the identification of the second terminal without answering the call. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Communication system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the gateway is arranged for establishing communication with the second node, and in that the gateway is arranged for answering the call of the terminal after the second terminal has been contacted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Gateway connected to a dial-up network, the gateway being arranged for receiving from a first terminal an identification of second terminal to be contacted by said gateway, characterized in that the gateway is arranged for receiving the identification of the second terminal to be contacted without answering the call. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Gateway according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the gateway is arranged for establishing communication with the second terminal, and in that the gateway is arranged for answering the call of the first terminal after the second terminal has been contacted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Communication method comprising dialing a gateway from a first terminal via a dial up network, and providing an identification of a second terminal connectable to said gateway, characterized in that the method comprises receiving the identification of the second terminal by the gateway without answering the call. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Communication method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the method comprises establishing communication with the second node, and in that the method comprises answering the call of the terminal after the second terminal has been contacted.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002475A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002475A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002475A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002475A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
