<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002704A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002704A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002704A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002704A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002704A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002704A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002704</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09988693</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011120</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04R025/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>381</class>
<subclass>374000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>381</class>
<subclass>375000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>381</class>
<subclass>379000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Foldable hook for headset</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60302491</doc-number>
<document-date>20010702</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<family-name>Pronk</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Amsterdam</city>
<country-code>NL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JENKENS &amp; GILCHRIST, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2>Suite 3200</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1445 Ross Avenue</address-1>
<city>Dallas</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75202-2799</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An apparatus for affixing a headset to the ear of a user includes a first member having a first end and a second end. The first end is rotatably connected to the headset. A second member also includes a first end and a second end, and the first end of the second member rotatably connects to the second end of the first member. The second member contacts at least a portion of the ear of the user assisting in affixing the headset to the ear of the user. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATION(S) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority from and incorporates herein by reference the entire disclosure of U.S. Provisional Application Serial No. 60/302,491 filed Jul. 2, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to headsets worn on the ear, and more particularly, to a foldable hook for connecting a headset to the ear of a user. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Headsets enable a user to carry out two-way communications while still leaving a user&apos;s hands free to perform other functions. Headsets are used with wireline telephones, wireless telephones and a variety of other communication devices wherein two-way communications occur between a user and another party or a voice actuated device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> One type of headset useful with portable communication devices are headsets that are attached to only the ear of a user, using some type of a hook or attaching component. The hook affixes the headset to the ear or head of the user and positions a speaker near the user&apos;s ear and a microphone near a user&apos;s mouth to enable hands free communication. These types of headsets are very popular with, for example, mobile telephones wherein a user may continue to perform other functions such as driving or working while still communicating via their mobile telephone. The problem with these types of headsets arises when they are not in use, i.e., placed upon the ear or head of a user. The combination of the main body of the headset and the hook for attaching it to a user produces a large product which is not easily stored. A headset having a hook sticking out from the main housing does not easily fit within a pocket or purse of a user. Additionally, the hook extending from the body of the headset makes it difficult to remove the headset from the storage area since the hook may snag or catch upon other items. Thus, there is needed some manner of providing a apparatus to provide a compact and more efficient storage for the headset when not in use. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention overcomes the foregoing and other problems with a foldable hook for affixing a headset to an ear or a user. The foldable hook consists of a first member having first and second ends. The first end of the first member rotatably connects to a headset. A second member also has first and second ends. The first end is rotatably connected to the second end of the first member and contacts at least a portion of the ear of the user. An integral third member can be used for rotating the second member about its connection with the first member and for rotating the first member about its connection with the housing of the headset.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A more complete understanding of the method and apparatus of the present invention may be obtained by reference to the following Detailed Description when taken in conjunction with the accompanying Drawings wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates the foldable headset hook of the present invention in an open position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates the foldable headset hook in a closed position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the foldable headset hook in a closed position around a headset housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the foldable headset hook attaching a headset to the ear of a user; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>illustrate the range of movement of the foldable headset hook. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the drawings, and more particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is illustrated the foldable hook of the present invention. The main portion of the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> consists of a first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and a second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> interconnects the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of a headset via a rotatable joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The rotatable joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> enables the first member of the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to rotate about the axis B and more compactly wrap the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> about a housing of the headset as will be more fully described in a moment. The rotatable joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> interconnecting the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to a housing of a headset includes a spring or other biasing unit for biasing the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to a closed (i.e., wrapped around the headset) position. The rotatable joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> also enables rotation of member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> about axis C to allow the headset to be worn on the left and right ears. Alternatively, member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be reattachable to joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to enable left/right wearing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is connected to the first member <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> via a second rotatable joint <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The second rotatable joint <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> enables the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to rotate about the axis A. As with the first joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the second joint <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes a spring (or other biasing unit) biasing the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to a closed position. The second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has a generally arcuate shape enabling the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to more effectively wrap around and engage an ear of a user. The second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may further include some type of padded covering to enable the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to more effectively and comfortably engage an ear of a user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, there is illustrated the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a closed position both disconnected from (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) and connected to (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of a headset. As can be seen from each figure, the first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is rotated toward the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the headset by the biasing forces of joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Likewise, the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is rotated toward the opposite side of the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> by the biasing forces of the spring within joint <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In this way, the first <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and second <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> members of the foldable spring <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> wrap around the earpiece <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> providing a much more compact package than if the hook remained in an extended position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> An actuator arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> integrally connected with the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may extend from the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or form an integral portion thereof By manipulating the actuator arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be rotated about its connection with the first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to enable the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to move from a closed to an open position in order to more easily engage the ear of the user. Additionally, the actuator arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> may be used to rotate the first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> about its rotatable joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> with the housing of the headset in order to better position the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for engaging the ear of a user. The actuator arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> may include a number of ridges <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> defined therein to provide the user&apos;s finger with a better grip of the actuator arm <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, there is illustrated a headset housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> including a foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention mounted on the ear of a user. As can be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> clamps on the back of the ear of a user while the biasing forces of joint <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> maintain the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in contact with the ear. Likewise, the first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is maintained in a position to support the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by the biasing forces of joint <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> which is not visible in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In this manner, a microphone and speaker (not shown) within the headset housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may be maintained in close proximity to both the mouth and ear of the user, respectively. While <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the use of a wireless headset including a wireless transceiver <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for establishing a connection with an associated device such as a mobile telephone, computer, etc., the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention may also be used with any type of wireless or wireline headset using, for example, the Bluetooth protocol or any known wireless or wireline protocols. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>there is illustrated the manner in which the foldable hook <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> moves from an open position about the ear of a user to a closed position wrapped around a housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of a headset. In the open position illustrated, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is extended away from the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the headset and the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> extends to wrap around the ear of a user. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrates a partially closed configuration wherein the first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> has moved to a closed position wrapped around the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the headset. The second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> remains open. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, the second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has also moved to a closed position wrapped around the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the headset. As can be seen, when the first member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and second member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are in the closed position and wrapped around the housing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the headset, a much smaller package is created for storage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Utilizing the above described invention, a user may store their headset in a substantially reduced size package enabling the headset to be easily placed within a pocket or purse of the user while greatly decreasing the potential for inadvertently snagging a hook on other items within a pocket, purse or other storage location. The previous description is of a preferred embodiment for implementing the invention, and the scope of the invention should not necessarily be limited by this description. The scope of the present invention is instead defined by the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A foldable hook for affixing a headset to an ear of a user, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first member having a first and second end, said first end rotatably connected to the headset; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second member for contacting at least a portion of the ear of the user having a first end and a second end, said first end of the second member rotatably connected to the second end of the first member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The foldable hook of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rotatable connection between the first end of the first member and the headset is biased to a first position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The foldable hook of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rotatable connection between the first end of the second member and the second end of the first member is biased to a first position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The foldable hook of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a third member integral with said second member for a moving said first member and said second member between a first position and said second position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The foldable hook of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second member has a substantially arcuate shape for fitting around the ear of the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The foldable hook of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second members are configurable for either a left ear or a right ear of the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The foldable hook of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a wireless transceiver within the headset for communicating with an associated device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wireless transceiver operates according to the Bluetooth protocol. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for affixing a headset to an ear of a user, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first member having a first end and a second end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second member for contacting at least a portion of the ear of the user having a first end and a second end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first rotatable connection rotatably interconnecting the first member with the head set about a first axis, said first rotatable connection biased to a closed position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second rotatable connection interconnecting the second member with the first member, said second rotatable connection biased to the closed position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third member integral to said second member for rotatably moving said second member about said second rotatable connection and rotatably moving said first member about said first rotatable connection. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second member has a substantially arcuate shape for fitting around the ear of the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second members are configurable for either a left ear or a right ear of the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first rotatable connection further provides movement of the first member about a second axis enabling configuration for the left ear and the right ear of the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A headset, comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first member having a first and second end, said first end rotatably connected to the headset; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second member for contacting at least a portion of the ear of the user having a first end and a second end, said first end of the second member rotatably connected to the second end of the first member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rotatable connection between the first end of the first member and the housing is biased to a first position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rotatable connection between the first end of the second member and the second end of the first member is biased to a first position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a third member integral with said second member for a moving said first member and said second member between a first position and a second position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second member has a substantially arcuate shape for fitting around the ear of the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second members are configurable for either a left ear or a right ear of the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first rotatable connection further provides movement of the first member about a second axis enabling configuration for the left ear and the right ear of the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a wireless transceiver within the housing for communicating with an associated device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wireless transceiver operates according to the Bluetooth protocol. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A headset, comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first member having a first end and a second end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second member for contacting at least a portion of the ear of the user having a first end and a second end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first rotatable connection rotatably interconnecting the first member with the head set about a first axis, said first rotatable connection biased to a first position and further providing movement of the first member about a second axis enabling configuration for the left ear and the right ear of the user; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second rotatable connection rotatably interconnecting the second member with the first member about a third axis, said second rotatable connection biased to a first position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third member integral to said second member for rotatably moving said second member about said second rotatable connection and rotatably moving said first member about said first rotatable connection. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a wireless transceiver within the housing for communicating with an associated device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The headset of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wireless transceiver operates according to the Bluetooth protocol.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002704A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002704A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002704A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
