<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000699A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000699A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000699A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000699A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000699A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000699A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000699A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000699A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000699A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000699A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000699A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000699A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000699A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000699A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000699A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000699A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000699</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893761</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E21B043/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>166</class>
<subclass>278000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>166</class>
<subclass>051000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR GRAVEL PACKING AN INTERVAL OF A WELLBORE</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Travis</given-name>
<middle-name>T.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hailey</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sugar Land</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES, INC.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P. O. Box 819052</address-1>
<city>Dallas</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75381-9052</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An apparatus (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>) and method for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore is disclosed. The apparatus (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>) comprises a sand control screen (<highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>) that is positioned within the wellbore and a tube and manifold system (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) positioned between the sand control screen (<highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>) and the wellbore. The tube and manifold system (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) delivers a fluid slurry to a plurality of levels within the interval when the apparatus (<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>) is in an operable position. The tubes (<highlight><bold>64, 70, 76</bold></highlight>) of the tube and manifold system (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) have first and second ends which are open such that the fluid slurry may enter one end, travel through the entire length of the tube (<highlight><bold>64, 70, 76</bold></highlight>) and exit the other end. The manifolds (<highlight><bold>66, 72</bold></highlight>) of the tube and manifold system (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) each have at least one exit port (<highlight><bold>68, 74</bold></highlight>) for the discharge of the fluid slurry from the tube and manifold system (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates in general to preventing the production of particulate materials through a wellbore traversing an unconsolidated or loosely consolidated subterranean formation and, in particular, to an apparatus and method for obtaining a substantially complete gravel pack within an interval of the wellbore. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Without limiting the scope of the present invention, its background is described with reference to the production of hydrocarbon fluids through a wellbore traversing an unconsolidated or loosely consolidated formation, as an example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> It is well known in the subterranean well drilling and completion art that particulate materials such as sand may be produced during the production of hydrocarbons from a well traversing an unconsolidated or loosely consolidated subterranean formation. Numerous problems may occur as a result of the production of such particulate. For example, the particulate cause abrasive wear to components within the well, such as tubing, pumps and valves. In addition, the particulate may partially or fully clog the well creating the need for an expensive workover. Also, if the particulate matter is produced to the surface, it must be removed from the hydrocarbon fluids by processing equipment at the surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> One method for preventing the production of such particulate material to the surface is gravel packing the well adjacent to the unconsolidated or loosely consolidated production interval. In a typical gravel pack completion, a sand control screen is lowered into the wellbore on a work string to a position proximate the desired production interval. A fluid slurry including a liquid carrier and a particulate material known as gravel is then pumped down the work string and into the well annulus formed between the sand control screen and the perforated well casing or open hole production zone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The liquid carrier either flows into the formation or returns to the surface by flowing through the sand control screen or both. In either case, the gravel is deposited around the sand control screen to form a gravel pack, which is highly permeable to the flow of hydrocarbon fluids but blocks the flow of the particulate carried in the hydrocarbon fluids. As such, gravel packs can successfully prevent the problems associated with the production of particulate materials from the formation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It has been found, however, that a complete gravel pack of the desired production interval is difficult to achieve particularly in long or inclined/horizontal production intervals. These incomplete packs are commonly a result of the liquid carrier entering a permeable portion of the production interval causing the gravel to form a sand bridge in the annulus. Thereafter, the sand bridge prevents the slurry from flowing to the remainder of the annulus which, in turn, prevents the placement of sufficient gravel in the remainder of the annulus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Prior art devices and methods have been developed which attempt to overcome this sand bridge problem. For example, attempts have been made to use devices having perforated shunt tubes or bypass conduits that extend along the length of the sand control screen to provide an alternate path for the fluid slurry around the sand bridge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It has been found, however, that shunt tubes installed on the exterior of sand control screens are susceptible to damage during installation and may fail during a gravel packing operation due, in part, to the perforations through the side wall of the shunt tubes. In addition, it has been found, that on site assembly of a shunt tube system around a sand control screen is difficult and time consuming due to the large number of fluid connections required for typical production intervals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Therefore a need has arisen for an apparatus and method for gravel packing a production interval traversed by a wellbore that overcomes the problems created by sand bridges. A need has also arisen for such an apparatus that is not susceptible to damage during installation and will not fail during a gravel packing operation. Further, a need has arisen for such an apparatus that is cost effective and does not require difficult or time consuming on site assembly. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention disclosed herein comprises an apparatus and method for gravel packing a production interval of a wellbore that traverses an unconsolidated or loosely consolidated formation that overcomes the problems created by the development of a sand bridge between a sand control screen and the wellbore. Importantly, the apparatus of the present invention is not susceptible to damage during installation or failure during the gravel packing operation, is cost effective to manufacture and does not require difficult or time consuming on site assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The apparatus comprises a sand control screen that is positioned within the wellbore and a tube and manifold system that is positioned between the sand control screen and the wellbore. The tube and manifold system may be constructed in sections that are integral with each section of the sand control screen such that sections of the apparatus are simply threaded together in a known manner prior to running it downhole. Alternatively, the tube and manifold system may be run downhole and positioned proximate the formation prior to running the sand control screen downhole. In this case, when the sand control screen is run downhole, it is positioned within the tube and manifold system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In either case, the tube and manifold system is used to selectively deliver the fluid slurry to a plurality of levels within the interval when the apparatus is in the operable position. The tube and manifold system comprises, in series, one or more tubes then a manifold followed by one or more tubes then another manifold and so forth. The tubes of the tube and manifold system have first and second ends which are open but do not have openings in their side walls as the fluid slurry is discharged from the tube and manifold system only through exit ports in the manifolds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In most embodiments of the present invention, the exit ports of the manifolds are circumferentially misaligned with the adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. In other embodiment, however, some or all of the exit ports of the manifolds may be circumferentially aligned with the adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. There may be the same number, more or less exit ports in each manifold than the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the present invention, each section of the sand control screen has a plurality of manifolds positioned adjacently thereto. The tubes that deliver the fluid slurry to and transport the fluid slurry from these intrasectional manifolds are axially aligned with one another. In addition to these intrasectional manifolds, there is one manifold positioned between adjacent sections of the sand control screen. The tubes that deliver the fluid slurry to and transport the fluid slurry from these intersectional manifolds are typically axially misaligned with one another. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> One method of the present invention involves traversing a formation with the wellbore, positioning a tube and manifold system within the wellbore proximate the formation, locating a sand control screen within the tube and manifold system, injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system such that the fluid slurry exits the tube and manifold system through the exit ports in the manifolds at a plurality of levels of the interval and terminating the injecting when the interval is substantially completely packed with the gravel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Another method of the present invention involves traversing a formation with the wellbore, positioning a tube and manifold system around a sand control screen, locating the sand control screen and the tube and manifold system within the wellbore proximate the formation, injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system such that the fluid slurry exits the tube and manifold system through the exit ports in the manifolds at a plurality of levels of the interval and terminating the injecting when the interval is substantially completely packed with the gravel. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> For a more complete understanding of the features and advantages of the present invention, reference is now made to the detailed description of the invention along with the accompanying figures in which corresponding numerals in the different figures refer to corresponding parts and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic illustration of an offshore oil and gas platform operating an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is partial cut away view of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is partial cut away view of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a side view of two adjacent sections of tubes meeting at a manifold of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore~ of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of two adjacent sections of tubes meeting at a manifold of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side view of two adjacent sections of tubes meeting at a manifold of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view of two adjacent sections of tubes meeting at a manifold of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention positioned taken along line <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view two adjacent sections of tubes meeting at a manifold of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a half sectional view depicting the operation of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> While the making and using of various embodiments of the present invention are discussed in detail below, it should be appreciated that the present invention provides many applicable inventive concepts which can be embodied in a wide variety of specific contexts. The specific embodiments discussed herein are merely illustrative of specific ways to make and use the invention, and do not delimit the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring initially to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore operating from an offshore oil and gas platform are schematically illustrated and generally designated <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A semi-submersible platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is centered over a submerged oil and gas formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> located below sea floor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A subsea conduit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> extends from deck <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to wellhead installation <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> including blowout preventers <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a hoisting apparatus <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and a derrick <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> for raising and lowering pipe strings such as work sting <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> A wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extends through the various earth strata including formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is cemented within wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by cement <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes various tools for completing the well. On the lower end of work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is an apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> for gravel packing an interval of wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> including sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> as well as tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is positioned adjacent to formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> between packers <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> in annular region or interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> including perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. When it is desired to gravel pack annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, a fluid slurry including a liquid carrier and a particulate material such as gravel is pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As explained in more detail below, the fluid slurry will generally be injected into annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> between apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in a known manner such as through a crossover tool (not pictured) which allows the slurry to travel from the interior of work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to the exterior of work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Once the fluid slurry is in annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, a portion of the gravel in the fluid slurry is deposited in annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Some of the liquid carrier may enter formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> through perforation <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> while the remainder of the fluid carrier entering sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. More specifically, sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> disallows further migration of the gravel in the fluid slurry but allows the liquid carrier to travel therethrough and up to the surface in a known manner, such as through a wash pipe and into the annulus <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> above packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. If a sand bridge forms during the injection of the fluid slurry into annular region <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, the fluid slurry will be diverted into tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to bypass this sand bridge. In this case, the fluid slurry will exit tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> through the manifolds at various levels within interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Again, once in annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, the gravel in the fluid slurry is deposited therein. Some of the liquid carrier may enter formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> through perforation <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> while the remainder of the fluid carrier enters sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as described above, and returns to the surface. The operator continues to pump the fluid slurry down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> into annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and through tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, as necessary, until annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> surrounding sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is filled with gravel, thereby achieving a complete pack of interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, it should be noted by those skilled in the art, that the fluid slurry may be injected entirely into tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> without first injecting the fluid slurry directly into annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts a vertical well, it should be noted by one skilled in the art that the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention is equally well-suited for use in deviated wells, inclined wells or horizontal wells. In addition, it should be apparent to those skilled in the art that the use of directional terms such as above, below, upper, lower, upward, downward and the like are used in relation to the illustrative embodiments as they are depicted in the figures, the upward direction being toward the top of the corresponding figure and the downward direction being toward the bottom of the corresponding figure. Also, even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts an offshore operation, it should be noted by one skilled in the art that the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention is equally well-suited for use in onshore operations. Further, even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> has been described with regard to a gravel packing operation, it should be noted by one skilled in the art that the apparatus of the present invention is equally well-suited for fracture operations and frac pack operations wherein a fluid slurry containing propping agents is delivered at a high flow rate and at a pressure above the fracture pressure of formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> such that fractures may be formed within formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and held open by the propping agents and such that annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is packed with the propping agents or other suitable particulate materials to prevent the production of fines from formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, therein is depicted a partial cut away view of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention that is generally designated <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> includes a tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> that has four tubes extending between each manifold. Specifically, four tubes <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, deliver the fluid slurry to manifold <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. A portion of the fluid slurry in manifold <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> will enter the annular interval surrounding apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> via two exit ports <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, only one of which is shown. The remainder of the fluid slurry enters four tubes <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, and is delivered to manifold <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Again, a portion of the fluid slurry in manifold <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> will enter the annular interval surrounding apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> via two exit ports <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, only one of which is shown. The remainder of the fluid slurry enters four tubes <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, and is delivered to the next manifold of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. This process continues through the various levels of the tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> along the entire length of the interval to be gravel packed such that a complete gravel pack of the interval can be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Importantly, the tubes of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> do not have openings or perforations in the side walls thereof for the discharge of the fluid slurry into the annular interval surrounding apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. It has been found that fluid delivery tubes, such as shunt tubes or conduits that have openings or perforations in their side walls are susceptible to damage during installation and failure during use due to their lack of strength. In fact, use of the non perforated tubes of the present invention allows for the delivery of a greater volume of fluid at a higher flowrate, making frac packing a possibility. In addition, having the exit ports in the manifolds instead of in the tubes allows for the use of nozzles in the exit ports which improve the overall delivery of the fluid slurry from tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Another important feature of this embodiment of the present invention is that the exit ports of the manifolds are not circumferentially aligned with the tubes of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. This feature helps to minimize liquid leak off after the area adjacent to a particular manifold has been packed with the gravel. Specifically, even after an area surrounding one of the manifolds has been packed with the gravel, it has been found that liquid from the fluid slurry may nonetheless leak off into this porous region causing not only a reduction in the velocity of the fluid slurry in tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, but also, an increase in the effective density of particles in the fluid slurry, each of which is a hindrance to particle transport to locations further along tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Positioning the exit ports out of phase with the tubes reduces the liquid leak off by increasing the pressure required to push the liquid through the porous matrix and reduces the velocity of the liquid near the exit ports, thereby reducing the rate of liquid leak off. This rate of liquid leak off is further reduced by using a liquid in the fluid slurry that is thixotropic such that its viscosity increases with reduced velocity through the porous matrix. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> has depicted exit ports <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> as being circular, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that exit ports <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> could alternatively have other shapes without departing from the principles of the present invention, those shapes being considered within the scope of the present invention. Also, it should be noted by those skilled in the art that even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> has depicted tubes <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> as having a rectangular cross section, tubes having other cross sectional configurations may alternatively be used without departing from the principles of the present invention and are considered within the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Disposed within tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is a sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. Sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> includes a base pipe <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which allow the flow of production fluids into the production tubing. The exact number, size and shape of openings <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> are not critical to the present invention, so long as sufficient area is provided for fluid production and the integrity of base pipe <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is maintained. Positioned around base pipe <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is a fluid-porous, particulate restricting, sintered metal material such as a plurality of layers of a wire mesh that are sintered together to form a porous sintered wire mesh screen <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Screen <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is designed to allow fluid flow therethrough but prevent the flow of particulate materials of a predetermined size from passing therethrough. Positioned around screen <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is a screen housing <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> which allow the flow of production fluids therethrough. The exact number, size and shape of openings <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is not critical to the present invention, so long as sufficient area is provided for fluid production and the integrity of housing <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is maintained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> It should be understood by those skilled in the art that other types of filter media may be used in conjunction with tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. For example, as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> wire wrap screen assembly <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> may alternately be used. Screen assembly <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> has a base pipe <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. A plurality of ribs <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are spaced around base pipe <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. Ribs <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are generally symmetrically distributed about the axis of base pipe <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. Ribs <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are depicted as having a cylindrical cross section, however, it should be understood by one skilled in the art that ribs <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> may alternatively have a rectangular or triangular cross section or other suitable geometry. Additionally, it should be understood by one skilled in the art that the exact number of ribs <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> will be dependent upon the diameter of base pipe <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> as well as other design characteristics that are well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Wrapped around ribs <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is a screen wire <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. Screen wire <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> forms a plurality of turns, such as turn <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, turn <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and turn <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Between each of the turns is a gap through which formation fluids flow. The number of turns and the gap between the turns are determined based upon factors such as the characteristics of the formation from which fluid is being produced and the size of the gravel to be used during the gravel packing operation.. Together, ribs <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and screen wire <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> may form a sand control screen jacket which is attached to base pipe <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> by welding or other suitable technique. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, an outer shroud <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> having a plurality of perforations <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is disposed around the tubes of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Outer shroud <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> provides protection to tubes <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> during, for example, installation of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> in an uncased well. Alternatively, it should be noted by those skilled in the art, that a shroud could be placed around both the tubes and the manifolds of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, therein is depicted an alternate embodiment of a manifold for the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore that is generally designated <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> includes a tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and a sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. Tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> includes four tubes <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, that deliver the fluid slurry to manifold <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. A portion of the fluid slurry in manifold <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> will enter the annular interval surrounding apparatus <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> via four exit ports <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, only two of which are shown. The remainder of the fluid slurry enters four tubes <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, and is delivered to the next manifold of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. This process continues along the entire length of the interval to be gravel packed such that a complete gravel pack of the interval can be achieved. In this embodiment, exit ports <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of manifold <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> are circumferentially aligned with or are in phase with the adjacent tubes <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> that deliver the fluid slurry to and transport the fluid slurry from manifold <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, therein is depicted an alternate embodiment of a manifold for the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore that is generally designated <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes a tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and a sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. Tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> includes four tubes <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, that deliver the fluid slurry to manifold <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. A portion of the fluid slurry in manifold <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> will enter the annular interval surrounding apparatus <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> via eight exit ports <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, only five of which is shown. The remainder of the fluid slurry enters four tubes <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, and is delivered to the next manifold of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. This process continues along the entire length of the interval to be gravel packed such that a complete gravel pack of the interval can be achieved. In this embodiment, there are more exit ports <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> in manifold <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> than there are tubes <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, respectively delivering the fluid slurry to and carrying the fluid slurry from manifold <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. In addition, some of the exit ports are circumferentially aligned with or are in phase with the adjacent tubes <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> and some of the exit ports <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are circumferentially misaligned with or are out of phase with the adjacent tubes <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, therein is depicted an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore at the point where sections of the sand control screen assembly are joined together, that is generally designated <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> includes a tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> and a sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> having sections <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> that are coupled together in a known manner such as via a threaded coupling. Tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> includes four tubes <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, that deliver the fluid slurry to manifold <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. A portion of the fluid slurry in manifold <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> will enter the annular interval surrounding apparatus <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> via two exit ports <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight>, only one of which is shown. The remainder of the fluid slurry enters four tubes <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, only three of which are pictured, and is delivered to the next manifold of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. This process continues along the entire length of the interval to be gravel packed such that a complete gravel pack of the interval can be achieved. As illustrated, tubes <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> that deliver the fluid slurry to manifold <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> are not axially aligned with tubes <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> that transport the fluid slurry from manifold <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. Unlike the manifolds pictured in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> that are positioned within the length of a single section of the sand control screen assembly and wherein the tubes adjacent to each manifold are axially aligned with one another, tubes <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> that are adjacent to a manifold between two sections of the sand control screen such as manifold <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> will likely not be axially aligned. If the tube and manifold system is preassembled on each section of the sand control screen prior to coupling the sections of the sand control screen assembly into a string, the adjoining sections of the tube and manifold system at the ends of each section of the sand control screen assembly are coupled when the sections of the screen assembly are threaded together. Accordingly, it is likely that the tubes on either side of this manifold will not be axially aligned with one another. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As should become apparent to those skilled in the art, even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> depicts tubes <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and tubes <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> at a forty-five-degree circumferential phase shift relative to one another, any circumferential phase shift is acceptable using the present invention as the relative circumferential positions of adjoining sections of the tube and manifold system of the present invention does not affect the operation of the present invention. As such, the mating of adjoining sections of the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention is substantially similar to mating typical joints of pipe to form a pipe string requiring no special coupling tools or techniques. As such, even if the tubes adjacent to a manifold are not axially aligned with one another, they are nonetheless in fluid communication with one another such that the fluid slurry may travel from one level of tubes to the next level of tubes as the manifolds provide a substantially annular region through which the fluid slurry travels allowing for such misalignment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, therein are depicted cross sectional views of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore that is generally designated <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> includes a tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and a sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> includes base pipe <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>, porous sintered wire mesh screen <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> and screen housing <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>. Tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> includes four tubes <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> that deliver the fluid slurry to manifold <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight>. A portion of the fluid slurry in manifold <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> will enter the annular interval surrounding apparatus <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> via two exit ports <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> which are not aligned with any of the tubes <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight>. The remainder of the fluid slurry enters four tubes <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, and is delivered to the next manifold of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> As illustrated, manifold <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> has an inner sleeve <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> that seals against screen housing <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> such that the fluid slurry passing through manifold <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> does not enter sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> through perforations <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight>. Manifold <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> also includes a pair of retainer members <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. Retainer member <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and inner sleeve <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> receive and provide a seal with the discharge ends of tubes <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight>. Retainer member <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and inner sleeve <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> receive and provide a seal with the receptor ends of tubes <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. Manifold <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> has an outer housing <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> that includes exit ports <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. An annular region <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is formed between outer housing <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and inner sleeve <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> that provides fluid communication between tubes <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> and tubes <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, therein is depicted a cross sectional view of an apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore showing adjacent tubes on either side of a manifold that is generally designated <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> includes a tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and a sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> includes base pipe <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>, porous sintered wire mesh screen <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and screen housing <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. Tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> includes four tubes <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>, only two of which are visible, that deliver the fluid slurry to manifold <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. A portion of the fluid slurry in manifold <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> will enter the annular interval surrounding apparatus <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> via exit ports (not pictured) which are not aligned with any of the tubes <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. The remainder of the fluid slurry enters four tubes <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>, only two of which are pictured, and is delivered to the next manifold of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As illustrated, manifold <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> has an inner sleeve <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> that seals against screen housing <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> such that the fluid slurry passing through manifold <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> does not enter sand control screen assembly <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> through perforations <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>. Manifold <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> has an outer housing <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> that includes exit ports (not pictured) . An annular region <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> is formed between outer housing <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> and inner sleeve <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> providing fluid communication between tubes <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> and tubes <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>. Partially disposed within outer housing <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> of manifold <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> is a pair of perforated outer shrouds <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. Outer shroud <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> protects tubes <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> and, along with inner sleeve <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, retains and provides a seal with the discharge ends of tubes <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight>. Likewise, outer shroud <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> protects tubes <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> and, along with inner sleeve <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, retains and provides a seal with the receptor ends of tubes <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Even though FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> have depicted the tube and manifold system of the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention as having four tubes at each tube level, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that a variety of configurations of the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention having different numbers of tubes, either more tubes or fewer tubes are possible and is considered within the scope of the present invention. In fact, it is likely and may even be preferable to use different configurations of the tube and manifold system of the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present within a single interval. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Specifically, it may be desirable to have a volumetric capacity within the tube and manifold system that is greater toward the near end, the top in a vertical well or heel in an inclined or horizontal well, than toward the far end, the bottom or toe, of the interval. This may be achieved by using a tube and manifold system having more tubes proximate the near end of the interval and fewer tubes proximate the far end of the interval. Likewise, it may be desirable to have different numbers of exit ports on different manifolds within a tube and manifold system installed within a single interval. Specifically, it may be desirable to have fewer exit ports toward the near end of the interval compared to the far end of the interval. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10, a</cross-reference> typical completion process using an apparatus <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention will be described. First, interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> adjacent to formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is isolated. Packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> seals the upper end of annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and packer <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> seals the lower end of annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is located adjacent to screen assembly <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>, traversing packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> with portions of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> on either side of packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. When the gravel packing operation commences, the objective is to uniformly and completely fill interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> with gravel. To help achieve this result, wash pipe <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> is disposed within screen assembly <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. Wash pipe <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> extends into cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> such that return fluid passing through screen assembly <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>, indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, may travel through wash pipe <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>, and into annulus <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, as indicted by arrow <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, for return to the surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The fluid slurry containing gravel is pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> into cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> along the path indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>. The fluid slurry containing gravel exits cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> through cross-over ports <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> and is discharged into annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight>. This is the primary path as the fluid slurry seeks the path of least resistance. Under ideal conditions, the fluid slurry travels throughout the entire interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> until interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is completely packed with gravel. If, however, a sand bridge forms in annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> before the gravel packing operation is complete, the fluid slurry containing gravel will enter tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> to bypass the sand bridge as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>269</bold></highlight>. As tubes <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> of tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> do not have openings in their side walls, the entire volume of fluid slurry entering each tube <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> exits that tube <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> into one of the manifolds <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>. Some of the fluid slurry exits each of the manifolds <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> through exit ports <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. Some of the fluid slurry may also exit tube and manifold system <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> through an opening in the bottom of the last manifold, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> As the fluid slurry containing gravel enters annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, the gravel drops out of the slurry and builds up from formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, filling perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> around screen assembly <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> forming the gravel pack. Some of the carrier fluid in the slurry may leak off through perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> into formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> while the remainder of the carrier fluid passes through screen assembly <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, that is sized to prevent gravel from flowing therethrough. The fluid flowing back through screen assembly <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>, as explained above, follows the paths indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> back to the surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In operation, the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention is used to distribute the fluid slurry to various locations within the interval to be gravel packed by injecting the fluid slurry into the tube and manifold system when sand bridge formation occurs. The fluid slurry exits through the various exit ports in the manifolds along the length of the tube and manifold system into the annulus between the apparatus and the wellbore which may be cased or uncased. Once in this annulus, a portion of the gravel in the fluid slurry is deposited around the apparatus in the annulus such that the gravel migrates both circumferentially and axially from the exit ports. This process progresses along the entire length of the apparatus such that the annular area becomes completely packed with the gravel. Once the annulus is completely packed with gravel, the gravel pack operation may cease. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, it should be noted by those skilled in the art that instead of first injecting the fluid slurry directly into annular interval <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> until a sand bridge forms, the fluid slurry may initially be injected directly into the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention. In either embodiment, once the gravel pack is completed and the well is brought on line, formation fluids that are produced into the gravel packed interval must travel through the gravel pack in the annulus prior to entering the sand control screen assembly. As such, the apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention allows for a complete gravel pack of an interval so that particulate materials in the formation fluid are filtered out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> While this invention has been described with reference to illustrative embodiments, this description is not intended to be construed in a limiting sense. Various modifications and combinations of the illustrative embodiments as well as other embodiments of the invention, will be apparent to persons skilled in the art upon reference to the description. It is, therefore, intended that the appended claims encompass any such modifications or embodiments. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a sand control screen positioned within the wellbore; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tube and manifold system positioned between the sand control screen and the wellbore, the tube and manifold system delivers a fluid slurry to a plurality of levels of the interval when the apparatus is in an operable position, the tubes of the tube and manifold system having first and second ends, the tubes being open only at the first and second ends, the manifolds of the tube and manifold system having at least one exit port for the discharge of the fluid slurry from the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein one tube extends between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a plurality of tubes extend between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the exit ports of the manifolds are not circumferentially aligned with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the exit ports of the manifolds are circumferentially aligned with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is less than the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is the same as the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is greater than the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sand control screen further comprises a plurality of sections, wherein each section of the sand control screen has a plurality of the manifolds positioned adjacent thereto and wherein one of the manifolds is positioned between each adjacent section of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the tubes on either side of -the manifolds positioned adjacent to the sections of the sand control screen are axially aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned between adjacent sections of the sand control screen are not axially aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a sand control screen positioned within the wellbore; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tube and manifold system positioned between the sand control screen and the wellbore, the tube and manifold system delivers a fluid slurry to a plurality of levels of the interval when the apparatus is in an operable position, the tubes of the tube and manifold system having first and second ends, the tubes being open only at the first and second ends, the manifolds of the tube and manifold system having at least one exit port for the discharge of the fluid slurry from the tube and manifold system, the exit ports of the manifolds are not circumferentially aligned with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein one tube extends between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a plurality of tubes extend between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is less than the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is the same as the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is greater than the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sand control screen further comprises a plurality of sections, wherein each section of the sand control screen has a plurality of the manifolds positioned adjacent thereto and wherein one of the manifolds is positioned between each adjacent section of the and control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned adjacent to the sections of the sand control screen are axially aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned between adjacent sections of the sand control screen are not axially aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a sand control screen having a plurality of sections, the sand control screen positioned within the wellbore; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tube and manifold system positioned between the sand control screen and the wellbore, the tube and manifold system delivers a fluid slurry to a plurality of levels of the interval when the apparatus is in an operable position, the tubes of the tube and manifold system having first and second ends, the tubes being open only at the first and second ends, the manifolds of the tube and manifold system having at least one exit port for the discharge of the fluid slurry from the tube and manifold system, the exit ports of the manifolds are not circumferentially aligned with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system, each section of the sand control screen having a plurality of manifolds positioned adjacent thereto and each adjacent section of the sand control screen having one of the manifolds positioned therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein one tube extends between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a plurality of tubes extend between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is less than the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is the same as the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> wherein the number of exit ports in each manifold is greater than the number of tubes delivering the fluid slurry to that manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned within the sections of the sand control screen are axially aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned between adjacent sections of the sand control screen are not axially aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>traversing a formation with the wellbore; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning a tube and manifold system within the wellbore proximate the formation, the tubes of the tube and manifold system having first and second ends, the tubes having openings only at the first and second ends, the manifolds of the tube and manifold system having at least one exit port; </claim-text>
<claim-text>locating a sand control screen within the tube and manifold system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system such that the fluid slurry exits the tube and manifold system through the exit ports in the manifolds at a plurality of levels of the interval; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>terminating the injecting when the interval is substantially completely packed with the gravel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system further comprises injecting the fluid slurry containing gravel through a single tube extending between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system further comprises injecting the fluid slurry containing gravel through a plurality of tubes extending between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of circumferentially misaligning the exit ports of the manifolds with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of circumferentially aligning the exit ports of the manifolds with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of positioning a plurality of manifolds adjacent to each section of the sand control screen and positioning one of the manifolds between adjacent sections of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of axially aligning the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned adjacent to the sections of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of axially misaligning the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned between adjacent sections of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A method for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>traversing a formation with the wellbore; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning a tube and manifold system around a sand control screen, the tubes of the tube and manifold system having first and second ends, the tubes having openings only at the first and second ends, the manifolds of the tube and manifold system having at least one exit port; </claim-text>
<claim-text>locating the sand control screen and the tube and manifold system within the wellbore proximate the formation; </claim-text>
<claim-text>injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system such that the fluid slurry exits the tube and manifold system through the exit ports in the manifolds at a plurality of levels of the interval; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>terminating the injecting when the interval is substantially completely packed with the gravel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system further comprises injecting the fluid slurry containing gravel through a single tube extending between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system further comprises injecting the fluid slurry containing gravel through a plurality of tubes extending between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of circumferentially misaligning the exit ports of the manifolds with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of circumferentially aligning the exit ports of the manifolds with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of positioning a plurality of manifolds adjacent to each section of the sand control screen and positioning one of the manifolds between adjacent sections of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of axially aligning the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned adjacent to the sections of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of axially misaligning the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned between adjacent sections of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A method for gravel packing an interval of a wellbore, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>traversing a formation with the wellbore; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning a tube and manifold system around a sand control screen having a plurality of sections, the tubes of the tube and manifold system having first and second ends, the tubes having openings only at the first and second ends, the manifolds of the tube and manifold system having at least one exit port; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning a plurality of manifolds adjacent to each section of the sand control screen and positioning one of the manifolds between adjacent sections of the sand control screen; </claim-text>
<claim-text>circumferentially misaligning the exit ports of the manifolds with adjacent tubes of the tube and manifold system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>locating the sand control screen and the tube and manifold system within the wellbore proximate the formation; </claim-text>
<claim-text>injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system such that the fluid slurry exits the tube and manifold system through the exit ports in the manifolds at a plurality of levels of the interval; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>terminating the injecting when the interval is substantially completely packed with the gravel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system further comprises injecting the fluid slurry containing gravel through a single tube extending between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of injecting a fluid slurry containing gravel through the tube and manifold system further comprises injecting the fluid slurry containing gravel through a plurality of tubes extending between each of the manifolds of the tube and manifold system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of axially aligning the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned adjacent to the sections of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of axially misaligning the tubes on either side of the manifolds positioned between adjacent sections of the sand control screen.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000699A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000699A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000699A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000699A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000699A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000699A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000699A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000699A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
