<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004505A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004505A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004505</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896131</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61B018/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61F002/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61N001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61N001/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61N001/05</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61N001/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>606</class>
<subclass>041000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>607</class>
<subclass>101000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>607</class>
<subclass>122000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Electrophysiological probes having selective element actuation and variable lesion length capability</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Bencini</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Miriam</given-name>
<middle-name>H.</middle-name>
<family-name>Taimisto</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HENRICKS SLAVIN AND HOLMES LLP</name-1>
<name-2>SUITE 200</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>840 APOLLO STREET</address-1>
<city>EL SEGUNDO</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90245</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An apparatus having a support structure, a plurality of longitudinally spaced conductive regions, and an actuation device including at least one electrical contact located within the support structure and movable between respective positions where the one electrical contact is in electrical connection with one of the spaced conductive regions. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of Inventions </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present inventions relate generally to medical devices that support one or more diagnostic or therapeutic elements in contact with body tissue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> There are many instances where diagnostic and therapeutic elements must be inserted into the body. One instance involves the treatment of cardiac conditions such as atrial fibrillation and atrial flutter which lead to an unpleasant, irregular heart beat, called arrhythmia. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Normal sinus rhythm of the heart begins with the sinoatrial node (or &ldquo;SA node&rdquo;) generating an electrical impulse. The impulse usually propagates uniformly across the right and left atria and the atrial septum to the atrioventricular node (or &ldquo;AV node&rdquo;). This propagation causes the atria to contract in an organized way to transport blood from the atria to the ventricles, and to provide timed stimulation of the ventricles. The AV node regulates the propagation delay to the atrioventricular bundle (or &ldquo;HIS&rdquo; bundle). This coordination of the electrical activity of the heart causes atrial systole during ventricular diastole. This, in turn, improves the mechanical function of the heart. Atrial fibrillation occurs when anatomical obstacles in the heart disrupt the normally uniform propagation of electrical impulses in the atria. These anatomical obstacles (called &ldquo;conduction blocks&rdquo;) can cause the electrical impulse to degenerate into several circular wavelets that circulate about the obstacles. These wavelets, called &ldquo;reentry circuits,&rdquo; disrupt the normally uniform activation of the left and right atria. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Because of a loss of atrioventricular synchrony, the people who suffer from atrial fibrillation and flutter also suffer the consequences of impaired hemodynamics and loss of cardiac efficiency. They are also at greater risk of stroke and other thromboembolic complications because of loss of effective contraction and atrial stasis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> One surgical method of treating atrial fibrillation by interrupting pathways for reentry circuits is the so-called &ldquo;maze procedure&rdquo; which relies on a prescribed pattern of incisions to anatomically create a convoluted path, or maze, for electrical propagation within the left and right atria. The incisions direct the electrical impulse from the SA node along a specified route through all regions of both atria, causing uniform contraction required for normal atrial transport function. The incisions finally direct the impulse to the AV node to activate the ventricles, restoring normal atrioventricular synchrony. The incisions are also carefully placed to interrupt the conduction routes of the most common reentry circuits. The maze procedure has been found very effective in curing atrial fibrillation. However, the maze procedure is technically difficult to do. It also requires open heart surgery and is very expensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Maze-like procedures have also been developed utilizing catheters which can form lesions on the endocardium to effectively create a maze for electrical conduction in a predetermined path. The formation of these lesions by soft tissue coagulation (also referred to as &ldquo;ablation&rdquo;) can provide the same therapeutic benefits that the complex incision patterns that the surgical maze procedure presently provides, but without invasive, open heart surgery. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Catheters used to create lesions typically include a relatively long and flexible body portion that supports a soft tissue coagulation electrode on its distal end and/or a series of spaced soft tissue coagulation electrodes near the distal end. The portion of the catheter body that is inserted into the patient is typically from 23 to 55 inches in length and there may be another 8 to 15 inches, including a handle having steering controls, outside the patient. The length and flexibility of the catheter body allow the catheter to be inserted into a main vein or artery (typically the femoral artery), directed into the interior of the heart, and then manipulated such that the coagulation electrodes contact the tissue that is to be ablated. Fluoroscopic imaging is used to provide the physician with a visual indication of the location of the catheter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Therapeutic lesions, whether formed alone or as part of a therapeutic lesion pattern, must often be formed in varying lengths to suit particular situations. In those instances where the catheter includes a single tip electrode, the physician must manipulate the catheter so that the tip electrode is dragged along the desired length of tissue during lesion formation. Such a technique is problematic because it is difficult to properly execute and often results in incomplete lesions, lesion gaps and tissue charring. Superior results have been obtained using catheters that support multiple electrodes. Here, some or all of the electrodes on the catheter may be selectively connected to an energy source to produce lesions of various lengths. The inventors herein have determined that, while superior to the drag technique, forming lesions of various lengths with conventional multiple electrode catheters can be inconvenient because such catheters require the use of a power supply and control device that is capable of selectively connecting some or all of the electrodes to the energy source. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> An apparatus in accordance with one embodiment of one present invention includes a support structure, a plurality of longitudinally spaced conductive regions, and an actuation device including at least one electrical contact located within the support structure and movable between respective positions where the electrical contact is in electrical connection with a respective conductive region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Such an apparatus provides a number of advantages over conventional apparatus. For example, lesions of various lengths and configurations may be produced by forming a portion of an overall lesion when the actuation device is in one position, then moving the actuation device to another position to form an additional portion of the lesion, and so on until the desired lesion is formed. As a result, the apparatus allows physicians to selectively actuate some or all of the conductive regions to form a variety of lesions without having to use a power supply and control device that is itself capable of selectively connecting some or all of the conductive regions to an energy source. Additionally, because such an apparatus also allows lesions of varying length to be created without moving the support structure, the precise positioning of the apparatus will not be compromised and the unintended ablation of non-target tissue will be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The above described and many other features and attendant advantages of the present inventions will become apparent as the inventions become better understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Detailed description of preferred embodiments of the inventions will be made with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side view of a probe in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side view of a portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side, partial section view of the distal portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a side view showing a portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is another side, partial section view of the distal portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of a portion of the handle in the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an illustration of exemplary lesions that may formed using probes in accordance with the present inventions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a side, partial section view of the distal portion of a probe in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the slidable actuator illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a side, partial section view of the distal portion of a probe in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a side view of a portion of a handle in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a side view of a probe in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a side, partial section view of the distal portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a section view taken along line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a side view of a probe in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a side, partial section view of the distal portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a section view taken along line <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a side view of a probe in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a side, partial section view of the distal portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a section view taken along line <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a side, partial section view of a portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a side view of a probe in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a side, partial section view of a portion of the probe illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23 a</cross-reference> partial side view of a distal structure that may be used in conjunction with a probe such as that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 21 and 22</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a side, section view of a temperature sensor arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> is a section view of a portion of a probe including the temperature sensor arrangement illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The following is a detailed description of the best presently known modes of carrying out the inventions. This description is not to be taken in a limiting sense, but is made merely for the purpose of illustrating the general principles of the inventions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The detailed description of the preferred embodiments is organized as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> I. Introduction </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> II. Catheter-Based Probe Structures </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> III. Catheter-Based Probe Structures With Porous Distal Regions </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> IV. Imaging </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> V. Surgical Probe Structures </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> VI. Temperature Sensing and Power Control </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The section titles and overall organization of the present detailed description are for the purpose of convenience only and are not intended to limit the present inventions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> I. Introduction </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The present inventions may be used within body lumens, chambers or cavities for diagnostic or therapeutic purposes in those instances where access to interior bodily regions is obtained through, for example, the vascular system or alimentary canal and/or with minimally invasive surgical procedures. For example, the inventions herein have application in the diagnosis and treatment of arrhythmia conditions within the heart. The inventions herein also have application in the diagnosis or treatment of ailments of the gastrointestinal tract, prostrate, brain, gall bladder, uterus, and other regions of the body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> With regard to the treatment of conditions within the heart, the present inventions are designed to produce intimate tissue contact with target substrates associated with various arrhythmias, namely atrial fibrillation, atrial flutter, and ventricular tachycardia. For example, the distal portion of a probe in accordance with a present invention can be used to create lesions of various shapes, lengths and widths to treat atrial fibrillation. The distal portion can also be used for sensing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> II. Catheter-Based Probe Structures </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As illustrated for example in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, a catheter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with a preferred embodiment of a present invention includes a hollow, flexible catheter body <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> that is formed from two tubular parts, or members, both of which are non-conductive. The proximal member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is relatively long and is attached to a handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, while the distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, which is relatively short, carries a plurality of spaced electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> that may be used for lesion formation, sensing, etc. The proximal member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is typically formed from a biocompatible thermoplastic material, such as a Pebax&reg; material (polyether block emide) and stainless steel braid composite or a polyethylene and stainless steel braid composite, which has good torque transmission properties. An elongate guide coil <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) is provided within the proximal member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is typically formed from a softer, more flexible biocompatible thermoplastic material such as unbraided Pebax&reg; material, polyethylene, or polyurethane. The proximal and distal members, which are about 5 French to about 9 French in diameter, may be either bonded together with an overlapping thermal bond or adhesively bonded together end to end over a sleeve in what is referred to as a &ldquo;butt bond.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Referring more specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, the exemplary distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> includes a pair of end sections <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and a plurality of intermediate sections <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> positioned between adjacent electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Each of the sections <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is non-conductive. The electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be secured to the distal member sections <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> with adhesive or thermal bonding techniques during assembly. In the exemplary embodiment, the lateral ends of the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the distal member sections <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> have corresponding protrusions that together form lap joints <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The exemplary embodiment illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes five (5) electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Nevertheless, the number of electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be varied as desired to suit particular applications from as few as two (2) to as many as 14 or more. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The exemplary electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be formed from metal or a conductive plastic material. Suitable metals include platinum, while suitable conductive plastic materials include composites consisting of plastic and metal powder. The electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be in the form of rings, coiled wire or coil-cut tubing. Flexible electrodes are typically about 4 mm to about 13 mm in length, and are preferably about 12 mm in length with about 1 mm to about 4 mm spacing. For rigid electrodes, the length of the each electrode can vary from about 2 mm to about 10 mm with about 1 mm to about 4 mm spacing. Using multiple rigid electrodes longer than about 10 mm each adversely effects the overall flexibility of the device, while electrodes having lengths of less than about 2 mm do not consistently form the desired continuous lesion patterns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In some implementations of the inventions, the portion of the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> that are not intended to contact tissue (and be exposed to the blood pool) may be masked through a variety of techniques with a material that is preferably electrically and thermally insulating. This prevents the transmission of coagulation energy directly into the blood pool and directs the energy directly toward and into the tissue. For example, a layer of UV adhesive (or another adhesive) may be painted on preselected portions of the electrodes to insulate the portions of the electrodes not intended to contact tissue. Deposition techniques may also be implemented to position a conductive surface only on those portions of the assembly intended to contact tissue. Alternatively, a coating may be formed by dipping the electrodes in PTFE material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may also include a porous material coating, which transmits coagulation energy through an electrified ionic medium. For example, as disclosed in U.S. application Ser. No. 08/879,343, filed Jun. 20, 1997, entitled &ldquo;Surface Coatings For Catheters, Direct Contacting Diagnostic and Therapeutic Devices,&rdquo; electrodes and temperature sensors may be coated with regenerated cellulose, hydrogel or plastic having electrically conductive components. With respect to regenerated cellulose, the coating acts as a mechanical barrier between the surgical device components, such as electrodes, preventing ingress of blood cells, infectious agents, such as viruses and bacteria, and large biological molecules such as proteins, while providing electrical contact to the human body. The regenerated cellulose coating also acts as a biocompatible barrier between the device components and the human body, whereby the components can now be made from materials that are somewhat toxic (such as silver or copper). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Finally, the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be operated in a uni-polar mode, in which the soft tissue coagulation energy emitted by the electrodes is returned through an indifferent patch electrode (not shown) externally attached to the skin of the patient. Alternatively, the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be operated in a bi-polar mode, in which energy emitted by one electrode is returned through a return electrode (not shown) that is mounted on the catheter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also be steerable. To that end, and as illustrated for example in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> steering center support <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is mounted on the distal end of the guide coil <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The steering center support <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is preferably about 0.035 inch wide, 0.005 inch thick, 2 to 6 inches long, and formed from stainless steel. Of course, center supports formed from other materials and having different dimensions may also be used. In order to increase the stiffness of the center support <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, optional leaf springs (not shown) may also be provided on one or both sides of the center support. The center support <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes a pair of shoulders <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. One of the shoulders is inserted into the guide coil <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the other is secured to a tip member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> formed from platinum or another suitable material. The tip metal may be used as an electrode, if desired, or as a non-conducting atraumatic tip. Preferably, the shoulder <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is soldered to the tip member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the tip member is bonded to the distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, thereby creating a rigid connection between the center support, the tip member, and the distal member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Steering wires <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are secured to opposing sides of the steering center support <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The steering wires <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> extend through the guide coil <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and are connected to a control knob <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> on the catheter handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). Rotation of the control knob causes the center support <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and, therefore, the distal portion of the catheter, to deflect. The guide coil <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, center support <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and steering wires <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are also preferably housed in an insulative tube <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> formed from material such as Kevlar, Teflon&trade; or polyester. Additionally, other types of steering devices, such as those discussed below with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, may also be employed in the exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Turning to the selective actuation of the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the exemplary embodiment illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, i.e. the selective electrical connection of the electrodes to a device such as an RF power supply and control device or a mapping device, the exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is provided with a slidable actuator that allows the electrodes to be used individually as desired by the user. As illustrated for example in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the exemplary actuator <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> includes a tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> that is positioned over the insulative tube <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a pair of flexible spring-like electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> that are mounted on the tubular member and biased against the inner surface of the catheter body (or electrodes, depending on location). The number of electrical contacts may be varied to suit particular situations and taking into account factors such as impedance considerations in RF generator algorithms, but from one (1) to three (3) is preferred. Wires <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extend from the electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to a PC board in the handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), where they are electrically coupled to a connector <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> that plugs into the power supply and control or mapping device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The exemplary tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, which is preferably formed from nonconductive material such as Teflon, kynar, polyethylene, and polyamide and is about 50 inches in length, is connected to a slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> on the handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> by a stylet <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>). Alternatively, the tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> may simply extend all the way into the handle or be relatively short and have a length corresponding to that of the distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> or less. Referring more specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 5</cross-reference>, the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are preferably numbered (1-5 in the illustrated embodiment) and corresponding indicia is provided on the handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> adjacent to the slider. The position of the slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> relative to the indicia on the handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> corresponds to the position of the electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> relative to the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Placing the slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> next to the &ldquo;1&rdquo; on the handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> will, for example, result in the tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> being positioned such that the electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> are in contact with electrode &ldquo;1.&rdquo; Similarly, placing the slider next to the &ldquo;2,&rdquo; &ldquo;3,&rdquo; &ldquo;4&rdquo; and &ldquo;5&rdquo; respectively moves the electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> into contact with electrodes &ldquo;2,&rdquo; &ldquo;3,&rdquo; &ldquo;4&rdquo; and &ldquo;5,&rdquo; respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Additional details concerning catheter steering handles which include a control knob and a slider may be found in U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,257,451, 5,582,609, 5,871,523 and 5,928,191, which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> It should be noted that, in alternative embodiments, the actuator <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>) may include additional electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> positioned such that the actuator can make selective electrical connection with two or more adjacent or spaced electrodes to simultaneously actuate two or more adjacent electrodes, or two or more spaced electrodes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Lesions of various lengths may be produced with the exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by forming a portion of an overall lesion when the actuator <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is in one position, and then moving the actuator to another position to form additional portions of the lesion. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, exemplary lesion L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> may be formed by first positioning the slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> at the &ldquo;5&rdquo; on the handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, thereby bringing the electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> into contact with electrode &ldquo;5.&rdquo; Power is then supplied to electrode &ldquo;5&rdquo; by way of the electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and wires <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is then moved to the &ldquo;4,&rdquo; &ldquo;3,&rdquo; &ldquo;2,&rdquo; and &ldquo;1&rdquo; positions, with power supplied to the corresponding electrode <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at each position, to form a lesion that spans all five electrodes. Exemplary lesion L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which is shorter than lesion L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, is formed by merely moving the slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> to the &ldquo;5&rdquo; and &ldquo;4&rdquo; positions and supplying power to electrodes &ldquo;5&rdquo; and &ldquo;4,&rdquo; while lesion exemplary L<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, which includes a gap, is formed by supplying power to electrodes &ldquo;5,&rdquo; &ldquo;4,&rdquo; &ldquo;2&rdquo; and &ldquo;1.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The width of an entire lesion, or a portion of a lesion, may be varied by varying the amount of power, temperature set point, time applied, or some combination thereof. To produce exemplary lesion L<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, a relatively large amount of power is supplied to electrodes &ldquo;5&rdquo; and &ldquo;4&rdquo; (about 50 watts for about 120 seconds), a relatively small amount of power is supplied to electrode &ldquo;3&rdquo; (about 20 watts for about 60 seconds) and an intermediate level of power (about 35 watts for about 120 seconds) is supplied to electrodes &ldquo;2&rdquo; and &ldquo;1.&rdquo; It should be noted that the lesions may also be asymmetrical. Lesion L<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, for example, is formed by supplying a relatively large amount of power to electrodes &ldquo;5&rdquo; and &ldquo;4&rdquo; and a relatively small amount of power to electrodes &ldquo;3,&rdquo; &ldquo;2&rdquo; and &ldquo;1.&rdquo; The same results may also be obtained by varying the temperature set point. For example, wide lesions may be produced with a 80&deg; C. set point, while narrow lesions may be formed with a 65&deg; C. set point. Curved lesions may also be formed by flexing the distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> with the steering wires <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> during lesion formation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The present inventions may be embodied in a variety of devices other than that illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. As illustrated for example in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, a slidable actuator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> may be used in place of the slidable actuator <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. The slidable actuator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, which is connected to a wire <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and is formed from flexible conductive material such as copper or 304 stainless steel, consists of a generally flat elongate portion <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> that slides along the insulative tube <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a curved, spring-like electrical contact <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> that maintains contact with the inner surface of the non-conductive portions of the distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, or electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, depending on its position. The actuator <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is also connected to the slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> by a stylet (not show). As such, the electrical contact <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> may be moved from electrode to electrode in the manner described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Another slidable actuator, which is generally represented by reference numeral <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, includes an electrical contact brush <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> that is mounted on the tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> in place of the spring-like contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The brush <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> includes a conductive base <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to which a wire <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is connected and a plurality of conductive bristles <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> that engage the inner surface of the non-conductive portions of the distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Here too, the tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is connected to the slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> by a stylet and, accordingly, the electrical contact brush <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> may be moved from electrode to electrode in the manner described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The handle may also be modified as desired. The handle <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, for example, does not include the slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> found on handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Instead, the handle <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, which is otherwise substantially identical to handle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, includes a rotatable knob <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> that is connected to a gear and rack arrangement within the handle (not shown) that drives the stylet. A suitable gear and rack arrangement is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,364,351, which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> III. Catheter-Based Probe Structures With Porous Distal Regions </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Turning to FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the present inventions also have application in probes that employ conductive fluid to transmit energy to tissue. The exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> includes a hollow, flexible catheter body <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> that is preferably formed from two tubular parts, or members, both of which are non-conductive. The proximal member <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is relatively long and is attached to a handle <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, while the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, which is relatively short, includes a plurality of small apertures <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The proximal member <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is typically formed from a biocompatible thermoplastic material, such as a Pebax&reg; material and stainless steel braid composite. The distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is typically formed from a softer, more flexible biocompatible thermoplastic material such as unbraided Pebax&reg; material, polyethylene, or polyurethane. The small apertures <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> typically range from about 0.02 micron to about 0.4 micron in diameter, but are functional in smaller sizes provided that the material is permeable and hydrophilic. Alternatively, 0.002 inch to 0.012 inch apertures with saline infusion to the outside of the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> may also be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The proximal and distal members, which are about 5 French to about 9 French in diameter, are preferably either bonded together with an overlapping thermal bond or adhesively bonded together end to end over a sleeve in what is referred to as a &ldquo;butt bond.&rdquo; The distal end of the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is sealed with a metal or plastic tip member <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> that is secured to the distal member with adhesive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Fluid is supplied to portions of the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> through a slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> that may be formed from Pebax&reg; or other suitable non-conducive material. The distal region of the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> includes a pair of fluid apertures <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and a pair of gaskets <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. Fluid flowing through the apertures <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is restricted to the region between the gaskets <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, thereby defining a movable lesion formation region R. A small protrusion or other stop member (not shown) may be provided near the distal end of the proximal member <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to prevent the distal portion of the lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and the gaskets <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> from being moved out of the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The proximal portion of the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> extends through an aperture in the handle <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and includes a connector <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> for connecting the lumen to a source of conductive fluid. A handle <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is provided to make it easier for the physician to grip the proximal portion of the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and move the lesion formation region R. A slidable tab <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>, which is connected to the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, may be positioned on the exterior of the handle <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> adjacent to indicia representative of various portions of the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to help the physician position the movable lesion formation region R. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> An electrode <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> that supplies coagulating energy to the tissue T by way of the conductive fluid to form the lesion L is carried by the portion of slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> between the gaskets <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. The electrode <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> should be formed from material with both relatively high electrical conductivity and relatively high thermal conductivity. Suitable materials include gold, platinum, and platinum/iridium. Noble metals are preferred. The electrode <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> is connected to a PC board within the handle <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> by a wire <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> that is secured to the exterior of the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> over much of its length. The PC board is, in turn, connected to a connector <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> in conventional fashion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The conductive fluid preferably possesses a low resistivity to decrease ohmic loses, and thus ohmic heating effects, within the catheter. The composition of the electrically conductive fluid can vary. A hypertonic saline solution, having a sodium chloride concentration at or near saturation, which is about 20% weight by volume is preferred. Hypertonic saline solution has a low resistivity of only about 5 ohm&middot;cm, compared to blood resistivity of about 150 ohm&middot;cm and myocardial tissue resistivity of about 500 ohm&middot;cm. Ionic contrast solution, which has an inherently low resistivity, can be mixed with the hypertonic saline solution. The mixture enables radiographic identification of the lesion formation region R without diminishing the ionic transfer through the pores. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The small apertures <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are large enough for the conductive fluid to flow through. Because the flow of conductive fluid into the body is often undesirable, the exemplary embodiment illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> includes a layer of microporous material <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> that covers the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and facilitates the transfer of energy into the tissue, while preventing most conductive fluid perfusion. The pores in the microporous layer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> establishes ionic transport of the tissue coagulating energy from the electrode <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> through the electrically conductive fluid to tissue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> More specifically, due largely to mass concentration differentials across the pores of the microporous layer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, ions in the conductive fluid will pass into the pores because of concentration differential-driven diffusion. Ion diffusion through the pores will continue as long as a concentration gradient is maintained across the microporous layer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The ions contained in the pores provide the means to conduct current across the microporous layer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. When RF energy is conveyed from a RF power supply and control apparatus to the electrode <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, electric current is carried by the ions within the pores. The RF currents provided by the ions result in no net diffusion of ions, as would occur if a DC voltage were applied, although the ions do move slightly back and forth during the RF frequency application. This ionic movement (and current flow) in response to the applied RF field does not require perfusion of fluid through the pores. The ions convey RF energy through the pores into tissue to a return electrode, which is typically an external patch electrode (forming a unipolar arrangement). Alternatively, the transmitted energy can pass through tissue to an adjacent electrode (forming a bipolar arrangement). The RF energy heats tissue (mostly ohmically) to coagulate the tissue and form a lesion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> With respect to materials, the exemplary microporous layer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is preferably formed from regenerated cellulose or a microporous elastic polymer. Materials such as nylons (with a softening temperature above 100&deg; C.), PTFE, PEI and PEEK that have micropores created through the use of lasers, electrostatic discharge, ion beam bombardment or other processes may also be used. Such materials would preferably include a hydrophilic coating. The micropores should occupy about 1% of the surface area and be about 0.02 micron to about 0.4 micron in diameter, but are functional in smaller sizes provided that the material is permeable and hydrophilic. A slightly larger pore diameter may also be employed. Because the larger pore diameter would result in significant fluid transfer through the porous region, a saline solution having a sodium chloride concentration of about 0.9% weight by volume is preferred. Smaller pores may be used. However, the surface are should be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is also a steerable catheter and, to that end, includes a pair of steering wires <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> that extend through steering wire lumens <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> that are formed in the catheter body wall. Preferably, the catheter body proximal and distal members <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> are triple lumen extrusions. The individual lumen portions are aligned during assembly of the catheter body <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> to form the steering lumens <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. &lsqb;The micropores should not be formed in the area of the steering lumens <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>.&rsqb; The proximal ends of the steering wires <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> are connected to a control knob <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> on the catheter handle <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and the distal ends are anchored near the distal ends of the steering wire lumens <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. So configured, rotation of the control knob <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> causes the distal portion of the catheter to deflect. Additional information concerning the use of steering wires in a catheter body wall may be found in U.S. Pat. No. 5,676,653 and U.S. application Ser. No. 09/165,652, which is entitled &ldquo;Steerable Device For Introducing Diagnostic And Therapeutic Apparatus Into The Body,&rdquo; both of which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The exemplary catheter illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> may be used to form lesions of various length much in the same manner as the catheters described above with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. More specifically, once the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is properly positioned within the body, the physician can move the lesion formation region R (by moving the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>) to the desired location. The lesion formation region R is then filled with conductive fluid and power is supplied to the electrode <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> to form the first portion of the lesion. The lesion formation region R is then moved to an adjacent tissue area and power is again applied to form the next portion of the lesion. This process may be repeated until a lesion having the desired length has been formed. Alternatively, power may be continuously applied as the lesion formation region R is being moved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> IV. Imaging </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> On-board imaging capability, which allows the physician to monitor the formation of lesions, may also be provided in probes embodying the present inventions. The exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes such imaging capability in addition to many of the features of the catheters described above with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. More specifically, exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> includes a hollow, flexible catheter body <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> that is preferably formed from a proximal member <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, which is relatively long and is attached to a handle <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and a distal member <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, which is relatively short and carries a plurality of spaced electrodes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The proximal member <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is typically formed from a biocompatible thermoplastic material, such as a Pebax&reg; or polyethylene material and stainless steel braid composite, which has good torque transmission properties, while the distal member <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is typically formed from a softer, more flexible biocompatible thermoplastic material such as unbraided Pebax&reg; material, polyethylene, or polyurethane. The proximal and distal members, which are about 5 French to about 9 French in diameter, are preferably either bonded together with an overlapping thermal bond or adhesively bonded together end to end over a sleeve in what is referred to as a &ldquo;butt bond.&rdquo; Here, however, the electrodes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> must be formed from conductive materials such as metal powder and plastic composites because pure metal electrodes would interfere with imaging. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Like the exemplary distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the exemplary distal member <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> includes a pair of end sections <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and a plurality of intermediate sections <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> positioned between adjacent electrodes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Each distal member section is non-conductive. The electrodes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may be secured to the distal member sections with adhesive or thermal bonding techniques during assembly. A tip member <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> is secured to the distal end of the catheter body <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> To facilitate bi-directional steering, the exemplary catheter <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes a pair of steering wires <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that extend through steering wire lumens <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Respective portions of the steering wire lumens <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are formed in the catheter body proximal member <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, distal member sections <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, and electrodes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, each of which has a triple lumen design. The proximal member <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, electrodes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and distal member sections <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> are preferably formed as triple lumen extrusions. The individual lumen portions are aligned with one another during assembly to form the steering lumens <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The proximal ends of the steering wires <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are connected to a control knob <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> on the catheter handle <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and the distal ends are anchored near the distal ends of the steering wire lumens <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. So configured, rotation of the control knob <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> causes the distal portion of the catheter <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to deflect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> A single lumen and steering wire may, of course, be used to provide unidirectional steering. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Turning to the imaging aspects, a slidable imaging device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is positioned within the catheter body <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Although not limited to such a device, the imaging device in the exemplary embodiment is an ultrasonic imaging device including a conventional ultrasonic transducer (not shown) that is located within a transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. The transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is mounted on the end of a rotatable cable <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. A motor <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, which is mounted within a slidable handle <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, is used to rotate the cable <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> (and transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>) in conventional fashion. Additional details concerning the operation of ultrasonic imaging devices may be found in U.S. Pat. No. 5,131,397, which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> The transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> also carries a pair of spring-like electrical contacts <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, thereby forming an actuator that may be moved from electrode to electrode by moving the slidable handle <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> to create lesions in the manner described above. The electrical contacts <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> are, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, curved to facilitate rotation of the transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. Movement of the housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and electrical contacts <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, which is limited by proximal (not shown) and distal protrusions <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, may be also monitored using a slidable tab <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> that is connected to the slidable actuator handle <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and handle indicia representative of the respective electrodes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. &lsqb;<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>.&rsqb; The ultrasonic transducer, motor <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and electrical contacts <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> are connected to PC board in the handle <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> by various wires in conventional fashion (not shown), which is in turn connected to a connector <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Another exemplary probe, which includes both on-board imaging capability and a porous distal region, is illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and is generally represented by reference numeral <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. Probe <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> includes many of the same elements as exemplary probe <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and exemplary probe <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>). The same (or similar) elements are represented by the same (or similar) reference numerals. Such common elements are discussed in detail above and, therefore, are only discussed as necessary with respect to probe <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The exemplary probe <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> includes a hollow, flexible catheter body <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> with a proximal member <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> that is relatively long and attached to a handle <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and a distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, which is relatively short and has a plurality of small apertures <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The distal end of the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is sealed with a metal or plastic tip member <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. Fluid is supplied to portions of the distal member <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> through a slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime; that includes a pair of fluid apertures <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>&prime;. A pair of gaskets <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>&prime; are positioned on opposite sides of the apertures <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>&prime;. Fluid flowing through the apertures <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>&prime; is restricted to the region between the gaskets <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>&prime;, thereby defining a movable lesion formation region R. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The proximal portion of the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime; is mounted within the slidable handle <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>&prime;. A rotatable cable <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> passes through the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime; and extends from a motor <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> to the housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>&prime; of an imaging device <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>&prime;. A fluid transmission space <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> is defined between the exterior of the cable <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and the inner surface of the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime;. A suitable gasket or other sealing device (not shown) is provided at the proximal end of the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime; to prevent fluid leakage. Fluid is supplied to the transmission space <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> by a tube <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> that is connected to a source of conductive fluid by a connector <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. The electrode <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> that supplies coagulating energy to the tissue by way of the conductive fluid is carried by the proximal end of the transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>&prime; and is connected to a source of energy by a wire <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the electrode <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> may be mounted on the distal end of the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime; between the apertures <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>&prime; and the gasket <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Referring more particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>, the transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>&prime; is preferably connected to the gasket <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>&prime; by a ball and socket arrangement <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> that allows the housing to rotate relative to the gasket and the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime;. In the illustrated embodiment, the transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>&prime; is provided with a ball <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> that is mounted within a socket <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> formed in the gasket <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>&prime;. This arrangement may be reversed such that the housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>&prime; includes the socket and the gasket <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>&prime; includes the ball. Other arrangements that rotatably connect the transducer housing <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>&prime; to the gasket <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>&prime; may also be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> V. Surgical Probe Structures </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Each of the structures described above are also adaptable for use with probes other than catheter-based probes. For example, the structures described above may also be used in the manner described above in conjunction with hand held surgical devices (or &ldquo;surgical probes&rdquo;). The distal end of a surgical probe may be placed directly in contact with the targeted tissue area by a physician during a surgical procedure, such as open heart surgery. Here, access may be obtained by way of a thoracotomy, median sternotomy, or thoracostomy. Exemplary surgical probes are disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,142,994, which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Surgical probes in accordance with the present inventions preferably include a handle, a relatively short shaft, and one of the actuation devices described above in the catheter context. Preferably, the length of the shaft is about 4 inches to about 18 inches. This is relatively short in comparison to the portion of a catheter body that is inserted into the patient (typically from 23 to 55 inches in length) and the additional body portion that remains outside the patient. The shaft is also relatively stiff. In other words, the shaft is either rigid, malleable, or somewhat flexible. A rigid shaft cannot be bent. A malleable shaft is a shaft that can be readily bent by the physician to a desired shape, without springing back when released, so that it will remain in that shape during the surgical procedure. Thus, the stiffness of a malleable shaft must be low enough to allow the shaft to be bent, but high enough to resist bending when the forces associated with a surgical procedure are applied to the shaft. A somewhat flexible shaft will bend and spring back when released. However, the force required to bend the shaft must be substantial. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> As illustrated for example in FIGS. <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, an exemplary surgical probe <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> includes a relatively short shaft <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, a handle <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, and a distal section <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. The shaft <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> consists of an outer polymer tube <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> and a hypo-tube (not shown), which is either rigid or relatively stiff (preferably malleable), positioned within the outer tube such that a small space is defined therebetween. The exterior of the distal section <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> is essentially identical to the exterior of the distal member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> described above with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the same elements are represented by the same reference numerals in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 21 and 22</cross-reference>. More specifically, the exemplary distal section <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> includes a pair of nonconductive end sections <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and a plurality of non-conductive intermediate sections <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> positioned between adjacent conductive electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The end section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and outer tube <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> may be either bonded together with an overlapping thermal bond or adhesively bonded together end to end over a sleeve in what is referred to as a &ldquo;butt bond.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> The interior of the distal section <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> preferably includes a spring member <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and a tapered malleable member <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. The spring member <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is secured to a tip member <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> by adhesive or welding, and the malleable member <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> is secured to the shaft hypotube by welding or other suitable methods. In a preferred implementation having five electrodes, the malleable member <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> will extend to third electrode, although this may be varied depending on the intended application. The spring member <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and malleable member <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> may be secured to one another with a stainless steel crimp tube <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, which is soldered or otherwise bonded to the malleable member and mechanically coupled to the spring member with crimps <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>. Suitable materials for the malleable member <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> include stainless steel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Exemplary surgical probe <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> is also provided with a selective electrode actuation arrangement similar to that illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>A. Referring more specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 21 and 22</cross-reference>, the exemplary surgical probe <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> also includes a slidable actuator that allows the electrodes to be used individually as desired by the user. As discussed in detail above, the exemplary actuator <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> includes a tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> (here positioned over the spring member <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and tapered malleable member <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>) and a pair of flexible spring-like electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> that are mounted on the tubular member and biased against the inner surface of the non-conductive portions of the distal section <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, depending on location. Wires <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extend from the electrical contacts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to a PC board in the handle <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, where they are electrically coupled to a connector <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> that plugs into the power supply and control or mapping device. The tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> may be connected to a slider <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> on the handle <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> by a stylet (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>) or, alternatively, the tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> may simply extend all the way into the handle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> VI. Temperature Sensing and Power Control </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> A plurality of temperature sensors, such as thermocouples or thermistors, may be located on, under, abutting the longitudinal end edges of, or in between, the electrodes. An exemplary sensing arrangement that may be used in conjunction with the devices illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 24 and 25</cross-reference>. Here, thermistors <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> may be embedded adjacent to each of the electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime; during assembly. The electrodes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;, the non-conducting portions of the distal section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>&prime;, and the proximal section (not shown here) are preferably multi-lumen extrusions similar to those discussed above with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 16</cross-reference>. The lumens <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> provide passage ways for signal wires <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, which are connected to the aforementioned PC board. Suitable temperature sensors and controllers which control power to electrodes based on a sensed temperature are disclosed in U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,456,682, 5,582,609 and 5,755,715. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> In those instances where conductive fluid is used, the temperature of the fluid is preferably monitored for power control purposes. To that end, a temperature sensing element, such as a thermocouple, the illustrated thermistor <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> or some other temperature sensing element (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>), may mounted on the slidable lumen <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> with the lesion formation region R. The thermocouple is connected to the aforementioned PC board in the catheter handle by a wire <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Although the present inventions have been described in terms of the preferred embodiments above, numerous modifications and/or additions to the above-described preferred embodiments would be readily apparent to one skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> By way of example, but not limitation, the insulative tube <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> could be externally threaded and the tubular member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> could have corresponding internal threads such that relative rotation would cause the tubular member to translate over the insulative tube. The structures disclosed herein may be used in conjunction with loop-type catheter-based probes such as those disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,071,279, which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> It is intended that the scope of the present inventions extend to all such modifications and/or additions and that the scope of the present inventions is limited solely by the claims set forth below. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for performing a diagnostic or therapeutic operation on body tissue, comprising: 
<claim-text>a support structure defining a proximal region and a distal region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second longitudinally spaced conductive regions associated with the distal region of the support structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuation device including at least one electrical contact located within the support structure and movable between a first position where the at least one electrical contact is in electrical connection with the first conductive region and a second position where the at least one electrical contact is in electrical connection with the second conductive region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the support structure comprises a catheter body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the proximal region of the support structure defines a proximal region stiffness and the distal region of the support structure defines a distal region stiffness, and the proximal region stiffness is greater than the distal region stiffness. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the proximal region of the support structure defines a proximal region length and the distal region of the support structure defines a distal region length, and the proximal region length is greater than the distal region length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second longitudinally spaced conductive regions comprise electrodes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second longitudinally spaced conductive regions comprise first and second tubular electrodes and the support structure distal region comprises a tubular member between the first and second tubular electrodes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second tubular electrodes define inner surfaces and the inner surfaces of the first and second tubular electrodes define respective portions of the inner surface of the support structure distal region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the actuation device is slidable relative to the support structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the actuation device includes a tubular member that supports the at least one electrical contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the actuation device includes a stylet that extends proximally from the tubular member to the proximal portion of the support structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one electrical contact comprises a flexible electrical contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one electrical contact comprises a brush. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a steering mechanism within the support structure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a handle associated with the distal region of the support structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control element carried by the handle and operatively connected to the actuation device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the control element comprises a slider. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an imaging device associated with the actuation device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for performing a diagnostic or therapeutic operation on body tissue, comprising: 
<claim-text>a support structure defining a proximal region and a porous distal region defining a porous region length; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a longitudinally movable device adapted to be connected to a source of conductive fluid and to supply the conductive fluid to a portion of the porous region, thereby defining a movable lesion formation region having a length that is less than the porous region length; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an electrode associated with the movable lesion formation region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the longitudinally movable device includes a tubular member having a wall defining in inner lumen and opening in the wall, and a pair of gaskets respectively located proximal and distal to the opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electrode is carried by the tubular member between the gaskets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for performing a diagnostic or therapeutic operation on body tissue, comprising: 
<claim-text>a support structure defining a proximal region and a distal region defining a distal region length; </claim-text>
<claim-text>energy transmission means, at least a portion of which is movable within at least the distal region of the support structure, for selectively transmitting energy along portions of the distal region that define lengths that are less than the distal region length. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the support structure comprises a catheter body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the proximal region of the support structure defines a proximal region stiffness and the distal region of the support structure defines a distal region stiffness, and the proximal region stiffness is greater than the distal region stiffness. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the proximal region of the support structure defines a proximal region length and the distal region of the support structure defines a distal region length, and the proximal region length is greater than the distal region length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a steering mechanism within the support structure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a handle associated with the distal region of the support structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control element carried by the handle and operatively connected to the movable portion of the energy transmission means. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the control element comprises a slider. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an imaging device associated with the movable portion of the energy transmission means.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004505A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
