<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000037A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000037A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000037A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000037A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000037A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000037A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000037A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000037A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000037A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000037A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000037A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000037A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000037A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000037A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000037</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895514</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A46B005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A46B015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>159100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>171000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>D04</class>
<subclass>134000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>248</class>
<subclass>682000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Brush with a wedge plate</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Adam</given-name>
<family-name>Carr</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Mendon</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Steve</given-name>
<family-name>Sieckowski</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Camillus</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>THOMPSON COBURN, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>ONE FIRSTAR PLAZA</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 3500</address-2>
<city>ST LOUIS</city>
<state>MO</state>
<postalcode>63101</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention is a new and unique device which allows a brush to be securely attached to a container. A wedge plate is located at the brush head and in line with the handle. Offset from the handle is a base plate. The base plate is wider and longer than the wedge plate. When forced onto the rim of a bucket the invention flattens a region of the rim between the base plate and the wedge plate. This creates three points of contact with the brush&mdash;one on the outside of the bucket and two flanking the first but on the inside of the bucket. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Not Applicable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Not Applicable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">REFERENCE TO A MICROFICHE APPENDIX </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Not Applicable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The invention relates generally to cleaning implements, and more particularly, to a brush combined with a support adapted to hang or otherwise mount the brush to the rim of a bucket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> There are many everyday jobs which require a brush and a container of liquid. Painting, cleaning, and wallpapering are examples of such jobs. When a break in the activity occurs, the problem of where to place the brush arises. Placing the brush on a floor or table creates a mess and can cause the brush to become lost. Placing the brush in the container requires placing one&apos;s hand into the liquid to retrieve the brush. There is thus a need for a brush having additional features which allow the brush to be suspended over a container. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is generally known to combine a brush with a hook, clip, notch, or angled recess in order to allow the brush to hang on or over the rim of a container. The most common application of this technology is with paint brushes. For example, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,689,851; 2,723,826; 2,309,990; 1,763,696; 1,653,374; and 1,083,772 all show a mechanism which allows the paint brush to be suspended over the open paint can allowing unused paint to drain from the bristles of the brush back into the paint can. These patents allow the brush to hang freely but do not provide a secure attachment to the container. This technology has been used with other types of devices. U.S. Patent No. D287,432 shows a commode brush in combination with a hook. Similar to the paint brushes, the hook allows the brush to hang freely. U.S. Pat. No. 5,706,546 shows a hook allowing the scoop to hang freely from the upper lip of a container. Finally, U.S. Pat. No. 3,170,183 shows a clip located on the handle which allows a broom to be securely attached to a dustpan. The location and placement of the clip to the side of the broom makes it difficult to align the clip with the rim of a container and attach the broom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As can be seen there is a need for a device which allows a brush to be located proximate a container. Depending upon the type of use, there exists a need for a mechanism which allows the brush to be suspended in such a manner as to allow liquid to drain from the bristles of the brush. At best, these prior art inventions suggest using two connecting points separated by an axial distance, where the axial distance is along the axis of the handle. The prior art is limited in this regard in that the hooks, clips, notches and angled recesses known allow a brush to be easily dislodged by accidental contact. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention is a new and unique device which allows a brush to be securely mounted on a container. The cheapest and most durable buckets produced are semi-rigid plastic and frusto-conical shaped. The present invention is especially suited for use with the round rim of such a bucket. A wedge plate is located at the brush head and in line with the handle. Offset from the handle is a base plate. The base plate is wider and longer than the wedge plate. When forced onto the rim of a bucket the invention flattens a region of the rim between the base plate and the wedge plate. This creates three points of contact with the brush, two endpoints and one center point. The three points of contact are laterally separated from each other in a direction that is generally perpindicular to the handle. The center point of contact must be on the opposite side of the rim from the two endpoints of contact.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top view of the brush. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of the brush. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a second embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of the invention in use with a bucket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cutaway view taken along line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Referring to the accompanying drawings, in which like reference numbers indicate like elements, FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> illustrate a brush <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a base plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and a wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> adapted to be wedged over a rim of a bucket. As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> the brush <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a handle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a head <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and a plurality of bristles <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the handle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and head <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are integrally formed of any suitable material, preferably plastic. In the alternative the handle could be connected by any suitable fastener. The length of handle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be increased as needed to extend the reach of a user. The length of the handle determines a center of gravity of the brush. For a longer handle the center of gravity would be located in the handle and for a shorter handle the center of gravity would be located in the head. A portion of the handle can have a series of raised ridges <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to enhance gripping, and other gripping means can also be used on the handle, such as a pattern of dimples or a soft spongy material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The head <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the brush <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, a base plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and a plurality of bristles <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The base plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be of any shape including but not limited to triangular, rectangular, oval and semi-circular. The bristles <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> can be any type of conventional brush bristles. The handle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is generally linear and defines an axis, and the base plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is generally two dimensional and defines a base plate plane that is preferably offset from the handle axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> flares out from the handle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and converges back to a point <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the handle axis preferably runs through the center of the wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the base plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> also flares out from the handle. The wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the base plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are spaced apart creating an empty space <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A second embodiment of the invention can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In this embodiment the brush does not have an elongated handle. The brush <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has bristles <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, a base plate <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and a wedge plate <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. The wedge plate <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> also serves as the handle and is ergonomically shaped to fit in a person&apos;s hand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, it can be seen that the invention is especially adapted for use with a semi-rigid plastic and frusto-conical bucket <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The bucket can be filled with a liquid <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and the brush <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> dipped into the bucket <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in a normal manner. To wedge the brush <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> on the rim <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the bucket <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, a person places the endpoint <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> such that the rim <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the bucket <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is aligned with the space <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> between the wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the base plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A downward push forces the brush <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> over the rim <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. With the bristles <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> located above the center of the bucket, the brush contacts the rim at three points. A central point <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of the wedge plate <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> contacts the outside of the bucket and two lateral points <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the base plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> contact the inside of the bucket. The spaced apart configuration of the plates <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> causes the rim <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> to deform between the two lateral points <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> from a curved configuration towards a linear configuration (best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). The resiliency of the rim <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> causes the deformed portion to attempt to return to a non-deformed configuration, exerting a force on the brush <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in both an axial and lateral direction. The configuration of the present invention creates a two-dimensional lateral mounting to a bucket and may also have an axial attachment. The prior art is limited to creating a one-dimensional attachment or a two dimensional axial attachment. For example, a simple hook or clip would attach to a bucket with an axial force, and would deform the rim at a single point creating axial compression at that point. In contrast, the brush of the present invention attaches to a bucket in a region of the rim creating both axial and lateral compression in that region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, it will be seen that the several advantages of the invention are achieved and attained. The preferred embodiment and alternatives were chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the invention and its practical application to thereby enable others skilled in the art to best utilize the invention in various embodiments and with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated. As various modifications could be made in the constructions and methods herein described and illustrated without departing from the scope of the invention, it is intended that all matter contained in the foregoing description or shown in the accompanying drawings shall be interpreted as illustrative rather than limiting. For example, the head could e connected to the handle by a fastener. Thus, the breadth and scope of the present invention should not be limited by any of the above-described exemplary embodiments, but should be defined only in accordance with the following claims appended hereto and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A brush adapted to be wedged over a rim of a bucket comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) a handle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a head connected to said handle wherein said head further comprises 
<claim-text>a wedge plate flaring out from said handle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a base plate flaring out from said handle and spaced apart from said wedge plate, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of bristles attached to said base plate, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said wedge plate and said base plate define a central point and two lateral points which contact the rim of the bucket when mounted. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said wedge plate and said base plate create a lateral and an axial mounting at said central point and said lateral points. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is integrally molded with said head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is connected by a fastener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is ergonomically shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising a center of gravity located on said head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising a center of gravity located between said handle and said head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A brush adapted to be wedged over a curved portion of a rim of a bucket comprising: 
<claim-text>a handle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a head connected to said handle, and wherein said head further comprises 
<claim-text>a base plate connected to said handle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of bristles attached to said base plate, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wedge plate connected to said handle and spaced apart from said base plate, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said wedge plate and said base plate define a central point and two lateral points which contact the rim of the bucket when mounted creating an axial and lateral mounting. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is integrally molded with said head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is connected by a fastener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is ergonomically shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising a center of gravity located on said head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising a center of gravity located between said handle and said head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A brush adapted to be wedged over a curved portion of a rim of a bucket comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) a handle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a head connected to said handle, wherein said head further comprises 
<claim-text>a plurality of bristles, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a means for laterally wedging the brush around the rim of the bucket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said head is flares out from said handle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said means for laterally wedging comprises 
<claim-text>a base plate connected to said handle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of bristles attached to said base plate, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wedge plate connected to said handle and spaced apart from said base plate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said wedge plate and said base plate define a central point and two lateral points contacting the rim of the bucket and creating a lateral and an axial mounting at said central point and said lateral points. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is integrally molded with said head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is connected by a fastener. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said handle is ergonomically shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising a center of gravity located on said head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The brush according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising a center of gravity located between said handle and said head.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000037A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000037A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000037A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000037A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000037A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000037A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000037A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
