<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003979A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003979A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003979A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003979A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003979A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003979A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003979A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003979A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003979A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003979A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003979A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003979A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003979</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894197</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A63F009/24</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>463</class>
<subclass>016000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>463</class>
<subclass>009000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Image alignment gaming device and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jerald</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Seelig</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Absecon</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lawrence</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Henshaw</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hammonton</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>IAN F. BURNS &amp; ASSOCIATES</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1575 DELUCCHI LANE, SUITE 222</address-1>
<city>RENO</city>
<state>NV</state>
<postalcode>89502</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A gaming device for playing a game. The device has a game display with several display sections. A game controller controls several fractional images that are displayed in the display sections. The game controller randomly selects the fractional image to display in each display section. A winning combination results when the fractional images are aligned such that they form a complete image. The game display can be a set of rotatable reels with each reel carrying the fractional images or the game display can be a video display. The reels are aligned vertically, horizontally, diagonally, a combination thereof, or in other ways. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to gaming devices and, more particularly, to a gaming device that adds to player excitement and satisfaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Many types of slot and video gaming machines have been designed over the years. The traditional slot machine has a series of annular reels disposed in side by side relationship that rotate separately about a common axis. The reels can be implemented mechanically or visually on a video display driven by a computer. The game players score or winnings are indicated by indicia on the peripheral surfaces of the reels which may align in any of a number of different combinations following a period of rotation of the reels. Players of gaming apparatus typically find it enjoyable to have a variety of different forms of gaming apparatus available. For this purpose, slot machines of the spinning reel type have been provided with a variety of different graphics, shapes, sound effects and scoring systems. Gaming machines that are more interesting generate more player excitement and in turn are played longer resulting in more revenue for the game operator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Unfortunately, the similarity of slot machines poses a problem for slot machine manufacturers in differentiating their machines from competitors. Modifying slot machines to enhance player enjoyment are not beneficial if the basic geometry and function of the visual components of the machine is retained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A current unmet need exists for a gaming device that is different than previous slot machines in order to provide game players with a more exciting and desirable gaming experience. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> 1. Advantages of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An advantage of the present invention is that it provides a gaming device that adds to player excitement and satisfaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of the present invention is that it provides a gaming device that is interesting to a player and results in longer playing time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A further advantage of the present invention is that it provides a gaming device that is readily distinguishable from conventional slot machines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of the present invention is that it provides a gaming device that awards a prize when several fractional images are assembled into a complete image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> These and other advantages of the present invention may be realized by reference to the remaining portions of the specification, claims, and abstract. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> 2. Brief Description of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention comprises a gaming device for playing a game that includes a game display having several display sections. A game controller controls several fractional images that are displayed in the display sections. The game controller randomly selects the fractional image to display in each display section. A winning combination results when the fractional images are aligned such that they form a complete image. The game display can be a set of rotatable reels with each reel carrying the fractional images. The reels can be aligned vertically, horizontally, diagonally, a combination thereof, or in other ways. In another embodiment, the game display is a video display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The above description sets forth, rather broadly, the more important features of the present invention so that the detailed description of the preferred embodiment that follows may be better understood and contributions of the present invention to the art may be better appreciated. There are, of course, additional features of the invention that will be described below and will form the subject matter of claims. In this respect, before explaining at least one preferred embodiment of the invention in detail, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited in its application to the details of the construction and to the arrangement of the components set forth in the following description or as illustrated in the drawings. The invention is capable of other embodiments and of being practiced and carried out in various ways. Also, it is to be understood that the phraseology and terminology employed herein are for the purpose of description and should not be regarded as limiting.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is substantially a front view of a gaming device in accordance with the present invention in which the image displayed is a whole image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is substantially a front view of the gaming device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in which the image is a non-whole image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is substantially a flow chart showing the operation of the gaming device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is substantially a front view of an alternative embodiment of a gaming device in which the present invention is used as a bonus game. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is substantially a flow chart showing the operation of the bonus gaming device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments, reference is made to the accompanying drawings, which form a part of this application. The drawings show, by way of illustration, specific embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. It is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized and structural changes may be made with out departing from the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Gaming Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a gaming device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown. Gaming device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a case <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a game display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> having several or more display sections <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, a lever <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, selector buttons <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a coin acceptor <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a coin bin <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a game controller <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> adapted to control a plurality of fractional images <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> displayed in the display sections <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The fractional images <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> form a whole or complete image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Case <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> contains the gaming device components. A coin acceptor <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> accepts wagers from a game player. The coin acceptor can also accept tokens, paper currency and vouchers. A coin bin <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is mounted below the case holds coins that are dispensed after a winning game event has occurred. Lever <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is used by the game player to initiate play on gaming device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Lever <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is pulled by the game player to start the game. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has three display sections <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be mechanical spinning reels or display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be a video display that simulates mechanical spinning reels or display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be other means to display an image, such as a video display. While display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is shown with three display sections <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, more of less sections could be used. For example, a 3&times;3 matrix of <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> display sections could be used. It is noted that the display sections are oriented or aligned vertically. The axis of rotation <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the reels is vertical with respect to viewing the display. The game player stands or sits upright facing the display. The axis of rotation is parallel to the game player. Each of the display sections contains a fractional image <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The fractional image <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is a portion of a whole or complete image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> can be a wide variety of interesting subjects such as pictures or paintings including movie stars, celebrities, famous landmarks, musicians, vehicles, buildings, politicians, etc. The whole image is a contiguous recognizable image. If desired a payline (not shown) can be added to the display to aid the player in seeing the alignment of the fractional images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The whole image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is broken up into fractional images <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the whole image has been broken into 3 fractional images. If desired, whole image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> could be broken into fewer or more fractional images <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. A conventional game controller <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> controls the displaying of the images. Game controller <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> contains a random number generator to cause the mechanical reels or video display to generate a particular combination of fractional images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> During game play, a game player inserts a wager into coin acceptor <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and then pulls lever <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to start play. In the case that display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are mechanical reels, the reels spin or rotate about axis <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Several of the fractional images would be placed on circumference of the reels. The fractional images move horizontally with respect the player viewing the display. As discussed above, the images could move vertically, diagonally, a combination thereof, or in other ways. The game controller <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> selects a particular image to stop at or display in each display section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Typically, the selector buttons <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are used to tell the controller when to stop the rotating reels. In the case that display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is a video display, the video display simulates the mechanical reels and game controller <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> selects a particular image to stop at or display in each display section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the fractional images <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> line up to form a complete or whole image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. In this example, the whole image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is a girls face. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the fractional images <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> do not line up to form a complete or whole image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> When the display sections <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> form a complete or whole image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, a game winning event is generated and the player is dispensed a payout in accordance with a payout table. When the display sections do not form a complete or whole image <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, a game losing event is generated and the player must deposit more coins or use accumulated credits to play again. If desired, the payout table can be structured to make a partial payout depending upon the number of fractional images that are properly aligned. For example, if 2 of the 3 images are properly aligned, the payout could be 50 percent of the payout for having all 3 of the images properly aligned. In the case where display <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has multiple spinning reels to form a matrix of display sections <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the complete image may be formed along a diagonal of the matrix or can be formed by having all of the display sections <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> show the complete images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Flowchart </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> flowchart <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is shown. Flowchart <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> depicts the steps followed in playing a game on gaming device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A wager is placed by the game player at step <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in order to start game play on gaming device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, the player pulls lever <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in order to start the game. At step <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, the game controller <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> determines which images are to be displayed in each display section and displays those images. Game controller <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> randomly selects the image to be displayed in each display section. Next, gaming device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> moves to a decision step <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. At decision step <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> the number of fractional images that are aligned in the correct location or display section are determined. If the number of correctly aligned images is equal to zero, a yes is returned and the game progresses to step <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> where a losing event is determined along with no payout of an award. From step <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, the game loops back to step <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to allow the game player to place another wager. If a no is returned at decision step <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, the game moves to decision step <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> At decision step <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> the number of fractional images that are aligned in the correct location or display section is compared to see if they are equal to one. In the case where the answer is &ldquo;yes&rdquo; at step <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, the game progresses to step <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> where a payout is determined according to a redefined pay table and paid. For example, if a wager of one dollar was placed, the payout for correctly aligning one of the three images could be 50 cents. From step <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, the game loops back to step <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to allow the game player to place another wager. If a no is returned at decision step <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, the game moves to decision step <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> At decision step <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> the number of fractional images that are aligned in the correct location or display section is compared to see if they are equal to two. In the case where a yes is returned at step <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, the game progresses to step <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> where a partial payout is determined and paid. For example, if a wager of one dollar was placed, the payout for correctly aligning two of the three images could be one dollar. From step <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, the game loops back to step <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to allow the game player to place another wager. If a no is returned at decision step <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, the game moves to step <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> At step <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> the number of fractional images that are aligned in the correct location or display section is equal to three. The game next moves to step <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> where a full payout is determined and paid for a game winning event. For example, if a wager of one dollar was placed, the payout for correctly aligning all of the three images could be two dollars. From step <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the game loops back to step <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to allow the game player to place another wager. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Bonus Game Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The gaming device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> is configured as a primary game. The gaming device can also be used as a bonus game that is attached to another primary game. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> bonus gaming device <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is shown. Gaming device <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> comprises a primary game <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and a bonus game <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> mounted on top. Primary game <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> can be almost any game. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, game <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is shown as a conventional slot machine. Primary game <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> comprises several rotating reels <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> with a payline <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> that is actuated by a lever <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. One or more meters or displays <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> tell the game player their winnings and remaining playing credits. A special symbol <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is generated on payline <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to signify a bonus qualifying or generating event. After a bonus qualifying event has occurred the bonus game <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> becomes available for play. Bonus game <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> would then be played in a similar manner as to gaming device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The conventional slot machine triggers a bonus qualifying event that allow the game player the opportunity to play game device <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> to win a bonus prize or payout. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Bonus Game Flowchart </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> flowchart <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of the operation of bonus gaming device <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is shown. Flowchart <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> depicts the steps followed in playing the bonus game. A wager is placed by the game player at step <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> in order to start game play on gaming device <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, the player plays the primary gaming device <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Next, gaming device <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> moves to a decision step <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. At decision step <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> the, game checks to see if the bonus qualifying event has occurred. If the bonus qualifying event has not occurred, the game loops back to step <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> to allow the player the opportunity to place another wager and play the primary game again. If the bonus qualifying event has occurred at step <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, the method continues to decision step <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. At decision step <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>, the player may elect to play the bonus game or return to the primary game. If the player elects to return to the primary game, the game loops back to step <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. If the player elects to play the bonus game, the game proceeds to step <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> , the player plays the bonus game <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> which generates and displays either fractional or whole images. The operation at this point of the bonus game <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is identical to that of gaming device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. At step <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, the game player is then paid a payout depending upon the number of images that are correctly aligned. The game then loops back to step <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> to allow the player to play the primary game <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> again. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CONCLUSION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The present invention solves many of the problems associated with the prior art. The present invention provides a gaming device that adds to player satisfaction and excitement. The present invention also provides a gaming device that is readily distinguishable from conventional slot machines. The present invention further provides a gaming device that awards a prize when several fractional images are displayed as a complete image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Although the description above contains many specifications, these should not be construed as limiting the scope of the invention but as merely providing illustrations of some of the presently preferred embodiments of this invention. Thus, the scope of the invention should be determined by the appended claims and their legal equivalents rather than by the examples given. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A gaming device for playing a game by a player, the gaming device comprising: 
<claim-text>(A) a display having a plurality of changeable sections; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(B) a whole image divided into a plurality of fractional images, one of the fractional images being displayed in each of the changeable sections; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(C) a game controller communicated with the display, the game controller adapted to generate a winning event in which the whole image is displayed and to generate a losing event in which a non-whole image is displayed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display is a plurality of vertically oriented mechanical spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display is a video screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the image is a picture. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game controller is a computer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game controller generates a partial payout event based on the number of images that are properly aligned on the display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display is a plurality of horizontally oriented mechanical spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display is a plurality of matrix of mechanical spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display is a plurality of diagonally oriented mechanical spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of playing a game using a gaming device comprising: 
<claim-text>(A) placing a wager on the gaming device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(B) starting the game; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(C) generating a game outcome; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(D) displaying an image on a display having a plurality of changeable sections, a fractional image being displayed in each of the changeable sections; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(E) displaying a whole image on the display when a game wining outcome is generated; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(F) displaying a non-whole image on the display when a game losing outcome is generated; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(G) paying a payout based upon the game outcome. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>paying a partial payout based on the number of images that are properly aligned on the display. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game is a primary game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game is a bonus game played in association with a primary game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the image is a picture of a celebrity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game outcome is generated by a game controller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display is a plurality of vertically oriented spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display is a plurality of horizontally oriented spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display is a plurality of diagonally oriented spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A gaming device for playing a game comprising: 
<claim-text>(A) a game display having a plurality of display sections; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(B) a game controller adapted to control a plurality of fractional images displayed in the display sections, the game controller randomly selecting the fractional image to display in each display section; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(C) a winning combination resulting when the fractional images are aligned such that they form a complete image. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game display is a set of rotatable reels, each reel carrying the fractional images. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reels are aligned vertically. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game display is a video display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game is a bonus game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the game is a primary game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reels are aligned horizontally. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reels form a matrix. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the complete image is formed along a diagonal of the matrix. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A method of playing a game, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>(A) allowing a player to place a wager; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(B) displaying a plurality of contiguous symbols; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(C) if a combination of the contiguous symbols form a predefined, recognizable, unitary image, awarding a prize to the player. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a partial prize is awarded, the partial prize being proportional to the number of contiguous symbols that are correctly aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein no prize is awarded if none of the contiguous symbols are correctly aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the symbols are displayed on a plurality of spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spinning reels have an axis of rotation that is parallel to a lever, the lever attached to the game and used to start the game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spinning reels are shown on a video display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spinning reels have an axis of rotation that is perpendicular to a lever, the lever attached to the game and used to start the game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spinning reels form a matrix of symbols. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of playing a game according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the unitary image is formed along a diagonal of the matrix. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A gaming device, the gaming device comprising: 
<claim-text>(A) a display device, the display device being configured to display a plurality of adjacent symbols; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(B) a controller in communication with the display device, the controller being configured to determine a plurality of symbols to be displayed and cause the display device to display the plurality of symbols, wherein the plurality of symbols may, when viewed as a whole, provide a predefined unitary recognizable image. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the controller awards a prize when the image is the predefined unitary image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the controller awards a partial prize when the symbols do not form the predefined unitary image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the controller awards no prize when the symbols do not form the predefined unitary image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gaming device is a primary game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gaming device is a bonus game mounted with the primary game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the display device is a plurality of spinning reels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the spinning reels are shown on a video display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spinning reels are aligned vertically. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the predefined unitary recognizable image is a picture of a famous person. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spinning reels are aligned horizontally. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spinning reels are aligned diagonally. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A gaming device for playing game comprising: 
<claim-text>(A) a plurality of spinning reels, the spinning reels being configured to display a plurality of adjacent symbols, the adjacent symbols aligned along an axis of rotation; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(B) a controller in communication with the spinning reels, the controller being configured to determine a plurality of symbols to be displayed and cause the spinning reels to display the plurality of symbols; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(C) a payline disposed adjacent the spinning reels, the payline parallel to the axis of rotation, wherein the payline and the axis of rotation are aligned vertically. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the axis of rotation is parallel to a standing game player. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a lever is mounted to the game, the lever adapted to initiate the game, the axis of rotation parallel to the lever. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spinning reels form a matrix of adjacent symbols. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The gaming device according to claim <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, wherein a game winning event occurs when the adjacent symbols are aligned along a diagonal of the matrix to form a recognizable unitary image.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003979A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003979A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003979A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003979A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003979A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003979A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
