<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001011A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001011A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001011</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10177401</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020619</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-190298</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010622</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>9-212259</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19970806</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06K007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>235</class>
<subclass>440000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Multifunction device and control method for the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10177401</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020619</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09987435</doc-number>
<document-date>20011114</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09987435</doc-number>
<document-date>20011114</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09130165</doc-number>
<document-date>19980806</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6350005</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sadao</given-name>
<family-name>Murata</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Okaya-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kunio</given-name>
<family-name>Omura</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Shiojiri-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>EPSON RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT INC</name-1>
<name-2>INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY DEPT</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>150 RIVER OAKS PARKWAY, SUITE 225</address-1>
<city>SAN JOSE</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95134</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Performing check processing operations from MICR processing to scanning the printed check as a continuous sequence of operations lightens the burden on the operator and shortens the required processing time. The compound processing system <highlight><bold>10 </bold></highlight>has a transportation path <highlight><bold>15 </bold></highlight>for conveying a check P, an MICR head <highlight><bold>17 </bold></highlight>positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15 </bold></highlight>for reading MICR text prerecorded on the check P, front print head <highlight><bold>23 </bold></highlight>positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15 </bold></highlight>for printing on the front of check P, back print head <highlight><bold>21 </bold></highlight>positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15 </bold></highlight>for printing on the back of check P, and a scanner head <highlight><bold>25 </bold></highlight>positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15 </bold></highlight>for scanning the printed side (either back or front) of the check P. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CONTINUING APPLICATION DATA </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. application Ser. No. 09/987,435 filed Nov. 14, 2001, which is a continuation-in-part of application Ser. No. 09/130,165, filed Aug. 6, 1998, issued as U.S. Pat. No. 6,350,005, the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a multifunction device such as a check processing system that performs multiple processes such as magnetic ink character recognition (MICR) processing, printing information on the check, and scanning the printed side of the check, and to a control method for the multifunction device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Checks are commonly used to pay for retail purchases and to settle business transactions. The checking account number and bank routing information is printed on the face of the check using magnetic ink, and can be used to determine whether or not the check is valid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> After the validity of a check received at the checkout counter in a retail store is confirmed, the verification number and other endorsement information is printed on the back of the check (referred to as endorsement printing below). The payee and amount information are typically handwritten by the payer (account owner) on the front of the check, but checkout terminals equipped with printers capable of printing this information are becoming increasingly common. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> After a check is processed at the store it is typically delivered to the bank or other financial institution on which it was drawn for final settlement. The settlement process can, however, be made more efficient by electronically sending the transaction content and an image of the printed check captured with a scanner directly to the financial institution, instead of sending the physical check. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> If scanning the check and transmitting the transaction content and scanned image are done using one or more devices separate from that used for such conventional processes as MICR reading and printing the check, operation becomes unnecessarily complicated for the operator, more time is needed to process each check, and additional space must be found to install the separate devices. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is therefore to provide a multifunction device and control method that can lighten the burden on the operator and shorten check processing time by performing as a single continuous check processing operation steps from capturing the MICR data to scanning the printed check. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A multifunction device according to the present invention achieving these and other objects has a transportation path for guiding a print medium, a magnetic head positioned along the transportation path for reading magnetic ink characters prerecorded on the print medium, a first print head positioned along the transportation path for printing on a first side of the print medium, a second print head positioned along the transportation path for printing on a second side of the print medium, and a scanner head positioned along the transportation path for scanning either the first or second side of the print medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> This multifunction device preferably also has an insertion opening formed at one end of the transportation path for inserting the print medium, and an exit opening formed at the other end of the transportation path for ejecting the print medium. The magnetic head in this case is positioned on the insertion opening side of the first and second print heads, and the scanner head is positioned on the exit opening side of the first and second print heads. When thus comprised, the magnetic ink character reading process can be run while the print medium inserted from the insertion open is transported into the multifunction device, and the print medium can be scanned with the scanner head while ejecting the print medium from the multifunction device. A short transportation path can therefore be used, reducing the size of the multifunction device and shortening the processing time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Further preferably, the insertion opening is horizontally oriented so that the print medium can be inserted substantially horizontally, and the exit opening is vertically oriented so that the print medium can be ejected substantially vertically. Compared with a configuration having a straight transportation path, this configuration enables the size of the multifunction device to be reduced, and the print medium can be held in the vertical end of the transportation path after processing the print medium is finished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Yet further preferably, the multifunction device also has a pressure feed roller positioned opposite the scanner head for transporting while pressing the print medium against the scanner head, and a roller retraction mechanism for retracting the pressure feed roller from the scanner head to open the transportation path. By thus retracting the pressure feed roller from the transportation path when not scanning, catching the print medium by the pressure feed roller is avoided, and paper jams and skips in the feed pitch can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Yet further preferably, the multifunction device also has a first process control unit for scanning and then ejecting the print medium, a second process control unit for ejecting the print medium without scanning, and a process selection unit for selecting either the first or second process control unit. This configuration enables the print medium to be selectively scanned in accordance with the type of print media and customer desires while being able to continuously run a series of multiple processes including scanning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A multifunction device control method according to the present invention achieving the above objects is a method for controlling a multifunction device as described above by reading the magnetic ink characters with the magnetic head while transporting the print medium inserted from the insertion opening toward the exit opening, transporting the print medium to a first print head printing starting position after reading the magnetic ink characters, printing on the first side of the print medium using the first print head while transporting the print medium in a direction along the transportation path, transporting the print medium to a second print head printing start position after finishing printing with the first print head, printing on the second side of the print medium using the second print head while transporting the print medium in a direction along the transportation path, transporting the print medium to a scanning start position, for scanning by the scanner head after finishing printing with the second print head, and scanning either the first or second side of the print medium with the scanner head while transporting the print medium toward the exit opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The print medium is preferably transported toward the insertion opening in this control method in the step of printing with the first print head or in the step of printing with the second print head. This enables a series of processes to be run while transporting the print medium bi-directionally in the transportation path, thereby enabling the transportation path to be shortened and the size of the multifunction device to be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Other objects and attainments together with a fuller understanding of the invention will become apparent and appreciated by referring to the following description and claims taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a multifunction device according to a preferred embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side section view showing the internal structure of the multifunction device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a typical check; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a side view of the scanner head and scanner feed rollers; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of the roller retraction mechanism; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view of the roller retraction mechanism; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing control unit inputs and outputs; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a flow chart of the first process control mode; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates operation in the first process control mode; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device during check insertion; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device during MICR reading; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device when printing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device during scanning; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing the second process control mode; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates operation in the second process control mode; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device showing removal of an ejected check.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments of the present invention are described below with reference to the accompanying figures. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a multifunction device according to a preferred embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> this multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is covered by a plastic cover <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> having an insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> formed at the front for manually inserting a check P (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) or other sheet, and an exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> formed on top for ejecting the check P. This multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> also has a roll paper housing (not shown in the figure) at the back for storing roll paper. Paper is transported through the printing unit from the roll in the roll paper housing, and is pulled out from a roll paper exit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> formed on top of the multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side section view showing the internal structure of the multifunction device. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2 a</cross-reference> check P transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, formed inside the multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, extends from insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> bends in an L-shape as seen in a side view from the horizontally oriented insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to the vertically oriented exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in order from the insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> side are form trailing edge detector <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, MICR head (magnetic head) <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, first feed roller pair <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, form leading edge detector <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, form positioning member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, back print head (second print head) <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, second feed roller pair <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, front print head (first print head) <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, form ejection detector <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>), and scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Opposite the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are scanner feed rollers (pressure feed rollers) <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The trailing edge detector <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, leading edge detector <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and form ejection detector <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are, for example, light transmitting or reflecting type photodetectors enabling non-contact detection of the check P at respective points along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The form positioning member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> stops a check P inserted from the insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> at a specific position, and can be moved using a solenoid or other actuator type drive source so that the form positioning member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> projects into and blocks the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, or is retracted from and opens the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The first feed roller pair <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and second feed roller pair <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> each have a pair of rollers positioned on opposing sides of the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> such that the rollers can be appropriately driven to transport the check P in forward or reverse direction. One roller in each pair can also be freely moved to or away from the opposing roller by driving a solenoid or other actuator to open and close the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> by advancing or retracting the rollers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> reads magnetic ink characters printed on the front of the check P, and validity of the check P is determined based on the data read by the MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. MICR text is recorded in a specific MICR recording area <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> on the front of the check P as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, and includes such information as the account number against which the check P is drawn. Opposite the MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is a pressure member <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>) for pressing a check P against the MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> during MICR reading. This pressure member <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is normally retracted from the MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> so that the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is open. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The front print head <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is used to print information on the front of the check P, such as the payee, date, check amount, and other information generally included on the face of the check (hereinafter &ldquo;check face information&rdquo;). This check face information is printed on a front printing area <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The front print head <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is preferably a serial print head supported on a carriage for printing a dot matrix of one or more rows as the front print head <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> moves widthwise across the front of the check. This embodiment of the invention uses a dot impact type print head for transferring ink from an ink ribbon to the check P as the front print head <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, but it will be evident that other types of print heads could be alternatively used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The back print head <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is used to print a customer verification number, date, check amount, and other information needed by the store on the back of the check P. This information is printed on the back in an endorsement printing area <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> such as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> in phantom. The back print head <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is preferably a shuttle print head with plural heads arrayed widthwise to the check P with a specific gap therebetween, and prints a dot matrix of one or more rows by moving the print head within this specific width. It will be further noted that while this embodiment uses a dot impact print head to transfer ink from an ink ribbon to the check P as the back print head <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, other types of print heads could be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is for scanning the surface of the printed check P. The scanned image data is then compressed and sent to and stored in a host computer, and used to electronically settle transactions. This embodiment of the invention uses a contact image sensor (CIS) for the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to scan checks P placed against the scanning glass <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> transports the check P for scanning, pressing the check P against the scanning glass <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> while transporting the check P to the exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> side. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, this scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> presses the check P against the scanning glass <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at a position offset slightly from the scanner focusing position A rather than directly at the scanner focusing position A. More specifically, scanner focusing position A is offset either upstream or downstream along the transportation path relative to the scanner contact position B of the scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment scanner focusing position A is offset 0.8 mm to the downstream side (the exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> side) from scanner contact position B of scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Applying pressure from the scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> directly to the scanner glass at the focusing position A is thus avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> It is therefore possible to reduce the likelihood of transferring ink onto the glass at scanner focusing position A when scanning a check P immediately after printing. This prevents a reduction in scanned image quality that can occur when ink adheres to the glass at the focusing position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the largest possible scanable area can be assured at the leading edge of the check P because the scanner focusing position A is offset to the downstream side from the scanner contact position B of scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. It should be noted that if the scanner focusing position A is greatly offset from the scanner contact position B of scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the check P could drift away from the scanning glass <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at scanner focusing position A. The offset in the present embodiment is only 0.8 mm, however. Separation of the check P from the scanning glass <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is therefore held to 0.2 mm or less, and there is no danger of a drop in scanned image quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> During scanner operation the scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> conveys the check P upward so that the check P is ejected from exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The trailing edge of the ejected check P is held at this time in the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> on the downstream side of the scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the exit end of the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> (the part between scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) is vertically oriented with a length of approximately L/6 (where L is the length of check P) so that the ejected check P can be held and will not fall out of the multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of the roller retraction mechanism and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view of the roller retraction mechanism. As shown in these figures a pair of scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is positioned with a specific gap therebetween on a roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is supported in the middle by a roller retraction mechanism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the ends of the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are guided in a guide channel <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> so as to move freely forward and back toward and away from the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The roller retraction mechanism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is configured to pull the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> back when driven by the scanner feed roller solenoid <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, thereby retracting the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and opening the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. In other words, when not scanning, the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are in the retracted position so that the end of the check P does not get caught by the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, after the check P is advanced to the scanning start position by the first feed roller pair <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and second feed roller pair <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for the scanning operation, the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are released from the retracted position to press the check P against the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and are then driven to advance the check P. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The roller retraction mechanism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a pressure lever (rotating member) <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> rotatably supporting and advancing or retracting the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> toward or away from the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, a presser spring <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> for urging the pressure lever <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> toward the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and a scanner feed roller solenoid <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> for retracting the pressure lever <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> against the urging force of the presser spring <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The pressure lever <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is a rotating member that can rotate freely forward and back about a rotating support shaft <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and by supporting the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so that the shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be freely advanced and retracted, the roller retraction mechanism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be compactly configured and the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be smoothly advanced and retracted. The pressure lever <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> rotatably supports the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> between the pair of right and left scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Substantially uniform pressure can therefore be applied by a single presser spring <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to the pair of scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the pair of scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> be advanced and retracted substantially parallel to the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be reliably opened. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, a drive system for driving the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is also positioned near the roller retraction mechanism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The scanner feed roller <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> drive system includes a first gear <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> integrally formed with the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> between the pair of scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, a second gear <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> positioned near the pressure lever <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and constantly meshed with the first gear <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, and a transfer mechanism <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> for transferring drive power from the scanner feed motor <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to the second gear <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A path for transferring roller drive power to the support part of the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is thus formed, power can be reliably transferred to the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be rotated without disrupting the pressure balance of the rollers by juxtaposing the position where pressure is applied to the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by the presser spring <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and the position where power is transferred to the roller support shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing control unit inputs and outputs. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> the multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a control unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> comprising a CPU, ROM, RAM, and other devices. In addition to the above-described trailing edge detector <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, leading edge detector <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, back print head <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, front print head <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, form ejection detector <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, scanner feed roller solenoid <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, and scanner feed motor <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> for driving the first feed roller pair <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and second feed roller pair <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, first feed roller pair actuator <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for opening and closing the first feed roller pair <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, second feed roller pair actuator <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> for opening and closing the second feed roller pair <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, form positioning member actuator <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> for operating the form positioning member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to open and closed positions, and mode selector switch <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> for selecting a first process control mode (with scanning) or a second process control mode (without scanning), are also connected to the control unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The compound process control sequence run by the control unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> for the first process control mode and second process control mode is described next with reference to the accompanying flow charts. The control unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> operating in the first process control mode forms a first process control unit in the present invention, and the control unit <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> operating in the second process control mode forms a second process control unit in the present invention. Mode selector switch <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> forms a process selection unit in the present invention. The mode selector switch <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> may be a panel button switch (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) that may be selected by the operator and/or a software switch that may be set according to the type of media being processed, i.e. automatically set to print and scan (first process mode) for checks and automatically set to print only (second process mode) for roll paper receipts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a flow chart of the first process control mode; <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates operation in the first process control mode; <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device during check P insertion; <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device during MICR reading; <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device when printing; and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device during scanning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As shown in the figures, the first step in the first process control mode is to wait for insertion of a check P (S<highlight><bold>801</bold></highlight>). During this time the first and second feed roller pairs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are held open, and the form positioning member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are held closed. Note that if operation was previously in the second process control mode, the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are open. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> When a check P is inserted from insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, check P insertion is detected from the detection signals output by trailing edge detector <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and leading edge detector <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>). When check P insertion is detected, the first feed roller pair <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> closes (S<highlight><bold>802</bold></highlight>), the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> open (S<highlight><bold>803</bold></highlight>), and the form positioning member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> opens (S<highlight><bold>804</bold></highlight>). MICR text is then read with the MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> (S<highlight><bold>806</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>) while driving the transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the form ejection direction (S<highlight><bold>805</bold></highlight>). After MICR reading, driving the transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> stops (S<highlight><bold>807</bold></highlight>) and the second feed roller pair <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> closes. The data read with the MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is sent to a host computer for check P verification. When the verification result is received from the host computer the result is evaluated (S<highlight><bold>808</bold></highlight>). If the check P is invalid, an invalid check ejection process (S<highlight><bold>809</bold></highlight>) is run and the first process control mode ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> If the check P is valid, the transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is driven in the form ejection direction (S<highlight><bold>810</bold></highlight>) to set the check for endorsement printing on the check back, (S<highlight><bold>811</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>), <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>). The check is set to the endorsement printing position and to other various positions noted below by driving the transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> a specified number of steps referenced to positions detected by the detectors <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> (including stopping form transport). When positioning for endorsement printing is completed the transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is driven in the insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> direction (S<highlight><bold>812</bold></highlight>) while running the endorsement printing process with the back print head <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> (S<highlight><bold>813</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>)). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> When the endorsement printing process is completed, the check P is set to the front printing position (S<highlight><bold>814</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>)), and then, while driving the transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the form ejection direction (S<highlight><bold>815</bold></highlight>), the front of the check is printed using the front print head <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> (S<highlight><bold>816</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>)). When printing the check front is completed the transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is again driven in the insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> direction (S<highlight><bold>817</bold></highlight>) to set the check P to the start scanning position (S<highlight><bold>818</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>)), the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are closed (S<highlight><bold>819</bold></highlight>), and the first and second feed roller pairs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are opened (S<highlight><bold>820</bold></highlight>). The scanning process (S<highlight><bold>822</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>), <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>) is then run while driving the scanner feed motor <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> in the form ejection direction (S<highlight><bold>821</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> A check ejection decision (S<highlight><bold>823</bold></highlight>) is then made after the scanning process ends. If the decision is to eject the check P (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>)), driving the scanner feed motor <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> stops (S<highlight><bold>824</bold></highlight>), the form positioning member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is set to the closed position (S<highlight><bold>825</bold></highlight>), and the first process control mode ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The ejected check P is prevented from dropping into the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> on the upstream side by the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and is held within the vertically oriented section of the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> on the downstream side so that it will not fall out from the multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> It should be noted that by controlling the transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> synchronized to the scanner feed speed in the first process control mode, the check P can be transported to the end of the scanning process with the first and second feed roller pairs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> closed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a flow chart of the second process control mode (without scanning); <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates operation in the second process control mode; and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is an internal side view of the multifunction device when removing an ejected check. As can be seen from the figures, steps S<highlight><bold>1401</bold></highlight> to S<highlight><bold>1416</bold></highlight> in this second process control mode are the same as steps S<highlight><bold>801</bold></highlight> to S<highlight><bold>816</bold></highlight> in the first process control mode. These steps will be understood from the preceding description of the first process control mode in conjunction with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> After the check front printing process ends in the second process control mode it is decided whether to continue driving the form in the form ejection direction and complete ejection of the check P (S<highlight><bold>1417</bold></highlight>). If the form ejection is completed, driving transportation motor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> stops (S<highlight><bold>1418</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>)) and the form positioning member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is closed (S<highlight><bold>1419</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The ejected check P is thus prevented from dropping into the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> on the upstream side by the second feed roller pair <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and is held in the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> on the downstream side so that it will not fall out from the multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Removal of the check P is then detected based on the detection signal from the form ejection detector <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> (S<highlight><bold>1420</bold></highlight>). If the check P was removed, the first and second feed roller pairs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> open (S<highlight><bold>1421</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>) and the second process control mode ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> As will be evident from the preceding description, a multifunction device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to a preferred embodiment of the invention has a transportation path, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for guiding a check P, an MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for reading MICR text prerecorded on the check P, front print head <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for printing on the front of check P, back print head <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for printing on the back of check P, and a scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> positioned along the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for scanning the printed side of the check P. Operations starting from reading MICR text and continuing to scanning the printed side of the check P can thus be performed as a continuous sequence of operations, thereby lightening the burden on the operator and shortening the required processing time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> As also described above, an insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> from which the check P is inserted is formed at one end of the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and an exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> from which the check P is ejected is formed at the other end of the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the MICR head <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is positioned on the insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> side of the print heads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, and the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is positioned on the exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> side of the print heads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The MICR reading process can therefore be performed as part of the process of conveying a check P placed in the insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> into the multifunction device, and the check P can be ejected while being scanned in the scanning process. A short transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can therefore be used, helping to make the multifunction device smaller and shortening the required processing time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, by forming a horizontally oriented insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> so that a check P can be inserted substantially horizontally and forming a vertically oriented exit opening <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> so that the check P is ejected substantially vertically, the multifunction device can be made smaller than when the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is a straight path, and the processed check can be held using the vertically oriented end of the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, by providing scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> positioned opposite the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for transporting the check P while pressing it against the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and a roller retraction mechanism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for retracting the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from the scanner head <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and opening the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be retracted when the scanning process is not being run. It is therefore possible to avoid checks P being caught by the scanner feed rollers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, thereby preventing jams and skips in the form feed pitch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, by providing a first process control mode whereby the check P is ejected after being scanned, a second process control mode whereby the check P is ejected without being scanned, and a mode selector switch <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> for selecting the first or second process control mode, the print medium can be selectively scanned according to the type of print media and customer desires while being able to continuously run a series of multiple processes including scanning. The mode selector switch <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> may be a panel button switch (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) that may be selected by the operator and/or a software switch that may be set according to the type of media being processed, i.e. automatically set to print and scan (first process mode) for checks and automatically set to print only (second process mode) for roll paper receipts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, by transporting the check P toward the insertion opening <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> when printing with the print heads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, a sequence of processes can be run while transporting the check P back and forth in the transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A short transportation path <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can therefore be used and the multifunction device can be made smaller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> As will be appreciated from the preceding description the present invention lightens the burden on the operator and shortens the required processing time by performing check processing operations from MICR text reading to scanning the printed side of a check as a single continuous process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Although the present invention has been described in connection with the preferred embodiments thereof with reference to the accompanying drawings, it is to be noted that various changes and modifications will be apparent to those skilled in the art. Such changes and modifications are to be understood as included within the scope of the present invention as defined by the appended claims, unless they depart therefrom. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A multifunction device comprising: 
<claim-text>a transportation path that guides a print medium; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a magnetic head positioned along the transportation path that reads magnetic ink characters prerecorded on the print medium; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first print head positioned along the transportation path that prints on a first side of the print medium; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second print head positioned along the transportation path that prints on a second side of the print medium; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a scanner head positioned along the transportation path that scans one of the first side and the second side of the print medium. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A multifunction device as described in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an insertion opening formed at one end of the transportation path for inserting the print medium; and 
<claim-text>an exit opening formed at the other end of the transportation path for ejecting the print medium; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the magnetic head being positioned along the transportation path on the insertion opening side of the first and second print heads, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the scanner head being positioned along the transportation path on the exit opening side of the first and second print heads. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A multifunction device as described in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the insertion opening is horizontally oriented so that the print medium can be inserted substantially horizontally, and the exit opening is vertically oriented so that the print medium can be ejected substantially vertically. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A multifunction device as described in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a pressure feed roller positioned opposite the scanner head that transports the print medium while pressing the print medium against the scanner; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a roller retraction mechanism that retracts the pressure feed roller away from the scanner head to open the transportation path. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A multifunction device as described in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a first process control unit that controls printing and scanning the print medium and then ejecting of the print medium; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second process control unit that controls printing and ejecting the print medium without scanning; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a process selection unit that selects one of the first process control unit and the second process control unit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A control method for a multifunction device having a transportation path that guides a print medium, a magnetic head positioned along the transportation path that reads magnetic ink characters prerecorded on the print medium, a first print head positioned along the transportation path that prints on a first side of the print medium, a second print head positioned along the transportation path that prints on a second side of the print medium, and a scanner head positioned along the transportation path that scans one of the first side and the second side of the print medium, the control method comprising: 
<claim-text>reading the magnetic ink characters with the magnetic head while transporting the print medium inserted from an insertion opening toward an exit opening; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transporting the print medium to a first print head printing starting position after reading the magnetic ink characters; </claim-text>
<claim-text>printing on the first side of the print medium using the first print head while transporting the print medium in a direction along the transportation path; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transporting the print medium to a second print head printing start position after finishing printing with the first print head; </claim-text>
<claim-text>printing on the second side of the print medium using the second print head while transporting the print medium in a direction along the transportation path; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transporting the print medium to a scanning start position after finishing printing with the second print head; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>scanning one of the first and the second side of the print medium with the scanner head while transporting the print medium toward the exit opening. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A multifunction device control method as described in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the print medium is transported toward the insertion opening while printing with the first print head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A multifunction device control method as described in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the print medium is transported toward the insertion opening while printing with the second print head.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030001011A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
