<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000046A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000046A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000046A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000046A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000046A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000046A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000046A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000046A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000046A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000046A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000046</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10042456</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020110</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>090210884</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E05F001/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>016</class>
<subclass>307000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Free positioning hinge</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chia</given-name>
<middle-name>Yu</middle-name>
<family-name>Liao</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Chia Yu Liao</name-1>
<name-2>235 Chung - Ho</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Box 8-24</address-1>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A free positioning hinge is especially used to a notebook computer, an electronic dictionary, a personal digital assistant, etc. for opening covers of these devices, or is used to a rear view mirror of a car. The free positioning hinge is formed by pivotally engaging a rotary shaft with a sleeve. The sleeve is formed by a plurality of stacking closed pads. Each pad has an axial hole. A hollow neck extends from the axial hole and two hollow shoulders are extended from the neck, thereby, two flexible arm portions being formed between the axial hole, the two shoulders, and the neck. The friction surface of the sleeve has a preferred flexibility so that it is difficult to damage the components assembled thereto. Furthermore, oil stored in the holes may provide a proper lubrication ability so as to prolong the lifetime of the device. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a hinge structure, and particularly to a free positioning hinge. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The free-positioning hinge is widely used in assembling the machine body of electronic devices, for example, notebook computers, personal digital assistants, etc., or rear view mirrors used in vehicles having two portions which are pivotally connected through a hinge. In these devices, as a display is opened to a position, it can be positioned in that position so not to fall down due to the gravitational force. In this hinge, the friction force between a rotary unit and a stator unit is utilized to cancel the twisting force of the gravitational force. Therefore, the size of the frictional force is a key point in designing the hinge. If the friction force is too large, not only a large force is necessary to open the device, but also the wearing between two portions of the device is also large. If the friction force is too smaller, then it is very possible that one portion slides with respect to the other portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Other than the precision of the components, the construction is also an important consideration about the friction (twisting force) of a hinge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In the prior art, a hinge is mainly formed by pivotally connecting a sleeve with a rotary shaft. However, these devices are lack of a means for resisting the twisting force induced from the two components. Once the volume of the machine body or the weight of the device to be installed with the hinge is changed, the hinge must be further designed. Therefore, new molds are required. However, currently, the machine bodies of electronic devices are changed frequently. Thus, the prior design is not economical. Next, the prior designs have no space for receiving lubricating oil. Therefore, the lubricating oil can not be contained in the friction surface for a long time period and thus the effect of lubrication is reduced day by day so as to increase the wearing between two connecting components. After being used for a longer time, the friction force is not sufficient to support the twisting force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To improve the defect in the prior art, in Taiwan Patent No. 90205536, filed in Apr. 10, 2001, disclosed by the inventor of the present invention, a plurality of triangular pads are stacked to form a sleeve. A round main axial hole is formed at the center of the pad. At least one auxiliary hole is formed aside the main axial hole for storing oil. Therefore, a friction force is generated as an elastic adjusting mechanism. Moreover, by the auxiliary hole to store lubricating oil, the friction surface has a preferred lubricating effect so as to prolong the lifetime of a device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> However, the inventor discovers that the prior design has some disadvantages, for example, the friction surface between the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the axial hole <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> of the pad <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are closed completely. Although the structure is rigid, it is lack of flexibility. If a very large twisting force generates, it is easy that some components will be destroyed. Furthermore, since the friction surface is closed, as the rotary shaft rotates, an outer cover seat <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> will be affected synchronously so as to increase the resistance force. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the primary object of the present invention is to provide a free positioning hinge which is especially used to a notebook computer, an electronic dictionary, a personal digital assistant, etc. for opening covers of these devices, or is used to a rear view mirror of a car. The free positioning hinge is formed by pivotally engaging a rotary shaft with a sleeve. The sleeve is formed by a plurality of stacking closed pads. Each pad has an axial hole. A hollow neck extends from the axial hole and two hollow shoulders are extended from the neck, thereby, two flexible arm portions being formed between the axial hole, the two shoulders, and the neck. The friction surface of the sleeve has a preferred flexibility so that it is difficult for the components assembled thereto to break. Furthermore, oil stored in the holes may provide a proper lubrication ability so as to prolong the lifetime of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The various objects and advantages of the present invention will be more readily understood from the following detailed description when read in conjunction with the appended drawing.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an assembled perspective view of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an exploded view showing an embodiment that the present invention is utilized with other device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows an assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a second embodiment of the pad of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a free positioning hinge of the present invention is illustrated, which is especially used to a notebook computer, an electronic dictionary, a personal digital assistant (PDA), etc. for opening covers of these devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The free positioning hinge of the present invention is formed by a rotary shaft <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is formed by stacking a plurality of closing type pads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. In the present invention, the shape of each pad <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is similar to a round shape. Each of two sides at the periphery thereof is reduced inwards to form a respective notch as a positioning portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The positioning portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is used to be engaged with a seat <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> described hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The pad <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> mainly includes an axial hole <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> for being inserted by the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The axial hole <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> extends to form a neck <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and two shoulders <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. Thereby, two friction arm portions <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> with a preferred flexibility are formed between the axial hole <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> and the two shoulders <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The neck <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the two shoulders <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> extending from the axial hole <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> can be used as lubricating holes. Therefore, as the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> passes through the sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> so as to generate a friction force, the friction surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a preferred flexibility so that it is difficult for the components assembled thereto to break. Furthermore, oil stored in the holes may provide a proper lubrication ability so as to prolong the lifetime of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, an application about a preferred embodiment of the present invention is illustrated. It can be known from the drawings that the seat <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the main machine of an open-able electronic device (such as a notebook computer, a PDA, etc.) encloses and thus fixes the sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by a cover <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. After the pads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are stacked one by one through the alignment of the positioning portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is inserted into the cover seat <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> with respect to the engaging hole <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> of the cover seat <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and is positioned therein so not to rotate. The movable end <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> (such as a panel, a display, etc.) of the open-able electronic device is connected to a jointing portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. When the movable end <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> rotates, the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is driven to rotate, then the twisting force due to the weight of the movable end <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is cancelled by the friction force generated between the rotary shaft <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the movable end <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can be positioned freely. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Since in the present invention, the sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a stacked structure. The length thereof is determined by the number of the pads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. That is, if a larger friction force is required, the number of the pads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> can be increased, and vice versa. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, if the oil storage space of the sleeve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is not sufficient, an auxiliary hole <highlight><bold>217</bold></highlight> can be formed near the axial hole <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> of each pad <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> so as to have a preferred lubricating effect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The present invention are thus described, it will be obvious that the same may be varied in many ways. Such variations are not to be regarded as a departure from the spirit and scope of the present invention, and all such modifications as would be obvious to one skilled in the art are intended to be included within the scope of the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A free positioning hinge formed by pivotally engaging a rotary shaft with a sleeve; said rotary shaft being connected to an open-able element of a device; said sleeve being confined to a connecting seat of said device; characterized in that: said sleeve is formed by a plurality of stacking closed pads; each pad has an axial hole for being inserted by said rotary shaft; a hollow neck extends from said axial hole and two hollow shoulders extends from said neck, thereby, two flexible arm portions being formed between said axial hole, said two shoulders, and said neck. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The free positioning hinge as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said hollow neck and said two hollow shoulders are utilized as lubricating oil holes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The free positioning hinge as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each pad has a round-like shape, an periphery thereof is formed with a positioning portion for being engaged to said connecting seat of said device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The free positioning hinge as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said positioning portion is formed by two reduced notches at two sides of said periphery of each said pad.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000046A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000046A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000046A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000046A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000046A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
