<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001008A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001008A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001008A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001008A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001008A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001008A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001008A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001008A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001008</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10149684</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020613</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>99/15813</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19991215</filing-date>
<country-code>FR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06K015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>235</class>
<subclass>383000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Electronic label system for displaying prices in a sale outlet</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Francois</given-name>
<family-name>Berrube</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Courbevoie</city>
<country-code>FR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Pierre</given-name>
<family-name>Legras</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Strasbourg</city>
<country-code>FR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>LERNER, DAVID, LITTENBERG,</name-1>
<name-2>KRUMHOLZ &amp; MENTLIK</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>600 SOUTH AVENUE WEST</address-1>
<city>WESTFIELD</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>07090</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/FR00/03504</doc-number>
<document-date>20001213</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The invention concerns an electronic label system comprising a central station and a plurality of distributed electronic labels, and communication means in particular wireless communication means for transmitting data particularly price data from the central station labels. This invention is characterized in that each label comprises a set of price registers and a set of coefficient registers and including a display unit comprising at least tow price displaying zones, and the data transmitted from the central station to a label comprise instructions fro assignment between a computed price equal to the price contained in the price register multiplied by a given coefficient, and a zone displaying a given price. Time-out instructions are also provided. The invention is useful in particular for displaying prices in shops. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to remote-controlled price display systems in stores. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> On the shelves of a site such as a supermarket, hypermarket, or other retail outlet (for example pharmacies, etc.), an essential object of such systems is to present consumers with a price for each article on sale, with that price being known to correspond reliably to the price that appears in the central file of the store, i.e. with the actual price that will be charged for the article at the checkout. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Another object of those prior art systems is to enable price changes to be made automatically in much shorter times than with a manual display, whether this is for particular promotional periods in the store, for all or some of the articles, to implement price changes, to deal with inflation when prices have to be increased very frequently, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Moreover, price display is subject to many constraints, in particular legal constraints, as to the nature of the prices displayed (unit price, promotional price, price in Euros, etc.), with which constraints electronic systems must conform in exactly the same way as displays on paper. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, although electronic label systems are tending to become more and more sophisticated as time goes on, they nevertheless remain relatively rigid in terms of display facilities and the organization thereof over time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention aims to alleviate those drawbacks of the prior art and to propose an electronic label system that offers a vast range of display facilities, in particular to meet to the constraints referred to above and to satisfy an increasing demand from users to modify displayed prices often and for short periods, which system can act extremely flexibly and quickly to display information other than prices, for example information relating to the products and/or to the labels themselves, and which also offers the facility of modifying all the labels of a given group or all the labels throughout the store in accordance with precise time periods that are accurately specified in terms of when they begin and/or their duration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> An object of the invention is to ensure that a label is returned to its initial state after the data displayed by the label has been modified temporarily. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> To this end, a first aspect of the invention proposes an electronic label system, in particular for displaying prices in stores, the system comprising a central station and a plurality of distributed electronic labels, together with communication means, in particular wireless communication means, for sending information, in particular price information, from the central station to the labels, the system being characterized in that each label includes a set of price registers, a set of coefficient registers and a display including at least two price display areas, and the information sent from the central station to a label includes assignment instructions linking a calculated price equal to the price contained in one of the price registers multiplied by a given coefficient with a given price display area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Preferred but non-limiting features of the above system comprise: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> the set of price registers comprises a main price register and one or more secondary price registers each adapted to contain a value equal to the main price multiplied by a coefficient contained in a coefficient register; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> the system includes a main price display area and one or more secondary price display areas; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> the system includes a plurality of secondary price registers and a plurality of secondary display areas, and the assignment instructions are adapted to make a choice from a predetermined set of assignments linking price registers and display areas; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> the number of secondary display areas is less than the number of secondary price registers; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> each price register is associated with a price attributes register and the contents of the two registers can be modified independently of each other; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> the information sent from the central station to a label further includes price transfer messages for a particular price register; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> each price transfer instruction is also able to contain a calculation or display parameter; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> the information sent from the central station to a label further includes coefficient transfer messages for a particular coefficient register; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> the information sent from the central station to a label further includes instructions for directly addressing segments of the price display areas forming characters in order to display information comprising alphanumeric and other signs; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> each segment of a character is assigned a numerical value, the numerical values assigned to the various segments are such that there is a one-to-one relationship between a sum of said values and the values contributing to that sum and designating the segments to be displayed, and the instructions for directly addressing the segments include a respective sum associated with each character; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> the information sent from the central station to a label further includes instructions for permutating the contents of two price registers or two coefficient registers; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> the information sent from the central station to a label further includes instructions for copying the content of a price or coefficient register to another price or coefficient register; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> the permutation and copying instructions consist of a single instruction containing a command code, two register addresses and a parameter indicating permutation or copying. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> A second aspect of the invention proposes an electronic label system, in particular for displaying prices in stores, comprising a central station and a plurality of distributed electronic labels, together with communication means, in particular wireless communication means, for sending information, in particular price information, from the central station to the labels, the system being characterized in that each label includes a memory, a display and means for controlling display on the basis of information contained in said memory, and the information sent from the central station to a label is contained in a single message, which message includes instructions containing data assigning the content of a particular memory area to a particular display area of the display and is adapted to contain time-delay data from which the label determines a timing parameter relating to said assignment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Preferred but non-limiting features of the above system comprise: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> the display of each label comprises a plurality of price display areas, the memory of each label includes a plurality of price memory areas, and said instructions includes instructions for assigning a particular set of price memory areas to said display areas; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> said timing parameter is a duration for which the assignment must be applied; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> said timing parameter is a delayed time from which the assignment must be applied; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> each label includes means for verifying the status of a power supply battery of the label and said particular memory area contains a battery status indicator; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> said particular memory area is an address area of the label; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> the system includes means for selectively loading a long address or a short address into an address memory of an electronic label; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> the long address consists at least in part of the characters of a standardized product code of a product associated with the label and the short address consists at least in part of a particular portion of the characters of said product code and other characters.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Other aspects, objects and advantages of the present invention become more apparent on reading the following detailed description of a preferred embodiment of the invention, which is given by way of non-limiting example and with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of some functions of an electronic price display label in accordance with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front view of a preferred embodiment of a liquid crystal display used in an electronic label of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a list of commands used in messages sent to the electronic labels, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a particular numerical coding of a seven-segment display.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Before starting the description proper, it should be noted that, in the following description, the terms register, memory and memory area are used interchangeably to designate the locations in the electronic label for variable information, whether that information consists of data, parameters, commands, etc. Also, the term digit is to be generally understood as referring to a group of four bits (a quad), although this is in no way limiting on the invention, of course. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> General Architecture </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Overall Structure </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Note first of all that the electronic labels of the system of the invention have a general architecture primarily comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> a control microcontroller, associated with an operating system contained in a read-only memory and with appropriate dedicated integrated circuits; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> a set of memories or registers for variables (price, label address, various flags, etc.); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> a circuit for receiving signals sent by a central station or a portable unit, associated with a receive antenna (radio transmission) or a photosensitive element (infrared transmission), for example; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> a control circuit that controls price display in particular on the basis of the content of the memories; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> a battery power supply for various circuits; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> a casing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> For more details on a label of the above kind, and in particular on how it communicates with a central station and portable terminals, see for example the document FR 2 658 645 A in the name of the Applicant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is shown a portion of the architecture of an electronic label which includes a liquid crystal display ACL having a main price display area ZP and two secondary price display areas ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which in this example are smaller than the main area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The label has five price registers, namely a main price register RPP and four secondary price registers RPS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, RPS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, RPS<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and RPS<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Four coefficient registers RC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, RC<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, RC<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and RC<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are associated with the four secondary price registers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The label controls operations that multiply the content of the main price register RPP by the contents of the coefficient registers RC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to RC<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> by means of four multipliers MU<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to MU<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> which are in practice implemented in the operating system of the microcontroller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The label is also able to control the assignment of the various price registers to the three display areas, using display commands CA symbolized shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> as switches. Note that the main price memory RPP can be assigned only to the main area ZP of the display whereas each secondary price memory RPS<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to RPS<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be assigned to either of the two secondary areas ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Note also in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> that the price data in the registers is associated with decimal point position, currency symbol and pictogram data stored separately in respective areas SVPP and SVPS<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to SVPS<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, for reasons explained later. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The left-hand part of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows diagrammatically a number of actions on the label, initiated by messages from the central station, and dashed or dotted lines designate corresponding actions in the block diagram on the right-hand side of the figure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Display </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows in more detail the organization of the liquid crystal display ACL, with: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> the main price area ZP, offering two decimal point position options V<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and V<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> the two secondary price areas ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, each offering two decimal point position options, respectively VS<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, VS<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and VS<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, VS<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> an upward arrow FH and a downward arrow FB for indicating where to find the product on sale corresponding to the label; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> currency symbols SYM; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> pictograms PIC; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> a promotion block PRO, indicating that the article is currently on sale at a promotional price. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> As explained in more detail hereinafter, the display can show either price data and other information supplied by the various registers of the label or bit map or like mode semi-graphical data from a central station. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Activating a Label </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> A label is activated in accordance with the following protocol: after correct reception of a normal activation command, the label sets a time-delay of approximately 36 seconds. At the end of this time-delay, the label tests for the presence of a weak field radio transmission. This test is then repeated, approximately every 37 seconds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> A special command for chaining commands is also provided, which executes a weak field reception test much faster, typically less than one second after processing the command. This enables some commands to be chained (see the description of the commands later), and economizes the time period of 72 seconds needed for synchronization in the event of additional commands. This special command is naturally usable only when addressing a single command individually to one label or to the whole of the installed base of labels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Moreover, this command chaining function is valid only for some of the commands described later, including: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> a set flag command B; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> a change label address command E; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> and also for the following commands, if the automatic display on reception function (see below) is deactivated: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> a send coefficient and price command 2; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> a send main price command 4; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> a send secondary price command 5; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> a send price and coefficient command A; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> a permutate or memory-to-memory copy command D. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE SYSTEM </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The organization of the various items of information in the label and the various commands that can be received, mainly from the central station (server) of the store, is described in more detail next. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> 1) Content and Processing of Memories </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> a) Prices and Coefficients and Associated Calculations </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> The label has nine memory areas or registers, namely: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> a main price area (six digits&plus;decimal points&plus;currency symbols); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> four secondary price areas (six digits&plus;decimal points&plus;currency symbols&plus;pictograms); and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> four coefficient areas (six mantissa digits&plus;one exponent digit). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Each main or secondary price memory area is associated with: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> one of three decimal point positions; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> one of three currency symbols. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Each secondary price memory area is associated with: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> one or more (from zero to four) pictograms; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> a coefficient (six digits&plus;an exponent digit). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> The dedication of the memories is defined as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> RPP: memory address 1: main price, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> RPS<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>: memory address 2: secondary price 0, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> RPS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>: memory address 3: secondary price 1, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> RPS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>: memory address 4: secondary price 2, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> RPS<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>: memory address 5: secondary price 3, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> RC<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>: memory address A: coefficient 0 (can be associated with secondary price 0), </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> RC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>: memory address B: coefficient 0 (can be associated with secondary price 1), </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> RC<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>: memory address C: coefficient 0 (can be associated with secondary price 2), </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> RC<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>: memory address D: coefficient 0 (can be associated with secondary price 3). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> The content of the main price memory RPP is always displayed in the main price area ZP of the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> The contents of the secondary price memories can be displayed cyclically in the secondary price areas ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the display, see below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Note that the communication protocol enables contents to be downloaded directly from the central station to all the memories, including the secondary price memories. However, as explained in more detail later, such downloading of the secondary price memories makes sense only if multiplication is disabled beforehand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Afterwards, as soon as multiplication is activated, the secondary prices are calculated by multiplying the main price by a coefficient and the associated secondary price memory receives the result of the multiplication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> The coefficients are downloaded into the coefficient memories in the form of an exponent followed by the most significant digit of the mantissa, which must not be zero. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> When a price is sent, the status of the promotion block PROMO of the display can be modified by inserting before the price either a digit of value A or a digit of value B (the values are in hexadecimal in this example). The value A turns off the promotion block while the value B causes it to blink on and off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> The content of a coefficient memory is not necessarily intended for the multiplication calculation described above, in which case There is no restriction on the format of this content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> On this subject, to prevent pricing errors that might be caused by unintentional multiplication of the main price value by the content of a coefficient memory if that content is not a coefficient, the central station can verify the plausibility of the result of the multiplication, and in particular can verify that the result of the multiplication is less than or equal to 999999 (in the case of a six-digit display). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Note that multiplying the main price by a coefficient consists in multiplying together two initial items of data, each on six digits, plus the exponent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> The complete result is therefore on thirteen digits plus the exponent, and is rounded to six digits employing the usual conventions employed for the Euro (whereby a value of 0.4 is rounded down to 0 whereas a value of 0.5 is rounded up to 1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> b) Flags and Parameters </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> The memory of the label has a number of locations for flags and parameters for modifying and adapting the operation of the label. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> The flags and parameters include: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> a general display status flag, coded on four bits (one quad): </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> the bit of weight 0 is a command for automatic display on receiving a price: if this bit is at 1, the secondary prices are recalculated on receiving a main price or a coefficient and the recalculated prices are displayed; on the other hand, if this bit is at 0, the display is not changed, the calculations are not done again, and the price or coefficient received is simply stored in the corresponding memory area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> the bit of weight 1 is a command to blink the display on and off: if this bit is at 1, the display blinks on and off; otherwise the display is fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> the bit of weight 2 is a command for cyclic display of secondary prices; if this bit is at 1, the secondary prices are displayed in the secondary display areas with a predefined rhythm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> the bit of weight 3 is a main price display command, authorizing or prohibiting display of the main price, according to its value. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> flags authorizing calculation of secondary prices; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> flags authorizing display of secondary prices in display area ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> flags authorizing display of secondary prices in display area ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> (The above authorization flags, which have a length of four bits, are coded in the following manner: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> bit of weight 0: secondary price 0; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> bit of weight 1: secondary price 1; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> bit of weight 2: secondary price 2; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> bit of weight 3: secondary price 3.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> a secondary area display timing parameter on four bits, for example with the following four (decimal) values, which can vary from less than one second to several seconds, for example: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> 2: fast timing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> 6: standard timing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> 9: slow timing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> 15: very slow timing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> a promotion block status parameter on one bit (1&equals;blinking on and off; 0&equals;off). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> a timing-delay parameter: some commands (in particular commands 8, 9 and C, see below) can be associated with a time-delay to limit the time for which the action initiated by the command continues. For example, it is possible to specify that the label can recalculate all the secondary prices and then display the new prices only after the expiry of a time-delay associated with a new main price transfer command. Other commands with a time-delay can be used to display service information and short-term messages contained in specific memory areas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> Another function associated with commands with a time-delay can shorten a time-delay already in progress, for example by sending the label a message containing a new time-delay less than the original one, possibly a zero time-delay, or by sending the label an immediate display command, or any appropriate instruction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> It is important to note here that the label can be designed so that if it is receiving a message that is not intended for it extends the time-delay by a time equal to the time taken to receive it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, it is advantageous if reception by the label of a command that is intended for it cancels the time-delay. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> The time-delay parameter (tempo) can be coded on four bits (sixteen hexadecimal values), for example, providing fourteen different time-delays, for example, in arithmetical, geometrical or other progression and varying from a few seconds to 24 hours or more. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> Note that the effective duration of the time-delay is equal to the value fixed by time-delay parameter (tempo) plus the time taken to receive it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> 2) Commands </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> a) Command Logic Tree </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> of the drawings shows in the form of a tree one example of a set of commands used in an electronic label system according to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> Note that there can be redundancy between some commands, and in particular: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> transfer of prices and/or coefficients by commands 2, 3 and 6; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> activation/deactivation of the promotion block by the commands 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> transfer of flags and general parameters by the commands 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> b) Detailed Description of Commands </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> Some of the commands shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> are described in detail next. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> Command 7&mdash;Customize Label </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> Note first of all that a command of this kind can be sent only in the strong field mode (i.e. by communication with a portable terminal). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> The hexadecimal code for the command is 7. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> This command conveys two sets of parameters, namely: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> general display flags (four-bit word, see above); and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> a parameter with N bits, which defines the status of N product designation arrows associated with the label: for each bit, the value O turns on the corresponding arrow and the value I turns it off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> Also, this command is used to set the address of the label by overwriting the preceding address, in particular if the label must be associated with a different product on the shelf. The format of this address is a word with 13 digits, corresponding to the value of the standardized EAN13 code of the associated product, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> (Note on Addressing </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> In the system according to the invention, a label can be addressed using a long address or a short address. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> The long address of the label comprises 13 digits, for example the 13 digits of the standardized EAN13 code of the associated product, preceded by three digits constituting a store code, that is to say 16 digits in total. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> The short address comprises only nine digits, namely, in order of decreasing weight: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> three digits (preferably the three digits of the store code), and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> an address on six digits, of which the four least significant digits can be the four least significant digits of the EAN13 code. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> In short addressing mode, it is these six digits which are used to address the individual labels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> The change from a long address to a short address is effected as follows: the address sent to the label by the command 7 is a long address, and if at least one of the six most significant digits of the 13-digit address is greater than nine (hexadecimal), then the label goes automatically to the short address mode.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> Note also that, at the time of a command 7, the label displays the last four digits of the address temporarily, for example in the main area, so that they can be verified by comparing them to the last four digits of the EAN13 code on the product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> Command 1&mdash;Characterize </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> This kind of command provides an introduction to other commands, and designates a group of labels intended to process subsequent commands. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> A command 1 contains at least the store code, in which case it designates all the labels in the store. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> It contains at most the store code plus the first 12 digits of the long address, in which case the label group it designates comprises all the labels whose first 12 address digits match those appearing in the command. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> Naturally, for designating larger or smaller groups of labels, any number of address digits from 0 to 12 can be envisaged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> Command 0&mdash;Escape </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> This is a command whose format is indeterminate and totally free and which contains the address of a label. After receiving its address, the label ignores the remainder of the command. This command is reserved for future development. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> Command 4&mdash;Send Main Price </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> This complete command includes a label address and a main price intended for that label, consisting of six digits followed by the position of the decimal point and a currency symbol code. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0171" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0171&rsqb;</number> The price information can be followed by a number of display and calculation flags and parameters, as described above: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0172" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0172&rsqb;</number> the status of the promotion block; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0173" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0173&rsqb;</number> prices displayed in the secondary display area ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0174" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0174&rsqb;</number> calculated prices; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0175" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0175&rsqb;</number> the general status of the display; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0176" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0176&rsqb;</number> prices displayed in the secondary display area ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0177" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0177&rsqb;</number> All the information previously contained in the memory of the label and to which the content of a command 4 message does not relate is retained. For example, it is possible to send only some of the price, decimal point position and currency symbol code digits, the others remaining unchanged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0178" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0178&rsqb;</number> Command 5&mdash;Send Secondary Price 0 (Register RPS<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0179" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0179&rsqb;</number> The rules are the same as for the command 4 (send main price), except that the price is followed by a digit indicating a pictogram or pictograms to be associated with secondary price 0. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0180" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0180&rsqb;</number> The status of the promotion block can be modified quickly by inserting the command before the price itself. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0181" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0181&rsqb;</number> Command 2&mdash;Send a Coefficient or a Price </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0182" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0182&rsqb;</number> Prices have the format indicated above (six digits, decimal point position and currency symbol). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0183" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0183&rsqb;</number> The coefficients are multiplier coefficients with six mantissa digits, and are always associated with an exponent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0184" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0184&rsqb;</number> For example, an exponent value equal to 8 (hexadecimal) corresponds to 10<highlight><superscript>0</superscript></highlight>, a value equal to 9 corresponds to 10<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, and so on; conversely a value equal to 7 corresponds to 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;1</superscript></highlight>, and so on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0185" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0185&rsqb;</number> The command further includes a digit designating the address in the label of the price or the coefficient sent, namely (see above) an address 1 for the main price, an address from 2 to 5 for one of the four secondary prices, and an address from A to D for one of the four coefficients. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0186" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0186&rsqb;</number> Once again, non-significant zeros are not necessarily sent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0187" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0187&rsqb;</number> Display and calculation parameters and flags can be sent, in the same way as for the commands 4 and 5 described above, and the same applies to fast access to the promotion block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0188" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0188&rsqb;</number> Command 3&mdash;Enter Individual Extended Command </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0189" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0189&rsqb;</number> This kind of command contains an individual label address and an extended command code, followed by parameters and the body of the command itself. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0190" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0190&rsqb;</number> This command is reserved for implementing special functions in a given label by means of subcommands (see below). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0191" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0191&rsqb;</number> Command 6&mdash;Enter Collective Extended Command </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0192" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0192&rsqb;</number> This command is collective in the sense that it does not include an individual label address, and the group of labels to which it relates is a group of labels designated by a command 1 (characterize) message sent previously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0193" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0193&rsqb;</number> The first digit of the command is the digit 6 and is followed by an extended command code, which is in turn followed by parameters constituting the body of the extended command. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0194" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0194&rsqb;</number> The command 6 enables a given group of labels to implement some functions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0195" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0195&rsqb;</number> The various extended commands that can be included in commands 3 and 6 are described next. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0196" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0196&rsqb;</number> Command 8&mdash;Address Display, Direct (Bit Map) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0197" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0197&rsqb;</number> Each display symbol comprises seven segments, some combinations of which can define letters or symbols other than those normally displayed by a conventional 7-segment coder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0198" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0198&rsqb;</number> In the present example, the seven segments are assigned respective pairs of hexadecimal values: 02, 04, 08, 10, 20, 40, 80, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> of the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0199" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0199&rsqb;</number> To each combination of segments turned on that forms a letter or a symbol there corresponds an unique sum of values assigned to those segments, and vice versa, as shown by the following table, which is provided merely by way of example (the calculations are in hexadecimal):  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="28PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="77PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="112PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Letter or symbol</entry>
<entry>sum</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>I</entry>
<entry>40 &plus; 20 &equals; 60</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>t</entry>
<entry>10 &plus; 8 &plus; 4 &plus; 2 &equals; 1E</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>-</entry>
<entry>02 &equals; 02</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>H</entry>
<entry>40 &plus; 20 &plus; 8 &plus; 4 &plus; 2 &equals; 6E</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>F</entry>
<entry>80 &plus; 8 &plus; 4 &plus; 2 &equals; 8E</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>y</entry>
<entry>40 &plus; 20 &plus; 10 &plus; 4 &plus; 2 &equals; 76</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>L</entry>
<entry>10 &plus; 8 &plus; 4 &equals; 1C</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>U</entry>
<entry>40 &plus; 20 &plus; 10 &plus; 8 &plus; 4 &equals; 7C</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>J</entry>
<entry>40 &plus; 20 &plus; 10 &equals; 70</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0200" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0200&rsqb;</number> The command 8 contains a set of sum values designating the required symbols for the N digits of the display, together with a time-delay digit representing the time period for which these symbols are to be displayed, with values that can vary in steps from a few seconds to several tens of hours for example (see above). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0201" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0201&rsqb;</number> It also contains a number of digits and/or bits constituting display parameters, for example: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0202" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0202&rsqb;</number> a digit: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0203" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0203&rsqb;</number> whose two least significant bits designate the area ZP, ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the display that is to display the received symbols; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0204" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0204&rsqb;</number> whose next bit indicates if the symbols and/or pictograms currently displayed in the designated area must be cleared or not when displaying the symbols; and, finally </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0205" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0205&rsqb;</number> whose most significant bit indicates if the label must first clear all of the designated display area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0206" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0206&rsqb;</number> another digit that designates the location within the designated display area at which the display of the symbols must begin, using the following convention, for example: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0207" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0207&rsqb;</number> 0: at the first digit (the leftmost digit) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0208" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0208&rsqb;</number> 2: at the second digit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0209" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0209&rsqb;</number> 4: at the third digit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0210" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0210&rsqb;</number> 6: at the fourth digit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0211" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0211&rsqb;</number> 8: at the fifth digit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0212" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0212&rsqb;</number> A: at the sixth digit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0213" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0213&rsqb;</number> It is advantageous if only the symbols that can actually be displayed, given the value of the last digit, are sent in a command 8 message. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0214" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0214&rsqb;</number> Command C&mdash;Address Display, Coded Direct </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0215" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0215&rsqb;</number> This command, for turning on certain alphanumeric or other signs on the displays, is identical to command 8 except that the data is numerical and not in the form of a segment map, as described. Thus a quad can cause display of digits, letters and symbols, for example in accordance with the following table:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="56PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="77PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="84PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Value</entry>
<entry>Display</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0 or O</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1 or I</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>5 or S</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>6 or G</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>7</entry>
<entry>7</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>8</entry>
<entry>8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>9</entry>
<entry>9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>A</entry>
<entry>empty</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>B</entry>
<entry>F</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>C</entry>
<entry>&equals;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>t</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>E</entry>
<entry>U</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>F</entry>
<entry>C</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0216" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0216&rsqb;</number> Command A&mdash;Send Coefficients or Prices, Associated Flags and General Parameters </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0217" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0217&rsqb;</number> This command is similar to command 2, using the same functions and the same format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0218" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0218&rsqb;</number> Its benefit is that it can be associated with command 6 and thereby address given groups of labels or even all of the labels of the same store. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0219" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0219&rsqb;</number> In the case of sending a price, fast control of the promotion block, as described above, is also available with this command. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0220" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0220&rsqb;</number> Command D&mdash;Permutate or Copy Prices </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0221" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0221&rsqb;</number> This command comprises blocks of three digits which can be linked to constitute a macrocommand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0222" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0222&rsqb;</number> It contains, after the code D of the command, series of digits constituting the blocks of commands. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0223" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0223&rsqb;</number> The most significant bit of the first digit of each block indicates whether a price must be copied or permutated. The three least significant bits indicate the number of digits of the price to which the copying or permutation applies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0224" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0224&rsqb;</number> For example, a value 0 for these bits (000) indicates that it concerns the first 6 digits, while the values 1, 2 and 3 (respectively 001, 010 and 011) respectively correspond to 7, 8 and 9 digits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0225" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0225&rsqb;</number> There are a number of exceptions to this: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0226" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0226&rsqb;</number> first exception (if the first digit of each block has the value 4, i.e. 0100): this enables the display and calculation flags to be modified, the value 4 introducing a subcommand chosen from the following subcommands, for example: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0227" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0227&rsqb;</number> followed by prices displayed on secondary display ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0228" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0228&rsqb;</number> followed by calculated prices; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0229" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0229&rsqb;</number> followed by general display status; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0230" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0230&rsqb;</number> followed by prices displayed on secondary display ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0231" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0231&rsqb;</number> second exception (if the first digit of each block has the value 6, i.e. 0110): this turns off the promotion block, by means of single-digit command; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0232" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0232&rsqb;</number> third exception (if the first digit of each block has the value 7, i.e. 0111): this turns on the promotion block, also by means of a single-digit command. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0233" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0233&rsqb;</number> The second digit designates a block of the source of the copy or permutation and the third digit designates its destination, the (hexadecimal) values of these digits being the addresses of the memories, from 1 to 5 for prices and from A to D for coefficients (see above). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0234" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0234&rsqb;</number> For example, the block with the value 01A designates a permutation between the value in the main price register and the value of the mantissa in the coefficient 0 register, and the block with the value 814 designates copying of the content of the main price register to secondary price register 2. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0235" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0235&rsqb;</number> Command B&mdash;Set Flag </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0236" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0236&rsqb;</number> This command can be chained, in the sense that it can comprise a succession of command blocks. These blocks can be linked to constitute a macrocommand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0237" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0237&rsqb;</number> The digits that follow the command code B constitute the blocks of commands whose first digit indicates the subcommand to be executed and whose subsequent digit(s) designate(s) the execution mode. In this example the available subcommand values are: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0238" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0238&rsqb;</number> 1: send a set arrow command (see above on the subject of flags and parameters); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0239" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0239&rsqb;</number> 2: send a promotion block command (blinking on/off or off); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0240" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0240&rsqb;</number> 3: send a secondary price display timing command (see above); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0241" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0241&rsqb;</number> 4: send a clear display and/or general calculation and display command (see above); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0242" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0242&rsqb;</number> 5: set/reset general status command: the next digit (second digit) is ANDed with the status digit (reset flag) and the third digit is ORed with the same status digit (set flag). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0243" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0243&rsqb;</number> The values of the above flags are as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0244" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0244&rsqb;</number> bit <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>: display automatically on receiving command; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0245" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0245&rsqb;</number> bit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>: blink display on/off; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0246" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0246&rsqb;</number> bit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>: activate cyclic display of secondary prices; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0247" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0247&rsqb;</number> bit <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>: activate display of main price. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0248" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0248&rsqb;</number> Note that resetting the flags produces a digit equal to 1101, i.e. D in hexadecimal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0249" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0249&rsqb;</number> 8: modify display and calculation flags command: the second digit of the block designates the subcommand to be executed, and in particular: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0250" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0250&rsqb;</number> followed by prices displayed on secondary display ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0251" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0251&rsqb;</number> followed by calculated prices; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0252" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0252&rsqb;</number> followed by general display status; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0253" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0253&rsqb;</number> followed by prices displayed on secondary display ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0254" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0254&rsqb;</number> 9: modify main price attributes command: the subcommand code 9 is followed by a digit representing the number of digits after the decimal point and the currency symbol associated with the main price, or a promotion block command digit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0255" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0255&rsqb;</number> A, B, C and D : modify attributes of respective secondary price command (i.e. commands 0, 1, 2 and 3): these subcommands are analogous to subcommand 9, except that the promotion block command is replaced by the command for the pictogram or pictograms associated with the secondary price concerned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0256" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0256&rsqb;</number> On the subject of the format of the decimal point position and associated pictogram flags, the following convention can be adopted, for example: the two least significant bits of the quad indicate the number of digits after the decimal point in the display (four values, specifying a number of digits after the decimal point from zero to three); the two most significant bits of the same quad code the currency symbol to be used, for example with the following convention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0257" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0257&rsqb;</number> 00: no currency symbol; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0258" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0258&rsqb;</number> 01: first currency symbol (e.g. the local currency); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0259" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0259&rsqb;</number> 10: second currency symbol; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0260" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0260&rsqb;</number> 11: third currency symbol. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0261" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0261&rsqb;</number> Note that these are only display rules, the label working only on anonymous integer numbers. Note also that the currency symbols can be highly diverse, depending on the country in which the system is used (local main currency, local secondary currency, Euros, or any other useful currency). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0262" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0262&rsqb;</number> The pictograms associated with the secondary prices are coded in the four bits of the next digit, to selectively turn on or off four different pictograms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0263" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0263&rsqb;</number> Command 9&mdash;Time-Delayed Command </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0264" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0264&rsqb;</number> This command can be chained, in the present example with nine types of time-delay command with the following format: the first digit in all cases designates the duration of the time-delay, as in command 8 (see above). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0265" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0265&rsqb;</number> The processing of a command 9 in the label consists in executing the command, and then starting the time-delay indicated by the first digit. When the time-delay expires, cyclic display of the secondary prices is activated, while the commands for calculating the secondary prices and displaying the main price are executed if the authorization parameters allow this (see above). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0266" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0266&rsqb;</number> Also, independently of the value of the flag concerned, the label automatically displays the data received as soon as it is received. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0267" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0267&rsqb;</number> Note that, during the time-delay, the label continues to be able to receive other commands sent by the central station (weak field) or a portable terminal (strong field). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0268" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0268&rsqb;</number> A command 9 is organized into sub-blocks of variable size. The first digit of each sub-block indicates the action to be effected and its second digit indicates the area of the display concerned, where applicable, using the following convention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0269" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0269&rsqb;</number> 1: main area; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0270" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0270&rsqb;</number> 2: first secondary price area; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0271" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0271&rsqb;</number> 3: second secondary price area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0272" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0272&rsqb;</number> The third digit of the sub-block indicates, where applicable, the memory area whose content must be displayed, preferably using the conventions explained above, namely 1 to 5 to display one of the five prices and A to D to display one of the four coefficients. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0273" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0273&rsqb;</number> The nine types of subcommands of a time-delayed command are as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0274" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0274&rsqb;</number> 0: test label stack (command on 2 digits): the result is the display of YES on the designated display, for the duration of the time-delay, if the label has verified that the battery is still sufficiently charged. If the battery is spent, the information bAtt is displayed. The YES and bAtt displays can blink on/off: note that this battery test also tests correct operation of the receive and other circuits of the label: accordingly, if this kind of subcommand does not provoke the above behavior, then the observer knows that the label is defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0275" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0275&rsqb;</number> 1: display label address (command on 2 digits): this command causes the display of the last four digits of the address (identical to the last four digits of the EAN13 product code, for example) on the designated display and for the time period fixed by the time-delay. These four digits are preferably followed by -C to indicate that they constitute a product code. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0276" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0276&rsqb;</number> 2: start defined time-delay (command on 1 digit): this command has no effect during the time-delay; when the time-delay expires, the display is merely refreshed or updated (as for the other time-delayed commands). Thus the time at which price changes previously loaded into a label actually appear on the display can be chosen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0277" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0277&rsqb;</number> 3: power save (command on 1 digit, not chainable): this command turns off the display throughout the time-delay, in particular to economize on the battery. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0278" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0278&rsqb;</number> 4: change status of display and start time-delay (command on 5 digits): the first digit contains the command code 4; the second digit designates the price to be displayed in the second area ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; the third digit designates the calculated price; the fourth digit is used to modify the display status, in accordance with the rules defined above; finally, the fifth digit designates the price that must be displayed in the second area ZS<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0279" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0279&rsqb;</number> 5: scroll label address (command on 1 digit, not chainable): the last four digits of the address are displayed in the main area ZP of the display and the 13 digits of the individual address of the label (excluding the store code) are shown on the secondary display ZS<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, scrolling horizontally from left to right. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0280" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0280&rsqb;</number> Note that, in the case of command 5, the digit normally used for the time-delay advantageously indicates the number of horizontal scanning steps to be effected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0281" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0281&rsqb;</number> 6: display content of memory (command on 3 digits): the two least significant bits of the second digit designate the display concerned and the third digit designates the memory area whose content is to be displayed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0282" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0282&rsqb;</number> Note that the bit immediately preceding the two least significant bits can advantageously be used for selectively deleting the decimal point, the currency symbol and the pictograms or pictograms associated with the display concerned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0283" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0283&rsqb;</number> 7: start blinking promotion block on/off (command on 1 digit): the command is executed as soon as it is received and it is a feature of this command that blinking continues when the time-delay expires. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0284" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0284&rsqb;</number> 8: stop blinking promotion block on/off (command on 1 digit): the promotion block is turned off as soon as the command is received, and remains turned off even after the time-delay expires. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0285" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0285&rsqb;</number> A number of concrete examples of using the system described above will now be described: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0286" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0286&rsqb;</number> i) a label can display, in an extremely flexible manner, and in particular as a function of the requirements of the user or of time, highly diverse prices such as current price, promotional price, old price (especially while the promotional price applies), price per liter or per kilo, price in one or more other currencies (in particular in Euros for countries adopting the single European currency), etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0287" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0287&rsqb;</number> ii) when a label has been sent a new main price, the label can automatically calculate and display secondary prices, such as the price in Euros or some other currency and the price per liter or per kilo. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0288" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0288&rsqb;</number> iii) a promotional price, or any other new price, can be stored in all the labels in advance, by means of a single collective command to update the display for a group of labels or for all the labels in the store, so that the labels can be switched to the new prices extremely quickly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0289" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0289&rsqb;</number> iv) in the same manner, the switching of prices at the time of a change of currency, such as the legal changeover from prices in a local currency to prices in Euros, can be prepared in advance and effected very quickly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0290" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0290&rsqb;</number> v) display of management data (quantity in stock, number of facings, consumer unit, restocking unit, etc.) can be instigated from the central station, with a time-delay if necessary, to ensure that the label reverts to its original status at the end of a particular time period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0291" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0291&rsqb;</number> vi) the last four digits of the label address (EAN13 code) can be displayed to verify the correct assignment of the label to the product, also with a time-delay if necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0292" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0292&rsqb;</number> vii) tests can be carried out, in particular a battery status test, and the results shown on the display, with the assurance that the label will resume its original status thanks to the time-delay. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0293" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0293&rsqb;</number> Of course, the present invention is in no way limited to the embodiment described hereinabove and shown in the drawings, many variations of or modifications to which will be evident to the person skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0294" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0294&rsqb;</number> In this regard, note that although the essential content of the various commands has been described in detail hereinabove, to facilitate interpreting them, and to make processing reliable, they can include various separators of different lengths, along with bits or digits for checksum or other type error checking functions. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An electronic label system, in particular for displaying prices in stores, the system comprising a central station and a plurality of distributed electronic labels, together with communication means, in particular wireless communication means, for sending information, in particular price information, from the central station to the labels, the system being characterized in that each label includes a set of price registers, a set of coefficient registers and a display including at least two price display areas, and the information sent from the central station to a label includes assignment instructions linking a calculated price equal to the price contained in one of the price registers multiplied by a given coefficient with a given price display area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the set of price registers comprises a main price register and one or more secondary price registers each adapted to contain a value equal to the main price multiplied by a coefficient contained in a coefficient register. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that it includes a main price display area and one or more secondary price display areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that it includes a plurality of secondary price registers and a plurality of secondary display areas, and the assignment instructions are adapted to make a choice from a predetermined set of assignments linking price registers and display areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the number of secondary display areas is less than the number of secondary price registers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A system according to any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">5</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that each price register is associated with a price attributes register and the contents of the two registers can be modified independently of each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A system according to any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">6</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the information sent from the central station to a label further includes price transfer messages for a particular price register. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that each price transfer instruction is also able to contain a calculation or display parameter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A system according to any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">8</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the information sent from the central station to a label further includes coefficient transfer messages for a particular coefficient register. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A system according to any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">9</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the information sent from the central station to a label further includes instructions for directly addressing segments of the price display areas forming characters in order to display information comprising alphanumeric and other signs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that each segment of a character is assigned a numerical value, the numerical values assigned to the various segments are such that there is a one-to-one relationship between a sum of said values and the values contributing to that sum and designating the segments to be displayed, and the instructions for directly addressing the segments include a respective sum associated with each character. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A system according to any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">11</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the information sent from the central station to a label further includes instructions for permutating the contents of two price registers or two coefficient registers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A system according to any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00012">12</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the information sent from the central station to a label further includes instructions for copying the content of a price or coefficient register to another price or coefficient register. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> or <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the permutation and copying instructions consist of a single instruction containing a command code, two register addresses and a parameter indicating permutation or copying. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An electronic label system, in particular for displaying prices in stores, comprising a central station and a plurality of distributed electronic labels, together with communication means, in particular wireless communication means, for sending information, in particular price information, from the central station to the labels, the system being characterized in that each label includes a memory, a display and means for controlling display on the basis of information contained in said memory, and the information sent from the central station to a label is contained in a single message, which message includes instructions containing data assigning the content of a particular memory area to a particular display area of the display and is adapted to contain time-delay data from which the label determines a timing parameter relating to said assignment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the display of each label comprises a plurality of price display areas, the memory of each label includes a plurality of price memory areas, and said instructions includes instructions for assigning a particular set of price memory areas to said display areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that said timing parameter is a duration for which the assignment must be applied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that said timing parameter is a delayed time from which the assignment must be applied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A system according to any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00015">claims 15</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00018">18</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that each label includes means for verifying the status of a power supply battery of the label and said particular memory area contains a battery status indicator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A system according to any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00015">claims 15</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00019">19</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that said particular memory area is an address area of the label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A system according to any preceding claim, characterized in that it includes means for selectively loading a long address or a short address into an address memory of an electronic label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the long address consists at least in part of the characters of a standardized product code of a product associated with the label and the short address consists at least in part of a particular portion of the characters of said product code and other characters.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001008A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001008A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001008A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001008A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
