<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002281A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002281A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002281A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002281A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002281A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002281A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002281A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002281A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002281A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002281A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002281A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002281A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002281A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002281A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002281A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002281A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002281</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10179377</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020626</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>P2001-194590</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>P2001-308256</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20011004</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F21V005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>362</class>
<subclass>245000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Shielded reflective light-emitting diode</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yoshinobu</given-name>
<family-name>Suehiro</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Nishikasugai-gun</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>PILLSBURY WINTHROP, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 10500</address-1>
<city>MCLEAN</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22102</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In a shielded reflective LED, each of light sources can be surface-mounted substantially without being influenced by heat distortion based on the difference in thermal expansion coefficient between resin and metal because the light source is so small-sized that only one light-emitting element is sealed with a resin. Moreover, variations in luminous intensity and chromaticity of each of light-emitting elements used in three-color light sources can be examined in advance. Hence, well-matched three-color light sources can be mounted in combination so that display unevenness of a full color display can be reduced greatly. Further, the surface of the substrate portion on which the light source is fixed is silk-screen-printed in black. Hence, external light which enters the device through the optical opening portion when the device is turned off is reflected by the reflecting mirror and absorbed to the surface of the substrate portion. As a result, pseudo-lighting in which external light is radiated out again through the optical opening portion can be prevented thoroughly, so that contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off can be made high. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present application is based on Japanese Patent Applications No. 2001-194590 and 2001-308256, which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a shielded reflective light-emitting diode (hereinafter also referred to as &ldquo;shielded reflective LED&rdquo;) having a light source including a light-emitting element, a reflecting mirror provided opposite to the light source, and a light-shielding member. Incidentally, in this specification, an LED chip itself is called a &ldquo;light-emitting element&rdquo;, a light-emitting substance including an optical device such as a package resin or a lens system in which an LED chip is mounted is called a &ldquo;light source&rdquo;, and a light-emitting device having a light source mounted therein is called a &ldquo;light-emitting diode&rdquo; or an &ldquo;LED&rdquo; as a whole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> As a light-emitting diode used in a full color display, there is known a light-emitting diode having three light-emitting elements which emit light in three primary colors R, G and B respectively and which are mounted on one lead frame and sealed with a resin. An example of this related-art polychromatic LED will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10A and 10B</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10A and 10B</cross-reference> are a plan view and a longitudinal sectional view showing the overall configuration of the related-art polychromatic LED. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10A and 10B</cross-reference>, in the polychromatic LED <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, a red light-emitting element <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>R, a green light-emitting element <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>G and a blue light-emitting element <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B are mounted on a bottom surface of a concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>which is formed on one lead <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Other three leads <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>B extended to the vicinity of the lead <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are bonded and electrically connected to the red light-emitting element <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>R, the green light-emitting element <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>G and the blue light-emitting element <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B by three wires <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>B respectively. The three light-emitting elements <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B, the concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, the three wires <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>B and part of the leads <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>B are sealed with a transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. At the same time, an ellipsoidal convex lens <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is molded of the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The major-diameter-direction length of the polychromatic LED <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is 7.5 mm. A plurality of this type polychromatic LEDs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are arranged at intervals of 10 mm pitch on a substrate to thereby form a full color display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> When such polychromatic LEDs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are to be mounted on a surface, however, the influence of heat distortion based on the difference in thermal expansion coefficient between the sealing resin and the metal of the lead portions at a high temperature near 200&deg; C. for surface mounting becomes larger because the length of each polychromatic LED <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in the direction of the major diameter thereof is large to be 7.5 mm. As a result, the probability that the wires <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>B will be broken increases, so that the percentage of defective products increases. Moreover, the respective light-emitting elements <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B vary in luminous intensity and chromaticity. For example, some green light-emitting elements <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>G emit bluish green light or yellowish green light. The yield is lowered as well as much labor is required for selecting light-emitting elements in advance and mounting the selected light-emitting elements, because classification by luminous intensity and classification by chromaticity must be combined with each other. Hence, it is impossible to combine well-matched light-emitting elements <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B in order to eliminate such variations in luminous intensity and chromaticity. As a result, display unevenness in color and brightness arises in the full color display. Moreover, because the respective light-emitting elements <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B vary in characteristic of luminous intensity distribution, color balance of each color varies in accordance with the viewing direction so that the resulting color may be recognized as a different color. In addition, because three kinds of light-emitting elements emitting light in three colors respectively are provided for one condenser lens, there is a problem that axial displacement occurs in light radiated from the polychromatic LED <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Next, a light-emitting diode (hereinafter abbreviated also to &ldquo;LED&rdquo;) called &ldquo;reflective LED&rdquo; is a kind of device. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, an example of the reflective LED will be described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing an example of the reflective LED. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the reflective LED <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is configured so that a light-emitting element <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is mounted on a forward end of one <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of a pair of leads <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>through which electric power is supplied to the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The light-emitting element <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the other lead <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are bonded and electrically connected to each other by a wire <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The light-emitting element <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the pair of leads <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the wire <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are sealed with a transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. At the same time, the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> forms a reflecting surface shaped like a paraboloid of revolution with the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> as its focal point so that the reflecting surface is disposed opposite to the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Aluminum vapor deposition is applied onto an outside of the reflecting surface so that a concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is formed on the outside of the reflecting surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> When light is emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the light is reflected by respective portions of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The reflected light advances upward in parallel with the center axis of the reflecting surface shaped like a paraboloid of revolution. Then, the light is radiated to the outside from a flat light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> which is an upper surface of the reflective LED <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the reflective LED <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is configured so that light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be radiated out as light condensed with high efficiency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The area of the reflecting surface of the reflective LED <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> viewed from the outside is, however, so large that dark noise (pseudo-lighting) due to reflection of external light occurs largely when the reflective LED <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is turned off. As a result, there arises a problem that contrast between light when the reflective LED <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is turned on and light when the reflective LED <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is turned off is low. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Therefore, an object of the invention is to provide a shielded reflective light-emitting diode which can be mounted on a surface and in which characteristics of luminous intensity distributions of light-emitting elements can be made uniform as well as display unevenness of a display can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Further, another object of the invention is to provide a shielded reflective device which is high in external radiation efficiency, high in contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off, and excellent in heat-radiating characteristic; and to provide a light source used for the shielded reflective device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> (1) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode having: at least one light source including at least one light-emitting element; a reflecting mirror provided opposite to the light source; and a light-shielding member for limiting external light incident on the reflecting mirror, wherein: the light-shielding member has an optical opening portion; and the reflecting mirror is shaped like a cylindrical surface in which light emitted from the light source and reflected by the reflecting mirror is condensed linearly so that the linearly condensed light is radiated out through the optical opening portion of the light-shielding member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Here, the &ldquo;optical opening portion&rdquo; may be a through-hole or a hole filled with a light-transmissive material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In the shielded reflective LED configured as described above, a small-sized light source having only one light-emitting element is used as the light source. Hence, the light source can be surface-mounted substantially without being influenced by heat distortion based on the difference in thermal expansion coefficient between resin and metal and accordingly with a very low defective rate even in the case where the light-emitting element is sealed with a resin. Moreover, variations in luminous intensity and chromaticity of each of light-emitting elements can be examined when light sources are produced. Hence, when a plurality of light sources are to be mounted in the shielded reflective LED, well-matched light sources can be used in combination after characteristic such as luminous intensity and chromaticity of each light-emitting element is examined. Accordingly, when the LED is applied to a display, display unevenness can be reduced greatly. In addition, when the way of mounting each light source is adjusted finely, variations in characteristics of luminous intensity distributions of the light-emitting elements can be cancelled by one another so that the characteristics of luminous intensity distributions of the light-emitting elements can be made uniform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode which can be surface-mounted and in which characteristics of luminous intensity distributions of light-emitting elements can be made uniform as well as display unevenness of a display can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> (2) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode with the configuration defined in (1), wherein the optical opening portion has a size and a shape equivalent to those of an area of light condensed by the reflecting mirror shaped like a cylindrical surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In this configuration, the optical opening portion has a size and a shape equivalent to those of an area of light condensed by the cylindrical reflecting mirror. Hence, while the light-shielding member can prevent external light from entering the LED, the efficiency in radiating light to the outside can be maximized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> (3) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode with the configuration defined in (1) or (2), wherein the light source further includes a concave reflecting mirror provided around the light-emitting element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In this configuration, light emitted from a light-emitting surface of the light-emitting element is not diffused horizontally but concentrated into an angle range of about 70 degrees with respect to the axis perpendicular to the light-emitting surface. Hence, the reflecting mirror provided opposite to the light source may be disposed suitably if the reflecting mirror can reflect light radiated in the angle range of about 70 degrees with respect to the axis perpendicular to the light-emitting surface. Accordingly, end portions of the reflecting mirror can be disposed so as to be far from the light source. The degree of freedom for designing the reflecting mirror is increased. Moreover, the reflecting mirror is shaped like a cylindrical surface. Hence, light applied to opposite end surfaces of the cylindrical surface is not reflected but absorbed. When the concave reflecting mirror is provided around the light-emitting element, however, light emitted from the light-emitting element can be prevented from being consumed wastefully because the opposite end surfaces of the cylindrical surface are not irradiated with light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode in which light emitted from the light-emitting element can be prevented from being consumed wastefully as well as the degree of freedom for arranging and designing the reflecting mirror can be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> (4) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode with the configuration defined in any one of (1) through (3), wherein the light source further includes a light-transmissive material with which the light-emitting element and the concave reflecting mirror are sealed and which forms a light-radiating surface on a light-emitting surface side of the light-emitting element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In the shielded reflective LED configured as described above, the light-emitting element is sealed with a light-transmissive material, so that the quantity of light emitted from the light-emitting element is increased to about twice compared with the case where the light-emitting element is not sealed. Hence, the luminous intensity of the light source, and, accordingly, the luminous intensity of the shielded reflective LED are increased greatly. Moreover, because the light-radiating surface is formed on the light-emitting surface side of the light-emitting element, light emitted from the light-emitting element is controlled so that the range of irradiation limited when the concave reflecting mirror is provided around the light-emitting element can be further limited. Hence, the degree of freedom for arranging and designing the reflecting mirror opposite to the light source can be increased more greatly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective LED in which the degree of freedom for arranging and designing the reflecting mirror can be increased more greatly as well as luminous intensity can be increased greatly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> (5) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode with the configuration defined in (4), wherein the light-radiating surface is constituted by a convex lens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In the shielded reflective LED configured as described above, the convex lens is formed on the light-emitting surface side of the light-emitting element. Hence, light emitted from the light-emitting element can be further condensed so that the range of irradiation can be narrowed more. Hence, end portions of the reflecting mirror provided opposite to the light source can be made farther from the light-emitting surface of the light-emitting element, so that the degree of freedom for designing the reflecting mirror can be further increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective LED in which the range of irradiation with light emitted from the light source can be further narrowed so that the degree of freedom for arranging and designing the reflecting mirror can be further increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> (6) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode with the configuration defined in (4) or (5), wherein the light-radiating surface is a curved cylindrical surface shaped so that a top portion of an ellipsoidal convex lens with a major diameter direction facing toward a direction substantially perpendicular to a lengthwise direction of the reflecting mirror shaped like a cylindrical surface is cut in the major diameter direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Hence, with respect to the direction of the major diameter of the ellipsoidal convex lens, all light emitted from the light-emitting element is radiated obliquely from the light-radiating surface, so that a portion of the reflecting mirror just under the light source is not irradiated with light. Hence, light radiated through the slit-like optical opening portion contains a large amount of light component advancing in the direction perpendicular to the optical opening portion. When the LED is applied to a display, the spreading angle of light in the vertical direction is narrowed so that light-radiating characteristic favorable to the display can be obtained. On the other hand, with respect to the lengthwise direction of the reflecting mirror, light emitted from the light-emitting element is radiated from the ellipsoidal light-radiating surface. Hence, light is diffused and reflected by the reflecting mirror, so that the reflected light is radiated all over the full length of the optical opening portion. Hence, when the LED is applied to a display, the spreading angle of light in the horizontal direction is widened so that light-radiating characteristic favorable to the display can be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode in which preferred light-radiating characteristic both in the vertical direction and in the horizontal direction can be obtained when the LED is applied to a display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> (7) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode with the configuration defined in any one of (1) through (6), wherein a plurality of light sources which are arranged along an axial direction of the reflecting mirror shaped like a cylindrical surface are used as the at least one light source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Because the plurality of light sources are arranged along the axial direction of the cylindrical reflecting mirror, there is no axial displacement among the plurality of light sources. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode in which a plurality of light sources can be mounted without causing any axial displacement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> (8) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode with the configuration defined in any one of (1) through (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>), wherein a plurality of light sources which emit light in different colors respectively are used as the at least one light source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In the shielded reflective LED configured as described above, a plurality of light sources for emitting light in a plurality of colors respectively are provided. Hence, the plurality of colors are mixed with one another, so that the light in the mixed color is radiated out. In this case, there is however a fear that color irregularity may occur because of the axial displacement and the difference in characteristic of luminous intensity distribution of the LED. When the plurality of light sources are arranged along the axial direction of the cylindrical reflecting mirror, the axial displacement can be prevented. Moreover, when the way of mounting each light source is adjusted finely, variations in characteristics of luminous intensity distributions of light-emitting elements can be cancelled with one another so that the characteristic of luminous intensity distribution of the LED can be made uniform. Hence, there is no color irregularity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode which has a plurality of light sources different in color and in which both axial displacement and color irregularity can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> (9) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode with the configuration defined in any one of (1) through (8), wherein a red light source having a red light-emitting element, a green light source having a green light-emitting element and a blue light source having a blue light-emitting element are used as the at least one light source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In the shielded reflective LED configured as described above, three light sources for emitting light in three primary colors respectively are provided. Hence, when electric power supplied to each of the light sources is changed, the resulting LED can be provided as a shielded reflective LED capable of emitting light in any color. When a plurality of such LEDs are disposed on a substrate, a full color display can be formed. Moreover, each of the light sources is a small-sized light source having only one light-emitting element. Hence, even in the case where the light-emitting element is sealed with a resin, the light source can be surface-mounted substantially without being influenced by heat distortion based on the difference in thermal expansion coefficient between resin and metal and with a very low defective rate. When light sources are produced in a state in which a light-emitting element in each of the light sources is sealed with a resin, variations in luminous intensity and chromaticity of each of the light-emitting elements used in the light sources can be easily examined and selected before the light sources are mounted. Hence, it is practically possible to mount well-matched light sources in combination after examination of the characteristics such as luminous intensity and chromaticity of three-color light-emitting elements. Display unevenness of a full color display can be reduced greatly. Moreover, when the way of mounting each of the light sources is adjusted finely, variations in characteristics of luminous intensity distributions of the light-emitting elements can be cancelled with one another so that the characteristic of luminous intensity distribution of the LED can be made uniform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective light-emitting diode which can be used for forming a full color display and can be surface-mounted and in which characteristics of luminous intensity distributions of light-emitting elements can be made uniform as well as display unevenness of the display can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> (10) Still further, according to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective device having: a light source portion including a light-emitting portion; a reflecting mirror provided opposite to a light-radiating side of the light source portion; and a douser (light-shielding member) including an optical opening portion, wherein: the shielded reflective device further has a substrate portion on which the light source portion is mounted; and a side of the substrate portion on which the light source portion is mounted is black. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Here, the &ldquo;optical opening portion&rdquo; means an opening portion through which light can pass. The optical opening portion may be a through-hole or a hole filled with a light-transmissive material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The shielded reflective device having this configuration further has a substrate portion on which the light source portion is mounted. A side of the substrate portion on which the light source portion is mounted is black. Hence, even in the case where external light enters the device through the optical opening portion when the device is turned off, the external light is reflected toward the light source portion-mounting side of the substrate portion by the reflecting mirror and absorbed to the substrate portion. That is, the external light never returns to the outside. Hence, pseudo-lighting is prevented thoroughly, so that contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off can be made high. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective device which is high in external radiation efficiency and high in contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> (11) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective device with the configuration defined in (10), further having a spacer which is provided for changing a height of the substrate portion and which is black. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Hence, the provision of the spacer makes the focal length long. There can be provided a shielded reflective device which has characteristic of luminous intensity distribution with a high degree of light condensation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> (12) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective device having: a light source portion including a light-emitting portion; a reflecting mirror provided opposite to a light-radiating side of the light source portion; and a douser including an optical opening portion, wherein the douser is shaped like a film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Strictly, because the light-emitting portion contained in the light source portion has a certain size, the condensed light has a certain degree of width in the vicinity of the focal point. For this reason, when the douser is a thick plate, external radiation efficiency cannot be made high if the width of the optical opening portion is not large. However, when the douser is shaped like a thin film, high external radiation efficiency can be obtained even in the case where the width of the optical opening portion is small. Accordingly, the width of the optical opening portion can be narrowed. As a result, entrance of external light can be suppressed to be minimized, so that contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off can be made high. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> (13) According to the invention, there is provided a light source having: a light-emitting element; a light-transmissive material with which the light-emitting element is sealed; and a substrate, wherein: a portion of the substrate on which the light-emitting element is mounted is made of a heat-dissipation conductive member; and the heat-dissipation conductive member reaches a rear surface of the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As described above, the light-emitting element is mounted on the heat-dissipation conductive member of the substrate and the heat-dissipation conductive member reaches the rear surface of the substrate. Hence, heat generated from the light-emitting element is transmitted to the rear side of the substrate through the heat-dissipation conductive member. Hence, heat generated from the light-emitting element can be radiated well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> (14) According to the invention, there is provided a light source with the configuration defined in (13), wherein the light-transmissive material forms a convex lens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Hence, light emitted from the light-emitting element is made incident on an interface of the light-transmissive material at an incident angle approximately perpendicular to the interface on the basis of the convex lens. Hence, when the light source is used as a light source for a shielded reflective device, light condensation property is improved so that external radiation efficiency is made high. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> (15) According to the invention, there is provided a light source with the configuration defined in (13) or (14), wherein the substrate is shaped so that four corners of the substrate are cut. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> As described above, the four corners of the substrate are cut. Hence, when the light source is used in a shielded reflective device, light reflected by the reflecting mirror is not blocked by the four corners and can be radiated out so as to be used effectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> (16) According to the invention, there is provided a light source with the configuration defined in (14), wherein (width of the substrate&minus;diameter of the convex lens) &lE;1 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The substrate type light source is superior to the lead type light source in that the width of the substrate can be reduced by the width of a protruded portion of the lead from side surfaces. Therefore, when the width of the protruded portion of the substrate from the diameter of the convex lens is suppressed to be not larger than 1 mm, the total size of the light source can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> (17) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective device using a light source defined in (16). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The light source as in (16) is configured so that the width of the protruded portion of the substrate from the diameter of the convex lens is suppressed to be not larger than 1 mm to thereby reduce the total size of the light source. When the light source is used in a shielded reflective device, the light source can be made to be approximated to a point source as well as space saving can be attained. Hence, external radiation efficiency can be made higher. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> (18) According to the invention, there is provided a shielded reflective device having a substrate portion on which a light source portion is mounted, wherein: a portion of the substrate portion on which the light source portion is mounted is made of a heat-dissipation conductive member; and the heat-dissipation conductive member reaches a rear surface of the substrate portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As described above, the light source portion is mounted on the heat-dissipation conductive member of the substrate portion. The heat-dissipation conductive member reaches the rear surface of the substrate portion. Hence, heat generated from the light source portion is transmitted to the rear surface of the substrate portion through the heat-dissipation conductive member. Hence, heat generated from the light source portion can be radiated well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The aforementioned all characteristics (1) to (18) can be combined into the possible extent to put the device or diode into practical use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Features and advantages of the invention will be evident from the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments described in conjunction with the attached drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In the accompanying drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the configuration of a shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to Embodiment 1 of the invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the Y direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the X direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the configuration of a light source used in the shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to Embodiment 1 of the invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the Y direction, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the X direction; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the configuration of a shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to Embodiment 2 of the invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the Y direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the X direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a front view showing the periphery of an optical opening portion in a shielded reflective device according to Embodiment 3 of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view showing the shielded reflective device according to Embodiment 3 of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the overall configuration of a light source according to Embodiment 3 of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view showing the overall configuration of the light source according to Embodiment 3 of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view showing a shielded reflective device according to Embodiment 4 of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing an example of a reflective LED; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the overall configuration of a related-art polychromatic LED, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view thereof.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the invention will be described below with reference to the drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Embodiment 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Referring first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>C and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>C, Embodiment 1 of the invention will be described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the configuration of a shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to Embodiment 1 of the invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the Y direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the X direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the configuration of a light source used in the shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to Embodiment 1 of the invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the Y direction. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the X direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, in the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 1, two slit-like optical opening portions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>extended in the X direction are formed in a light-shielding member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> which serves also as a mount substrate. LED light is radiated out through these optical opening portions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B, a</cross-reference> light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> having a light-emitting element is mounted on a rear surface of the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and between the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. As will be described later, the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is so small-sized that only one light-emitting element is sealed with a resin. Hence, the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be surface-mounted with a very low defective rate and substantially without being influenced by heat distortion based on the difference in thermal expansion coefficient between resin and metal even at a high temperature near 200&deg; C. required for surface mounting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> A reflecting substrate <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is disposed in a position opposite to the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and far from the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The reflecting substrate <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> has a concave surface of a polycarbonate resin, and a reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> formed on the concave surface by aluminum vapor deposition. A reflecting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is formed as a cylindrical surface in which a part of an ellipse with the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as its two focal points is extended in the lengthwise direction of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(X direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>). On the other hand, a reflecting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is formed as a cylindrical surface in which a part of an ellipse with the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as its two focal points is extended in the lengthwise direction of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Hence, all light emitted from the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflected by the reflecting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is condensed into the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and then radiated out through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Further, all light emitted from the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflected by the reflecting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is condensed into the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and then radiated out through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C, in the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 1, three light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B are mounted on the rear surface of the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> so as to be arranged side by side in the X direction. That is, a red light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, a green light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and a blue light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B for emitting light in three primary colors respectively are mounted densely in the X-direction center. Hence, when electric power supplied to each of the light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B is controlled, light in any color can be radiated from the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. That is, the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be applied to a full color display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> In each of the three-color light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B, a light-emitting element is sealed with a resin. Hence, variations in luminous intensity and chromaticity of light-emitting elements used for each of the three-color light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B can be easily examined and selected before mounting. Hence, it is practically possible to mount well-matched three-color light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B in combination, so that display unevenness of a full color display can be reduced greatly. Moreover, because the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> has cylindrical surfaces in which a part of an ellipse with the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as its two focal points is extended in the lengthwise direction of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, there is no axial displacement when such a plurality of light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B are arranged along the lengthwise direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Referring next to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>C, the configuration of the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> used in the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 1 will be described. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference>, the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a pair of leads <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>through which electric power is supplied to the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and a concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>formed at a forward end of one <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the leads. The light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is mounted on a bottom surface of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>by silver paste. After the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is bonded and electrically connected to the other lead <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>by a wire <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, the wire <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and part of the pair of leads <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are sealed with a transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> which serves as a light-transmissive material. At the same time, a light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed on the light-emitting surface side of the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Then, portions of the leads <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>protruded from the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are bent substantially perpendicularly along the side surfaces of the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and further bent substantially perpendicularly along the rear surface of the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Thus, the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is provided as a light source which can be surface-mounted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> In the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> configured as described above, the concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is provided around the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Hence, light emitted horizontally from the light-emitting surface of the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is also reflected by the concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, so that light can be radiated from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> while concentrated into an angle range of about 70 degrees with respect to the axis perpendicular to the light-emitting surface of the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Hence, the necessity that an end surface of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> must reach a position tangent to the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is eliminated. That is, the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> can be disposed so as to be far from the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and from the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Light applied to opposite end surfaces <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the cylindrical reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> may be absorbed without being reflected. In the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 1, however, the range of light applied to the concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is narrowed to an angle range of about 70 degrees with respect to the axis perpendicular to the light-emitting surface. Hence, light can be prevented from being applied to the opposite end surfaces <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. That is, light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be prevented from being consumed wastefully. Besides the cylindrical reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, reflecting mirrors may be disposed on the opposite end surfaces <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>perpendicular to the cylindrical surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, the light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is shaped so that a top portion of an ellipsoidal convex lens is cut in the direction of the major diameter of the ellipsoid by a curved cylindrical surface. As a result, the Y-direction component of light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and radiated from the light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is refracted obliquely. Hence, as shown in FIG. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>B, a portion of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> just under the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is little irradiated with light. That is, light radiated out through the slit-like optical opening portions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a large amount of Z-direction component. Hence, when the LED is applied to a display, the spreading angle of light in the vertical direction (Y direction) is narrowed so that light-radiating characteristic favorable to the display can be obtained. On the other hand, the X-direction component of light is spread and reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> because light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is radiated from the light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which is an elliptic surface. As a result, the reflected light is radiated all over the slit length of the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Hence, when the LED is applied to a display, the spreading angle of light in the horizontal direction (X direction) is widened so that light-radiating characteristic favorable to the display can be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Further, a large part of external light incident on the LED is absorbed to the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A very small part of the external light entering the LED through the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and then most of the light is absorbed. Hence, the amount of the external reflected light is slight. Hence, light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be radiated out effectively when the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is turned on. On the other hand, when the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is turned off, the problem of pseudo-lighting or dark noise which makes the LED whitish as a whole does not arise. The LED can be provided as a shielded reflective LED which is high in contrast between light at the time of turning-on and light at the time of turning-off. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Embodiment 2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>C, Embodiment 2 of the invention will be described below. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the configuration of a shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to Embodiment 2 of the invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the Y direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view taken along the X direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, in the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 2, four slit-like optical opening portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>extended in the X direction are formed in a light-shielding member <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> which serves also as a mount substrate. LED light is radiated out through these optical opening portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B, a</cross-reference> light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> having a light-emitting element is mounted on a rear surface of the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and between the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The configuration of the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is the same as that in Embodiment 1. The light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is so small-sized that only one light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is sealed with a transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Hence, the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be surface-mounted with a very low defective rate and substantially without being influenced by heat distortion based on the difference in thermal expansion coefficient between resin and metal even at a high temperature near 200&deg; C. required for surface mounting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> A reflecting substrate <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is disposed in a position opposite to the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and far from the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The reflecting substrate <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> has a concave surface of a polycarbonate resin, and a reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> formed on the concave surface by aluminum vapor deposition. A reflecting surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is formed as a cylindrical surface in which a part of an ellipse with the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as its two focal points is extended in the lengthwise direction of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(X direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>). Similarly, a reflecting surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is formed as a cylindrical surface in which a part of an ellipse with the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as its two focal points is extended in the lengthwise direction of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Similarly, a reflecting surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is formed as a cylindrical surface in which a part of an ellipse with the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>as its two focal points is extended in the lengthwise direction of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Similarly, a reflecting surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is formed as a cylindrical surface in which a part of an ellipse with the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>as its two focal points is extended in the lengthwise direction of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Hence, all light emitted from the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflected by the reflecting surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is condensed into the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and then radiated out through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Similarly, all light emitted from the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflected by the reflecting surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is condensed into the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and then radiated out through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Similarly, all light emitted from the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflected by the reflecting surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is condensed into the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and then radiated out through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Similarly, all light emitted from the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflected by the reflecting surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is condensed into the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and then radiated out through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Like Embodiment 1, the light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in this embodiment is shaped so that a top portion of an ellipsoidal convex lens is cut in the direction of the major diameter of the ellipsoid by a curved cylindrical surface. As a result, the Y-direction component of light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and radiated from the light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is refracted obliquely. Hence, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B, a</cross-reference> portion of the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> just under the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is little irradiated with light. That is, light radiated out through the slit-like optical opening portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>has a large amount of Z-direction component. Hence, when the LED is applied to a display, the spreading angle of light in the vertical direction (Y direction) is narrowed so that light-radiating characteristic favorable to the display can be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the X-direction component of light is spread and reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> because light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is radiated from the light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which is an elliptic surface, as described above for Embodiment 1. As a result, the reflected light is radiated all over the slit length of the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. Hence, when the LED is applied to a display, the spreading angle of light in the horizontal direction (X direction) is widened so that light-radiating characteristic favorable to the display can be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Further, a large part of external light incident on the LED is absorbed to the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A very small part of the external light entering the LED through the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and then most of the light is absorbed. Hence, the amount of the external reflected light is slight. Hence, light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be radiated out effectively when the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is turned on. On the other hand, when the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is turned off, the problem of pseudo-lighting or dark noise which makes the LED whitish as a whole does not arise. The LED can be provided as a shielded reflective LED which is high in contrast between light at the time of turning-on and light at the time of turning-off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>C, in the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 2, three light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B are mounted on the rear surface of the light-shielding member <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> so as to be arranged side by side in the X direction in the same manner as in Embodiment 1. That is, a red light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, a green light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and a blue light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B for emitting light in three primary colors respectively are mounted densely in the X-direction center. Hence, when electric power supplied to each of the light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B is controlled, light in any color can be radiated from the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. That is, the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can be applied to a full color display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> In each of the three-color light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B, a light-emitting element is sealed with a resin. Hence, variations in luminous intensity and chromaticity of light-emitting elements used for each of the three-color light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B can be easily examined and selected before mounting. Hence, it is practically possible to mount well-matched three-color light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B in combination, so that display unevenness of a full color display can be reduced greatly. Moreover, because the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> has cylindrical surfaces in which a part of an ellipse with the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and each of the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>as its two focal points is extended in the lengthwise direction of the optical opening portion, there is no axial displacement when such a plurality of light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B are arranged along the lengthwise direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Light applied to opposite end surfaces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the cylindrical reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> may be absorbed without being reflected. Also in the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 2, the range of light applied to the concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is narrowed to an angle range of about 70 degrees with respect to the axis perpendicular to the light-emitting surface. Hence, light can be prevented from being applied to the opposite end surfaces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. That is, light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be prevented from being consumed wastefully. Besides the cylindrical reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, reflecting mirrors may be disposed on the opposite end surfaces <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>perpendicular to the cylindrical surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>C, etc. in the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are sealed with the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> which serves as a light-transmissive material, the invention may be applied also to the case where they are not sealed with such a resin. Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where the light-radiating surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed by the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is shaped so that a top portion of an ellipsoidal convex lens is cut in the direction of the major diameter of the ellipsoid by a curved cylindrical surface, the invention maybe applied also to the case where the light-radiating surface is shaped variously, such as like a flat surface, a semi-spherical surface with the light-emitting element as its origin, or an elliptic surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where the concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is provided around the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the invention may be applied also to the case where the concave reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is not provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is used as a light-transmissive material which serves as a sealing material, any light-transmissive material such as a transparent silicone resin may be used if conditions such as fluidity and filling characteristic before curing and transparency and strength after curing can be satisfied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where each of the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is shaped like a slit, the optical opening portion need not be shaped like a slit, that is, any shape may be used if the shape is formed so that light condensed by the reflecting mirror can be transmitted through the optical opening portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where each of the optical opening portions <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is formed as a through-hole, the invention may be applied also to the case where the optical opening portion is formed as a hole filled with a light-transmissive material such as transparent epoxy resin or glass. Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where two or four slit-like optical opening portions are provided, the number of slit-like opening portions is not limited thereto, that is, one slit-like opening portion may be provided or three slit-like opening portions may be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where a mount substrate for surface-mounting the light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is provided with slit-like optical opening portions and serves as a light-shielding member, the invention may be applied also to the case where a light-shielding member is provided separately from a mount substrate in the condition that holes larger than the optical opening portions are formed in the mount substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Although the respective embodiments have been described upon the case where the red light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>R, the green light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>G and the blue light source <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B for emitting light in three primary colors respectively are mounted as light sources <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the colors of light emitted from the light sources are not limited to these three colors and the light sources need not emit light in such a plurality of colors. The number of light sources is not limited,that is, one light source may be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> The other configuration of the shielded reflective light-emitting diode as to the shape, the number of parts, the material, the size and the connecting relation thereof is not limited to the embodiments. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Embodiment 3 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 through 7</cross-reference>, a shielded reflective device (shielded reflective light-emitting diode) and a light source according to Embodiment 3 of the invention will be first described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a front view showing the periphery of an optical opening portion in the shielded reflective device according to Embodiment 3 of the invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view showing the shielded reflective device according to Embodiment 3 of the invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the overall configuration of the light source according to Embodiment 3 of the invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view showing the overall configuration of the light source according to Embodiment 1 of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which is the shielded reflective device according to Embodiment 3 of the invention has an optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> which is substantially circularly shaped and very narrow. Even in the case where the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is narrow as described above, high external radiation efficiency can be obtained. This is because the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is provided in a 0.1 mm-thick black PET film (douser) <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. The black PET film <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> has front and rear surfaces which are sandblasted so as to be matted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is a lens type LED having a light-emitting element sealed with a transparent epoxy resin. A concave reflecting surface, which is formed so that a part of an ellipsoid with the light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> as its two focal points is rotated around the center axis of the light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, is formed on a reflecting substrate <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> which is injection-molded of an acrylic resin. Aluminum vapor deposition is applied onto the reflecting surface to thereby form a reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Hence, all light emitted from the light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is radiated out through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Strictly, because the light-emitting element included in the light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has a certain size, the condensed light has a certain degree of width in the vicinity of the focal point. Hence, when the douser (light-shielding member) <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> is a thick plate, external radiation efficiency cannot be made high if the width of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is not large. In Embodiment 3, however, high external radiation efficiency can be obtained even in the case where the width of the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is narrow, because the douser <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> is a 0.1 mm-thick film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> The douser <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> is stuck onto a 0.6 mm-thick transparent glass plate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. A substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> made of a double-side through-hole glass epoxy substrate is fixed to a rear surface of the transparent glass plate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is mounted on a lower surface of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> through a substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> of a light source portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, the detailed configuration of the light source portion and the substrate portion will be described below. The substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> of the light source portion is made of a glass epoxy double-side through-hole substrate having four corners which are cut so that the cut four corners correspond to through-holes respectively. That is, because the substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> is shaped so that its four corners are cut, light reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> can be prevented from being blocked. A through-hole is also formed in the center portion of the substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> on which the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> will be mounted. A hollow portion of the through-hole is filled with metal powder <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and the through-hole is plated with the metal powder <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. If the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is mounted obliquely at the time of auto wire-bonding, the recognition rate is lowered. However, because the through-hole is filled with metal powder <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and plated with the metal powder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, sufficient flatness can be obtained so that there is no influence on the operating efficiency of auto wire-bonding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> The light-emitting element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is mounted on the plating and electrically connected by a wire <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> in the manner of auto wire-bonding. Thus, a lens <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>shaped like a semi-sphere with the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> as its origin is formed of a transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. According to this semi-spherical lens <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, light emitted from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is made perpendicularly incident on the transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> and then radiated out without being refracted. Hence, the apparent light-emitting area of the light source portion can be minimized. The light source portion <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and the substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> produced in this manner are further placed on the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. The substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> is made of a double-side through-hole substrate which is thicker than the substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and which is cut into a substantially cylindrical shape. The portion extended upward in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is equivalent to a connecting portion <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the douser <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. The through-hole of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> is located just under the portion filled with the metal powder <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, of the substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. The through-hole is filled with solder <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> so that the left side of the substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and the left side of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to each other by the solder <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and the right side of the substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and the right side of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to each other by the solder <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> while the left side and the right side as a whole are kept electrically insulated from each other. In this manner, the through-hole just under the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is filled with metal powder <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and the through-hole just under the first-mentioned through-hole is further filled with solder <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>. Hence, heat generated from the light-emitting element <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is transmitted through the metal powder <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and the solder <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> and radiated out. In this manner, the light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is provided as a light source excellent in heat-radiating characteristic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> The surface <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and cylindrical circumference of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>resilk-screen-printed in black. Hence, external light which enters the inside of the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> is reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. As a result, the reflected light strikes the surface <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> so as to be absorbed thereto. Hence, pseudo-lighting in which external light reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is radiated out again through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> when the device is turned off can be prevented thoroughly. The LED <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> can be provided as a shielded reflective LED which is high in contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which is high in external radiation efficiency, high in contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off, and excellent in heat-radiating characteristic; and there can be also provided a light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> for the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Embodiment 4 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8, a</cross-reference> shielded reflective LED according to Embodiment 4 of the invention will be described below. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a longitudinal sectional view showing the shielded reflective device according to Embodiment 4 of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> The point of difference of the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 4 from the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> according to Embodiment 3 is in that a first spacer <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and a second spacer <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> are put between the glass plate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the through-hole substrate (substrate portion) <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> and between the through-hole substrate <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> and the reflecting substrate <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> respectively. As a result, the focal length from the light source <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can be made so large that characteristic of luminous intensity distribution with high degree of light condensation can be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> The surface of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, the surface of the first spacer <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and the surface of the second spacer <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> are silk-screen-printed in black. Hence, external light which enters the inside of the shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The reflected light strikes the surfaces of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> and the first and second spacers <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> so as to be absorbed thereto. Hence, pseudo-lighting in which external light reflected by the reflecting mirror <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is radiated out again through the optical opening portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> when the device is turned off can be prevented thoroughly. The shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> can be provided as a shielded reflective LED which is high in contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> In this manner, there can be provided a shielded reflective LED <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> which is high in external radiation efficiency, high in contrast between light when the device is turned on and light when the device is turned off, and high in degree of light condensation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Although the embodiments have been described upon shielded reflective LEDs <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> as examples of shielded reflective devices each using an LED as a light source, the light source portion is not limited to such an LED. For example, the invention may be applied also to a shielded reflective device using any other light source such as an EL or the like as a light source. The LED light-emitting element is suitable for the shielded reflective device because the light-emitting area of the LED light-emitting element is so small that the width of light condensation at the light-condensing portion can be narrowed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> Although the embodiments have been described upon the case where the whole surface of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> is silk-screen-printed in black, the invention maybe applied also to the case where only the surface <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the substrate portion <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> on which the light source portion <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and the substrate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> are mounted is printed in black. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> Although the embodiments have been described upon the case where the substrate portion is made of a glass epoxy substrate, the invention may be applied also to the case where the substrate portion is made of any other material such as a ceramic substrate or made of a material like a metal stem. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> Although the embodiments have been described upon the case where a transparent epoxy resin <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> is used as a light-transmissive material, the invention is not limited thereto. For example, any other material such as a transparent silicone resin may be used as the light-transmissive material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> The other portions of the shielded reflective device and the light source as to the configuration, shape, number of parts, material, size and connection relation thereof are not limited to the embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Further, the aforementioned all characteristics in each embodiment separately explained can be combined into the possible extent. For example, the black substrate portion, space or heat-dissipation conductive member in the Embodiments 3 and 4 can be incorporated into the shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to the Embodiments 1 and 2. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> This invention is not limited to the above description of the mode for carrying out the invention and embodiments thereof at all, and includes various modifications that can be conceived by those skilled in the art without departing from the scope of the claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one light source including at least one light-emitting element; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflecting mirror provided opposite to said light source; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a light-shielding member for limiting external light incident on said reflecting mirror, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said light-shielding member has an optical opening portion, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said reflecting mirror is shaped like a cylindrical surface in which light emitted from said light source and reflected by said reflecting mirror is condensed linearly so that the linearly condensed light is radiated out through said optical opening portion of said light-shielding member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said optical opening portion has a size and a shape equivalent to those of an area of light condensed by said reflecting mirror shaped like a cylindrical surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said light source further includes a concave reflecting mirror provided around said light-emitting element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said light source further includes a light-transmissive material with which said light-emitting element and said concave reflecting mirror are sealed and which forms a light-radiating surface on a light-emitting surface side of said light-emitting element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said light-radiating surface is constituted by a convex lens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said light-radiating surface is a curved cylindrical surface shaped so that a top portion of an ellipsoidal convex lens with a major diameter direction facing toward a direction substantially perpendicular to a lengthwise direction of said reflecting mirror shaped like a cylindrical surface is cut in said major diameter direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plurality of light sources which are arranged along an axial direction of said reflecting mirror shaped like a cylindrical surface are used as said at least one light source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plurality of light sources which emit light in different colors respectively are used as said at least one light source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a red light source having a red light-emitting element, a green light source having a green light-emitting element and a blue light source having a blue light-emitting element are used as said at least one light source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a substrate portion for mounting said light source on said light-shielding member, and a side of said substrate portion on which said light source is mounted is black. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a spacer which is provided for changing a height of said substrate portion and which is black. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective light-emitting diode according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said light-shielding member is shaped like a film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective device comprising: 
<claim-text>a light source portion including a light-emitting portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflecting mirror provided opposite to a light-radiating side of said light source portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a douser including an optical opening portion, wherein said shielded reflective device further comprises a substrate portion on which said light source portion is mounted, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a side of said substrate portion on which said light source portion is mounted is black. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a spacer which is provided for changing a height of said substrate portion and which is black. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective device comprising: 
<claim-text>a light source portion including a light-emitting portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflecting mirror provided opposite to a light-radiating side of said light source portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a douser including an optical opening portion, wherein said douser is shaped like a film. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A light source comprising: 
<claim-text>a light-emitting element; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a light-transmissive material with which said light-emitting element is sealed; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a substrate, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a portion of said substrate on which said light-emitting element is mounted is made of a heat-dissipation conductive member, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said heat-dissipation conductive member reaches a rear surface of said substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A light source according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said light-transmissive material forms a convex lens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A light source according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said substrate is shaped so that four corners of said substrate are cut. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A light source according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein (width of said substrate&minus;diameter of said convex lens) &lE;1 mm is satisfied. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A shielded reflective device comprising: 
<claim-text>a light-emitting element; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a light-transmissive material with which said light-emitting element is sealed; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a substrate, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflecting mirror provided opposite to a light-radiating side of said light-emitting element; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a douser including an optical opening portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a portion of said substrate on which said light-emitting element is mounted is made of a heat-dissipation conductive member, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said heat-dissipation conductive member reaches a rear surface of said substrate, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said light-transmissive material forms a convex lens, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(width of said substrate&minus;diameter of said convex lens) &lE;1 mm is satisfied.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002281A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002281A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002281A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002281A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002281A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002281A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002281A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002281A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
