<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002815A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002815A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002815A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002815A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002815A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002815A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002815A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002815A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002815A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002815A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002815A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002815A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002815A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002815A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002815A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002815A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002815</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10164050</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020606</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-198111</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B006/36</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>078000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Optical fiber connector plug protecting cap</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kiyoshi</given-name>
<family-name>Tanaka</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chiba-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yuukou</given-name>
<family-name>Hata</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chiba-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ADAMS &amp; WILKS</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>31st Floor</address-1>
<address-2>50 Broadway</address-2>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap mounted to an optical fiber connector plug having an ferrule to which an optical fiber is insertion-mounted and a holding member for holding the ferrule, including a resin-made cap member fitted to a tip opening of the holding member and covering a tip portion of the ferrule in a non-contacting state, and a strap member consisting of an elastic body relatively having more flexibility than the cap member, wherein the cap member is provided with a lock hole for locking one end portion of the strap member in an insertion state and the one end portion of the strap member is provided with an engagement protrusion engaging with the lock hole in a state that the one end portion has been passed through the lock hole to thereby make it engageable, and wherein an end portion side from the engagement protrusion of the strap member becomes a pinching portion capable of being pinched in order that the engagement protrusion is locked to an outer edge portion of the lock hole. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap (hereafter, referred to as protecting cap) for protecting a ferrule end face of an optical fiber connector plug. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Hitherto, in case where an optical fiber is fixed to a ferrule attached to an optical fiber connector plug, the optical fiber is bonded/fixed to the optical fiber connector plug by pouring a thermosetting adhesive into the optical fiber connector plug, then inserting the optical fiber whose coating has been peeled over a certain length, and heating/hardening the adhesive by a heater. After the optical fiber has been bonded/fixed, the optical fiber connector plug is used by smoothly polishing a ferrule end face and an optical fiber end face to mirror finish. If the polished faces, of the ferrule and the optical fiber, having been subjected to the polish finish are injured, when the ferrules are oppositely connected each other, an opposed position accuracy is deteriorated, so that a loss becomes large. Therefore, for the purpose of protecting the ferrule end face and the optical fiber end face after the polish finish, there has been known a protecting cap fitting to a tip portion of the optical fiber connector plug and formed by rubber, plastic and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> As such a protecting cap, there has been proposed a cap <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with strap for an FC type optical fiber connector as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference>. Incidentally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the cap with strap according to the prior art, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> a plan view of the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In the cap <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with strap, a cap portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and a strap portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are integrally molded. The cap portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> has an engagement hole <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> engaging with an outer periphery of a plug housing of the FC type optical fiber connector (not shown). The engagement hole <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> has a shape in which its diameter gradually decreases toward a tip of the cap portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. And, the cap portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is mounted so as to cover the ferrule protruding from a tip of the plug housing. Further, in the strap portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> molded integrally with the cap portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, at its tip portion in a side opposite to the cap portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> there is provided a passage hole <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> for the purpose of being mounted to an optical fiber cord of the FC type optical fiber connector, so that it is adapted such that the cap portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> itself is not disconnected from the optical fiber cord. As a material for the cap <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with strap, polyvinyl chloride and rubber have been used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> However, with the conventional protecting cap, since the cap portion and the strap portion are integrally molded, the cap portion where a comparatively high hardness is demanded and the strap portion where a flexibility in some extent is demanded become the same material, so that there has been a problem that characteristics of any one of the cap portion and the strap portion are sacrificed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Further, since the cap with strap is integrally molded in a state having the strap, there is a problem that the number of products obtained in a mold cannot be increased. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In view of such circumstances, according to the invention, there is provided an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap whose manufacturing time can be remarkably shortened, whose manufacturing cost can be reduced, and in which an optimum material can be selected for both of the cap portion and the strap portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A 1st mode of the invention solving the problem is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap mounted to an optical fiber connector plug comprising an ferrule to which an optical fiber is insertion-mounted and a holding member for holding the ferrule, characterized in that it comprises a resin-made cap member fitted to a tip opening of the holding member and covering a tip portion of the ferrule in a non-contacting state, and a strap member consisting of an elastic body relatively having more flexibility than the cap member, that the cap member is provided with a lock hole for locking one end portion of the strap member in an insertion state and the one end portion of the strap member is provided with an engagement protrusion engaging with the lock hole in a state that the one end portion has been passed through the lock hole to thereby make it engageable, and that an end portion side from the engagement protrusion of the strap member becomes a pinching portion capable of being pinched in order that the engagement protrusion is locked to an outer edge portion of the lock hole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A 2nd mode of the invention is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap characterized in that, in the 1st mode, the other end portion of the strap member is provided with a passage hole for passing the optical fiber coated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A 3rd mode of the invention is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap characterized in that, in the 1st or 2nd mode, at a side opposite to the end portion side of the engagement protrusion of the strap member there is provided a butting portion which butts against the outer edge portion of the lock hole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A 4th mode of the invention is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap characterized in that, in any of the 1st-3rd modes, the lock hole is provided in an end portion of the cap member at a side opposite to an insertion side of the ferrule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A 5th mode of the invention is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap characterized in that, in the 4th mode, the lock hole is formed in a protrusion portion whose cross-section is smaller than that of the cap member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A 6th mode of the invention is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap characterized in that, in any of the 1st-5th modes, at least one surface of the pinching portion is provided with a slip prevention portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A 7th mode of the invention is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap characterized in that, in any of the 1st-6th modes, a thin-walled portion is provided between the pinching portion and the engagement protrusion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> An 8th mode of the invention is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap characterized in that, in any of the 1st-7th modes, the strap member consists of elastomer or rubber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A 9th mode of the invention is an optical fiber connector plug protecting cap characterized in that, in any of the 1st-8th modes, the optical fiber connector plug is any of an FC type, an SC type, an LC type and an MU type. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In the invention, since the protecting cap is divided into the cap member and the strap member, an optimum material can be used for each of the cap member and the strap member. Further, it can be use only as the cap member.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view of an optical fiber connector plug to which a protecting cap according to an embodiment 1 of the invention is mounted; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a main portion enlarged view of the same; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a side view of the protecting cap according to the embodiment 1 of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a plan view of the same; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a plan view of a cap member according to the embodiment 1 of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the same; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a side view of a strap member according to the embodiment 1 of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is a plan view of the same; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a main portion enlarged side view of the strap member according to the embodiment 1 of the invention, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is a main portion enlarged plan view of the same; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference> is another main portion enlarged plan view of the same; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> is a main portion enlarged side view of the strap member according to other embodiment of the invention, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> is a main portion enlarged plan view of the same; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a cap with strap according to the prior art; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> is a plan view of the same.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Hereunder, the invention is detailedly described on the basis of embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> First, it is explained about a structure of an optical fiber connector plug to which a protecting cap of the invention is mounted. Incidentally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view of an optical fiber connector plug to which the protecting cap of the invention is mounted, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> a main portion enlarged view of the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> (Embodiment 1) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, an optical fiber connector plug is an SC type optical fiber connector plug <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The SC type optical fiber connector plug <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises an SC type plug housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> fitted to an SC type optical connector adapter (not shown), and an SC type plug frame <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> fitted into the SC type plug housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. And, although detailedly mentioned later, a protecting cap <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the invention is fitted to a tip opening of the SC type optical fiber connector plug <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B, within the SC type plug frame <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> there are held a ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> consisting of a collar member <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and a ferrule cylindrical body <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> for holding an optical fiber, and a compression spring <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> held on an outer periphery of a rear end portion of the collar member <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Such an SC type plug frame assembly is assembled by inserting in order the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in which the optical fiber is held in the SC type plug frame <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and the compression spring <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. And, after the assembly, the SC type plug frame <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> penetrating through in a longitudinal direction. The ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> protrudes in the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the SC type optical fiber connector plug <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is obtained by inserting this SC type plug frame assembly into the SC type plug housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> And, the protecting cap <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is fitted into the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the SC type optical fiber connector plug <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>,thereby protecting a tip of the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in a non-contacting state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Hereunder, it is detailedly explained about the protecting cap <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> fitted to the SC type optical fiber connector plug <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Incidentally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a side view of the protecting cap according to this embodiment, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> a plan view of the same. Further, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a plan view of the cap member according to this embodiment, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> a sectional view of the same. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a side view of a strap member according to this embodiment, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> a plan view of the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, the protecting cap <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of this embodiment is composed of a resin-made cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> fitted to the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the SC type plug frame <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and covering the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the non-contacting state, and of a strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> which consists of an elastic body relatively having more flexibility than the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and which is locked to the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in a state that its tip is protruded by a predetermined amount. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>B, the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is provided with an engagement hole <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> covering, in the non-contacting state, the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> which has an outer diameter fitting into the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> that is a tip opening of the SC type optical fiber connector plug <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and which, in a state that it is fitted in the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, protrudes into the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The engagement hole <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> has an inner diameter larger than the outer diameter of the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in order that, in a state that the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is fitted into the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, it is held in a state non-contacting with the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, and it has a sufficient depth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Further, an outer peripheral face of the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> becomes a taper portion <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> for fitting the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> into the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> at a constant position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The taper portion <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is provided on an outer peripheral face of the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> contacting with an opening edge portion of the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> such that its outer diameter gradually increases toward a direction opposite to a side, of the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, at which the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is inserted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In this manner, since the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is fitted inside the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> in a state not contacting with the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> can be surely protected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Further, the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> has, at its side opposite to a side at which it is fitted inside the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, a convex portion <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> whose cross-section is smaller than that of the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The convex portion <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is provided with a lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> penetrating in a direction approximately perpendicular to a direction along which the ferrule <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> engages inside the engagement hole <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> of the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> has an approximately rectangular sectional shape through which a tip portion of a strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> can be inserted. Further, although detailedly mentioned later, the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is one for locking the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Further, an end portion at an engagement hole <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> side of the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is beveled at a predetermined angle. By this, the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> can be easily fitted into the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Of course, it is needless to say that the beveling is not made as occasion demands. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As to a material used for the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, it is not limited especially so long as it is a thermoplastic or thermosetting resin material capable of being manufactured by injection molding, and polyamide, polypropylene can be enumerated for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Further, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> locked to the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is a fine band-like long shape having a predetermined thickness, has an insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> capable of being inserted through the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> at its tip portion side, and has a passage portion <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> for passing the optical fiber cord at its base end portion side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>B, the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is provided with an engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> protruding in a thickness direction of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Incidentally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a main portion enlarged side view of the strap member according to this embodiment, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> a main portion enlarged plan view of the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is provided at a predetermined position from a tip of the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, and has a slant portion <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> having a slant face whose thickness gradually increases from the tip portion of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> toward the base end portion side and which has a predetermined angle, and a vertical portion <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> having a face approximately perpendicular to a thickness direction of the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> has a shape inserted into the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, and is one functioning such that the vertical portion <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> butts against an outer edge portion of the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> in an inserted state, so that the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is made difficult to be drawn out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Further, a tip portion side of the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> from the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> becomes a pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is one for pulling the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> by pinching its tip when the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is inserted through the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is passed through the engagement hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. That is, by pulling the pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in a direction along which the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> comes out from the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> can be easily passed through the engagement hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Additionally, at a base end portion side from the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> of the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, there is provided a butting portion <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> having a butting face <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> mutually opposing to the vertical portion <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> of the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> with a predetermined spacing. The butting portion <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> butts against an outer end portion of the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> by passing the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> through the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and pulling the pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, thereby regulating an excessive insertion of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. By this, after the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> has been passed by pulling the pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the butting face <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> butts against the outer end portion of the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, so that the tip of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is prevented from being excessively pulled out from the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In this manner, by providing the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> and the butting portion <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, it becomes possible to simply pass the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> through the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, and the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> can be comparatively easily locked to the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>C, the passage portion <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> at the base end portion side of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has a shape protruding to both sides in a width direction. The passage portion <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> has a passage hole <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> penetrating in a thickness direction of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The passage hole <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is an elongated hole extending along a longitudinal direction of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> After the optical fiber cord has been passed through the passage hole <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> at a side opposite to the passage portion <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is locked to the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. By this, even if the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> fitted to the ferrule insertion hole <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is separated, the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> can be prevented from being lost because the optical fiber cord has been passed through the passage hole <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> As to a material of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, it is not limited especially so long as it is a material comparatively flexible in comparison with the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and capable of being injection-molded, and rubber, thermoplastic elastomer can be enumerated for instance. Among these, it is preferable to use polyurethane, amide-based elastomer and the like, which are excellent in flexibility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> (Other Embodiments) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> In the above, the embodiment 1 of the invention has been described, but the protecting cap is not limited to one mentioned above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment 1 mentioned above, the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is provided so as to protrude in the thickness direction of the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, but it is not limited to this especially, and it may be provided so as to protrude to both sides in a width direction of the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Further, also the butting portion <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> may be provided so as to similarly protrude to both sides in the width direction of the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Further, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>B, the pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> passed through the engagement hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> by pulling the tip of the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> may be provided with a slip prevention portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> on at least one surface of the pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Incidentally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> is a main portion enlarged side view of the strap member according to this other embodiment, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> a main portion enlarged plan view of the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The slip prevention portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is formed by being made into a concave/convex form such as a striped pattern simultaneously with when the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is formed by the injection molding. Incidentally, the slip prevention portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> may be formed by a blast working for instance after the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has been injection-molded. In this manner, by providing the slip prevention portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> in the pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, a slip occurring when passing the insertion portion <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> provided with the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> through the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Additionally, in order to cut out the pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> protruding from the cap member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> after the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has been locked to the lock hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, a thin-walled portion where a thickness of the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has been reduced be provided between the pinching portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and the engagement protrusion <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. In this manner, by providing the thin-walled protion <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> in the chipping portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>,the excess chipping portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> can be easily cut out, so that a beautiful spectacle can be improved. Of course, it is needless to say that, even in case where there is no thin-walled portion <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>, the strap member <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> may be used with the chipping portion <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> being cut. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Additionally, in the embodiment 1 mentioned above there has been exemplified and described the SC type optical fiber connector plug <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as the optical fiber connector plug to which the protecting cap <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is mounted, but it is not limited to this especially. The protecting cap <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the invention may be mounted to such an optical fiber connector plug as FC type, LC type and MU type for instance. Incidentally, the LC type optical fiber connector plug is a type in which the ferrule is directly mounted to the plug housing without using the plug frame. Therefore, in this case, the protecting cap can protect the end face of the ferrule by the fact that it fits to a tip opening portion of the plug housing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, since the protecting cap is divided into the cap member and the strap member, an optimum material can be selected in compliance with a used mode of each of them. That is, since the cap member protects the end face of the ferrule in the non-contacting state, a comparatively hard material can be selected for it. Further, since the strap member is elastically deformed, a comparatively flexible material allowing an elastic deformation can be selected for it. Additionally, since each of them can be formed by the injection molding, a manufacturing time can be shortened and a manufacturing cost can be reduced. Of course, as to the protecting cap of the invention, it is possible to use only the cap member in compliance with a use. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap mounted to an optical fiber connector plug having an ferrule to which an optical fiber is insertion-mounted and a holding member for holding the ferrule, 
<claim-text>comprising a resin-made cap member fitted to a tip opening of the holding member and covering a tip portion of the ferrule in a non-contacting state, and a strap member consisting of an elastic body relatively having more flexibility than the cap member, wherein the cap member is provided with a lock hole for locking one end portion of the strap member in an insertion state and the one end portion of the strap member is provided with an engagement protrusion engaging with the lock hole in a state that the one end portion has been passed through the lock hole to thereby make it engageable, and wherein an end portion side from the engagement protrusion of the strap member becomes a pinching portion capable of being pinched in order that the engagement protrusion is locked to an outer edge portion of the lock hole. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the other end portion of the strap member is provided with a passage hole for passing the optical fiber coated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at a side opposite to the end portion side of the engagement protrusion of the strap member there is provided a butting portion which butts against the outer edge portion of the lock hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lock hole is provided in an end portion of the cap member at a side opposite to an insertion side of the ferrule. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lock hole is formed in a protrusion portion whose cross-section is smaller than that of the cap member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one surface of the pinching portion is provided with a slip prevention portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a thin-walled portion is provided between the pinching portion and the engagement protrusion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the strap member consists of elastomer or rubber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An optical fiber connector plug protecting cap set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical fiber connector plug is any of an FC type, an SC type, an LC type and an MU type.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002815A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002815A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002815A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002815A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002815A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002815A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002815A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002815A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
