<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002193A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002193A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002193A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002193A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002193A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002193A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002193A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002193A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002193A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002193A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002193</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10150662</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020517</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11B005/03</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>360</class>
<subclass>066000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method of providing a programmable voltage bias during multi channel servo mode</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301997</doc-number>
<document-date>20010628</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Echere</given-name>
<family-name>Iroaga</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Scarborough</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TEXAS INSTRUMENTS INCORPORATED</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P O BOX 655474, M/S 3999</address-1>
<city>DALLAS</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75265</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A circuit to voltage bias a first head to access a disk includes a circuit to bias the head with said voltage, a feedback circuit to measure the voltage and generate a feedback signal to correct deviations in the voltage, and a switch circuit to switch the feedback circuit to a serial head while maintaining the feedback head or said first head. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to disk circuits and more particularly to a method and apparatus for reading information and writing information to and from a magnetic disk. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> When a head is voltage biased, this voltage bias requires a feedback loop to assure that the correct voltage bias is applied to the head to avoid too high a voltage being applied to the head. One method of achieving the voltage bias is by biasing the head with a current across a resistor and then using a feedback loop to measure the voltage drop across the resistor and correspondingly adjusting the current. However, during multi channel servo operation, multiple heads are selected that vary in resistance value. With MR heads, the resistor across the head is designed by R<highlight><subscript>MR</subscript></highlight>. Associated with the MR head is a separate write head. If one head has a particularly low resistance R<highlight><subscript>MR</subscript></highlight>, this low resistance would cause the feedback loop to increase the bias current and stress the other heads having a higher resistance R<highlight><subscript>MR</subscript></highlight>. Consequently, it is necessary to control the feedback loop during multi channel servo operation to provide an accurate feedback. With the prior art, the feedback circuit is connected to all the heads in parallel so that each head receives the same feedback. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In a multi head environment, not all the head locations have a physical head mounted. In such case, if a head is mounted, such a head is called a populated head, and the missing head locations are called a unpopulated head. A typical servo sequence is as follows, the disk drive is operating in read mode on a selected populated head. This populated head has been selected by the select decode circuit. A switch to servo read mode is desired. All fault circuits such as reader open circuits and short fault circuits are disabled. The select decode circuit is still enabled to select a single channel read head. The serial port select code which is connected to the select decode circuit is switched to prepare for servo write. The serial port is set to the appropriate value for multi-head select decode to prepare for a multi channel operation. The disk system is switched into servo write mode. The select channel decode circuit is enabled, and multiple heads are selected. Write mode is enabled. To switch back to servo read for single channel, the select decode circuit is enabled for single channel operation. The serial port select bits are switched to select the required single channel head. The circuit is switched out of servo read mode. As discussed above, unpopulated head positions are open heads which introduce large amounts of error to the feedback. It is further possible that the decoder circuit can obtain an invalid single code address from the fact that the head is not populated. Consequently, the feedback is incorrect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> It is known to include servo information on some of the tracks and to provide servo transducer heads for reading such information to enable control of the lateral position of the head assembly thereby dynamically maintaining the respective transducer elements of the head assembly relative to the tracks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In the embedded servo type system, servo information or servo bursts are recorded on data tracks which also contains stored data. The servo bursts are typically temporarily spaced evenly about the circumference of each data track. Data is recorded on a data track between the servo bursts. In an dedicated servo type systems, the entire disk service in a disk drive is dedicated to storing the servo information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As the data head reads the servo information, the transducer provides a position signal which is decoded by the position modulator and is presented in digital form to a servo control processor. The servo control processor essentially compares actual radial position of the transducer over the disk (as indicated by the embedded servo burst) with a desired position and commands this actuator to move in order to minimize position error. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The servo information is written on the disk surfaces during manufacturer of the disk drive module. Each disk module is mounted to a servo writer support assembly which properly locates the disk surfaces relative to the reference or origin. The servo writer support assembly supports a position sensor such as a laser light interferometer meter which detects the position to the actuator relative to the disk surfaces. The position sensor is electronically inserted within the disk drives negative feedback, closed loop servo system for providing position information to the servo system while the servo data was being written to the disk surfaces. The servo writer support position assembly may also support a clock writer transducer which writes a clock pattern onto disk surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a circuit that controls the head selection as well as the feedback circuit with a common signal. The heads selection determines the feedback. It is impossible to separate the head from the feedback. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> With the present invention, the feedback for the read head is always based upon a selected read head, and for example, head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> could be chosen as feedback head even though another head is actually selected manufacturers. Consequently an accurate value of the feedback can be obtained. However, R<highlight><subscript>MR </subscript></highlight>value can vary between 30 ohms to 150 ohms. The present invention may use the lowest R<highlight><subscript>MR </subscript></highlight>value for feedback. Thus, the present invention protects all the heads from feedback values which are inaccurate. Additionally, the present invention provides for a serial port control of the feedback so that the head with the lowest resistance or any other head can be select for feedback. Thus, with the present invention under multi channel mode, the feedback is based upon a single head which has been pre-selected.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a voltage bias circuit and feedback circuit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a bias circuit and feedback circuit of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a signal diagram of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a side view of a disk drive system; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a top view of a disk drive system. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The following invention is described with reference to figures in which similar or the same numbers represent the same or similar elements. While the invention is described in terms for achieving the invention&apos;s objectives, it can be appreciated by those skilled in the art that variations may be accomplished in view of these teachings without deviation from the spirit or scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> show a side and top view, respectively, of the disk drive system designated by the general reference <highlight><bold>1100</bold></highlight> within an enclosure <highlight><bold>1110</bold></highlight>. The disk drive system <highlight><bold>1100</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of stacked magnetic recording disks <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight> mounted to a spindle <highlight><bold>1114</bold></highlight>. The disks <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight> may be conventional particulate or thin film recording disk or, in other embodiments, they may be liquid-bearing disks. The spindle <highlight><bold>1114</bold></highlight> is attached to a spindle motor <highlight><bold>1116</bold></highlight> which rotates the spindle <highlight><bold>1114</bold></highlight> and disks <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight>. A chassis <highlight><bold>1120</bold></highlight> is connected to the enclosure <highlight><bold>1110</bold></highlight>, providing stable mechanical support for the disk drive system. The spindle motor <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and the actuator shaft <highlight><bold>1130</bold></highlight> are attached to the chassis <highlight><bold>1120</bold></highlight>. A hub assembly <highlight><bold>1132</bold></highlight> rotates about the actuator shaft <highlight><bold>1130</bold></highlight> and supports a plurality of actuator arms <highlight><bold>1134</bold></highlight>. The stack of actuator arms <highlight><bold>1134</bold></highlight> is sometimes referred to as a &ldquo;comb.&rdquo; A rotary voice coil motor <highlight><bold>1140</bold></highlight> is attached to chassis <highlight><bold>1120</bold></highlight> and to a rear portion of the actuator arms <highlight><bold>1134</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A plurality of head suspension assemblies <highlight><bold>1150</bold></highlight> are attached to the actuator arms <highlight><bold>1134</bold></highlight>. A plurality of inductive transducer heads <highlight><bold>1152</bold></highlight> are attached respectively to the suspension assemblies <highlight><bold>1150</bold></highlight>, each head <highlight><bold>1152</bold></highlight> including at least one inductive write element. In addition thereto, each head <highlight><bold>1152</bold></highlight> may also include an inductive read element or a MR (magneto-resistive) read element. The heads <highlight><bold>1152</bold></highlight> are positioned proximate to the disks <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight> by the suspension assemblies <highlight><bold>1150</bold></highlight> so that during operation, the heads are in electromagnetic communication with the disks <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight>. The rotary voice coil motor <highlight><bold>1140</bold></highlight> rotates the actuator arms <highlight><bold>1134</bold></highlight> about the actuator shaft <highlight><bold>1130</bold></highlight> in order to move the head suspension assemblies <highlight><bold>1150</bold></highlight> to the desired radial position on disks <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A controller unit <highlight><bold>1160</bold></highlight> provides overall control to the disk drive system <highlight><bold>1100</bold></highlight>, including rotation control of the disks <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight> and position control of the heads <highlight><bold>1152</bold></highlight>. The controller unit <highlight><bold>1160</bold></highlight> typically includes (not shown) a central processing unit (CPU), a memory unit and other digital circuitry, although it should be apparent that these aspects could also be enabled as hardware logic by one skilled in the computer arts. Controller unit <highlight><bold>1160</bold></highlight> is connected to the actuator control/drive unit <highlight><bold>1166</bold></highlight> which is in turn connected to the rotary voice coil motor <highlight><bold>1140</bold></highlight>. A host system <highlight><bold>1180</bold></highlight>, typically a computer system or personal computer (PC), is connected to the controller unit <highlight><bold>1160</bold></highlight>. The host system <highlight><bold>1180</bold></highlight> may send digital data to the controller unit <highlight><bold>1160</bold></highlight> to be stored on the disks, or it may request that digital data at a specified location be read from the disks <highlight><bold>1112</bold></highlight> and sent back to the host system <highlight><bold>1180</bold></highlight>. A read/write channel <highlight><bold>1190</bold></highlight> is coupled to receive and condition read and write signals generated by the controller unit <highlight><bold>1160</bold></highlight> and communicate them to an arm electronics (AE) unit shown generally at <highlight><bold>1192</bold></highlight> through a cut-away portion of the voice coil motor <highlight><bold>1140</bold></highlight>. The AE unit <highlight><bold>1192</bold></highlight> includes a printed circuit board <highlight><bold>1193</bold></highlight>, or a flexible carrier, mounted on the actuator arms <highlight><bold>1134</bold></highlight> or in close proximity thereto, and an AE module <highlight><bold>1194</bold></highlight> mounted on the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>1193</bold></highlight> or carrier that comprises circuitry preferably implemented in an integrated circuit (IC) chip including read drivers, write drivers, and associated control circuitry. The AE module <highlight><bold>1194</bold></highlight> is coupled via connections in the printed circuit board to the read/write channel <highlight><bold>1190</bold></highlight> and also to each read head and each write head in the plurality of heads <highlight><bold>1152</bold></highlight>. The AE module <highlight><bold>1194</bold></highlight> includes the head circuit of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a circuit to bias the head of the present invention. Circuit <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is a head voltage bias circuit for head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. Head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> being represented by resistor <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>, R<highlight><subscript>MR</subscript></highlight>. It is to be understood that although a magnetic resistive head is illustrated; a write head is also intended to be illustrated by resistor <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. Additionally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a head voltage bias circuit <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> for head <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which is similar to head bias circuit <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> except a different head (heads) is bias. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a feedback circuit <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> to provide feedback to the head voltage bias circuit <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Additionally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a head decoder circuit <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> and feedback decoder circuit <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. The head bias circuit <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> includes a switch, for example a FET <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, a transistor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> having a base connected to the drain of FET <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The collector of transistor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is connected to voltage V<highlight><subscript>CC </subscript></highlight>while the emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is connected to the read write head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> having resistance R<highlight><subscript>MR</subscript></highlight>. The head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> illustrated by a resistor having the resistance of the R<highlight><subscript>MR </subscript></highlight>head has another end connected to the emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. The collector of transistor <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> is connected to voltage V<highlight><subscript>CC </subscript></highlight>while the base of transistor <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> is connected to the collector of transistor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>. The FET <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> acts as a switch to select this head based upon a signal from the head select decode circuit <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. The emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is additionally connected to the base of transistor <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>. The collector of transistor <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> is connected to voltage V<highlight><subscript>CC </subscript></highlight>while the emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> is connected to FET <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> or switch <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and additionally connected to a current source <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>. The other end of read/write head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> is connected to the base of transistor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The collector of transistor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is connected to voltage V<highlight><subscript>CC </subscript></highlight>while the emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is connected to the current source <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is connected to the source of FET <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. The FETs <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> act as switches to selectly disconnect and connect the feedback circuit <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> from controlling the voltage of the read/write head for example, here, head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. The gate of FET <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and FET <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> are connected together and connected to the feedback decoder circuit <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. The feedback decoder circuit <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> selectly activates these switches <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> to engage the feedback circuit for this head. Transistor <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> operates as a switch that connects the linear amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> with the head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> or switch <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> performs the same function as transistor <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> to connect the feedback linear amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> with the head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. The FET <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> acts as a head switch to control which head is being bias. Transistor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> supply a bias voltage to head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> to supply voltage across the head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> provides a path for bias current through the head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. The feedback circuit <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> includes a feedback linear amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>. In addition, a DAC circuit which is digital to analog converter <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> provides current through transistor to <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> from the collector of transistor <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> to the emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>, which is connected to ground. The base of transistor <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> is connected to the collector of transistor <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> to form a current mirror with transistor <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight>. The DAC circuit <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> supplies a current to the transistor <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> and this current is mirrored to the first current path I<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>through to the collector and emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> and second current path I<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>through collector and emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight>. The base of transistor <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> is connected to the base of transistor <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>, and the base of transistor <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> is connected to the base of transistor <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. The emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> is connected to ground and the emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> is connected to ground. The collector of transistor <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> is connected between the feedback linear amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and the resistor <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>. The collector of transistor <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> is connected between the resistor <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and the FET <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>. The DAC circuit <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> controls the current flowing in a transistor <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight>. Correspondingly, the current flowing in transistor <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> control the differential voltage drop across resistors <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>. As the current increases in transistor <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight>, the voltage drop between transistor <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> is reduced. Thus, the difference in voltage between transistor <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> are correspondingly reduced. Since the output of feedback linear amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> depends on the difference in voltage at its inputs, the output of linear feedback circuit <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> is correspondingly reduced. The resistor <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> is connected to one input of the feedback linear amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and the other input of feedback linear amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> is connected to resistor <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The output of feedback linear amplifier is connected to, capacitor <highlight><bold>263</bold></highlight>, transistor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>, and transistor <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> by virtue of the connection of the linear feedback amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> to the base of transistor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. The current which is output from feedback linear amplifier <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> is converted to a voltage by capacitor <highlight><bold>263</bold></highlight> and thus this capacitor voltage formed on capacitor <highlight><bold>263</bold></highlight> controls transistor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. The collector and emitter of transistor <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> form a third current path I<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and collector and base of transistor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> form a fourth current path I<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. Transistor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> and transistor <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> are connected to different current paths (I<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and I<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) of current mirror <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. PFET <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> and PFET <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> are shown illustrating the current mirror <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The collector of transistor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> is connected to the base of transistor <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. The collector of transistor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> is connected to resistor <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. The feedback decoder circuit <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> controls which head the feedback is to be used from. Serial port <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> controls the feedback decode circuit <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. To input a head number such as head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. A code could be input to the serial port <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> for even number heads, all the head; or any particular head. The serial port <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> could select the head that has the lowest resistance of the MR head. The last head selected in the single channel read mode could be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a timing diagram showing the feedback from specific heads used on conjunction with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In operation, assuming that head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is selected to have the feedback of head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> applied to either head <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> designed by head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. Head <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> could have been selected to have the feedback of head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> applied to head <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The head select circuit <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> activates switch <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, and the feedback select circuit <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> activates switch <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and switch <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. The feedback from head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>) is applied to the operation of head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The head select circuit <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> activates switch <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. The feedback select circuit <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> continues to activate switch <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and switch <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. The feedback from head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>) is applied to the operation of head <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> (head <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The feedback of any head could be applied to any head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> At time <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> when the head switch is changing from single channel to multi channel, head <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is selected and addition feedback <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is selected. At time <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> when the write sequence starts the feedback from head <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> seizes and the feedback from head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> begins. At time period <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> when the write had ended the feedback from head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is turned off and the feedback from head <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is activated. At time period <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> the multi channel ends and the single channel period begins and feedback from head <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is activated. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A circuit to voltage bias a first head to access a disk; comprising: 
<claim-text>a circuit to bias said first head with a voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a feedback circuit to measure said voltage and generate a feedback signal to correct deviations in said voltage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch circuit to switch said feedback circuit to a second head while maintaining said feedback based as said first head. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A circuit to voltage bias as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said switch circuit includes a feedback decode circuit to switch said feedback circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A circuit to voltage bias as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said feedback decode circuit includes a serial port to enter a code for said feedback decode circuit to select said first head or said second head for feedback. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A circuit to voltage bias as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said switch is operable to switch the feedback from a plurality of feedback circuits.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002193A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002193A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002193A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002193A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002193A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
