<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003793A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003793A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003793A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003793A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003793A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003793A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003793A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003793A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003793A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003793A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003793A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003793A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003793</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09898113</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01R004/24</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01R004/26</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01R011/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>439</class>
<subclass>402000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Electrical connector with distribution contacts</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Che-Chia</given-name>
<family-name>Chang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TROXELL LAW OFFICE PLLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>5205 LEESBURG PIKE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1404</address-2>
<city>FALLS CHURCH</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22041</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The connector of the present invention comprises at least one contact plate or a plurality of contact plates, wherein one end of each contact plate has a plurality of terminals or pins and another end has a connecting section. Because the pins carry the same voltage and are connected together, the total voltage or current capacity of the contact plate is increased. Since the terminals or pins are connected to form a contact plate, only one signal wire is required to be connected to a contact plate that distributes the signal or voltage of the wire to a plurality of pins instead of a wire or jumper connecting to each of the desired pins as in the conventional method. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to an electrical connector. More particularly, the present invention relates to an electrical connector with distribution contacts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Present-day society increasingly relies on computers, computer systems, computer software applications and computer devices as computers become more essential in everyday life. With the increasing demands of computer applications in various areas, the utility and usefulness of computers increase, and integrated circuit (IC) connections become more complex. Various techniques have been developed to increase the number of IC device connections while providing a more compact computer with high performance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Devices such as hard disk drives or cd-rom drives or peripherals such as printers or external mass storage devices are connected to a host computer by cables. These cables have connectors and contacts attached to the wires in the cables. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> There are common methods for connecting wires to the pins of the connectors. However, these methods require considerable time and skill. For example, with some methods, during the process of attaching each wire to each pin, the temperature has to be controlled carefully so that the wire can be bonded to the pin strongly without overheating the wire. Other methods require considerable force, and if too much force is applied, the copper portion of the wire can be damaged or even break off. Additionally, each pin has to be connected to every wire in order to make the proper connection. In a 40 pin connector, for example, 40 individual wires need to be attached or connected to the connector contact. Therefore, making the connections is time consuming, resulting in an increased production cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As a result, an improved electrical connector that reduces production time, defects, and lowers production costs is needed. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the present invention to provide a more compact, reliable and cost-effective connector by utilizing an improved connector with improved connections and contacts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The previous example describes a one wire to one contact connector where each contact is attached to only one wire. In some situations a wire or a plurality of wires must be connected to a plurality of contacts or pins of the connector. This can be accomplished by connecting jumpers between the plurality of contacts. However, this increases the production time and increases the probability of a damaged or imperfect part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> As a result, an improved connector incorporating contacts that distribute a signal or voltage to a plurality of pins or contacts has been developed. Therefore a wire or a plurality of wires can be connected to a plurality of pins of the connector without requiring jumpers to make the multiple connections. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary and explanatory only and are not restrictive of the invention, as claimed.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings are included to provide a further understanding of the present invention, and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification. The drawings illustrate embodiments of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention. In the drawings, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an assembly view showing a connector with distribution contacts in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a drawing showing an alternative cover of a connector in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a contact plate of a connector in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a magnified view showing a portion of a contact plate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a distribution contact plate of a connector in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a solder-able contact plate of a connector in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a crimp-able contact plate of a connector in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the present invention to provide a more compact, reliable and cost-effective connector by utilizing a connector with improved connections and contacts allowing a wire or wires to be electrically connected to a plurality of contact pins or points. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The previous example describes a one wire to one contact connector where each contact is attached to only one wire. In some situations a wire or a plurality of wires must be connected to a plurality of contacts or pins of the connector. This can be accomplished by connecting jumpers between the plurality of contacts. However, this increases the production time and increases the probability of a damaged or imperfect part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As a result, an improved connector incorporating contacts that distribute a signal or voltage to a plurality of pins or contacts has been developed. Therefore a wire or a plurality of wires can be connected to a plurality of pins of the connector without requiring jumpers to make the multiple connections. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, which illustrates an assembly view of a connector in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention. A connector <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprises: a housing <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, a cover <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and a contact plate <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. A housing <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> has a plurality of slots <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and protrusions <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The protrusions <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> are arranged in such a way so as to be separated from each other by the slots <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to form a finger-like structure. A cover <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has a plurality of concave surfaces <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Also, refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, which is a drawing showing an alternative cover according to an embodiment of the present invention. The top row of concave surfaces <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> that are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> has been replaced with protrusions <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. Locations of the concave surfaces <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and the protrusions <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the cover <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are matched and correspond to positions of the slots <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the protrusions <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The housing <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, cover <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and contact plate <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> are examples and do not limit the present invention to those types shown. Various other types of housing are also envisioned depending on the size and number of pins required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> During an integrating process, at least one contact plate <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> is inserted into the housing <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, and the cover <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is integrated onto a top part of the housing <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. For example purposes, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows five contact plates but the number of contact plates <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> can be increased or decreased as determined by the number of contact plates <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> required by the connector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a contact plate of a connector in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the contact plate <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> comprises a top portion <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and a forked portion <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The top portion <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> comprises an oblong-shaped slot, which is an insulation displacement contact (IDC) section <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> extending into a wider hole <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> via a Y-shaped transition portion <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. The circular hole <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> is for positioning the contact plate during a fabrication process. In an integrating process, the top portion <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> will be broken off along a line N-N. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A standard insulated wire can be inserted into the IDC section <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. The wire is inserted through the Y-shaped transition portion <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> into the IDC section <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a magnified view of a portion of the contact plate according to an embodiment of the present invention. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the Y-shaped transition portion <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> comprises a pair of sharp edges <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a Y-shaped opening <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>A distance between the sharp edges <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is smaller than an outer diameter of the conductive wire portion <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> contained in the wire <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. When the wire <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is inserted into the Y-shaped opening <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the sharp edges <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>will cut through an insulating portion <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> of the wire <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, and a conductive wire portion <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of the wire <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is exposed and comes into contact with the IDC section <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. The Y-shaped transition portion <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> is designed in such way that it allows the wire to electrically connect to the terminals without soldering or crimping and without any damage to the conductive wire portion <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of the wire <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the forked portion <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of the contact plate <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> comprises two conducting terminals, pins or leads <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>, which are connected at one end into a contact part <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, thus forming a fork-shaped structure. The conducting terminals, pins or leads <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> can be made of, for example, copper alloy for good conductivity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> After the wire is connected to the contact plate, any signal or voltage level that passes through the wire, is distributed to a plurality of contact pins or terminals of the connector. In this way, a wire or a plurality of wires can be connected to a plurality of pins of the connector without requiring jumpers to make the multiple connections. In the conventional method a wire is attached to a first contact. Then one end of a jumper is connected to the wire or first contact. Finally, the other end of the jumper is connected to the second contact. This requires 3 connecting steps during the manufacturing process. However, with the present invention, only one connection is required where the wire is connected to the contact pad and the contact pad distributes the signal to the appropriate contact terminals or pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The embodiments given are using an insulation displacement contact method for attaching the wire or wires to the contact plate or pins. However, in other embodiments of the present invention, the IDC connecting method is replaced by soldering, crimping, or other connecting methods or means. Two alternative connecting methods are shown in the drawings. Refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, which is a drawing showing a contact plate of a connector in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention wherein the wire or wires are to be soldered to the contact plate. Also, refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, which is a drawing showing a contact plate of a connector in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention wherein the wire or wires are to be crimped to the contact plate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The connector of the present invention comprises at least one contact plate or a plurality of contact plates, wherein one end of each contact plate has a plurality of terminals or pins, such as two pins, for example, and another end has a connecting section. Each pin can carry a signal, current or voltage, for example 3V, 5V, or 12V. The pins that carry the same signal, current or voltage are then combined together into one contact plate. Because the pins carry the same voltage and are connected together, the total voltage or current capacity of the contact plate is increased. Since the pins are connected to form a contact plate, only one signal wire is required to connect to a contact plate instead of every wire connecting to every pin as in the conventional method. Therefore, the number of wire connections is reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The contact plate of the present invention is not limited to the number of conducting forked structures in each contact plate. Also, the number of contact plates can be combined into more than two conducting structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a contact plate of a connector with distribution contacts in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention. Based on the same principles and theory, a contact plate comprising three terminals or pins <highlight><bold>407</bold></highlight> is shown. The number of terminals or pins can be any quantity and is not limited to two or three as shown in the drawings. In fact, as shown above, increasing the number of terminals or pins increases the value of the present invention. The present invention only requires one connection per contact pin in order to distribute a signal or voltage to a plurality of pins. However, with the conventional method, if a signal is to be sent to four pins a total of seven connections is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Advantages of the present invention are at least; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> 1. The number of connections that are required is reduced; therefore, less time is required and the cost is reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> 2. The total voltage or current capacity of the contact plate is greatly increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> 3. The connection between wires to pins or wires to wires is more effective and rapid. No damage occurs to the conductive portion of the wire. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> 4. The cost of production is significantly reduced, and the integrating process and fabrication process are simplified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Other embodiments of the invention will appear to those skilled in the art from consideration of the specification and practice of the invention disclosed herein. It is intended that the specification and examples to be considered as exemplary only, with a true scope and spirit of the invention being indicated by the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An electrical connector comprising: 
<claim-text>a contact plate comprising a plurality of conductive terminals electrically coupled to the contact plate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one conductive wire connected to the contact plate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the contact plate distributes signals received via the at least one conductive wire, to the plurality of conductive terminals; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing for holding the contact plate; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate with an insulation displacement contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate by solder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate by crimping. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the contact plate and conductive terminals are made of copper alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An electrical connector comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing having a plurality of first protrusions on one end, wherein the first protrusions are separated from each other by a plurality of slots; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a contact plate having a plurality of conducting structures, wherein the conducting structures are connected at one end to form a contact part, and the contact plate is inserted into the housing; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover having a plurality of indentations formed on one side, wherein positions of the indentations match positions of the slots, wherein the cover is fit onto the contact plate and the housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate with an insulation displacement contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate by solder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate by crimping. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the contact plate and conductive terminals are made of copper alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An electrical connector comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing having a plurality of first protrusions on one end, wherein the first protrusions are separated from each other by a plurality of slots; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a contact plate having a plurality of conducting structures, wherein the conducting structures are connected at one end to form a contact part, and the contact plate is inserted into the housing; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover having a plurality of second protrusions formed on one side, wherein positions of the second protrusions match positions of the slots, wherein the cover is fit onto the contact plate and the housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate with an insulation displacement contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate by solder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate by crimping. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the contact plate and conductive terminals are made of copper alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An electrical connector comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing having a plurality of first protrusions on one end, wherein the first protrusions are separated from each other by a plurality of slots; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a contact plate having a plurality of sets of conducting structures, wherein the conducting structures of each set are connected together at one end to form a contact part, and an oblong-shaped slot is formed on the contact part, the contact plate being inserted into the housing; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover having a hollow in the middle and a plurality of second protrusions formed on one side, wherein a portion of the second protrusions have a concave surface, the second protrusions being separated from each other by a plurality of holes, and positions of the second protrusions and the holes of the cover are matched and correspond to positions of the slots and first protrusions of the housing, wherein the cover is fit onto the contact plate and the housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate with an insulation displacement contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate by solder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive wire is connected to the contact plate by crimping. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each set of the conducting structures comprises two conducting structures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each set of the conducting structures comprises three conducting structures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The connector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conducting structures are made of copper alloy.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003793A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003793A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003793A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003793A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003793A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003793A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
