<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003840A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003840A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003840A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003840A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003840A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003840A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003840A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003840A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003840A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003840A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003840A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003840A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003840</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10173348</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020617</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A63H003/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>446</class>
<subclass>221000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Interconnecting inflatable play structure</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10173348</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020617</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09479804</doc-number>
<document-date>20000108</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yaw-Yuan</given-name>
<family-name>Hsu</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chin-Hsiang</given-name>
<family-name>Pan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei Hsien</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kun</given-name>
<middle-name>Chao</middle-name>
<family-name>Hsu</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>John S. Christopher, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>LEWIS, D&apos;AMATO, BRISBOIS &amp; BISGAARD LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite #1200</address-1>
<address-2>221 North Figueroa Street</address-2>
<city>Los Angeles</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90012</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An inflatable play structure comprises at least one inflatable house defining a cavity for accommodating a child and an inflatable tunnel detachably attached to the house. The house includes two side walls and front and rear walls connected together to form a continuous wall, and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls. The house has a first access opening and a first one flap extending from a lower portion of the wall having a pair of hook and loop fasteners. The inflatable tunnel has two arched tubes erected from and affixed to a bottom wall defining a first opening and a second opening. The tunnel includes at least one open window and a second flap extending along the bottom wall and having a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the house. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a Continuation-in-Part application of the pending application having Ser. No. 09/479,804 filed on Jan. 8, 2000 entitled Interconnecting Inflatable Play Structure by inventors Yaw-Yuan Hsu, Chin-Hsiang Pan and Kun Chao Hsu.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to inflatable play structures, and more particularly, to children&apos;s play structures, such as inflatable houses and tunnels, which are easily attachable to and removable from each other by using hook and loop fasteners. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Discussion of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Children enjoy playing in inflatable toy structures. Conventional inflatable toy structures are individually free standing without being able to interconnect between them. Many types of toys have been devised to help develop children&apos;s body spatial relationships. As an example, rigid tubes positioned together, end to end with a wood base, to prevent rolling, are presently in use. Other such tunnels, using helical spring steel hoops covered with a cloth or plastic material are commonly in use and are known in the industry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In child growth, the use of devices that help development of body control in motion, such as creeping and crawling, are becoming more prevalent. Presently, rigid structural tubes, or pipes, are in use both indoors and out. Flexible collapsing tunnels are especially popular for indoor use, however, these devices, as well as the outdoor equipment with a hard bottom surface, have a tendency to scuff the children&apos;s legs and clothing and are uncomfortable when in use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Children are typically fond of tunnel like structures, such as large boxes, in which they may play. This preference is embodied in many playgrounds and parks and indoor toys where enclosed slides and tire tunnels are commonly constructed for the children&apos;s enjoyment. Recognizing the play value of tunnels, several toy tunnel structures have been developed in the prior art and marketed to children. As is typical with such prior art toy tunnels, the tunnel structure only has openings at its two ends. Accordingly, using a single tunnel structure, children can only enter into one opening and exit at the other opening. As a result, the amusement value of the tunnel quickly wanes as the children become familiar with the tunnel structure. The continuous structure of the toy tunnel and other structure also makes it very difficult to assemble the play structures in a confined area or indoors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A play structure with much more entertainment value is one that allows a child to enter and exit at multiple points. As a result, more than one child can play with the play structure at once, meeting at various points without concern of one child blocking another&apos;s passage. Play structures with multiple entrances and exits have been limited mostly to playhouse structures and tents. However, these devices are not easily connected to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Therefore, there is a need in the art for an interconnecting inflatable play structure that is easily attachable to and removable from other play structures to provide entrances at multiple points. Accordingly, several structures can be joined together in hundreds of differing configurations. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present invention is directed to an interconnecting inflatable play structure that substantially obviates one or more of the problems due to limitations and disadvantages of the related art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> An object of the invention provides a multitude of combined shapes and matrixes when houses and tunnels are joined together. A number of tunnels and houses may be attached in tandem with one end of the assembly connected to a multiple opening intersection. Also, others may be attached projecting at various angles therefrom. This flexible arrangement allows the children to use their imagination and creativity in organizing the desired shape or form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention provides collapsible and deflatable play structures, thereby allowing the house and tunnel structures to be easily stored when not in use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Still another object allows construction with cost effective material, such as polyvinyl chloride sheeting, or any other substance having characteristics suitable for inflating, including thermoplastic impregnated cloth, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Additional features and advantages of the invention will be set forth in the description which follows, and in part will be apparent from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The objectives and other advantages of the invention will be realized and attained by the structure particularly pointed out in the written description and claims hereof as well as the appended drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> To achieve these and other advantages and in accordance with the purpose of the present invention, as embodied and broadly described, an inflatable play structure for use by a child comprises an inflatable first structure defining a cavity sufficiently large to accommodate the child, the first structure having at least one side wall defining a first opening, the side wall of the first structure having at least one flap extending from a lower portion of the side wall, wherein the flap has at least one hook and loop fastener thereon; and an inflatable second structure having at least one flap extending therefrom, the flap having at least one hook and loop fastener thereon which is aligned with the hook and loop fastener of the first flap to releasably couple the first and second structures to allow the child to move from the first structure to the second structure. Preferably, the first and second structures are comprised of polyvinylchloride sheeting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the preferred embodiment, the first structure is an inflatable house, and the second structure is an inflatable tunnel. The house includes two side walls and front and rear walls which are connected together to form a continuous wall and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls. The side wall of the house defining the first opening has the flap extending therefrom. The flap includes a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the second structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The tunnel includes at least two arched tubes erected from and affixed to a bottom wall, a first arched tube defining a first opening and a second arched tube defining a second opening. The tunnel also includes the flap extending from and substantially along the width of the bottom wall. The flap of the tunnel includes a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the first structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> According to another embodiment of the present invention, an inflatable play structure comprises an inflatable first structure defining a cavity sufficiently large to accommodate the child, the first structure having at least one side wall defining a first opening; an inflatable second structure defining a cavity sufficiently large to accommodate the child; and a connecting means on exposed outside surfaces of the first and second structures for releasably attaching the first and second structures, wherein the connecting means is attached to uninflated portion of the first and second structures. Preferably, the connecting means includes at least one first flap extending from a lower portion of the side wall of the first structure, wherein the first flap has at least one hook and loop fastener thereon and at least one second flap extending from the second structure, the second flap having at least one hook and loop fastener thereon which is aligned with the hook and loop fastener of the first flap to releasably couple the first and second structures to allow the child to move from the first structure to the second structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> According to another embodiment of the present invention, the play structure comprises an inflatable house defining a cavity sufficiently large to accommodate the child, the house including two side walls and front and rear walls which are connected together to form a continuous wall and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls, one of the walls having a first opening and a plurality of hook and loop fasteners at lower end of the first opening; and an inflatable tunnel having at least two arched tubes erected from and affixed to a bottom wall, a first arched tube defining a first opening and a second arched tube defining a second opening, wherein one end of the bottom wall has a plurality of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the house to releasably couple the house and the tunnel, wherein the house and the tunnel are comprised of polyvinylchloride sheeting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary and explanatory and are intended to provide a further explanation of the invention as claimed.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are included to provide a further understanding of the invention and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective view of a preferred embodiment of an interconnecting inflatable play structure; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a detached view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing a tunnel placed between and connecting two inflatable play houses according to the preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a left elevational view of the interconnecting inflatable play structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a right elevational view of the interconnecting inflatable play structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a bottom planar view of the interconnecting inflatable play structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a detail view of a flap extending from the inflatable tunnel having a plurality of hook and look fasteners affixed thereon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a detail view showing the connection between the inflatable tunnel and a play house; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a detached view of the interconnecting inflatable play structure according to another embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> With reference to the drawings, and in particular to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> thereof, an interconnecting inflatable play structure embodying the principles and concepts of the present invention will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective view of a preferred embodiment of an interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a detached view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing a tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> placed between and connecting two inflatable playhouses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> according to the preferred embodiment of the present invention. The present invention is directed to an interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> typically used by children in-doors or out-of-doors. The interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of play structures which are easily interconnected to allow children to move between or among various play structures, such as houses and tunnels. According to the preferred embodiment, the interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> connected to a second inflatable house <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> through an inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The use of the first and second inflatable houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are for illustration purposes only and should not limit the scope of the present invention. The present invention may be used with any number of inflatable houses with or without tunnels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment, a continuous side wall <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of polygon shaped, preferably rectangular, walls. In particular, the side wall <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> comprises an inflatable first side wall <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> having an access opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, front wall <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> having an access opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, second sidewall <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and rear wall <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> both of which do not have any openings. The child access openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> are sufficiently large to allow children to enter or exit the inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. It is noted that the access openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> are continuously open to the atmosphere, i.e., air freely flows through the entire interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. This construction facilitates the ability of children to enter and exit the interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> which is not sealed off, isolated, or air tight in any manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The first side wall <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> has an appearance of a corrugated surface to simulate the shape of a plurality of vertical tubes fused or connected side by side. The first side wall <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> preferably has one air pocket or chamber which defines the rectangular access opening <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> once inflated with pressurized air. The same is also true for the front wall <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. The second side wall <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and the rear wall <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> each includes a plurality of vertical tubes which are in fluid communication with respect to each other. The side edges of the walls <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> are fused together in tandem to form the continuous side wall <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> using the process of radio frequency sealing or other processes known to those having ordinary skill in the art. In the preferred embodiment, each one of the walls <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is individually equipped with an inflation air valve <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> to insert and discharge pressurized air. The material utilized for the first house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is comprised of a flexible inflatable material, such as polyvinylchloride sheeting (typically referred to as PVC), thermoplastic impregnated cloth, or other materials known to those having ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> also includes two arched inflatable support tubes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> preferably placed at the four corners of the side wall <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The support tubes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> extend over the height of the side wall <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to form the facades of the house. Each support tube <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is equipped with one of the inflation air valves <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> for the insertion and discharge of pressurized air. The two arched inflatable support tubes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are preferably made with PVC or other suitable materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Placed between the two support tubes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is a ceiling tube <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> which defines the top of the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The ceiling tube <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> has an independent air chamber. Two ends of the ceiling tube <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> are fused between the two support tubes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> using a suitable process, such as radio frequency sealing or another process known to those of ordinary skill in the art. The air chamber of the ceiling tube <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> is also equipped with an inflation air valve <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> for the insertion and discharge of pressurized air. The ceiling tube <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> is also preferably made with PVC or other suitable materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has a roof sheet <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> supported by and attached to the ceiling tube <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> and the two arched inflatable support tubes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In particular, the middle of the roof sheet <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is supported by and attached to the ceiling tube <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>. The side edges of the roof sheet <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are fused to the upper portion of the support tubes <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to form a roof of the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The roof sheet <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is preferably made with a PVC sheet or fabric for easy folding and flexibility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has a plurality of flaps <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> extending from the lower end portion of the side walls having child access openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. In particular, the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has a side flap <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and a front flap <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> extending from the lower end portion of the side wall <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and the front wall <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, respectively. Each flap <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> includes a pair of hook and loop fasteners securely affixed thereto for easy connection with another toy play structure also equipped with hook and loop fasteners. The side flap <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and the front flap <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> are each made of at least one layer of PVC sheets which are used for constructing the side and bottom walls. Because the flaps <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> are not inflated, the hook and loop fasteners can be stitched directly onto each respective flap. In addition, other suitable attachment methods may also be utilized, such as employing adhesives, etc. Preferably, the side and front flaps <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> extend along the length of their respective sides between four vertical posts formed by two arched supports <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The details of the flap <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and the hook and look fasteners are described in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> and similarly to the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, the second inflatable house <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> includes a continuous side wall <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> fused at four corners to a pair of arched support tubes <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. The components and the structure of the second inflatable house <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are identical to that of the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and therefore the description with regard to such components will not be repeated here. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the second inflatable house <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> also has a plurality of flaps <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> extending from the lower end portion of the continuous side wall <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> having child access openings <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The access openings <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are sufficiently large to allow children to enter or exit the inflatable house <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. It is noted that the access openings <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are continuously open to the atmosphere, i.e., air freely flows through the entire interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. This construction facilitates the ability of children to enter and exit the interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> which is not sealed off, isolated, or air tight in any manner. The second inflatable house <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> includes a side flap <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and a front flap <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> extending from the bottom edge of the side wall and the front wall, respectively as is best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Each flap includes a pair of hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> securely affixed thereto for each connection with another toy play structure or one or more tunnels <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> According to the preferred embodiment, one or more inflatable tunnels <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> may be used with inflatable houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to provide access to one or more inflatable houses interconnected with the tunnels. The inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is placed, for example, between the first and second inflatable houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to connect the front access opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the front access opening <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of the second inflatable house <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> includes three arched tubes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> which are serially placed, with the two opposite tubes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> placed at an equal distance from the middle tube <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> as is best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Connected between the arched tubes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> are inflatable tubes <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> that are either fully or partially covering the roof portion of the tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Also placed between the arched tubes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> are inflatable side walls <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> having a plurality of open windows <highlight><bold>149</bold></highlight> formed therein to allow viewing of the tunnel&apos;s interior. It is noted that the plurality of open windows <highlight><bold>149</bold></highlight> formed within the inflatable side walls <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> of the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are continuously open to the atmosphere, i.e., air freely flows through the entire interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. This construction facilitates the ability of children to see into the interior of the tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> from outside the tunnel, and to see exterior of the tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> from inside the tunnel. The interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is not sealed off, isolated, or air tight in any manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The side walls <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> and the inflatable tubes <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> are preferably in fluid communication with each other so that one air valve <highlight><bold>147</bold></highlight> can be used to input pressurized air into the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The inflatable tubes <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> and the side walls <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> of the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are made of PVC or other suitable material known to those of ordinary skill in the art. The inflatable tubes <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> are fused together with the side walls <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> by such method as radio frequency sealing or by using adhesives or other methods known to those of ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> also includes a bottom wall <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> which comprises a rectangular tube with <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> a plurality of air pockets. The side walls <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> and the arched tubes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, lo <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> are erected from and fused to the top surface and along the length of the bottom wall <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. In particular, the bottom ends of the side walls <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> and the arched tubes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> are fused together with the bottom wall <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> to complete the dome portion of the tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The bottom wall <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> is also preferably made with the same material as the side walls <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> includes a first opening <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and a second opening <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> for allowing children to crawl there through as is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In particular, the openings <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> are defined by the arched tubes <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and the bottom wall <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. The diameter of the first and second openings <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> is sized to substantially cover the front child access openings <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of the first and second inflatable houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> includes first and second flaps <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> extending from the opposite ends of the bottom wall <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> for connecting with the first and second inflatable houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Each one of the first and second flaps <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> has a plurality of hook and loop fasteners which are aligned with the hook and loop fasteners placed on the flaps of the inflatable houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a left elevational view of the interconnecting inflatable play structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the side child access openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of the first and second inflatable houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The front flaps <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> and the front access openings <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of the first and second houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are hidden from view as they are blocked by the supports <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The first and second flaps <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> of the tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are extended from the opposite ends of the bottom wall <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a right elevational view of the interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The side walls of the play house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> do not have any openings and are solidly blocked. As shown in this particular arrangement, the two inflatable houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are linearly positioned to allow children to travel from the first house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to the second house <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The first and second flaps <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> of the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are aligned with the front or side flaps <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> of the play houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> for easy connection and disconnection by children as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a bottom planar view of the interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. As shown, the first and second flaps <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> extending from the bottom wall <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> of the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are overlapped with the front flaps <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> of the first and second houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The pair of hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> of the front flap <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> are aligned with the hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> of the first flap <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the pair of hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> of the front flap <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> are aligned with the hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> of the second flap <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a detail view of a flap <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> extending from the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> having a pair of hook and look fasteners <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> affixed thereon. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a detail view showing the connection between the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. In the preferred embodiment of the present invention, the hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> are placed on an under surface of the front flaps <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> of the first and second houses <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, respectively. However, the first and second flaps <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> extending from the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> have the hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> on the upper surface to interlockingly overlap the corresponding opposite flaps <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. As a result, the flaps may be tilted at any angle to allow, for example, the tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to be at an angle with respect to the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to allow the children to use the tunnel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> as a slide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Moreover, because hook and loop fasteners, by their design, collect and hold loose hairs, dirt, threads, etc., the use of the uninflated overlapping flaps <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> prevent foreign objects from being tangled with the hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. In addition, unlike the hook and loop fasteners which are directly attached to an inflated structure, the hook and loop fasteners of the preferred embodiment of the present invention will not tear off from the flaps because the flaps are not inflated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a detached view of the interconnecting inflatable play structure <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> according to a second embodiment of the present invention. The second embodiment has substantially identical first and second inflatable play houses <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and an inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. However, in lieu of having front and side flaps in the inflatable play houses <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and first and second flaps in the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, a plurality of hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> are directly affixed to the side of the bottom tubes of each structure. The hook and loop fasteners are positioned so that each respective piece of play structure (i.e., first and second inflatable play houses <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>) must to pushed against, i.e., make contact with, each other for achieve attachment. In particular, the hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> of the first inflatable house <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> are aligned with and connected to the hook and loop fasteners <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of the inflatable tunnel <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> as is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made in the present invention without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention. Thus, it is intended that the present invention cover the modifications and variations of this invention provided they come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An inflatable play structure for use by a child, the play structure comprising: 
<claim-text>an inflatable first structure defining a cavity, the first structure having at least one side wall defining a first access opening, the side wall of the first structure having at least one first flap extending from a lower portion of the side wall, wherein the first flap has at least one hook and loop fastener thereon; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inflatable second structure having at least one open window and at least one second flap extending therefrom, the second flap having at least one hook and loop fastener thereon which is aligned with the hook and loop fastener of the first flap to releasably couple the first and second structures to allow movement from the first structure to the second structure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first structure is an inflatable house. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second structure is an inflatable tunnel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the house includes two side walls and front and rear walls which are connected together to form a continuous wall and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the side wall of the house defining the first opening has the first flap extending therefrom, the first flap containing a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the second structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tunnel includes at least two arched tubes erected from and affixed to a bottom wall, a first arched tube defining a first opening and a second arched tube defining a second opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tunnel includes the second flap extending from and substantially along the width of the bottom wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second flap of the tunnel includes a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the first structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first structure is comprised of polyvinylchloride sheeting. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second structure is comprised of polyvinylchloride sheeting. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second structure is an inflatable tunnel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the house includes two side walls and front and rear walls which are connected together to form a continuous wall and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls and the side wall of the house defining the first access opening has the first flap extending therefrom, the first flap containing a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the second structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tunnel includes at least two arched tubes erected from and affixed to a bottom wall, a first arched tube defining a first opening and a second arched tube defining a second opening, and further includes the second flap extending from and substantially along the width of the bottom wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second flap of the tunnel includes a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the first structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An inflatable play structure for use by a child, the play structure comprising: 
<claim-text>an inflatable first structure defining a cavity, the first structure having at least one side wall defining a first access opening; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inflatable second structure defining a cavity and having at least one open window; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting means on exposed outside surfaces of the first and second structures for releasably attaching the first and second structures, wherein the connecting means is attached to an uninflated portion of the first and second structures. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connecting means includes at least one first flap extending from a lower portion of the side wall of the first structure, wherein the first flap has at least one hook and loop fastener thereon and at least one second flap extending from the second structure, the second flap having at least one hook and loop fastener thereon which is aligned with the hook and loop fastener of the first flap to releasably couple the first and second structures to allow movement from the first structure to the second structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first structure is an inflatable house. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second structure is an inflatable tunnel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the house includes two side walls and front and rear walls which are connected together to form a continuous wall and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the side wall of the house defining the first access opening includes at least one first flap extending therefrom, the flap containing a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the second structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tunnel includes at least two arched tubes erected from and affixed to a bottom wall, a first arched tube defining a first opening and a second arched tube defining a second opening and further includes at least one second flap extending substantially along the width of the bottom wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The inflatable play structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second flap of the tunnel includes a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the first structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An inflatable play structure for use by a child, the play structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a first inflatable house defining a cavity, the first house including two side walls and front and rear walls which are connected together to form a continuous wall and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls, one of the walls having a first access opening and at least a first flap extending from a lower portion of the wall, wherein the first flap has a pair of hook and loop fasteners thereon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second inflatable house defining a cavity, the second house including two side walls and front and rear walls which are connected together to form a continuous wall and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls, one of the walls having a second access opening and at least a second flap extending from a lower portion of the wall, wherein the second flap has a pair of hook and loop fasteners thereon; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inflatable tunnel disposed between the first and second houses and having at least one open window and at least two arched tubes erected from and affixed to a bottom wall, a first arched tube defining a first opening and a second arched tube defining a second opening, wherein the tunnel includes a first flap extending substantially along the width of the bottom wall defining the first access opening and a second flap extending substantially along the width of the bottom wall defining the second access opening, the flaps having a pair of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the first and second houses to releasably couple the first and second houses and the tunnel, wherein the first and second houses and the tunnel are comprised of polyvinylchloride sheeting. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An inflatable play structure for use by a child, the play structure comprising: 
<claim-text>An inflatable house defining a cavity, the house including two side walls and front and rear walls which are connected together to form a continuous wall and support tubes placed at each corner of the two side walls and front and rear walls, one of the walls having a first access opening and a plurality of hook and loop fasteners at a lower end of the first access opening; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inflatable tunnel having at least one open window and at least two arched tubes erected from and affixed to a bottom wall, a first arched tube defining a first opening and a second arched tube defining a second opening, wherein one end of the bottom wall has a plurality of hook and loop fasteners aligned with corresponding hook and loop fasteners of the house to releasably couple the house and the tunnel, wherein the house and the tunnel are comprised of polyvinylchloride sheeting.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003840A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003840A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003840A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003840A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003840A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003840A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
