<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002353A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002353A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002353A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002353A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002353A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002353A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002353A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002353A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002353A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002353A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002353A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002353A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002353A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002353A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002353A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002353A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002353</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10147555</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020517</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-38815</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010630</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11C007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>189110</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>203000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>207000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Integrated circuit memory devices having sense amplifiers therein that receive nominal and boosted supply voltages when active and methods of operating same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jae-Goo</given-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyungki-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MYERS BIGEL SIBLEY &amp; SAJOVEC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO BOX 37428</address-1>
<city>RALEIGH</city>
<state>NC</state>
<postalcode>27627</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Integrated circuit devices provide supplemental pull-up drive currents to one or more sense amplifiers therein during operations (e.g., read operations) to sense and amplify differential signals established across inputs of the sense amplifiers. These additional pull-up drive currents are provided to improve the timing characteristics of the sense amplifiers by making them less susceptible to degraded performance that may be caused by insufficiently high internal voltages. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority to Korean Patent Application No. 2001-38815, filed on Jun. 30, 2001, the disclosure of which is hereby incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to semiconductor memory devices, and more particularly, to semiconductor memory devices having sense amplifiers therein that amplify differential input signals. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Semiconductor devices have been continuously developed to increase their capacity and speed and lower their power consumption. To realize low power consumption, a dynamic random access memory (DRAM) device may use a bit-line sense amplifier that is shared by two neighboring memory cell array blocks and an internal memory cell array power supply voltage as a power supply voltage of the shared bit-line sense amplifier. The internal memory cell array power supply voltage is a voltage that is typically reduced from an external power supply voltage. If the internal memory cell array power supply voltage is excessively reduced, the operational features of the bit-line sense amplifier may be degraded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a memory cell array of a conventional DRAM and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a waveform diagram illustrating the operation of a sense amplifier in the conventional DRAM shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, bit-line sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are shared by two neighboring memory cell arrays <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Pairs of bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bi that are connected to a first memory cell array block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are initially equalized to a level Vb<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> by equalization circuits E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through E<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and other pairs of bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bj through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bj that are connected to a second memory cell array block <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are initially equalized to the level Vb<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> by equalization circuits E<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> through E<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, first and second isolation control signals PISOi and PISOj initially rise to the level of an external power supply voltage Vdd. Thereafter, the first isolation control signal PISOi rises to the level of a boosted voltage Vpp and the second isolation control signal PISOj falls to the level of the ground voltage Vss. As a result, pairs of first isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are turned on, whereas pairs of second isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are turned off. That is, the first memory cell array block <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> is selected, but the second memory cell array block <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is not selected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Then, a word line WL of a row of memory cells of the first memory cell array <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> reaches the boosted voltage level Vpp, a sense amplifier control signal LAPG reaches logic a &ldquo;low&rdquo; level and an inverted sense amplifier control signal LANG rises to a logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level. As a result, sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> begin to operate. That is, a first switch SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is turned on to provide pull-up current to a power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> by connecting the memory cell array power supply voltage V-array to the node LA. A second switch SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is also turned on to provide a ground voltage node LAB with the ground voltage VSS. The sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> amplify data in the form of differential signals established across the pairs of the bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bi connected to the first memory cell array block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> However, according to the operation of the sense amplifier shown <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the pairs of the first isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are turned on earlier as expected by the first isolation control signal PISOi rising almost to the Vpp level during the initial operation of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Thus, a load of the pairs of bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bi connected to the first memory cell array block II is increased. This increased loading degrades the operational features of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and, further, reduces amplification speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a waveform diagram illustrating another operation of the sense amplifier in the conventional DRAM shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Here, the sense amplifier has improved operational features compared to that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the first and second isolation control signals PISOi and PISOj initially rise to the external power supply voltage level Vdd. Then, the first isolation control signal PISOi is kept at the outside power supply voltage Vdd level and the second isolation control signal PISOj falls to the ground voltage Vss level during the initial operation of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, the first isolation control signal PISOi rises to the boosted voltage level Vpp during the middle part of the operation of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to the operation of the sense amplifier shown <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the pairs of the first isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> have lower conductivity because the first isolation control signal PISOi has a lower level of Vdd and, therefore, a load on the pairs of the bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bi connected to the first memory cell array block <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is decreased. As a result, the amplification speed of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> However, if the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray provided to the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is comparatively high, data values which are achieved by sharing charge between a memory cell and bit line cannot be satisfactorily transmitted to the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. To prevent this, the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray must be lowered. However, in this case, the operational features of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> may deteriorate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Integrated circuit devices according to embodiments of the present invention provide supplemental pull-up drive currents to one or more sense amplifiers therein during operations (e.g., read operations) to sense and amplify differential signals established across inputs of the sense amplifiers. These additional pull-up drive currents are provided to improve the timing characteristics of the sense amplifiers by making them less susceptible to degraded performance that may be caused by insufficiently high internal voltages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In particular, first embodiments of the present invention include integrated circuit devices having preferred control circuitry therein. This control circuitry drives a power supply terminal of a differential sense amplifier with a plurality of pull-up drive currents. These pull-up drive currents are derived from a corresponding plurality of signal lines that are each electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of the differential sense amplifier. These signal lines are driven at different positive voltage levels during sense and amplify time intervals (i.e., when the sense amplifier is active). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Additional embodiments of the present invention include integrated circuit memory devices having multiple banks of memory arrays therein. These memory arrays may be coupled to a bank of sense amplifiers, with each sense amplifier having first and second inputs electrically coupled to a pair of differential signal lines. A pull-up control circuit is also provided. The pull-up control circuit provides pull-up drive currents in parallel from first and second voltage supply sources having different magnitudes to a power supply terminal of the sense amplifier when the sense amplifier is amplifying a differential input signal established across the first and second inputs. Memory devices according to this embodiment may also include first and second isolation transistors having first and second gate electrodes electrically coupled to an isolation control signal line. Furthermore, the pull-up control circuit may include a first MOS transistor (e.g., NMOS or PMOS transistor) having a first current carrying terminal (source/drain) electrically coupled to the isolation control signal line and a second current carrying terminal (source/drain) electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of the sense amplifier. The first and second isolation transistors also have first current carrying terminals that are electrically coupled to the pair of differential signal lines, which are provided to inputs of the sense amplifier. The pull-up control circuit further includes a second MOS transistor (e.g., PMOS transistor) having a first current carrying terminal (source/drain) electrically coupled to a memory array power supply line (e.g., Varray) and a second current carrying terminal (source/drain) electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of the sense amplifier. According to a preferred aspect of this embodiment, a magnitude of the first voltage supply source is greater than a magnitude of the second voltage supply source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Integrated circuit memory devices may also include a memory cell array block, a pair of bit lines connected to the memory cell array block, a sense amplifier for sensing and amplifying a voltage difference between the pair of the bit lines, a pair of isolation transistors for connecting the pair of bit lines and the sense amplifiers or isolating them from each other in response to a isolation control signal, a first switch for transmitting a memory cell array power supply voltage to a power supply voltage node of the sense amplifiers in response to a sense amplifier control signal, and a second switch for transmitting the isolation control signal to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to a predetermined control signal. The memory cell array power supply voltage and the isolation control signal are used as power supply voltages of the sense amplifiers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Still further memory devices may include a first memory cell array block, a pair of first bit lines connected to the first memory cell array block, a second memory cell array block, a pair of second bit lines connected to the second memory cell array block, a first equalization unit for equalizing the pair of first bit lines in response to the first equalization signal, a second equalization unit for equalizing the pair of second bit lines in response to the second equalization signal, a sense amplifier for sensing and amplifying a voltage difference between the pair of the first bit lines or the pair of the second bit lines, a pair of first isolation transistors for connecting the pair of first bit lines and the sense amplifier or separating the pairs of first bit lines from the pair input by the sense amplifier in response to a first isolation control signal, a pair of second isolation transistors for connecting the pair of the second bit lines and the sense amplifier or isolating them from each other in response to a second isolation control signal, a first switch for transmitting the memory cell array power supply voltage to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to the sense amplifier control signal, a second switch for transmitting the first isolation control signal to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to a first control signal, a third switch for transmitting the second isolation control signal to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to the second control signal, and a control signal generation circuit for generating the first and second control signals in response to the sense amplifier control signal, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal and the first and second equalization signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It is preferable that the control signal generation circuit includes a first control signal generation circuit for generating the first control signal in response to the sense amplifier control signal, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal and the second equalization signal, and a second control generation circuit for generating the second control signal in response to the sense amplifier control signal, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal and the first equalization signal. The second and third switches preferably include nMOS transistors. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The above objective and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent by describing in detail a preferred embodiment thereof with reference to the attached drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an electrical schematic of a conventional DRAM device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference> are waveform diagrams illustrating operations of a sense amplifier of the conventional DRAM device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an electrical schematic of a DRAM device according to an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an electrical schematic of the control signal generation circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a timing diagram that illustrates operation of the control signal generation circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an electrical schematic of the isolation control circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a timing diagram that illustrates operation of the isolation control circuits of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a timing diagram that illustrates operation of the DRAM device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The present invention now will be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which preferred embodiments of the invention are shown. This invention may, however, be embodied in many different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein; rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the invention to those skilled in the art. Like numbers refer to like elements throughout. Signal lines and signals thereon may be referred to by the same reference names and characters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a DRAM device having two memory cell array blocks <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The DRAM device includes a first memory cell array block <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, pairs of first bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bi connected to the first memory cell array block <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and first equalization circuits E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through E<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for equalizing the pairs of the first bit-lines in response to a first equalization signal PEQi. Also, the DRAM device includes a second memory cell array block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, pairs of second bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bj through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bj connected to the second memory cell array block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and second equalization circuits E<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> through E<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> for equalizing the pairs of the second bit-lines in response to a second equalization signal PEQj. Further, the DRAM device includes pairs of first isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, pairs of second isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, an isolation control circuit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, shared sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, a first switch SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a second switch SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The pairs of first isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> respond to the first isolation control signal PISOi and connect the pairs of the first bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bi to the shared sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or electrically isolate them from each other. The pairs of the second isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> respond to the second isolation control signal PISOj and connect the pairs of the second bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bj through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bj to the shared sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or electrically isolate them from each other. The pairs of the isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are formed with iMOS transistors. In the meantime, the isolation control circuit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> generates the first and second isolation control signals PISOi and PISOj. The construction and operation of an exemplary isolation control circuit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> will be described in detail with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The first switch SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is composed of a pMOS transistor and transmits the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray to the power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in response to the sense amplifier control signal LAPG. The second switch SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is illustrated as an nMOS transistor and transmits the ground voltage VSS to the ground voltage node LAB of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in response to the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal LAPG. The memory cell array power supply voltage Varray is typically a voltage that is reduced from an exterior power supply voltage Vdd that is supplied to the DRAM device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The shared sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> sense and amplify a voltage difference between the respective pairs of the first bit-lines or the respective pairs of the second bit-lines. Specifically, when the first isolation control signal PISOi is at the logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level and the second isolation control signal PISOj is at the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level, the pairs of the first isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are turned off and the pairs of the second isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> through T<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are turned on. As a result, the pairs of the first bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bi and the shared sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are separated from each other, whereas the pairs of the second bit-lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bj through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/bL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bj and the shared sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. Thereafter, the shared sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> sense a voltage difference between the respective pairs of the second bit lines BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bj through BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>Bj and amplify the same. The voltage difference is established across the bit lines using conventional reading operations that follow equalization of the bit lines to a voltage level of Vb<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> when the first equalization circuits E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-E<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are enabled. The construction and operation of the equalization circuits is well known to those skilled in the art and need not be described further herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The DRAM according to the present invention further includes a third switch SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> for transmitting the first isolation control signal PISOi to the power supply node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in response to a first control signal CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a fourth switch SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for transmitting the second isolation control signal PISOj to the power supply node LA of the sense amplifiers S <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in response to a second control signal CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> for generating the first and second control signals CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Here, nMOS transistors are used for the third and fourth switches SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, but pMOS transistors may also be used and may be preferred depending on the application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> generates the first and second control signals CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in response to the sense amplifier control signal LAPG, the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal and the first and second equalization signals PEQi and PEQi. The construction and operation of an exemplary control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> will be described in detail with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The DRAM device according to the present invention uses any one of the first and second isolation control signals PISOi and PISOj and the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray as power supply voltages. For instance, when the first control signal CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level, the third switch SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is turned on and the first isolation control signal PISOi is used together with the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray as power supply voltages of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, if the second control signal CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level, the fourth switch SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is turned on and the second isolation control signal PISOj and the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray are used as power supply voltages of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Thus, switches SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be used to provide additional pull-up drive current to node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a schematic diagram of the control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the control signal generation signal <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> includes a first control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> for generating the first control signal CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in response to the sense amplifier control signal LAPG, the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal and the second equalization signal PEQj, and a second control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> for generating the second control signal CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in response to the sense amplifier control signal LAPG, the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal and the first equalization signal PEQi. The first control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> includes a pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, an nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and an nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, connected as illustrated. In the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the second equalization signal PEQj is applied to a source, the sense amplifier control signal LAPG is applied to the gate and the drain is connected to an output node for generating the first control signal CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the drain is connected to the second equalization circuit PEQj, the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and the source is connected to the output node. Also, in the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the drain is connected to the output node, the sense amplifier control signal LAPG is applied to the gate and the ground voltage Vss is applied to the source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The second control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> includes a pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, an nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and an nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. In the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the first equalization signal PEQi is applied to its source, the sense amplifier control signal LAPG is applied to its gate and its drain is connected to an output node for generating the second control signal CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the first equalization signal PEQi is applied to its drain, the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal is applied to its gate and the source is connected to the output node (i.e., signal line CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). In the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the source is connected to the output node, the sense amplifier control signal LAPG is applied to the gate and the ground voltage Vss is applied to the source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows an example of the timing of the signals associated with the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the operations of the circuits shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 4</cross-reference> will now be described in more detail. When the equalization circuits E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-E<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are active, the first and second equalization signals PEQi and PEQj are at the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level, the sense amplifier control signal LAPG is at the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level and the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal is at the logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level. Then, the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are turned off, whereas the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are turned on. Thus, the first and second control signals CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are both logic &ldquo;low&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As a result, the third and fourth switches SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> are turned off. Also, the sense amplifier control signal LAPG is logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; and the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal is logic &ldquo;low&rdquo;, and therefore, the first and second switches SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned off, so that the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> do not function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Next, the second equalization signal PEQj is maintained at the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level, the first equalization signal PEQi is switched to the logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level, the sense amplifier control signal LAPG is switched to the logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level and the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal is switched to the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level. As a result, the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are turned on, whereas the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are turned off. Then, the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; value of the second equalization signal PEQj is transmitted via the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the first control signal CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> becomes logic &ldquo;high&rdquo;. Further, the logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; value of the first equalization signal PEQi is transmitted through the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the second control signal CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> becomes a logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As a result, the third switch SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is turned on and the fourth switch SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is turned off. At this time, since the sense amplifier control signal LAPG is at the logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; level and the inverted signal LANG of the sense amplifier control signal is at the logic &ldquo;high&rdquo; level, the first and second switches SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned on. Therefore, the first isolation control signal PISOi is transmitted to the power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> through the third switch SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray is transmitted to the power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> through the first switch SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. That is, the first isolation control signal PISOi and the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray are both used as separate power supply voltages of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In the meantime, if the second equalization signal PEQj is logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; and the first equalization signal PEQi is logic &ldquo;high&rdquo;, the first control signal CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; and the second control signal CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is logic &ldquo;high&rdquo;. As a result, the third and fourth switches SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, respectively, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> are turned off and on. Then, the second isolation control signal PISOj is transmitted to the power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> through the fourth switch SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray is transmitted to the power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> through the second switch SW<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. That is, the second isolation control signal PISOj and the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray are both used as separated power supply voltages of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Here, the first and second isolation signals PISOi and PISOj are generated by the isolation control circuit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> positioned in the peripheral circuit domain. The circuit diagram of the isolation control circuit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the isolation control circuit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> includes a first isolation control generation circuit <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> for generating the first isolation control signal PISOi in response to control signals BLEQj and BLSiDP and a second isolation control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> for generating the second isolation control signal PISOj in response to control signals BLEQi and BLSjDP. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The first isolation control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> includes pMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and nMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> through N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and the second isolation control signal generation signal <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> includes pMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and nMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> through N<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows an example of the timing of the signals shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a waveform diagram illustrating the operation of the sense amplifier in the DRAM device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>, the operation of the isolation control circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> and of the sense amplifiers shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> will now be explained more specifically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> At the initial stage, the control signals BLEQj, BLSiDP, BLEQi and BLSjDP are logic &ldquo;low&rdquo;, logic &ldquo;high&rdquo;, logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; and logic &ldquo;high&rdquo;, respectively. As a result, the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are turned on, so that the first isolation control signal PISOi is at the outside power supply voltage level Vdd, and the nMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the pMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are turned on, so that the second isolation control signal PISOj is also at the outside power supply voltage level Vdd. Thus, during the initial operation of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the first or second isolation control signal PISOi or PISOj, which are held at the outside power supply voltage Vdd level, is provided together with the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray to the power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the first and second isolation control signals PISOi and PISOj may be switched to a set-up voltage level Vpp and the ground voltage level Vss when the control signals BLEQj, BLSjDP, BLSiDP and BLEQi are maintained to be logic &ldquo;low&rdquo;, logic &ldquo;high&rdquo;, logic &ldquo;low&rdquo; and logic &ldquo;high&rdquo;, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As described above, during the initial operation of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the isolation control signal PISOi or PISOj at the external power supply voltage level Vdd is provided together with the memory cell array power supply voltage level Varray to the power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, in the DRAM according to the present invention, the operation of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can be enhanced even if the memory cell array power supply voltage Varray becomes low (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>). In other words, the power supply voltage level of the pair of bit lines BL/BLB can be amplified rapidly and completely. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The isolation control signal PISOi or PISOj having the outside power supply voltage Vdd level can be continuously provided to the power supply voltage node LA of the sense amplifiers S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> until the level of bit line BL reaches Vdd-Vthn. In the event that the level of the bit-line BL is beyond the above level, the NMOS transistors SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are automatically turned off, thereby preventing an excessive rise in the level of the bit line BL. Here, Vthn denotes the threshold voltage of the nMOS transistors SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, as described above with respect to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, methods of operating integrated circuit devices, such as multi-bank memory devices having multiple memory arrays therein, preferably include driving a power supply terminal LA of a differential sense amplifier (e.g., S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) with a plurality of pull-up drive currents derived from a corresponding plurality of signal lines. These signal lines, which are electrically coupled (e.g., by MOS pull-up transistors) to the power supply terminal LA of the differential sense amplifier S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, are driven at different positive voltage levels (Varray and (PISOi or PISOj)) during a sense and amplify time interval. These operations are performed by control circuitry that drives a power supply terminal LA of a differential sense amplifier (e.g., S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) with a plurality of pull-up drive currents derived from a corresponding plurality of signal lines (e.g, Varray and (PIOSi or PIOSj)) that are each electrically coupled to the power supply terminal LA of the differential sense amplifier (e.g, S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) and driven at different positive voltage levels during a sense and amplify time interval. This control circuit preferably includes a control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, an isolation control circuit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and MOS transistors SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> As illustrated by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, an integrated circuit memory device may include a sense amplifier S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having first and second inputs electrically coupled to a pair of differential signal lines. These differential signal lines may extend between current carrying terminals (e.g., source/drain regions) of a first pair of isolation transistors (e.g., T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) associated with a first memory cell array <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and current carrying terminals of a second pair of isolation transistors (T<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) associated with a second memory cell array <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A pull-up control circuit is included that provides pull-up drive currents in parallel from first and second voltage supply sources having different magnitudes to a power supply terminal LA of the sense amplifier S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> when the sense amplifier is amplifying a differential input signal established across the first and second inputs. The pull-up control circuit may comprise a control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and a plurality of switches (shown as SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). The pull-up control circuit may also be configured to include an isolation control circuit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The integrated circuit memory device of FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> may also be treated as including a sense amplifier (S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) having first and second inputs electrically coupled to a pair of differential signal lines. A first memory cell array <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> may be provided having a first pair of bit lines (BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bi) electrically coupled thereto. A first pair of isolation transistors (T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) is provided. These isolation transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> have a first pair of current carrying terminals that are electrically coupled to the pair of differential signal lines, a second pair of current carrying terminals that are electrically coupled to the first pair of bit lines (BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bi) and a pair of gate electrodes that are responsive to a first isolation control signal (PISOi) provided on a first isolation control signal line (PISOi). A first bit line equalization circuit (E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) is also provided. The first bit line equalization circuit is electrically coupled to the first pair of bit lines (BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bi) and is responsive to a first equalization signal (PEQi) provided on a first equalization signal line (PEQi). The memory device may also include a second memory cell array having a second pair of bit lines electrically coupled thereto. A second pair of isolation transistors is provided. This second pair of isolation transistors has a first pair of current carrying terminals that are electrically coupled to the pair of differential signal lines, a second pair of current carrying terminals that are electrically coupled to the second pair of bit lines and a pair of gate electrodes that are responsive to a second isolation control signal (PISOj) provided on a second isolation control signal line (PISOj). A second bit line equalization circuit (E<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) is provided. This circuit (E<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) is electrically coupled to the second pair of bit lines (BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>/BL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>Bj) and is responsive to a second equalization signal (PEQj) provided on a first equalization signal line (PEQj). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> A pull-up control circuit according to a preferred aspect of the present invention is also provided. The control circuit provides pull-up drive currents in parallel from first and second voltage supply sources having different magnitudes to a power supply terminal (LA) of the sense amplifier (S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) when the sense amplifier (S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) is amplifying a differential input signal established across the first and second inputs. The pull-up control circuit preferably includes a first MOS transistor (SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the first isolation control signal line (PISOi) and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal (LA) of the sense amplifier. The first MOS transistor (SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) is shown as an NMOS transistor, however, the first MOS transistor (SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) may also constitute a PMOS pull-up transistor. The pull-up control circuit also includes a second MOS transistor (SW<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). This second MOS transistor has a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to a memory array power supply line (Varray) and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of the sense amplifier. A third MOS transistor, which performs the function of a fourth switch SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, has a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the second isolation control signal line (PISOj) and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of the sense amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The pull-up control circuit also preferably includes a control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. This control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> drives gate electrodes of the first and third MOS transistors (SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and is responsive to the first and second equalization signals (PEQi, PEQj). As illustrated best by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> drives the gate electrode of the first MOS transistor (SW<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) with an active signal (e.g., CNT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&equals;1), subject to the constraint that the second equalization signal (PEQj) is active (e.g., PEQ;&equals;1). The control signal generation circuit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> also drives the gate electrode of the third MOS transistor (SW<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) with an active signal (e.g., CNT<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&equals;1), subject to the constraint that the first equalization signal (PEQi) is active (e.g., PEQi&equals;1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In the drawings and specification, there have been disclosed typical preferred embodiments of the invention and, although specific terms are employed, they are used in a generic and descriptive sense only and not for purposes of limitation, the scope of the invention being set forth in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of operating an integrated circuit device, comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>driving a power supply terminal of a differential sense amplifier with a plurality of pull-up drive currents that are provided by a corresponding plurality of signal lines that are driven at different positive voltage levels during a sense and amplify time interval. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the different positive voltage levels include an internal power supply voltage level and a voltage level that is greater than the internal power supply voltage level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of signal lines are electrically coupled to the power supply terminal by respective pull-up transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit device, comprising: 
<claim-text>control circuitry that drives a power supply terminal of a differential sense amplifier with a plurality of pull-up drive currents that are derived from a corresponding plurality of signal lines that are driven at different positive voltage levels during a sense and amplify time interval. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a sense amplifier having first and second inputs electrically coupled to a pair of differential signal lines; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pull-up control circuit that provides pull-up drive currents in parallel from first and second voltage supply sources having different magnitudes to a power supply terminal of said sense amplifier when said sense amplifier is amplifying a differential input signal established across the first and second inputs. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>first and second isolation transistors having first and second gate electrodes electrically coupled to an isolation control signal line; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said pull-up control circuit comprises a first MOS transistor having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the isolation control signal line and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of said sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first and second isolation transistors have first current carrying terminals that are electrically coupled to the pair of differential signal lines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pull-up control circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a second MOS transistor having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to a memory array power supply line and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of said sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a magnitude of the first voltage supply source is greater than a magnitude of the second voltage supply source; wherein the isolation control signal line electrically connects the first current carrying terminal of said first MOS transistor to the first voltage supply source; and wherein the memory array power supply line electrically connects the first current carrying terminal of said second MOS transistor to the second voltage supply source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a memory cell array; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pair of bit lines electrically coupled to said memory cell array and to second current carrying terminals of said first and second isolation transistors. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a first bit line equalization circuit that is electrically coupled to said first pair of bit lines and is responsive to a first equalization signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pull-up control circuit comprises a control signal generation circuit that drives a gate of said first MOS transistor and is responsive to the first equalization signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a sense amplifier having first and second inputs electrically coupled to a pair of differential signal lines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first memory cell array having a first pair of bit lines electrically coupled thereto; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pair of isolation transistors having a first pair of current carrying terminal that are electrically coupled to the pair of differential signal lines, a second pair of current carrying terminals that are electrically coupled to the first pair of bit lines and a pair of gate electrodes that are responsive to a first isolation control signal provided on a first isolation control signal line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first bit line equalization circuit that is electrically coupled to the first pair of bit lines and is responsive to a first equalization signal provided on a first equalization signal line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second memory cell array having a second pair of bit lines electrically coupled thereto; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pair of isolation transistors having a first pair of current carrying terminal that are electrically coupled to the pair of differential signal lines, a second pair of current carrying terminals that are electrically coupled to the second pair of bit lines and a pair of gate electrodes that are responsive to a second isolation control signal provided on a second isolation control signal line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second bit line equalization circuit that is electrically coupled to the second pair of bit lines and is responsive to a second equalization signal provided on a first equalization signal line; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pull-up control circuit that provides pull-up drive currents in parallel from first and second voltage supply sources having different magnitudes to a power supply terminal of said sense amplifier when said sense amplifier is amplifying a differential input signal established across the first and second inputs. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pull-up control circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a first MOS transistor having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the first isolation control signal line and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of said sense amplifier; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second MOS transistor having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to a memory array power supply line and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of said sense amplifier; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third MOS transistor having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the second isolation control signal line and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of said sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pull-up control circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a control signal generation circuit that drives gate electrodes of said first and third MOS transistors and is responsive to the first and second equalization signals. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said control signal generation circuit drives the gate electrode of said first MOS transistor with an active signal, subject to the constraint that the second equalization signal is active, and drives the gate electrode of said third MOS transistor with an active signal, subject to the constraint that the first equalization signal is active. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a sense amplifier having first and second inputs electrically coupled to a first pair of differential signal lines; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pull-up control circuit electrically coupled to a power supply terminal of said sense amplifier, said pull-up control circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pull-up transistor having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of said sense amplifier and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to a first power supply signal line; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pull-up transistor having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to the power supply terminal of said sense amplifier and a second current carrying terminal electrically coupled to a signal line that receives a boosted voltage signal when said sense amplifier is amplifying a differential input signal across the first and second inputs. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first pull-up transistor comprises a PMOS transistor; and wherein said second pull-up transistor comprises a NMOS transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The memory device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first and second pull-up transistors comprises PMOS transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a differential sense amplifier; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control circuit that drives a positive power supply terminal of said differential sense amplifier with a boosted voltage level that is also provided to a gate electrode of an isolation transistor having a first current carrying terminal electrically coupled to an input of said differential sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a differential sense amplifier having first and second inputs electrically coupled to a pair of differential signal lines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of isolation transistors having first current carrying terminals electrically coupled to the pair of differential signal lines; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch electrically coupled in series in an electrical path extending between a gate of at least one of said pair of isolation transistors and a power supply terminal of said differential sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device comprising: 
<claim-text>a memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of bit lines connected to the memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sense amplifier for sensing and amplifying a voltage difference between the pair of the bit lines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of isolation transistors for connecting the pair of bit lines and the sense amplifiers or isolating them from each other in response to an isolation control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switch for transmitting a memory cell array power supply voltage to a power supply voltage node of the sense amplifiers in response to a sense amplifier control signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switch for transmitting the isolation control signal to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to a predetermined control signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the memory cell array power supply voltage and the isolation control signal are used as power supply voltages of the sense amplifiers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second switch comprises an nMOS transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second switch comprises a pMOS transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device comprising: 
<claim-text>a first memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of first bit lines connected to the first memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of second bit lines connected to the second memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sense amplifier for sensing and amplifying a voltage difference between the pair of first or second bit lines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of first isolation transistors for connecting the pair of first bit lines and the sense amplifiers or isolating them from each other in response to a first isolation control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of second isolation transistors for connecting the pair of second bit lines and the sense amplifiers or isolating them from each other in response to a second isolation control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switch for transmitting the memory cell array power supply voltage to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to a sense amplifier control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switch for transmitting the first isolation control signal to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to a first control signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third switch for transmitting the second isolation control signal to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to a second control signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein any one of the first isolation control signal and the second isolation control signal, as well as the memory cell array power supply voltage, is used as a power supply voltage of the sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a first equalization unit for equalizing the pair of first bit lines in response to a first equalization signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second equalization unit for equalizing the pair of second bit lines in response to a second equalization signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first control signal generation circuit for generating the first control signal in response to the sense amplifier control signal, an inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal and the second equalization signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second control signal generation circuit for generating the second control signal in response to the sense amplifier control signal, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal and the first equalization signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second and third switches comprise NMOS transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first control signal generation circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a pMOS transistor in which the second equalization signal is applied to any one of the source or drain, the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and any one of the source or drain is connected to an output node for generating the first control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first nMOS transistor in which the second equalization signal is applied to any one of the source or drain, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and any one of the source or drain is connected to the output node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second NMOS transistor in which any one of the source or drain is connected to the output node, the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and a ground voltage is applied to any one of the source or drain. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second control signal generation circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a pMOS transistor in which the first equalization signal is applied to any one of the source or drain, the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and any one of the source or drain is connected to an output node for outputting the second control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first nMOS transistor in which the first equalization signal is applied to any one of the source or drain, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and any one of the source or drain is connected to the output node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second nMOS transistor in which any one of the source or drain is connected to the output node, the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and the ground voltage is applied to any one of the source or drain. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second and third switches comprise pMOS transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device comprising: 
<claim-text>a first memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of first bit lines connected to the first memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of second bit lines connected to the second memory cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first equalization unit for equalizing the pair of first bit lines in response to the first equalization signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second equalization unit for equalizing the pair of second bit lines in response to the second equalization signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sense amplifier for sensing and amplifying a voltage difference between the pair of the first bit lines or the pair of the second bit lines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of first isolation transistors for connecting the pair of first bit lines and the sense amplifier or separating the pairs of first bit lines from the pair input by the sense amplifier in response to a first isolation control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of second isolation transistors for connecting the pair of the second bit lines and the sense amplifier or isolating them from each other in response to a second isolation control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switch for transmitting the memory cell array power supply voltage to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to the sense amplifier control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switch for transmitting the first isolation control signal to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to a first control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third switch for transmitting the second isolation control signal to the power supply voltage node of the sense amplifier in response to the second control signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control signal generation circuit for generating the first and second control signals in response to the sense amplifier control signal, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal and the first and second equalization signals. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the control signal generation circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a first control signal generation circuit for generating the first control signal in response to the sense amplifier control signal, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal and the second equalization signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second control generation circuit for generating the second control signal in response to the sense amplifier control signal, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal and the first equalization signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second and third switches comprise nMOS transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first control signal generation circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a pMOS transistor in which the second equalization signal is applied to any one of the source or drain, the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and any one of the source or drain is connected to an output node for outputting the first control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first nMOS transistor in which the second equalization signal is applied to any one of the source or drain, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and any one of the source or drain is connected to the output node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second nMOS transistor in which any one of the source or drain is connected to the output node, the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and the ground voltage is applied to any one of the source or drain. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second control signal generation circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a pMOS transistor in which the first equalization signal is applied to any one of the source or drain, the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and any one of the source or drain is connected to an output node for outputting the second control signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first NMOS transistor in which the first equalization signal is applied to any one of the source or drain, the inverted signal of the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and any one of the source or drain is connected to the output node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second NMOS transistor in which any one of the source or drain is connected to the output node, the sense amplifier control signal is applied to the gate and the ground voltage is applied to any one of the source or drain. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor memory device as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second and third switches comprise pMOS transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002353A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002353A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002353A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002353A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002353A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002353A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002353A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002353A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
