<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001876A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001876A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001876</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10179948</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020626</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>90115501</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G09G005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>345</class>
<subclass>709000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>345</class>
<subclass>771000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>System using graphic interface to perform stock management</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kuang-Shin</given-name>
<family-name>Lin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jeff</given-name>
<family-name>Song</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yi-Song</given-name>
<family-name>Li</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tianjin</city>
<country-code>CN</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BIRCH STEWART KOLASCH &amp; BIRCH</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO BOX 747</address-1>
<city>FALLS CHURCH</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22040-0747</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system that uses a graphic interface to perform stock management is disclosed. It is comprised of a database to store data needed for stock management and to link each of the following modules to perform stock management using the graphic interface. The modules include a stock allocation designing module, which helps a user decide the size of a stock, storage areas, storage space and relevant attributes according to practical needs; a data receiving module, which receives the data of the stock, the storage areas, the storage space and a plurality of goods; a stock layout generating module, which plots a stock layout according to the data received by the data receiving module; a stock operating module, which displays messages corresponding to the operations the user has performed on the stock layout; and a data storage module, which saves the results of the operations performed on the stock layout by the user in the database. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a stock management system and, in particular, to a system that uses a graphic interface to perform stock management. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In conventional production-distribution systems, stock performs the roles of &ldquo;storage&rdquo; and &ldquo;maintenance&rdquo;. However, under the pressures of new consumer demands, huge amounts of complicated data, and competitive markets, goods must enter and leave a stock system in a rapid and complicated manner so as to achieve proper timing and satisfy the market&apos;s requirements of quantity and variety. Therefore, a dynamic management function for stock systems has become more important than the simple maintenance function in conventional stock. The dynamic management function combines the conventional stock system and the currently popular data warehouse system. The purpose of such a combination is to plan and manage storage space so as to effectively control the sources, destinations and fluctuations of goods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Along with the changes in the consumer market, the industry faces a competitive environment with rapid changes, low inventory (null inventory), fast responses, and high customer satisfaction guarantee requirements. A complete supply chain system is a key factor for a company&apos;s success. In particular, the designs of the stock and distribution network systems determine the operational efficiency of the whole supply chain system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In the prior art, the applications of data warehousing focus on providing accurate and integrated data to the marketing, financial, stocking, manufacturing, and other units in the enterprise that are in need of information to make decisions. Information established by each operating unit in the enterprise can provide a knowledge database for employees to search. This is particularly useful in providing integrated observations of the enterprise such as integrated sales, manufacturing and inventory data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> However, conventional data warehousing systems have a data updating cycle of one month or one week, and data searches and modifications are usually initiated within a group-oriented environment (sometimes completed by manual operations). These processes often take quite a long time. Thus, typical applications can be processed in real time during the daytime. Such batch tasks as client classification, inventory management, distribution flows, profit computations, and predictive model estimations and analyses cannot be fed back into the operating system within a short period of time to serve as references for better decisions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, applications of data warehousing will greatly enlarge the scope of the technology in the field. Event estimations for online users should be done quickly and a minimal response time is required. Such requirements must be implemented in the conventional decision-supported large database and should apply to complicated searches. In addition, data access has to be closer to a real-time response than conventional data warehousing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Nowadays, many stock management systems do not have a sufficient number of functions. Without a client operating interface, the following situations occur: (a) the client rents space from a host stock and directly operates using the client&apos;s stock management system; (b) the client does not use its own stock management system and the host enters data for the client; and (c) stock operation information is entered repeatedly (in both the client and the host systems). This is all because the production distribution information cannot be transmitted or shared, causing a cycle of bad production distribution quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In current production distribution systems or warehouse management systems, table views or table browsers are widely used to organize and manipulate data. Although table views are detailed and well organized, the data presentation is not intuitive and the data are difficult to manipulate. To obtain useful information one usually needs to go through complicated searches or inspection. Even if auxiliary means such as circle graphs, curve graphs, or rectangular graphs are employed, the user can only roughly understand the situation without being able to complete meaningful operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, an intuitive, simple and graphic operation management interface is an urgent need in stock management systems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The invention provides a stock management system using a graphic interface. An objective of the invention is that the graphic interface is used to implement stock management designs and provide access to messages. It reflects actual storage areas, storage locations and sizes, and the quantities and status of goods. It also implements maintenance to the system. One can perform storage location moves and mergers for stock goods through the graphic interface. Reasonable rules are also provided for database modifications and maintenance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Another objective of the invention is to automatically suggest storage location moves and mergers that satisfy the rules so as to consolidate stock space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The disclosed stock management system using a graphic interface contains at least a database to store data needed for stock management and to link each of the following modules to perform stock management using the graphic interface. The modules include a warehouse allocation designing module, which helps a user decide the size of a stock, its storage areas, its storage space and other relevant attributes according to practical needs; a data receiving module, which receives the data of the stock, the storage areas, the storage space and a plurality of goods; a stock layout generating module, which plots a stock layout according to the data received by the data receiving module; a stock operating module, which displays messages corresponding to the operations the user has performed on the stock layout; and a data storage module, which saves the results of the operations performed on the stock layout by the user in the database.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The invention will become more fully understood from the detailed description given hereinbelow. However, this description is for purposes of illustration only, and thus is not limitative of the invention, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of the main functional modules in the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the stock allocation designing module of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flowchart of the data-receiving module of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a local stock; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flowchart of the stock layout-generating module; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flowchart of the stock layout-operating module; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flowchart of the data storing module; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic view showing a preferred embodiment of stock management.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Any successful data warehouse application must be combined with functions for stock management. This necessarily requires improvement in order to make substantial contributions to a successful enterprise. Thus, active data warehousing has become an important subject that provides new functions to the enterprise mainstream. The main challenge in establishing an active data warehouse application lies in providing an immediate response time for approximate trade variations estimated online that can satisfy the real-time requirements of the supplier, the inventory and the customer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> However, the invention utilizes a graphic interface to implement stock designs and to provide an intuitive display for stock data. A user can perform stock data maintenance, and since the graphic interface reflects the situation clearly and accurately, the user can easily understand the details of a stock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The main functional modules of the invention are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, which includes a stock allocation designing module <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a database <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, a data receiving module <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a stock layout generating module <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, a stock layout operating module <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, and a data storage module <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The stock allocation designing module <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is an independent module for the user to design the size of the stock, its storage areas and storage locations, and other relevant parameters according to practical needs. The database <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> stores data for stock management. The data receiving module <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> receives messages of the stock, the storage areas, the storage location and good data. The stock layout generating module <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> plots a stock layout according to the messages received by the data receiving module <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The stock layout operating module <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> displays messages corresponding to the operations done by the user on the stock layout and completes the designated functions. The data storage module <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> stores the results of the operations done by the user on the stock layout in the database. The function and detailed procedure of each of the above-mentioned modules are described as follows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> (1) The stock allocation designing module <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> This module is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Rulers <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> are provided along a vertical axis and a horizontal axis for the user to locate a storage area. A stock message panel <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is used to display stock related messages, such as the warehouse code, the stock name, the stock specifications, and the storage base sizes. Moreover, an ADD/MODIFY button <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> is provided to add and/or modify the design of the storage locations. The storage area graph <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> reflects actual storage locations and sizes. The storage area message panel <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> has detailed messages about the storage area, such as the storage area number, the row number, the column number, the initial point, and the customer name. Through the function of plotting a new storage area <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, a new storage area can be generated according to the messages entered by the user, and the corresponding storage area graph is formed. A DELETE button <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> is also provided to delete a designated storage area. The corresponding messages in the database <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> are also deleted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> (2) The data receiving module <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> This module is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Data search conditions are first formed in step <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> to obtain messages of the stock and commodities. The database is then opened in step <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> to obtain the required data. Afterwards, data are processed in step <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> to produce the data needed for processing the stock layout. Finally, the data are sent to the stock layout-generating module <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. The data receiving procedure is thus completed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> (3) The stock layout generating module <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> storage area <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight> refers to a partitioned area in a stock. Each storage area is further divided into M rows and N columns, accommodating M*N commodity bases, where M and N are natural numbers. A storage location <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> refers to one row in a storage area <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, which is one unit for disposing goods. A storage location status legend bar <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight> is further provided to display the status of a stock layout. Possible statuses include vacant storage locations, occupied storage locations, delivery lock-in, arrival lock-in, item moving-out, and item moving-in labeled by different icons or colors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The procedure of this module is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. A stock background graph is plotted in appropriate proportions according to the stock messages, and the stock messages are stored (step <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>). Storage areas are then plotted in proportion within the stock background graph and the storage area messages are stored (step <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>). Afterwards, storage locations are plotted within the storage areas (step <highlight><bold>503</bold></highlight>). In accordance with the storage location messages, the storage locations can be both horizontal and vertical. Therefore, they have to be processed independently. Each non-vacant storage location has one type of item. The information about the item in the storage location is stored in step <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. Finally, the storage location status is set in step <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>. Different colors and icons are used to represent different item statuses. For example, green icons indicate vacant storage locations, red ones indicate lock-in status of the delivery and arrival of goods, and blue ones indicate normal occupied storage locations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> (4) The warehouse layout operation module <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The procedure of this module is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Through the user operations (step <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>), a user can choose the functions for selecting an occupied storage location (step <highlight><bold>601</bold></highlight>), selecting a vacant storage location (step <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>), performing storage location adjustment (step <highlight><bold>603</bold></highlight>), and selecting an adjusted storage location (step <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> When the user selects an occupied storage location in step <highlight><bold>601</bold></highlight>, the system obtains detailed storage location and commodity data. After the selection, the commodity information is shown in the message area (step <highlight><bold>605</bold></highlight>) for the user&apos;s reference. At the same time, the commodity information is stored according to the user&apos;s selection (step <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>) so that the user can adjust the stock data in the next step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The user can select a vacant storage location in step <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. The system stores the user&apos;s selection as the adjustment information (step <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>) for the user to adjust the stock data in the next step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> If the user performs the storage location adjustment using the method provided by the system (step <highlight><bold>603</bold></highlight>), certain rules are used to determine whether an adjustment is legitimate (step <highlight><bold>607</bold></highlight>). If illegitimate, the system displays the reason why (step <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>). If legitimate, then relevant storage location statuses are changed on the stock layout (step <highlight><bold>609</bold></highlight>). The data storage module is then called to adjust the database contents (step <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> If the user first selects an adjusted storage location (step <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>) and then cancels the storage location adjustment operation (step <highlight><bold>611</bold></highlight>), the system cancels previously completed adjustments. The data storage module is then called to adjust the database contents (step <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The user can also utilize the automatic suggestion function for the system to follow certain rules and user defined settings to list all allowed adjustment contents so that the user can determine whether an adjustment is needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The above-mentioned rules include: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> 1. Different goods cannot be in the same storage location; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> 2. The combination date for the same goods cannot surpass a predetermined interval limit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> 3. The quantities after the storage location combination cannot exceed the capacity of the storage locations; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> 4. The goods quantity disposed in a vacant storage location cannot exceed the capacity of the vacant storage location; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> 5. Delivery and arrival locked-in goods cannot be adjusted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> (5) The data storage module <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The procedure of this module is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Step <highlight><bold>701</bold></highlight> follows the user&apos;s operation contents to obtain data that need to be modified and stored. Step <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> generates search conditions. Step <highlight><bold>703</bold></highlight> then stores the modified contents in the database. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic view showing a preferred embodiment of stock management. It illustrates that a graphic interface is used for a logistics distribution stock management subsystem. The subsystem can utilize user-friendly visual effects to satisfy users&apos; requirements for checking stock conditions and adjusting stock data. The user can use a mouse or other clicking control devices, such as a digital touch-control panel or keyboard, to select an occupied storage location <highlight><bold>801</bold></highlight>. The user can simultaneously refer to displayed item information <highlight><bold>802</bold></highlight> and storage location numbers <highlight><bold>803</bold></highlight>. An adjustment icon <highlight><bold>804</bold></highlight> can be used to adjust the user-designated selection. A recovery icon <highlight><bold>805</bold></highlight> can undo the user&apos;s adjustment. These actions are completed through the graphic interface. The corresponding messages in the database <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> (referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) are also updated. The adjusted storage location <highlight><bold>806</bold></highlight> can be tagged by the corresponding icon or color. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The invention being thus described, it will be obvious that the same may be varied in many ways. Such variations are not to be regarded as a departure from the spirit and scope of the invention, and all such modifications as would be obvious to one skilled in the art are intended to be included within the scope of the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A stock management system using an graphical interface, which comprises: 
<claim-text>a database, which stores data for the stock management and links each of the following modules for performing the graphical interface stock management; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a warehouse allocation designing module, which allows a user to design the sizes of a stock, its storage areas and storage locations along with relevant parameters according to practical needs; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a data receiving module, which receives the data of the stock, the storage areas, the storage locations and a plurality of goods; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a stock layout generating module, which plots a warehouse layout according to the data received by the data receiving module; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a warehouse layout operating module, which displays message corresponding to the operations done by the user to the warehouse layout; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a data storing module, which stores the warehouse layout operations done by the user in the database. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the warehouse allocation designing module includes horizontal and vertical rulers for the user to determine the locations of the storage areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the storage allocation designing module further contains a warehouse message panel to display messages about the warehouse. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the warehouse message panel shows a warehouse code, a warehouse name, a warehouse specification and a storage base specification. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the storage allocation designing module further includes a warehouse ADD/MODIFY button to add and modify the design of the storage locations. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the warehouse allocation designing module further includes a storage area diagram to reflect the locations and sizes of actual storage areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the warehouse allocation designing module further includes a storage area message panel to record detailed information of the storage areas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the storage area message panel shows a storage area number, a row number, a column number, an initial point and a client name. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the data receiving module executes the steps of: 
<claim-text>generating data search conditions to obtain the information of the warehouse and the good; </claim-text>
<claim-text>opening the database to obtain the required data; </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing data to generate data satisfying the warehouse layout processing requirements; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the data to the warehouse layout generating module, thus completing data reception. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the operation interface generated by the warehouse layout generating further contains a plurality of storage areas for disposing a plurality of item storage bases. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of storage areas further contains a plurality of storage locations, each being a unit for storing goods. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the operation interface generated by the warehouse layout generating module further contains a storage location status legend bar for displaying the statuses of the storage locations in the warehouse layout. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the storage location status legend bar shows possible statuses of vacant storage locations, occupied storage locations, delivery lock-in, arrival lock-in, item moving-out, and item moving-in labeled by different icons or colors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the stock layout generating module executes the steps of: 
<claim-text>plotting a warehouse background graph in an appropriate proportion according to the stock data and storing the stock data; </claim-text>
<claim-text>plotting the storage areas in proportion according to the stock background graph and storing the storage location data; </claim-text>
<claim-text>plotting the storage locations in the storage area graphs and performing horizontal and vertical storage location processing according to the storage location data; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting the status of each of the storage locations by providing different colors and icons. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the stock layout operating module performs an operation selected from the group comprising selecting an occupied storage location, selecting a vacant storage location, adjusting a storage location, and selecting an adjusted storage location. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the data storing module executes the steps of: 
<claim-text>obtaining data that need to be modified and stored according to the user&apos;s operation contents; </claim-text>
<claim-text>generating search conditions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the modified data to the database.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001876A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
