<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000540A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000540A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000540A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000540A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000540A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000540A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000540A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000540A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000540</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10181711</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020722</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-392193</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001225</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A41G003/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A41G005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>132</class>
<subclass>201000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>132</class>
<subclass>053000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Artificial hair material, hair restoring apparatus, and hair restoring method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Masahiro</given-name>
<family-name>Makino</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mayumi</given-name>
<family-name>Sekizaki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Makiko</given-name>
<family-name>Tsuruma</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>WENDEROTH, LIND &amp; PONACK, L.L.P.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2033 K STREET N. W.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 800</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20006-1021</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/JP01/11273</doc-number>
<document-date>20011221</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An artificial hair restorer has a trunk hair with plural restoring hairs fixed to at a certain point of the trunk hair, a loop formed by folding one or two trunk hair(s) in two through which the original hair(s) passes(pass) at one end, and a knot close to the tying point end of the restoring hairs but opposite to the loop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">A hair restoring method comprises step of inserting one or plural of the original hair(s) into the loop <highlight><bold>3 </bold></highlight>of the trunk hair and then fixing it to the point in the vicinity of the original hair root. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to an artificial hair restorer, a hair restoring apparatus and a hair restoring method for tying and fixing natural or artificial hairs on one or several original hair(s) of the head. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> It&apos;s been prevalent to wear wigs when the number of one&apos;s hair diminishes and he or she becomes thin on top by alopecia, a burn or a scald and so on. But wearing wigs is bothering, and many methods for restoring the hair by tying artificial hairs to the remained original hairs as a base and then grooming to look natural have been invented and put to practical use these days. Commonly in these hair restorings, one or several artificial hairs of synthetic fibers are tied to one original hair of the head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> For example, in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. Showa 61-97409, there discloses a hair restoring method wherein one or two artificial hair(s) is(are) fixed around one hair root of the original hair by using an adhesive or by Wa (overhand) knotting. But in this method, each of the original hair has to bear relatively large load since the artificial hairs are tied and fixed to its root with fingers. Furthermore, since the several artificial hairs are fixed in one place, the ball of knotting or adhesive yields so that one&apos;s hairs might entangle with a comb. Those are inconvenient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. Heisei 2-264005, there discloses a hair restoring method in which some split hairs are glued to one trunk hair with an adhesive at certain intervals and this trunk hair in turn is glued to the original hair with an adhesive, i.e. one trunk hair with some split hairs is glued around the original hair root. With this attachment method using the adhesive, the bonding work has to be done over again because of the deterioration in adhesive, and there&apos;s a limit in the number of the split hairs capable of gluing to the trunk hair. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Further, a hair restoring method in Japanese Utility Model Laid-open Publication No. Heisei 3-78019 comprises steps of making several loops at certain intervals with an artificial trunk hair, inserting an original hair through each of the loops, and fixing the loops to the original hair with an adhesive wherein said trunk hair is placed in the vicinity of the original hair roots along the skin of the head. In other words, it comprises steps of inserting the original hair through each of the loops and fixing therebetween with an adhesive. However, with this method, since one trunk hair is glued to adjoining some original hairs, the comb may entangle with the trunk hair or the original hairs at the time of combing after hair restoring. This is inconvenient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A hair restoring method in Japanese Patent Publication No. Heisei 4-15285 comprises steps of arranging one or two thread-like supporting base (trunk hair) in a straight line along the skin of the head, transplanting the split hairs for restoring to the thread-like supporting base uprightly, and adhering the base to the original hair with a special adhesive. With this hair restoring method wherein the thread-like supporting base to which the plural of spilt hairs are transplanted uprightly is arranged along the skin of the head, it is still inconvenient in hair combing, because the comb may catch the supporting base. This is inconvenient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> There are still other hair restoring methods in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication Nos. Heisei 5-156506, Heisei 7-173704 and Heisei 11-217715. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A hair restoring method in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. Heisei 5-156506 (Japanese Patent Publication No. Heisei 7-96722) comprises steps of making a knot with an original hair near the root thereof, and tying the restoring hair directly to the original hair between the skin and the knot. This tying step includes steps of tying many restoring hairs to a pipe, passing the original hair through the pipe, and adhering the restoring hairs to the original hair passing therethrough after moving them aside the pipe. However, the knotting of the original hair is so difficult that the original hair can be harmed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The invention disclosed in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. Heisei 7-173704 relates to a hear fixing tool for attaching one restoring hair to the original hair. Thus, one or two restoring hair(s) folded in two is(are) loosely tied on a guidestick pipe, then the holding member which projects at the tip of the guide pipe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is fixed close to the original hair root, and finally the loosened knots of the restoring hair are moved along the guide pipe to adhere it with the original hair. With this method, since plural of restoring hairs are adhered to one original hair, the original hair has to bear large load. And, the number of the restoring hairs capable of adhering to one original hair is limited as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Further, the hair restoring method in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. Heisei 11-217715 relates to a method wherein the restoring hairs with cuticles are adhered to one original hair at certain intervals. As a result, more voluminous hair restoring can be obtained comparing to one with using one or two normal restoring hair(s). With this method, since plural of restoring hairs with cuticle are adhered to one original hair, the original hair has to bear large load, and therefore the plural number of the restoring hairs can not be adhered to the original hair after all. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the invention disclosed in Japanese Patent No. 2951259 relates to a hairpiece made by putting the restoring hairs in flat, folding them in two, putting the doubled parts, in belt-like fashion, and then curling these restoring hairs with the belt-like connecting part as their centers. The belt-like connection parts of this hairpiece are attached to the original hairs to get hair restoring effect. However, since big hairpiece is to be attached to plural of the original hairs in this case, people can easily see that the hair has been restored due to unusual appearance at the curled part of the restoring hair comparing to the original hair. This is a fault. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> As mentioned above, the prior art hair restoring methods are to fit plural restoring hairs directly to the original hair or to put the trunk hair with some restoring hairs along the skin of the head and adhere some original hairs to this trunk hair with an adhesive. And there still remain a lot of weak points as hair restoring methods. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> An object of this invention is to provide an artificial hair restorer that can be fitted to original hair(s) easily and has a superior effect in hair restoring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Other object of this invention is to provide a hair restoring apparatus that can easily tie the artificial hair restorer that consists of the trunk hairs, to which plural of restoring hairs are tied, to one or more original hairs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Another object of this invention is provide a hair restoring method wherein the load to the original hair(s) is(are) lessened and hair restoring effect is securely obtained by tying the artificial hair restorer of trunk hairs with plural restoring hairs to one or several original hair(s). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The above objects are achieved by an artificial hair restorer consisting of a trunk hair with plural restoring hairs tied to a certain point thereof and a loop at its one end; an artificial hair restorer with plural restoring hairs tied to predetermined point, a loop at its one end and a knot close to the tying point end of said restoring hairs but opposite to said loop; or an artificial hair restorer wherein the loop is formed at the doubled parts of one to several trunk hair(s) or is provided by folding said trunk hair(s). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> And the above mentioned objects are achieved by a hair restoring method; a method comprising a step of attaching and fixing said artificial hair restorer to one or plural original hair(s) in the vicinity of its(their) root(s) by inserting the original hair(s) into a loop formed at one end of said trunk hair and fastening therebetween while plural of restoring hairs being fixed to the trunk hair, or a method comprising a step of attaching and fixing said artificial hair restorer to one or plural original hair(s) by adhering the former to the later at the tying point. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> And furthermore, the above mentioned object is achieved by a hair restoring method comprising steps of tying loosely an artificial hair restorer at a certain point on a fitting bar after inserting the fitting bar through the loop formed to the end of said artificial hair restorer, sliding this loosely tying loop along the fitting bar to set aside the fitting bar so that the original hair(s), which passes(pass) through the ring at the end of the fitting bar having the bar part, passes(pass) through the loop of the artificial hair restorer, pulling both ends of this artificial trunk hair oppositely to tightly tie the artificial hair restorer to the original hair(s). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a hair restoring apparatus having a fitting bar and a thread like line provided at one end of the fitting bar to make a ring through which one or plural original hair(s) passes(pass), said fitting bar is to be inserted through a loop of an artificial hair restorer of a trunk hair, to whose one end plural restoring hairs are tied, or a loop of an artificial hair restorer formed at the turn of the folded trunk hair, to whose one end plural restoring hairs are tied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The fitting bar is inserted trough the loop or loose tie part of the trunk hair of the artificial hair restorer so that this artificial hair restorer is loosely tied thereon. The present hair restoring apparatus is obtained by repeating the above at the plural positions in a certain interval. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In the artificial hair restorer according to the present invention, as one trunk hair is tied to plural, i.e. several to dozens of restoring hairs and has a loop at one end, it is very easy to mount this loop to the fitting bar, and more, to tie and fix the artificial hair restorer to the 1-4 original hairs by the hair restoring apparatus to which many artificial hair restorers are mounted, and therefore hair restoring is simple. And when the knot is formed outside and opposite to the loop that is at the end of the connecting point of the restoring hairs to the artificial trunk hair, the restoring hairs can be prevented from falling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Since the hair restoring method according to the present invention comprises the steps of inserting the bar part or part of the fitting bar through the loop of the 1-2 trunk hair(s) of the artificial hair restorer to which several to dozens of the restoring hairs are fixed, loosely tying the plural artificial hair restorers to the fitting bar, sliding this loop along and off the bar part to the ring of its end, making it tangled with and tightly tying to the original hair(s) which is(are) inserted through the thread-like line which makes the ring at the bar part. So the artificial hair restorer isn&apos;t only adhered to the original hair with an adhesive but also tied and fixed to the original hair root by using its loop. In this manner, since plural restoring hairs can be fixed to one or more original hair(s), the hair with the restoring hairs looks voluminous. And furthermore, it is not need to fear that the adhesive melts into the water at the time of shampooing, which results in fallen hairs, because the artificial hair restorer having the restoring hairs is tieded and fixed to the original hair.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION TO THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view of an embodiment of a hair restoring apparatus adopted in the hair restoring method according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a pictorial view explaining how the artificial hair restorer is tied to the fitting bar of the hair restoring apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D are pictorial views for explaining a method for tying and fixing the artificial hair restorer to the original hair by using the hair restoring apparatus according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the enlarged plan view for showing the connecting part of the original hair and the artificial hair restorer with using a hair restoring method according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is the rough pictorial view showing the skin of the head to be restored hairs by this invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">THE BEST MODE CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Now, detailed explanation will be made with reference to the drawings showing preferred embodiments of the artificial hair restorer and the hair restoring method according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A hair restoring apparatus illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> has plural of artificial hair restorers <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> loosely tied at a certain interval to the outer periphery of the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The fitting bar with a bar part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is a fitting tool which is like a plastic straw or bar member. Plural restoring hairs <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are tied and fixed to the trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that is a part of the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The loop <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> formed at the turn of the trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is loosely tied to the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The way of tying, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, forms the loop <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> at the turn of one trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is loosely tied to the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> so as to make the loop <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> therearound. In this case, to prevent the tying parts arranged at a certain interval from getting entangled, plural grooves <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are formed on the outer surface of the bar part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which avoids the loosely tying knots from moving aside easily. This fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be as a bar, but it&apos;s convenient to use if it&apos;s tubular in form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> To the trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of this artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the knot <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is formed at one end side and plural restoring hairs <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are tied and fixed between this knot <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the loop <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of this artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be one string of an artificial hair. However, it&apos;s better to bind two of them together with an adhesive. The trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>made by tying this way gets its adhesive melted at the time of shampooing, gets loose and goes back to two hairs bringing a lot for the effect of hair restoring. No restoring hair <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is tied to the opposite end side of the turn of the trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of this artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The both ends of the thread-like nylon line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, which forms a ring, are fixed to the end of the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Especially if the bar part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is formed as a pipe, the both ends of the thread-like line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> can be inserted inside of the pipe and fixed, and the loose loop or knot can be slide or moved laterally. This thread-like line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is preferably to be made of synthetic fiber. The original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is(are) inserted in the ring of the thread-like line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The restoring hairs <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> fixed to the trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are tied being folded in two. This restoring hair <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is to be as thick as the original hair <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, i.e. about 0.08 mm thick. The ratio of the restoring hairs to the original hair <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> can be properly adjusted according to the state of the fallen hairs. The number of the restoring hairs <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> fixed to one trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is not fixed, but the number that is easiest to fit is about ten, i.e. twenty restoring hairs <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are attached to the trunk hair <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, because they are folded in two. The number of the restoring hairs is not limited to this number, so twenty of them or forty of them by folding in two again is also acceptable with taking the effect of hair restoring as a whole into consideration. These artificial hair restorers <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are arranged and loosely tied at a certain interval to the bar part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG.1</cross-reference>. Reference number <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrates the skin of the head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Then, a hair restoring method with using the hair restoring apparatus of the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, to which the artificial hair restorers <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> with plural restoring hairs <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are loosely tied, will be explained as follows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the method comprises the steps of making one to four of the original hairs <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> (after putting them together and bound when plural of hairs) pass through the ring of the thread-like line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> which is formed at the end of the bar part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, picking up the loop <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which is loosely tied to the bar part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the fitting bar, with the fingers, moving it along the bar part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the ring of the thread-like line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), and drawing the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> into the loop <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by pulling the fitting bar <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> so that the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is(are) folded in two at the loop <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>) and is (are) unfolded to let the free end of the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> protrude out of the loop (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>). The number of the original hairs to be passing through this loop isn&apos;t limited, but one to four is proper, for the knot will be too big with more than eight of them. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> By getting the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> down to the point close to the root of the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, tying the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> as shown in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, and pulling the ends A and B in the opposite direction to get the knot <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> stiffer and tying the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> with plural restoring hairs <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. After restoring the hair partially by fitting the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to some points of the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in this way, the tips are trimmed with a cutting tool as scissors to unify the length of the original hairs <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the restoring hair <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> (a dotted line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> If needed, adhesive is applied at the knot <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and is hardened after predetermined time of curing to firmly secure the artificial hair restorer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The adhesive force decreases after certain days due to fat from the cortex or sweat and therefore it needs to loosen the knot <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and get it down to the point close to the root of the original hair(s) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In this way, the hair restoring method of the present invention capable of fitting and tying plural restoring hairs to the original hair(s) with the simple hair restoring apparatus, to restore the hair entirely voluminous by tying a lot of artificial hair restorers <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to adjoining original hairs. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">INDUSTRIAL POSSIBILITY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As it&apos;s tied a few to dozens of restoring hairs to its trunk hair, the artificial hair restorer of the present invention capable of restoring the hair voluminously when it is fixed to the original hair(s), and is very effective to the whole hair restoring of the head. Furthermore, it is possible to tie and fix them to the original hair(s) with a simple hair restoring apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> And the hair restoring method of the present invention capable of fixing the artificial hair restorer, that has the trunk hair to which plural restoring hairs are tied and fixed, to the points close to the original hair root easily. It is capable of doing voluminous hair restoring without putting any excessive load to the original hair as the artificial hair restorer is tied only to one point of the original hair. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An artificial hair restorer being characterized in that it consists of a trunk hair with plural restoring hairs tied to at a certain point of the trunk hair, and a loop through which the original hair(s) passes(pass) at one end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An artificial hair restorer defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> having a trunk hair with plural restoring hairs tied to at a certain point of the trunk hair, and a loop through which the original hair(s) passes(pass) at one end, said artificial hair restorer being characterized in that it has a knot close to the tying point end of the restoring hairs but opposite to the loop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An artificial hair restorer defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> being characterized in that the loop of said trunk hair(s) is formed at the turn made by folding one or two trunk hair(s) in two. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A hair restoring method characterized in that it comprises a step of tying and fixing an artificial hair restorer to one or plural original hair(s) in the vicinity of its(their) root(s) by inserting the original hair(s) into a loop formed at one end of said trunk hair and fastening therebetween while plural of restoring hairs being fixed to the trunk hair. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A hair restoring method defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> being characterized in that it comprises a step of tying and fixing said artificial hair restorer to one or plural original hair(s) by adhering the former to the later at the tying point. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A hair restoring method defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> being characterized in that it comprises step of tying loosely an artificial hair restorer to certain point of a fitting bar after inserting the fitting bar through the loop at the end of said artificial hair restorer, sliding this loosely tying loop along the fitting bar to set aside the fitting bar so that the original hair(s), which passes(pass) through the ring at the end of the fitting bar having a bar part, so as to make the original hair(s) passes(pass) through the loop of the artificial hair restorer, pulling both ends of this trunk hair of the artificial hair restorer oppositely to tightly tie the artificial hair restorer to the original hair(s). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A hair restoring apparatus having a fitting bar and a thread like line provided at one end of the fitting bar to make a ring through which one or plural original hair(s) passes(pass), a bar part of said fitting bar being arranged with many of artificial hair restorers at certain intervals therealong, said bar part of the fitting bar is to be inserted through the loop of each said artificial hair restorer of a trunk hair, to whose one end plural restoring hairs are fixed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A hair restoring apparatus having a fitting bar and a thread like line provided at one end of the fitting bar to make a ring through which one or plural original hair(s) passes(pass), a bar part of said fitting bar being arranged with many of artificial hair restorers at certain intervals therealong, said bar part of the fitting bar is to be inserted through the loop of each said artificial hair restorers formed at the turn of the folded trunk hair, to whose one end plural restoring hairs are fixed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An hair restoring apparatus defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> wherein said artificial hair restorer has a trunk hair with plural restoring hairs fixed to at a certain point thereof and a loop through which the original hair(s) passes(pass) at one end being characterized in that said trunk hair has a knot close to the tying point end of the restoring hairs but opposite to the loop.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000540A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000540A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000540A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000540A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
