<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00019.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00020.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00021.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00022.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00023.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00024.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00025.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00026.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00027.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00027.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00028.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00028.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00029.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00029.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00030.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00030.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00031.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00031.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00032.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00032.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00033.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00033.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000271A1-20030102-D00034.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000271A1-20030102-D00034.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000271</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10234359</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020904</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B21D005/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>072</class>
<subclass>176000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Rollforming machine and methods</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10234359</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020904</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09777015</doc-number>
<document-date>20010205</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alfred</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Patty</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Portage</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Pacalo</family-name>
<name-suffix>III</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Pittsburgh</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Norman</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hedman</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hilliard</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Larry</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Stimpert</family-name>
<name-suffix>II</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ashland</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Joseph</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Jinkens</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>New Albany</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KIRKPATRICK &amp; LOCKHART LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>535 SMITHFIELD STREET</address-1>
<city>PITTSBURGH</city>
<state>PA</state>
<postalcode>15222</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Rollforming machines and methods for adjusting a forming roll for forming components from materials of different thicknesses. The rollforming machines and methods may also provide for overbending the component being rollformed. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a Divisional Patent Application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/777,015, filed Feb. 5, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Not applicable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to rollforming machines and, more particularly, to adjustable rollforming machines for forming components from materials of different thicknesses and rollforming machines having the capability to overbend the component being formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Invention Background </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Rollforming is a well-know process of bending a continuous strip or cut to length strip of metal through a series of shaped rolls. Common rollforming processes gradually form a strip of metal into a predetermined shape. The shapes may include, for example, generally C-shaped cross sections or generally U-shaped cross sections, or may include relatively complex formations being formed along the length of the material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Rollforming processes are widely used because they are regarded as being a highly efficient means for continuously forming metal strip. Any number of other operations may be performed while the metal is taking shape. These other operations may include, for example, punching, tabbing, cutting to length, perforating, drawing, lancing, embossing, knurling, edge conditioning and curving. One particular benefit of rollforming is that strength and function are added to the metal as a result of the rollforming process. Rollforming, therefore, provides for many advantages in comparison to other known processes for forming metal materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The marketplace for shaped, rollformed sections has expanded into virtually every field of industry thereby replacing other known processes such as extrusions, brake forming and punch press operations in the areas such as the aircraft industry and the automotive industry. Another industry that heavily relies on rollforming is the architectural industry, and more specifically, the metal frame construction industry. As an alternative to traditional wood construction components, a variety of metal frame constructions and associated components have been developed for use in the residential and/or commercial building industry. The components needed for the metal frame construction industry are greatly varied and thus can be time consuming and expensive to manufacture using conventional rollforming techniques. For example, the needed components must be manufactured in an assortment of sizes, gauges and shapes depending upon the particular need for an assortment of different residential and/or commercial structures in which the components will be utilized. In addition, such components must be manufactured to relatively close tolerances to ensure that they will fit together properly and can easily be assembled and installed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Rollforming machines for producing components used, for example, in the metal frame construction industry, are well known and typically include a plurality of sets of forming rolls arranged in upper and lower pairs and spaced apart along the length of the rollforming machine on rollforming support stands. As is also well known, the forming rolls at one stand will produce a continuous formation in the material and the forming rolls of the next stand will produce another formation, or for example, increase the angle of the formation which has already been started at the previous stand and so on. Examples of such rollforming machines are disclosed, in U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,970,764 and 5,829,295. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> When rollforming a strip of metal to produce a component, it is advantageous for the rollforming machine to be capable of working on materials of different thicknesses, also referred to as the &ldquo;gauge&rdquo; of the material in the metals industry. In order to achieve this flexibility of working on materials of different thicknesses, early rollforming machines required that the forming rolls be replaced entirely or substantially changed when it was desirable to form a material having a different thickness. As can be appreciated, this practice of completely replacing the forming rolls was very costly in terms of material costs to provide numerous different forming rolls, labor costs for the added time of installing and reinstalling the forming rolls, and the manufacturing costs in view of the time that the rollforming machine could not be in operation during replacement of the forming rolls. More modem rollforming machines provide for automatic adjustment of the forming rolls to accommodate the materials of different thicknesses. For example, the aforementioned U.S. Pat. No. 5,970,764 discloses a first rack and pinion arrangement in combination with an eccentrically mounted shaft for adjusting the clearance between forming rolls in a first plane and a second rack and pinion arrangement in combination with an additional eccentrically mounted shaft for adjusting the clearance between the forming rolls in a second plane. While apparently effective at adjusting the clearance between the forming rolls for materials of different thicknesses, such an arrangement still has many disadvantages and shortcomings. For example, many mechanical parts are necessary to achieve the desired adjustment resulting in increased costs for manufacturing and maintaining the rollforming machine, and also resulting in the increased likelihood of mechanical failure leading to down time and lost operating revenue for the rollforming machine. In addition, such arrangement is apparently unable to accurately and consistently maintain the required tolerances when rollforming a component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> When performing a rollforming process to produce a component of a particular shape, it is desirable for the component to maintain the desired shape after the rollforming process is completed and the component exits the rollforming machine. One problem that can occur when rollforming products is commonly referred to in the rollforming industry as &ldquo;springback&rdquo;. The bending process that takes place during rollforming is a complex process which seeks to avoid stress concentration at the points of bending. Because the material being rollformed has a modulus of elasticity, the material tries to assume a shape having a bend of lesser extent than was desired. Therefore, springback is generally defined as the elastic recovery of metal after a stress has been applied. Other properties of the metal which may affect and contribute to springback are, for example, tensile strength, yield strength and Rockwell hardness. As can be appreciated, the amount of springback that may occur will vary for different materials and for different shapes depending upon the degree of bending. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> One solution to correcting springback is to rework the rollformed component to mitigate the effects of the springback. However, to rework the component greatly increases the unit cost for the component and, therefore, is not an effective solution. Another solution to springback is to employ additional rollforming stands on the rollforming machine that include forming rolls cut to specific angles in order to overbend the component once the desired shape has been achieved. However, this also greatly increases the costs of rollforming by requiring additional rollforming stands and increased material and labor costs to install and replace the forming rolls depending upon the particular angle that is needed in order to achieve the necessary overbend to compensate for the springback. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> There is identified, therefore, a need for an improved rollforming machine that overcomes limitations, shortcomings and disadvantages of known rollforming machines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> There is also a need for an improved rollforming machine that is capable of accommodating materials of different thicknesses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> There is a further need for an improved rollforming machine that can be easily and efficiently adjusted for materials of different thicknesses and profiles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> There is a further need for an improved rollforming machine that is capable of producing a component of a desired shape or configuration wherein the component maintains the desired shape or configuration once the rollforming is completed and the component is removed from the rollforming machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Still another need exists for an improved rollforming machine with effective overbending capabilities for ensuring that the component formed by the rollforming machine maintains the desired shape or configuration once the rollforming is completed and the component is removed from the rollforming machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A need also exists for an improved rollforming machine that includes overbend capabilities wherein the desired and necessary amount of overbending can easily be adjusted and maintained while running production and during non-production. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The embodiments of the invention meet the above-identified needs, as well as other needs, as will be more fully understood following a review of this specification and drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the invention includes a rollforming apparatus comprising a moveable support stand, a first forming roll, a second forming roll and a third forming roll. The first forming roll is rotatably mounted to a first spindle, wherein the first spindle is moveably connected to the support stand to provide for angular movement of the first forming roll. The second forming roll is mounted to a second spindle that extends through a central aperture defined by the first forming roll. The second spindle is moveably connected to the support stand to provide for movement of the second forming roll relative to the angular movement of the first forming roll. The third forming roll is rotatably supported by the support stand for movement therewith. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The rollforming apparatus may be utilized in conjunction with a rollforming machine that is structured and arranged to form components of different shapes and configurations, such as, for example, components having a generally C-shaped cross section, components having a generally U-shaped cross section or components with other cross sections as may be needed for particular applications. Advantageously, the first, second and third forming rolls of the rollforming apparatus are structured and arranged to perform, for example, overbending of the component to counter the effects of springback that may occur during the rollforming process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A further embodiment of the invention includes a method of forming components of different shapes and configurations, such as, for example, a component having a generally C-shaped cross section, a component having a generally U-shaped cross section or a component having other cross sections depending upon the particular shape needed for a particular application of the component. The method includes feeding a sheet or coil of material to a rollforming station structured and arranged to form a portion of the component. The method also includes feeding the sheet of material to an additional rollforming station having a plurality of forming rolls supported by a plurality of spindles. The method further includes adjusting the position of at least one of the forming rolls resulting in moving the position of at least one of the spindles. Advantageously, the method may further include employing the roll station having a plurality of forming rolls supported by a plurality of spindles for overbending of a sheet of material to compensate for springback conditions that may develop in the component being formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> An additional embodiment of the invention includes a rollforming apparatus comprising a support stand, a forming roll supported on a spindle, an adjustment block and a slide assembly. The spindle is rotatably secured to the adjustment block. The slide assembly is in cooperative engagement with the support stand and the adjustment block to provide movement of the forming roll axially along an axis of rotation of the spindle and transversely to the axis of rotation of the spindle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The slide assembly may include an inner gage block mounted to the adjustment block and an outer gage block mounted to the support stand. The slide assembly may further include a rail member and a bearing member such that one of the rail member and the bearing member is attached to the inner gage block and the other of the rail member and the bearing member is attached to the outer gage block. The rail member and the bearing member are positioned for cooperative engagement to facilitate movement between the support stand and adjustment block to provide for movement of the forming roll. Advantageously, the rollforming apparatus provides for easy and efficient adjustment of the forming roll for materials of different thicknesses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the invention, the rollforming apparatus having a support stand, a forming roll supported on a spindle, an adjustment block and a slide assembly may be utilized in conjunction with a rollforming machine having a plurality of rollforming stations to form a component of a desired shape and configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> An additional embodiment of the invention includes a method of forming a component that includes feeding a sheet or coil of material to a rollforming station having a forming roll supported by a spindle rotatably secured to an adjustment block to form the component. The method also includes adjusting the position of the forming roll by employing a slide assembly in cooperative engagement with the adjustment block to facilitate movement of the forming roll in a direction that is the resultant of normal and axial components of motion of the spindle.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a top-plan view of a rollforming machine in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a top-plan view illustrating a portion of the rollforming machine shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a side-elevational view of the rollforming machine as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> is a top-plan view of an embodiment of rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the rollforming machine shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side-elevational view taken along line <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is an isometric view of a component C capable of manufactured by the rollforming machine shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a front-elevational view taken along line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>B-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>B of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>M are partial front-elevational views of the rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>of the rollforming machine illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A</cross-reference> is an exploded isometric view of a typical support stand, adjustment block and slide assembly in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6B</cross-reference> is an isometric view illustrating the exploded view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> as assembled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a front-elevational view of an embodiment of an adjustment block of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a side-elevational view of a rollforming apparatus employed at, for example, rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>of the rollforming machine shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a rear-elevational view of the rollforming apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is an isometric view of the rollforming apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a side-elevational view of the rollforming apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, with the rolls in a different position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a partial rear-elevational view of the rollforming apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a rear-elevational view of a pivot plate assembly of the rollforming apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a partial, exploded isometric view of the rollforming apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, and that is similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is an isometric view illustrating <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> as assembled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view of rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>of the rollforming machine in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view of rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>of the rollforming machine in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is an isometric view of a typical straightener for use in accordance with an embodiment of the invention, and as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view of the straightener shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>D and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, there is illustrated a rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the invention. In general, rollforming machines are well known machines and they include numerous parts and components for the assembly and operation thereof. Many of these numerous parts and components that make up rollforming machines that are well known to those skilled in the art of manufacturing and operating rollforming machines will not be described in detail herein. Rather, the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be described in general details with specific emphasis on the inventive aspects and the various embodiments of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m. </italic></highlight>The plurality of rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>are positioned along the length of the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for gradually forming a strip or coil of metal into a predetermined shape or profile such as the component C, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>having a generally C-shaped cross section. Other components may be formed having different shapes or profiles such as, for example, a generally U-shaped cross section or other more relatively complex cross sections or formations that may be desired. The component C may be, for example, a metal stud member used, for example, in the metal frame construction industry. The component C generally includes a web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a pair of legs <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> connected to the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and a pair of lips <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> connected to the legs <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. For purposes of illustration only, the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be described in conjunction with the rollforming of the component C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The rollforming machines <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also include a plurality of corresponding transmissions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>connected to the plurality of rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>by a plurality of corresponding upper drive shafts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>for stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>and lower drive shafts <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>for stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m. </italic></highlight>The plurality of transmissions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>may be integrally connected and driven by a common drive motor <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> that transmits a driving force to the transmissions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>via drive chain <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> or drive belt. The drive motor <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> may be of an appropriate size and capacity for providing the appropriate driving force to the plurality of rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m. </italic></highlight>The drive shafts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>will be discussed in more detail herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> also includes moveable support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to which the plurality of rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>are mounted. The support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are connected to a respective plurality of linear slides <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to provide for lateral adjustment of the plurality of rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>in order for the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to accommodate a particular component C having a web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of different widths. The linear slides <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are mounted to a base assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> which serves as the foundation for the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>C, the support frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is laterally adjustable in the directions indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, while the support frame <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is laterally adjustable in the directions indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In order to facilitate the lateral adjustment of the support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may include lateral adjustment assemblies <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> that are connected to the base assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The lateral adjustment assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> may be connected to a drive motor <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> for actuation thereof. The lateral adjustment assembly <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> may be connected by, for example, a drive belt <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to the lateral adjustment assembly <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Many types of lateral adjustment assemblies may be employed, as is well known, for moving the support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> laterally. The lateral adjustment assemblies <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> include, for example, pneumatic cylinders, hydraulic cylinders, powered and/or unpowered screw closure devices, including ball screws, acme screws or oppositely threaded screws for providing the desired lateral adjustment of the support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. In addition to accommodating materials of different widths, the lateral adjustment of the support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> also provide for formation of components C having legs <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of unequal length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also include a support bridge <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> having a plurality of rollers <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> for contacting the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the component C being formed in order to prevent deflection of the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The support bridge <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> may be mounted to the base assembly <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> or may be mounted to one of the support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>D, the rollforming machine may include a split platform design to allow for enhanced lateral adjustment capabilities. This may be achieved by, for example, mounting rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>on support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>&prime; to increase the overall lateral adjustment capabilities. This is particularly advantageous for sheets of material entering the rollforming station <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> when the lips are being initially formed to accommodate the overall width of the sheet of material or when producing a component C having legs <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of unequal lengths. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also include a pair of straighteners <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which will be described and shown in more detail herein. Generally, straighteners are well known components that are used in association with rollforming machines in order to correct, for example, bow, twist or camber that may result in the component C as it is being rollformed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>I, the operation of the plurality of rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>will be described in more detail. Each of the rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>include a pair of upper forming rolls mounted on a spindle and a pair of lower forming rolls mounted on a spindle. A strip of material is fed to the rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>which progressively form the component C, and more specifically, form the legs <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and lips <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A, rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>includes upper forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and lower forming rolls <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>initiates the formation of the component C by bending the end of the strip of material to begin to form the lips <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A and as will be described in more detail herein, the forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are laterally adjustable, as shown in dotted line, to accommodate forming components C that have webs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of different widths. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> illustrates rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>having a pair of upper forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a pair of lower forming rolls <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>continues the formation of the lips <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the component C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIG.<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>C, there is illustrated rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>having a pair of upper forming rolls <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and a pair of lower forming rolls <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>Rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>completes the formation of the lips <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the component C such that the lips <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are positioned generally perpendicular to the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>D-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>I, there is illustrated rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i, </italic></highlight>respectively. Each of the rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>include a pair of upper forming rolls and a pair of lower forming rolls configured to form the legs <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the component C. The remaining rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>are illustrated respectively in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>J-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>M and will be described in more detail herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, there is illustrated a view of rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i. </italic></highlight>Rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>is typical of the preceding rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h. </italic></highlight>It will be appreciated, as explained in detail herein and illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>H, that each of the preceding rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h </italic></highlight>include differently configured forming rolls in order to progressively form a specific portion of the component C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Still referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>(for purposes of simplification of the description of rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i, </italic></highlight>the suffix &ldquo;i&rdquo; will not be repeatedly used herein but may be shown in the drawings) includes a pair of support stands <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> each having a base <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, respectively, for connecting the support stands <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> to the support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and a lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are rotatably secured to the support stands <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> supports the pair of upper annular forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, while the lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> supports the pair of lower annular forming rolls <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. More particularly, the forming roll <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is mounted on a sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> for rotation therewith and the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is moveably connected to the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for rotation therewith. The sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, for example, may include a key for cooperating with an elongated keyway formed in the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to allow for sliding, longitudinal movement between the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the forming roll <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is mounted on a sleeve <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> for rotation therewith and the sleeve <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is moveably connected, by the described key and keyway arrangement, for rotation with the lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is rotatably secured to the support stand <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by an adjustment block <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> includes a pair of spaced apart bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> that permit the rotatable motion of the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Similarly, an adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> rotatably supports the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> which supports the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> therein. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> includes an additional pair of spaced-apart bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> that cooperate with the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to allow the rotatable motion thereof. In addition, the lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is rotatably secured to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> by an adjustment block <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> having a pair of spaced apart bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> therein to allow the rotatable motion of the lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> relative to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The sleeve <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are rotatably secured to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> by an additional adjustment block <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> having a pair of spaced apart bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. Each of the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> are essentially identical and, therefore, only bearing assembly <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> will be described in detail. Bearing assembly <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is, for example, a pair of opposed tapered roller bearings having an inner race or cone <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>&prime; that is secured to the spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for rotation therewith and an outer race or cup <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>&Prime; that is stationary within the adjustment block <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> with the roller <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; positioned therebetween. The bearing assembly <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> may be, for example, available from The Timken Company of Canton, Ohio as Part Nos. 47487 and 47420. However, other conventional bearings may be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, there is illustrated in more detail one embodiment of the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> includes a first leg <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and a second leg <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> extending from the base <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A pair of structural flanges <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> may be connected to the base <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and the legs <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> to provide structural support for the legs <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is received in a bottom portion of the support stand between the legs <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the adjustment block <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> includes tabs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> for receipt in slots <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> (only one slot <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6a</cross-reference>) formed on inner, bottom portion of the legs <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is received in an upper portion of the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> between the legs <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> remains stationary with respect to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, while the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is moveably connected to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, to provide for the moveable connection of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, there is provided a first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and a second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated that the first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> are essentially identical. The slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> includes an outer gage block <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and an inner gage block <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> also includes an outer gage block <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and an inner gage block <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> each include a bearing member <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>, respectively, that is rigidly secured to the respective outer gage blocks <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the bearing member <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is received in a bearing slot <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and the bearing member <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is received in a bearing slot <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> and, for example, a plurality of fasteners (not shown) may be utilized for rigidly securing the bearing members <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> to the outer gage blocks <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> further includes a rail member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> that is received in a rail slot <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> formed on the inner gage block <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. A plurality of fasteners (not shown) may also be provided for rigidly securing the rail member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to the inner gage block <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> also includes a rail member <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> received in a rail slot (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is assembled such that the bearing member <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is in cooperative engagement with the rail member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to allow movement therebetween. Similarly, the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is assembled such that the bearing member <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is positioned for cooperative engagement with the rail member <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> to allow movement therebetween. The bearing member <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and rail member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and the bearing member <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and rail member <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> are commercially available components and may be, for example, a THK Miniature LM Guide Type RSR . . . Z manufactured by THK. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is mounted to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> by rigidly securing the inner gage block <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to a first side <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> using, for example, a plurality of fasteners (not shown) that extend through the apertures <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> formed in the inner gage block <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is connected to a second side <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> by rigidly securing the inner gage block <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> to a second side <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> using, for example, a plurality of fasteners (not shown) that extend through the plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> formed in the inner gage block <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> After the first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> are mounted to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is positioned between the legs <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. As shown, the outer gage block <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is at least partially received in a generally U-shaped receptacle <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> formed in the first leg <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the outer gage block <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is at least partially received in a generally U-shaped receptacle <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> formed in the second leg <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The outer gage block <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is positioned such that a plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> formed in the outer gage block <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are aligned with a corresponding plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> formed in the first leg <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. A plurality of fasteners (not shown) extend through the apertures <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> to rigidly secure the outer gage block <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to the first leg <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the outer gage block <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> that are aligned with a corresponding plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> formed in the second leg <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. A plurality of fasteners (not shown) extend through the apertures <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> to rigidly secure the outer gage block <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> to the second leg <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. As will be appreciated, the described arrangement allows for linear movement of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> in an angled direction, and specifically in a direction corresponding to an angle at which the bearing members <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> are in cooperative engagement with the rail members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> for movement therebetween, as will be described in more detail herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> will be described in more detail. It will be appreciated that the adjustment block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is essentially identical to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. As previously described, the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> includes a first side <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> for attaching the inner gage block <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> thereto and a second side <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> for attaching the inner gage block <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> thereto. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> also includes a central opening <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> extending therethrough. The opening <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is generally circular for receipt of the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> therein, or in the case of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> for receipt of the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> only therein. As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> includes bearing pockets <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> for receipt of the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, as previously described, rotatably secure the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> includes an annular bearing support <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> positioned between and about the bearing pockets <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> in order to maintain the position of the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> within the bearing pockets <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> also includes an inner bearing plate <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and an outer bearing plate <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> for further securing and maintaining the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> in the bearing pockets <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> In addition, the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> includes an opening <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> therethrough for receiving a clevis pin <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> also includes an additional opening <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> that extends generally transverse to the opening <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. A clevis with bushing <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> extends into the opening <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and is slideably connected at one end to the clevis pin <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and at the other end is attached to a shaft <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) of a screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> which provides a driving movement to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, as will be described in more detail herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 2</cross-reference>, each rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>includes a screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>that are interconnected by linkage arrangements <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The linkage arrangements <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> are in turn connected to a drive motor <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> to actuate each of the individual screw jack assemblies for operation of the adjustment blocks, as described herein. Rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><italic>l </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>include drive motors <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> for actuating the adjustment block that controls movement of the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 5</cross-reference>, the transmission <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to an upper drive shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by a conventional universal coupling, generally designated by reference number <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and the upper drive shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is connected to the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> by an additional universal coupling, generally designated by reference number <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. The described arrangement provides for rotation of the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The upper drive shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a telescoping type drive shaft to allow for the individual segments of the drive shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to telescope in the directions indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Such drive shafts are well known components. Similarly, drive shaft <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is connected to the transmission <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by a universal coupling <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and the lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is connected to the lower drive shaft <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> by additional universal coupling <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The lower drive shaft <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is also a telescoping type for movement in the directions indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The support stands <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> may be simultaneously adjusted in an inward direction, as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> or may be simultaneously adjusted in an outward direction as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> in order for the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to accommodate a component C having a web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of different widths. The movement of the support stands <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is accomplished by simultaneously moving the support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, to which the support stands <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are respectively connected, in the direction of arrows <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> or arrows <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. During movement of the support stands <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, the transmission <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>remains stationary. Movement of the support stand <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the inward direction of arrow <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> results in the expansion or extension of the drive shafts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> because the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are rotatably secured to the support stand <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by respective adjustment blocks <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and more specifically by the pairs of bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. During inward movement of the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, the sleeves <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, which are rotatably secured to respective adjustment blocks <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, also move inward with respect to the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. As previously described, the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is moveably connected to the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> by a key and keyway arrangement and similarly the sleeve <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is moveably connected to the lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> by a key and keyway arrangement. The inward movement of the spindles <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> results in the inward movement of forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and the inward movement of sleeves <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> results in the inward movement of forming rolls <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> During outward movement of the support stand <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> as, indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the drive shafts <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> collapse in order to accommodate the outward movement. In addition, outward movement of the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, results in the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> moving with respect to the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the sleeve <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> moving with respect to the lower spindle <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The described movement results in outward movement of the forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> In addition to adjusting the rollforming stations <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> inwardly and outwardly for a component C having a web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of different widths, the invention includes adjusting the forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> relative to the forming rolls <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, respectively, to accommodate forming a component C of a material having different thicknesses or different gauges. To make the necessary adjustments for materials of different thicknesses, it is necessary to adjust each of the forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in two different planes. Specifically, it is necessary to adjust the forming roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in the direction of an axis of rotation of the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and in a direction transversely to the axis of rotation of the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. Similarly, it is necessary to adjust forming roll <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> axially in the direction of an axis of rotation of the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and in a direction of transversely to the axis of rotation of the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>. Advantageously, the previously described arrangements of adjustment blocks <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> each having the first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, allows for one continuous movement of the forming roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and for one continuous movement of the forming roll <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight>. As can be appreciated, the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is in a direction that is the resultant of the axial component <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the normal component <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of motion of upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Likewise, the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> is in a direction that is the resultant of the axial component <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and the normal component <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> of motion of the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. It will be appreciated that the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> is essentially along the same line of action as movement between the bearing member <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and rail member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the bearing member <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and rail member <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> of the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. To achieve adjustment of the forming rolls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in two planes for materials of different thicknesses while maintaining equal axial and transverse movement, the direction of arrows <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> should be generally <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> degrees with respect to the horizontal or the axial components <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. However, it should be appreciated that the angular position of the arrows <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> may be at any desired angle by altering the position of the bearing members <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and rail members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> of the first slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The structural arrangement of support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in order to achieve the adjustment of forming roll <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> will now be described in more detail. It will be appreciated that the structural arrangement of support stand <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is similar to support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and that operation of the same to achieve adjustment of forming roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is essentially the same. As previously described, support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> includes a screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, which is a generally well known component. The screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes the shaft <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> that is connected to the clevis with bushing <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> which in turn is moveably connected to the dowel pin <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> which is supported in the aperture <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is preferably rigidly mounted to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. Actuation of the screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a generally upward direction results in the shaft <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> moving the clevis with bushing <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> in a generally upward direction as well. As a result of this upward movement of the screw jack <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and clevis with bushing <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>, the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> must also move as a result of the slideable connection between the clevis with bushing <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> and the clevis pin <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. The resulting movement of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight>. This movement results from the relative movement between the bearing member <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and rail member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and the relative movement between the bearing member <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and the rail member <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The rail members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, which are rigidly secured to the inner gage blocks <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, respectively, which are in turn rigidly secured to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, move with respect to the bearing members <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight>. Because of the described structural arrangement, this is the only direction in which the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> can move in response to actuation of the screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Actuation of the screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in the opposite direction, i.e., a generally downward direction, will result in movement of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> in the angular orientation of arrow <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, only in the opposite direction from the previously described movement. Accordingly, actuation of the screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a generally upward direction will result in adjustment of the forming roll <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in a direction for materials having a greater thickness while actuation of the screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a generally downward direction will result in adjustment of the forming roll <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in a direction for materials having a lesser thickness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> During movement of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, one of the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, and specifically the inner race or cup <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>&prime; thereof, acts against a first shoulder <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> formed on the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the other bearing assembly <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, and specifically the other inner race or cup <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>&prime; thereof, acts against a bearing nut <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> attached to the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The action of the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> against the shoulder <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and bearing nut <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> causes the sleeve <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, which has the forming roll <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> attached thereto, to move in the desired direction with respect to the upper spindle <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><italic>l </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m, </italic></highlight>as will be described in detail herein, provide for both rollforming of the component C and overbending of the component C to compensate for springback that may develop during the rollforming process. In this embodiment, rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><italic>l </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>are essentially identical except that the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> at each of the stations is located on opposite sides of the rollforming line. Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, a rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of this embodiment employed by rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><italic>l </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight>will be described in detail (for purposes of simplification of the description, the suffixes &ldquo;l&rdquo; or &ldquo;m&rdquo; will not be repeated herein, but may be shown in the drawings). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes a support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>, that is similar to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> described herein, having a base <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> and a first leg <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> and a second leg <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> extending from the base <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>). The rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> also includes a first support member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> connected to the first leg <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> and a second support member <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> connected to the second leg <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. The first support member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the second support member <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> are rigidly secured to the first leg <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> and the second leg <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>, respectively, of the support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>. The rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> also includes the structural flanges <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> for providing structural support to the first leg <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> and the second leg <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> The rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> further includes a pivot plate assembly, generally designated by reference number <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, that is moveably connected to the first and second support members <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. The pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> includes an overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> rotatably mounted thereto. As shown and described herein, roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> is an idle roller that is rotated by contact with the component C passing through the rollforming station. However, roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> could be positively driven, if desired. Movement of the pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> with respect to the first and second support members <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> provides for angular movement of the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> for overbending and/or the component C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</cross-reference>, the pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> of this embodiment will be described in more detail. In this embodiment, the pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> includes a first pivot plate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> moveably connected to the first support member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and a second pivot plate <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> moveably connected to the second support member <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. A connector plate <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> extends between the first pivot plate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and second pivot plate <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> for supporting the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>. To provide for the moveable connection between the first pivot plate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and the first support member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the moveable connection between the second pivot plate <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> and the second support member <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, the first and second pivot plates <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> each include a plurality of rollers <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> mounted thereto for receipt in corresponding arcuate slots <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> formed in the first support member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the second support member <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>). The plurality of rollers <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> provide for a structurally stable connection between the pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and the first and second support members <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> while providing for relative movement therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> To adjust the positions the pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and the first and second support members <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, there is provided a screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. The screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> is mounted to a mounting plate <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> having a first mounting leg <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> that is secured by a fastener <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> to the first support member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. The mounting plate <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> also includes a second mounting leg <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> that is secured by a fastener <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> to the second support member <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. The screw jack assembly <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> includes a shaft <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> that is connected to an actuator bar <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. A first fastener <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> secures an end of the actuator bar <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> to the first pivot plate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and a second fastener <highlight><bold>229</bold></highlight> secures another end of the actuator bar <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> to the second pivot plate <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. The actuator bar passes through an actuator slot <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> formed in the first support member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</cross-reference>) and an additional actuator slot formed in the second support member <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. As can be appreciated, actuation of the screwjack assembly <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> results in movement of the shaft <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> which in turn causes movement of the actuator bar <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. Because the actuator bar <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> is connected to the first pivot plate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> by fastener <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> and to the second pivot plate <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> by fastener <highlight><bold>229</bold></highlight>, the pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is moved along an arcuate path corresponding to the arcuate slots <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> which receive the plurality of rollers <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The embodiment of the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>) includes a motor <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> connected by a motor coupling <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> to the screwjack assembly <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. The rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> also includes a pivot stop <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> connected to the first support member <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> for cooperation with the first pivot plate <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and an additional pivot stop (not shown) positioned for cooperation with the second pivot plate <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. This prevents overbending that may cause the lip <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to contact the roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and distort or bend the shape of the lip <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</cross-reference>, the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> is rotatably mounted on a spindle assembly, generally designated by reference number <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight>, that is mounted to the connector plate <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the spindle assembly <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight> includes a bearing assembly <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>, a bearing retainer <highlight><bold>239</bold></highlight> and a seal retainer <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> which mount the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> to a spindle <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> for rotation of the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> thereabout. The spindle <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> is rigidly secured to the connector plate <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. As can be appreciated, such arrangement enables the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> to be pivoted, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>, when the pivot plate assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is moved, as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Also in this embodiment, the spindle <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> defines a central aperture <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> which allows for a support structure for an angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> to pass therethrough, as will be explained in more detail herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Referring specifically to FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, it will be further appreciated that, in this embodiment, the support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> is similar to the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, as described herein. The support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> includes an adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> for supporting the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and an additional adjustment block <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> for supporting a lower forming roll <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. As shown and described herein, the roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> is an idle roller that is rotated by contact with the component C. However, roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> could be positively driven, if desired. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> is structured similarly to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> as described herein. The essential difference between adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> and the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is that adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> does not include the central aperture <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> extending therethrough and, further, does not include the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. Rather, the adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> supports a rigid structural shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight> that protrudes from the adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> but does not move with respect to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight>. The shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight> extends through the central aperture <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> formed in the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and has an axis generally designated as &ldquo;A-A&rdquo; (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>). The central aperture <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> is sized to permit for movement of the adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> and shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight> for adjusting the position of angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> for forming components C from materials of different thicknesses. Positioned at the end of the shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight> is a bearing housing <highlight><bold>259</bold></highlight> for supporting a pair of spaced apart bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight>. Rotatably supported by the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight> is a spindle <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> that has an axis &ldquo;B-B&rdquo; and that rotates within the bearing housing <highlight><bold>259</bold></highlight>. As can also be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, spindle <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> may be oriented such that its axis &ldquo;B-B&rdquo; is oriented at an angle relative to axis &ldquo;A-A&rdquo; of shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight>. The angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> is rotatably secured to the spindle <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> for rotation therewith. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, the support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> of this embodiment also includes a first slide assembly <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> and a second slide assembly <highlight><bold>261</bold></highlight>, which are similar to the slide assemblies <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> described herein in conjunction with the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The first slide assembly <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> includes an outer gage block <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>, an inner gage block <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>, a bearing member <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> and a rail member <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> includes an outer gage block <highlight><bold>263</bold></highlight>, an inner gage block <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight>, a bearing member <highlight><bold>267</bold></highlight> and a rail member <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight>. The first slide assembly <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> and the second slide assembly <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> are positioned between the adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> and the first leg <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> and the second leg <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> of the support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> to provide for movement of the adjustment block with respect to the support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>, in essentially the same manner as described herein for the adjustment block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and the support stand <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. Those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that such arrangement permits the position of the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> to be adjusted for accommodating materials of different thicknesses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> To achieve this adjustment, it is necessary to adjust the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> axially along longitudinal axis &ldquo;A-A&rdquo; of the shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, and transversely to the longitudinal axis &ldquo;A-A&rdquo; of the shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>). This results in movement of the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> which is the resultant sum of the axial component <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight> and the normal component <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, the support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> also includes the adjustment block <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> which is constructed and arranged in essentially the same manner as adjustment block <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, as described herein. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> includes bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> that rotatably secure the sleeve <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> for rotation therein. Spindle <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> is received in the sleeve <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> and moveably connected thereto by the previously described key and keyway arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> A lower support roll <highlight><bold>279</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4M</cross-reference>) is also attached to the spindle <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> for supporting the component C during the rollforming and/or overbending at station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m. </italic></highlight>The support roll is rotatably secured to an additional adjustment block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) that is similar to the adjustment block <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> described herein. The support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> and opposing support stand that contains adjustment block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> are adjustable in an inward and outward direction, in essentially the same manner as described hereinabove for support stands <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 13</cross-reference>, the rollforming and overbending of the component C by the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> will be described in more detail. As shown, the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> engages an outer portion of the leg <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of component C. The angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> contacts a junction between an inner portion of the leg <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the inner portion of the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The lower forming roll <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> engages an outer portion of the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> adjacent the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>. With the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> in the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> (generally perpendicular to the axis &ldquo;C-C&rdquo; of the shaft <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> upon which the lower forming roll <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> is journaled) the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is capable of forming and/or overbending the component C with the leg <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> generally perpendicular to the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the axis &ldquo;B-B&rdquo; of the shaft <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> is not parallel to the axis C-C of the shaft <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. If the material being used to form the component C lacks properties that might result in springback, then upon exiting the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> the component C should remain with the leg <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> generally perpendicular to the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. For materials that do exhibit properties that may result in springback, angular adjustment of the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> and as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, will result in overbending of the component C. Specifically, additional bending application is applied to the leg <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> about the junction where the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> contacts the component C such that when the component C exits the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, the leg <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> should return, as a result of the springback, to a position that is generally perpendicular to the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The range of angular motion of the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> may be about <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> degrees with respect to a generally horizontal axis. It will be understood that the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is capable of rollforming and/or overbending the component C such that the leg <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be at other angles than generally perpendicular with respect to the web <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it will be appreciated that the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> provides an efficient and flexible apparatus for rollforming and/or overbending the component C. The overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and the lower forming roll <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> of the rollforming apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be adjusted and positioned, as described herein, to provide for a high degree of flexibility when rollforming and/or overbending the component C. As can be appreciated from the description set forth herein and the drawings attached hereto, the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, as rotatably mounted to the spindle <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>, is independently adjustable from the angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and the lower forming roll <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The angled roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, which is secured to spindle <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> for rotation therewith, is also independently adjustable of the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and the lower forming roll <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The lower forming roll <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> is laterally adjustable by moving the stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> in an inward or outward direction which will result in the overbend roll <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and spindle <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>, as well as the overbend roll <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and spindle <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> also moving in an inward or outward direction in conjunction with movement of the support stand <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>J-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>K and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, there is illustrated rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k. </italic></highlight>Rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>are essentially identical only positioned on opposing sides of the rollforming line of rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Rollforming stations <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>further progress the formation of the legs <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the component C. Rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>includes adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>for supporting shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>which in turn supports angled roller <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j. </italic></highlight>The adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j, </italic></highlight>the shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>and the angled roller <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>operate in essentially the same manner as adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight>, shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight> and angled roller <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, as described herein. The adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>allows for adjustment of the angled roller <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>in order to accommodate materials of different thicknesses for forming the component C. Similarly, rollforming station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>includes adjustment block <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k, </italic></highlight>shaft <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>and angled roller <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>to provide for adjustment of the angled roller <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 22 and 23</cross-reference>, there is illustrated a typical straightener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for use with the rollforming machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The straightener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may be a conventionally known straightener utilized to adjust the component C for camber, twist, bow, etc., as is generally known in the rollforming industry. Generally, the straightener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes an adjustable top roll <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight>, an adjustable bottom roll <highlight><bold>391</bold></highlight> and a side roll <highlight><bold>392</bold></highlight>. The straightener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is mounted to a linear slide bearing <highlight><bold>393</bold></highlight> which in turn is mounted to the support frames <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The linear slide bearing <highlight><bold>393</bold></highlight> allows for the entire straightener <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to be laterally adjustable in order to accommodate the component C having a web of different widths. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Whereas particular embodiments of the invention have been described herein for the purpose of illustrating the invention and not for the purpose of limiting the same, it will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that numerous variations of the details, materials, and arrangement of parts and directional references, such as, for example, up, down, horizontal, vertical, top or bottom, may be made within the principle and scope of the invention without departing from the invention as described in the appended claims. For example, the described adjustment blocks may be alternately constructed and arranged to achieve similar movement thereof by using similar means such as opposed wedges cut on angles that may be attached internally or externally to the adjustment block housing for movement with respect to the stand. In addition, the adjustment blocks for adjustment of the upper spindle and associated forming rolls may be employed with the lower spindle and associated forming rolls, if desired. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A rollforming apparatus for overbending a generally C-shaped component with a web, a pair of legs connected to the web, and a lip protruding from an end of each leg, said apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a support stand; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower forming roll rotatably supported on said stand for supporting a portion of the web thereon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a backup roll pivotably supported on said stand for engagement with an outer portion of one of the legs, said backup roll being selectively independently pivotable relative to said lower forming roll without contacting the lips on the legs; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an angled forming roll positioned for selective engagement with a junction between an inner portion of the web and an inner portion of one of the legs without contacting any of the lips protruding from the legs. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A rollforming apparatus for overbending a generally C-shaped component with a web and a pair of legs connected to the web, said apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a support stand; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower forming roll rotatably supported on said stand for supporting a portion of the web thereon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a backup roll pivotably supported on said stand for engagement with an outer portion of one of the legs, said backup roll being selectively independently pivotable relative to said lower forming roll; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an angled forming roll positioned for selective engagement with a junction between an inner portion of the web and an inner portion of one of the legs. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A rollforming apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a vertically extending support stand; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a forming roll supported on a spindle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment block movably supported on said support stand, said spindle rotatably supported by said adjustment block; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a slide assembly in cooperative engagement with said support stand and said adjustment block to provide for selective angular movement of said forming roll upon moving said adjustment block vertically on said support stand. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said slide assembly is positioned between said support stand and said adjustment block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said slide assembly includes a rail member and a bearing member, said rail member and bearing member in cooperative engagement to provide relative movement therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the movement between said rail member and said bearing member is linear movement. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the linear movement between said rail member and said bearing member is along an axis that extends at an angle of greater than 0 degrees and less than 90 degrees with respect to a generally horizontal axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rail member is connected to one of said support stand and said slide assembly, and said bearing member is connected to the other of said support stand and said slide assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein slide assembly further includes an inner gage block mounted to said adjustment block, and wherein one of said rail member and said bearing member is attached to said inner gage block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein slide assembly further includes an outer gage block mounted to said support stand, and wherein one of said rail member and said bearing member is attached to said outer gage block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said inner gage block moves relative to said outer gage block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said forming roll is affixed directly to said spindle for rotation with said spindle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said forming roll is affixed directly to a sleeve, said sleeve being slideably connected to said spindle for rotation with said spindle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a screw jack assembly connected to said adjustment block for driving movement of said adjustment block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said screw jack assembly is mounted to said support stand. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said support stand includes a base having a first leg and a second leg extending therefrom, said slide assembly in cooperative engagement with at least one of said first leg and said second leg. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said forming roll is contained in a plane that is generally perpendicular to a longitudinal axis of said spindle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A rollforming apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a support stand; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a forming roll supported on a spindle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment block, said spindle rotatably secured to said adjustment block; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a slide assembly in cooperative engagement with said support stand and said adjustment block to provide movement of said forming roll in a direction that is the resultant of normal and axial components of motion of said spindle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A rollforming apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a support stand; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a forming roll supported on a spindle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment block, said spindle rotatably secured to said adjustment block; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a slide assembly including an inner gage block mounted to said adjustment block and an outer gage block mounted to said support stand, said slide assembly further including a rail member and a bearing member, one of said rail member and said bearing member attached to said inner gage block and the other of said rail member and said bearing member attached to said outer gage block, said rail member and bearing member in cooperative engagement to facilitate movement between said support stand and adjustment block to provide movement of said forming roll axially along an axis of rotation of said spindle and transversely to said axis of rotation of said spindle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A rollforming machine, comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of rollforming stations, at least one of said plurality of rollforming stations comprising: 
<claim-text>a support stand; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a forming roll supported on a spindle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment block, said spindle rotatably secured to said adjustment block; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a slide assembly in cooperative engagement with said support stand and said adjustment block to provide movement of said forming roll axially along an axis of rotation of said spindle and transversely to said axis of rotation of said spindle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a component, comprising: 
<claim-text>feeding a sheet of material to a rollforming station having a forming roll supported by a spindle rotatably secured to an adjustment block to form said component; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting the position of the forming roll by employing a slide assembly in cooperative engagement with the adjustment block to facilitate movement of the forming roll in a direction that is the resultant of normal and axial components of motion of the spindle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a structural component from a flat piece of sheet metal comprising: 
<claim-text>bending a portion of the sheet metal to form a leg portion and a web portion such that the leg portion is oriented at an angle relative to the web portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>supporting the web portion along a horizontal plane; </claim-text>
<claim-text>engaging a junction formed between the leg portion and the web portion with a member; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a further bending force to the leg in a direction which reduces the angle between the leg portion and the web portion while said engaging the junction between the leg portion and web portion with the member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the angle relative to the web portion is reduced to an angle within the range of eighty-four to ninety-one degrees upon said applying a further bending force to the leg. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said engaging a junction formed between the leg portion and web portion further comprises engaging the junction with an angled roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising removing at least some camber in the component after said applying a further bending force. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising removing at least some twist in the component after said applying a further bending force. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising removing at least some bow in the component after said applying a further bending force. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a structural component from a flat piece of sheet metal having a pair of lateral sides, said method comprising: 
<claim-text>bending portions of the flat piece of sheet metal along each lateral side to form lip portions that each protrude at an angle relative to a remaining portion of the piece of sheet metal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>bending the remaining portion of the piece of sheet metal to form a leg portion corresponding to each lip portion such that the lip portion protrudes from the corresponding leg portion at an angle and such that each leg portion forms a corresponding junction with a web portion extending between the leg portions, each leg portion oriented at an angle relative to the web portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>supporting the web portion along a horizontal plane; </claim-text>
<claim-text>engaging the junction formed between one of the leg portions and the web portion with a member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a further bending force to the one of the leg portions in a direction which reduces the angle between the one of the leg portions and the web portion while said engaging the junction between the one of the leg portions and web portion with the member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>engaging another junction formed between another of the leg portions and the web portion with another member; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying another further bending force to the another of the leg portions in a direction which reduces the angle between the another of the leg portions and the web portion while said engaging the junction between the another of the leg portions and web portion with the another member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the angle of one of the leg portions relative to the web portion is reduced to an angle within the range of eighty-four to ninety-one degrees upon said applying a further bending force to the one of the leg portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the angle of the another of the leg portions relative to the web portion is reduced to another angle within the range of eighty-four to ninety-one degrees upon said applying another further bending force to the another of the leg portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said engaging a junction formed between the one of the leg portions and web portion further comprises engaging the junction with an angled roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said engaging another junction formed between the another of the leg portions and web portion further comprises engaging the another junction with another angled roller. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising removing at least some camber in the component after said applying another further bending force. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising removing at least some twist in the component after said applying another further bending force. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising removing at least some bow in the component after said applying another further bending force.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>10</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00019">
<image id="EMI-D00019" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00020">
<image id="EMI-D00020" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00021">
<image id="EMI-D00021" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00022">
<image id="EMI-D00022" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00023">
<image id="EMI-D00023" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00024">
<image id="EMI-D00024" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00025">
<image id="EMI-D00025" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00026">
<image id="EMI-D00026" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00027">
<image id="EMI-D00027" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00027.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00028">
<image id="EMI-D00028" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00028.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00029">
<image id="EMI-D00029" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00029.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00030">
<image id="EMI-D00030" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00030.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00031">
<image id="EMI-D00031" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00031.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00032">
<image id="EMI-D00032" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00032.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00033">
<image id="EMI-D00033" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00033.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00034">
<image id="EMI-D00034" file="US20030000271A1-20030102-D00034.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
