<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002997A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002997A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002997A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002997A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002997A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002997A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002997A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002997A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002997A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002997A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002997</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10184923</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-198528</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F04B017/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>417</class>
<subclass>360000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Fuel supply apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tadashi</given-name>
<family-name>Hazama</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chita-gun</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Larry S. Nixon, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>NIXON &amp; VANDERHYE P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>8th Floor</address-1>
<address-2>1100 North Glebe Rd.</address-2>
<city>Arlington</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22201-4714</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A fuel supply apparatus in which, even if a column support receiving region of a supporting member is broken, the breakage is prevented from reaching both surfaces of the supporting member. A flange member includes a circular plate-shaped flange body attached to a fuel tank, an inner sleeve into which a column support is inserted, and an outer sleeve located at an outer periphery of the inner sleeve that is integrally formed. A bottom portion of the inner sleeve extends farther on the opposite side of a sub tank than the flange body, and the column support for providing a connection between the sub tank and the flange member has one end press-inserted into the inner sleeve beyond the flange body to a point opposite the sub tank. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is based upon, and claims the benefit of priority of, prior Japanese Patent Application No. 2001-198528 filed on Jun. 29, 2001, the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a fuel supply apparatus in which a supporting member attached to a fuel tank and a sub tank for housing a fuel pump are coupled to each other by a column support. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Generally, an example of what is commonly referred to as an in-tank type fuel supply apparatus which is designed to house a fuel pump in a fuel tank consists of a flange member of a fuel supply apparatus, attached to an upper wall of a fuel tank, coupled by a column support made of metal to a pump case for housing a fuel pump. In such a fuel supply apparatus, it is preferable that a part of the flange member that extends toward the pump case be made as small as possible in length. This is especially advantageous in a fuel supply apparatus in which an interval between the flange member and the pump case is reduced in keeping with the use of a lower-profile fuel tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Moreover, it is preferable to bring the pump case into contact with the bottom of the fuel tank. By doing so, when the fuel remaining in the fuel tank decreases in volume, the fuel contained in the fuel tank is drawn by the fuel pump through a fuel inlet of the pump case. Also, in a case where a sub tank is used as a pump case, and the fuel within the fuel tank is supplied to the sub tank by a jet pump or the like so the liquid level of the fuel within the sub tank raises to a position above the liquid level of the fuel within the fuel tank, the sub tank should preferably be pressed against the bottom of the fuel tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> To achieve this, in general, the pump case is coupled to a column support in such a way as to be movable with respect to the supporting member, and a coil spring is disposed around the column support. By increasing an urging force exerted by the coil spring, the pump case presses against the bottom of the fuel tank. In a case where the fuel tank is made of resin, the fuel tank may expand or contract due to a change in its internal pressure. This results in deformation of the fuel tank. Therefore, it is necessary to ensure that the sub tank keeps up with deformation of the fuel tank by pressing the pump case against the bottom of the fuel tank using the urging force of the coil spring. In order to secure the urging force of the coil spring required to press the pump case against the fuel tank bottom, and an adequate amount of movement of the pump case relative to the metal column support while being urged by the coil spring, an interval between a tubular portion of the flange member, into which the metal column support is inserted, and the pump case needs to be kept at least at a predetermined length. To secure as long an interval as possible between the tubular portion of the flange member for receiving the metal column support and the pump case, it is preferable that a part of the tubular portion formed in the flange member that extends out toward the pump case be made smaller in length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In light of the foregoing, a fuel supply apparatus is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> in which an insertion portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in the form of a bottomed sleeve, composed of a tubular portion <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and a bottom portion <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, is formed so as to extend from a plate-shaped flange body <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> of a flange member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> toward the side opposite to a pump case (not shown), and a metal column support <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is inserted into the insertion portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. A coil spring <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> loads the pump case with a force that tends to move the pump case in a direction away from the flange member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Here, assume that a vehicle experiences a collision and a harsh impact force is applied to the fuel tank mounted therein. In this case, the flange member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, being attached to the upper wall of the fuel tank, concurrently moves with the fuel tank. The pump case, being coupled to the flange member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> by the metal column support <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and being pressed against the bottom of the fuel tank by the urging force of the coil spring <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, is forced to move by inertia even after the movements of the fuel tank and the flange member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are stopped. Since one end of the metal column support <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> coupled to the pump case is moved concurrently with the pump case, its other end is forced to tilt obliquely with respect to the flange member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. That is, the metal column support may not be at a 90 degree angle with the flange member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Consequently, a crack <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may develop in a corner portion which the flange body <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> forms with the tubular portion <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, which results in fuel leaking from within the fuel tank through the crack <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, an object of the present invention is to provide a fuel supply apparatus which is designed so that, even if a column support receiving portion of a supporting member is broken, the breakage is prevented from reaching both surfaces of the supporting member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In a fuel supply apparatus according to a first aspect of the present invention, a bottom portion of an outer sleeve, formed continuously with a bottom portion of an inner sleeve for receiving a column support, is located on a same plane as the bottom portion of the inner sleeve, or extends farther on an opposite side of a pump case than the bottom portion of the inner sleeve. By this construction, even if a harsh impact force is applied to the fuel supply apparatus and as a result cracking occurs in a corner portion which a tubular portion of the inner sleeve forms with the bottom portion thereof, the resultant crack is prevented from reaching the tubular or bottom portion of the outer sleeve. That is, both surfaces of a supporting member are free from cracking. Accordingly, even if a crack develops in a column support receiving portion of a supporting member in a state where the fuel supply apparatus is attached to the fuel tank, fuel within the fuel tank is prevented from leaking through the crack to the outside. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Further, since the inner sleeve extends farther on the opposite side of the pump case than a supporting body, the length of the part of the inner sleeve that protrudes toward the pump case decreases. In the foregoing description, the pump case may be coupled to the column support so as to be movable along a longitudinal direction of the column support. The coil spring may load the pump case with a force that tends to move it in a direction away from the supporting member. Accordingly, it is possible to ensure that the pump case remains pressed against the bottom of the fuel tank in a state where the fuel supply apparatus is attached to the fuel tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the sub tank to which the fuel within the fuel tank is supplied may be used as a pump case for housing a fuel pump. By keeping the level of the fuel within the sub tank higher than the level of the fuel within the fuel tank, even if the fuel remaining in the fuel tank becomes lower in volume, the fuel pump will be able to reliably draw in and discharge the fuel within the sub tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the inner sleeve may have a rib formed at the outer periphery thereof. This helps improve the strength of the inner sleeve, and consequently the inner sleeve becomes resistant to breakage. When an impact force is applied to the fuel supply apparatus, breakage tends to occur particularly in the mechanically weak portion formed in the inner sleeve&apos;s tubular portion for receiving the column support. Consequently, in the foregoing construction, the inner sleeve may have a mechanically weak portion formed in the tubular portion, thereby the parts of the inner sleeve other than the tubular portion are protected from cracking. Furthermore, the supporting member may be made of resin and thus can be molded in one piece with ease. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Further areas of applicability of the present invention will become apparent from the detailed description provided hereinafter. It should be understood that the detailed description and specific examples, while indicating the preferred embodiment of the invention, are intended for purposes of illustration only and are not intended to limit the scope of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The present invention will become more fully understood from the detailed description and the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> showing a flange member employed in a fuel supply apparatus in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a view taken in a direction of arrow B shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front view showing the fuel supply apparatus in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view showing the flange member of the fuel supply apparatus in accordance with a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view showing the flange member of the fuel supply apparatus in accordance with a third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view showing the flange member of the fuel supply apparatus in accordance with a fourth embodiment of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view showing a flange member in a conventional example of a fuel supply apparatus.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The following description of the preferred embodiments is merely exemplary in nature and is in no way intended to limit the invention, its application, or uses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> (First Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a fuel supply apparatus in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention. The fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> which is attached to an upper wall of a fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> made of resin. The other components constituting the fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are accommodated in the fuel tank <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, acting as a supporting member, and a sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, acting as a pump case, are each made of resin and coupled to a column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> made of metal. The column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is inserted through a tubular portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of a stay <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> supported by the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is movable along a longitudinal direction of the column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A coil spring <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> loads the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with a force that tends to move it in a direction away from the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, that is, moves it toward a bottom of the fuel tank. In this way, a bottom portion of the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> remains pressed against an inner bottom surface of the fuel tank in a state where the fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is attached to the fuel tank. With such a construction, even if the resin-made fuel tank expands or contracts due to a change in its internal pressure resulting from a temperature change, or a change in the amount of fuel, the bottom portion of the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is constantly kept pressed against the inner bottom surface of the fuel tank by an urging force exerted by the coil spring <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises: a flange body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, provided as a supporting body, in the shape of a circular plate that is attached to the fuel tank; an inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> into which the column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is inserted; and an outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> located at an outer periphery of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. These components are formed integrally with one another by using resin. The inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the form of a bottomed sleeve includes a tubular portion <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and a bottom portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and has on its sub-tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> side an opening. An inner bottom surface of the bottom portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> extends farther on the opposite side of the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> than the flange body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has its one end press-inserted into the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> beyond the flange body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to a point opposite the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may alternatively be inserted into the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by insert molding instead of by press insertion. The outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> includes a tubular portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a bottom portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The bottom portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> extends farther on the opposite side of the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> than the bottom portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the tubular portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is formed continuously with the flange body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, and the bottom portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is formed continuously with the bottom portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</cross-reference>, at the outer periphery of the tubular portion <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are formed four pieces of ribs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The ribs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> do not necessarily have to be four in number. The ribs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> serve to improve the mechanical strength of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, so that the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> resists breaking. Between the tubular portion <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the tubular portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are formed spaces <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, which are arranged between the adjacent ribs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> so as to surround the column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further comprises: a discharge pipe <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>; a return pipe <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>; and an electric connector <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> that are formed integrally with one another by using resin. Alternatively, the discharge pipe <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the return pipe <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and the electric connector <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be provided separately from one another when attached to the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The discharge pipe <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> serves to discharge fuel discharged from a fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> housed in the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to the outside of the fuel tank. The discharge pipe <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are connected to each other by an accordion pipe <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is arranged horizontally within the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The return pipe <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> serves to return excessive fuel fed from the engine side into the fuel tank, and is connected to a jet pump <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> by an accordion pipe <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The electric connector <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> serves to supply a driving current to the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and to output signals detected in a level gage (not shown). The electric connector <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, an electric portion of the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and the level gage are connected to one another by a lead wire <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The jet pump <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> emits, through a jet nozzle <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, fuel which has been returned through the accordion pipe <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> from the return pipe <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, draws in the fuel within the fuel tank by exploiting a suction pressure generated by a jet of the fuel that is lower than an atmospheric pressure, and forcibly feeds the fuel into the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Next, the fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> will be described. When the engine is driven to operate and a driving current is supplied from the electric connector <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> draws in the fuel within the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and then, after removing foreign substances, discharges the fuel through the discharge pipe <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> toward the engine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The fuel having been returned from the engine side to the accordion pipe <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> through the return pipe <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> passes through the jet pump <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, and is thereafter emitted into the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. At this time, the fuel within the fuel tank is drawn by a suction pressure resulting from a jet of the fuel. By the injection pressure of the jet pump <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, the level of the fuel within the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is raised with respect to the outside of the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and is maintained at a predetermined level. Consequently, even if no fuel exists around the jet pump <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> when the vehicle corners or is operated on a steep incline when the level of the fuel within the fuel tank is low, the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is able to draw in the fuel within the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> without causing improper fuel suctioning, that is, a disruption, thereby making it possible to continuously supply fuel to the engine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> When a considerable impact force is applied to the fuel supply apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> due to collision of the vehicle or other accident, and the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the fuel pump <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are moved relative to the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the fuel tank, the column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is forced to tilt obliquely with respect to the flange member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Then, a tensile force is applied to a corner portion formed by the tubular portion <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the bottom portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. This results in development of a crack <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. However, since the bottom portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is located farther on the opposite side of the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> than the bottom portion <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the crack <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> developed in the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will reach the tubular portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the bottom portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Consequently, even if the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> suffers from the crack <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the fuel within the fuel tank will not leak to the outside of the fuel tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> (Second Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a second embodiment of the present invention. In a flange member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, provided as a supporting member, according to the second embodiment, no rib is formed at the outer periphery of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> (Third Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a third embodiment of the present invention. In a flange member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> according to the third embodiment, an annular recess <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is formed in an outer corner portion which a tubular portion <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of an inner sleeve <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> forms with a bottom portion <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> thereof. When an impact force is applied to the fuel supply apparatus, cracking tends to occur particularly in the annular recess <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> because of its weak mechanical strength. Consequently, regions of the flange member <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, other than the annular recess <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, are less susceptible to cracking, and thus no crack is developed in the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> (Fourth Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a fourth embodiment of the present invention. In this embodiment, an inner sleeve <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> has four pieces of ribs <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> formed at its outer periphery. The ribs <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> are each shaped so that its overhanging portion becomes gradually smaller from the interior of the bottom portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> toward a front end of a tubular portion <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. Providing these ribs helps improve the mechanical strength of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, and consequently the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> becomes resistant to breakage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In the plurality of embodiments described herein above, on the outside of the inner sleeve for receiving the column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is additionally arranged the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, so that the bottom portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> extends farther on the opposite side of the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> than the bottom portion of the inner sleeve. In this construction, even if an impact force is applied to the fuel supply apparatus and the column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is inclined with respect to the inner sleeve, resulting in a crack in the inner sleeve, the crack never reaches the outer sleeve <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, even if, for example, a vehicle experiences a collision and the resultant shock causes breakage in the inner sleeve of the flange member, the fuel within the fuel tank is prevented from leaking to the outside of the fuel tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Moreover, a part of the inner sleeve <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> of the flange member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> for receiving the column support <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> protrudes in the direction opposite to the sub tank. This arrangement helps reduce the length of the part of the inner sleeve that protrudes from the flange member toward the sub tank, and thereby increases the interval between the inner sleeve and the sub tank. Also in a case where the fuel supply apparatus is accommodated in a low-profile fuel tank, the interval between the inner sleeve and the sub tank can be kept at a predetermined length or above. This makes it possible to keep an appropriate urging force exerted by the coil spring, and to secure an adequate amount of movement of the sub tank <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> required to keep up with the deformation of the fuel tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Although, in the above-described embodiments, the bottom portion of the outer sleeve is located farther on the opposite side of the sub tank than the bottom portion of the inner sleeve, the bottom portion of the inner sleeve and the bottom portion of the outer sleeve may be located on the same plane. Moreover, the flange member may be made of metal or other material instead of resin. Further, where the fuel tank is made of metal instead of resin, the fuel tank is less likely to deform. Thus, in this case, in order to bring the sub tank into contact with the inner bottom surface of the fuel tank with the fuel supply apparatus attached to the fuel tank, the sub tank should preferably be securely fixed to the other end of the column support. This eliminates the need to provide the coil spring for loading the sub tank with a force that tends to move it in a direction away from the flange member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In any of the above-described embodiments, instead of the sub tank for storing fuel in such a way that its level is kept higher than the level of the fuel within the fuel tank, a pump case may be employed that serves merely to store a fuel pump. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The description of the invention is merely exemplary in nature and, thus, variations that do not depart from the gist of the invention are intended to be within the scope of the invention. Such variations are not to be regarded as a departure from the spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A fuel supply apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a pump case housed in a fuel tank; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fuel pump housed in the pump case, for drawing in and discharging fuel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a supporting member attached to an upper wall of the fuel tank; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a column support for providing a connection between the supporting member and the pump case, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the supporting member comprises: 
<claim-text>a plate-shaped flange body defining an inner sleeve; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom portion formed in the inner sleeve, the inner sleeve having on its pump-case side an opening and having an inner bottom surface which is located farther from the pump case than a portion of the supporting body, one end of the column support being inserted in the inner sleeve beyond the supporting body to the inner bottom surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an outer sleeve with a bottom formed in it, the outer sleeve having a bottom portion which is formed continuously with the bottom portion of the inner sleeve and having a tubular portion which is formed continuously with the supporting member, the bottom portion of the outer sleeve being located in a plane farther from the pump case than the bottom portion of the inner sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a coil spring disposed around the column support, for supplying the pump case with a force that tends to move the pump case in a direction away from the supporting member, wherein the pump case is coupled to the column support so as to be movable along a longitudinal direction of the column support. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pump case is a sub tank, and the fuel pump draws and discharges fuel which is fed from the fuel tank to the sub tank. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pump case is a sub tank, and the fuel pump draws and discharges fuel which is fed from the fuel tank to the sub tank. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a rib formed at an outer periphery thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a rib formed at an outer periphery thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a rib formed at an outer periphery thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the inner sleeve has a rib formed at an outer periphery thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a mechanically weak portion formed in a tubular portion thereof into which the column support is inserted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a mechanically weak portion formed in a tubular portion thereof into which the column support is inserted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a mechanically weak portion formed in a tubular portion thereof into which the column support is inserted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a mechanically weak portion formed in a tubular portion thereof into which the column support is inserted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a mechanically weak portion formed in a tubular portion thereof into which the column support is inserted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a mechanically weak portion formed in a tubular portion thereof into which the column support is inserted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve has a mechanically weak portion formed in a tubular portion thereof into which the column support is inserted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the supporting member is made of resin, and the column support is made of metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A fuel supply apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a pump case housed in a fuel tank; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fuel pump housed in the pump case, for drawing in and discharging fuel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a flange body defining an outer sleeve and an inner sleeve, wherein the flange body is attached to an upper wall of the fuel tank; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom portion formed in the outer sleeve and a bottom portion formed in the inner sleeve, wherein the bottom portion of the outer sleeve and the bottom portion of the inner sleeve are parallel to each other and continuously formed with the flange body and each bottom portion closes an end portion of each respective sleeve at a location farthest from the pump case. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of ribs located about an outer periphery of the inner sleeve, wherein the sleeves taper from a thickest portion adjacent a bottom portion of the outer sleeve to a point along the inner sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a coil spring abutting the inner sleeve and coaxial with the inner sleeve; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a column support passing through the coil spring and into the inner sleeve and abutting against an inner sleeve bottom surface, wherein the pump case is coupled to the column support so as to be movable along a longitudinal direction of the column support. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The fuel supply apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inner sleeve defines an annular recess to provide a mechanically weak point in the inner sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002997A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002997A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002997A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002997A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002997A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
