<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003784A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003784A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003784A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003784A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003784A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003784A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003784A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003784A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003784A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003784A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003784A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003784A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003784</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09897332</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01R012/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>439</class>
<subclass>082000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Interposer assembly.</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Douglas</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Neidich</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Harrisburg</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Thomas Hooker, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>Thomas Hooker, P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 304</address-1>
<address-2>100 Chestnut Street</address-2>
<city>Harrisburg</city>
<state>PA</state>
<postalcode>17101</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An interposer assembly includes a dielectric plate having a plurality of contact passages extending through the plate with a contact in each passage. Each contact includes a pair of laterally spaced contact points at the top and bottom of the plate. Sandwiching of the interposer assembly between two substrates brings the contact points on each spring arm into engagement with a pad, elastically bends the contacts and forms redundant high pressure wiped electrical connections between the contact points and pads. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to interposer assemblies of the type which are sandwiched between substrates to form electrical connections between opposed pads on the substrates, and to cantilever contacts for forming electrical connections with contact pads. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Interposer assemblies typically include plastic plates with through passages and contacts in the passages for forming electrical connections between opposed contact pads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Interposer assemblies form electrical connections between contact pads arranged in a very close proximity to each other. The pads may be arranged on a one millimeter center-to-center grid. Each assembly may include as many as 961 contacts with four interposer assemblies mounted in a single frame with a total of 3,844 contacts in the frame. The contacts must establish reliable electrical connections with the pads when the assemblies are sandwiched together between circuit members. Failure of a single contact to make a reliable connection renders the entire frame useless. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Contacts in interposer assemblies include contact surfaces which mechanically engage the contact pads and form electrical connections with the contact pads. Conventional interposer assemblies have single surface contacts which engage each pad to form a single electrical connection with each pad. The contact may wipe along the pad to improve the quality of the electrical connection. Impurities, oxides or contaminants on either the contact surface or the pad can impair the single surface electrical connections with the pads. Contacts used in interposer assemblies are typically symmetrical about the center of the insulating plate, each including a separate spring which biases a single contact surface against a pad. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, there is a need for an improved interposer assembly in which each contact makes redundant contacts with each pad so that when the assembly is sandwiched between overlying and underlying substrates each contact establishes two reliable electrical connections with each pad. The connections should have small contact areas to increase the contact pressure between the contact and the pad. Wiped high contact pressure redundant connections would provide reliable interposer assembly electrical connections. There is also a need for a method of making a contact with spaced contact points from strip stock, which may be very thin and difficult to form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Further, there is need for a spring contact having spaced contact points for engaging a contact pad and forming redundant wiped high pressure redundant electrical connections between the contact and the pad. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The invention is an improved interposer assembly including contacts mounted in passages extending through an insulating plate with each contact having two contact points on each end of the contact. When the interposer assembly is sandwiched between overlying and underlying substrates the pairs of contact points are brought into wiped pressure engagement with overlying and underlying pads and forms redundant electrical connections with the pads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The contact points are formed on rounded edge corners of the contacts and have small contact areas, resulting in high contact pressure and reliable electrical connections despite debris, oxides and surface contaminants on the contacts and pads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Each contact includes two tapered spring arms joined to a central portion. A pair of contact points is formed on the outer end of each spring arm. The points project above and below the plate. The arms are independently deflected during compression of the contact by overlying and underlying substrates. The spring arms may include retention legs extending outwardly from the contact points for engagement with adjacent cam surfaces. Compression of the contacts moves the ends of the legs along the cam surface to further stress the spring and increase contact force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the invention relates to a contact having a beam with a mounting end and a contact end carrying a pair of laterally spaced contact points. Movement of a pad against the contact points stresses the beam and moves the contact points laterally along the pad to form wiped high pressure electrical connections between the contact and the pad. The contact points are rounded edge corners and have a very small contact area in order to increase contact pressure and form redundant wiped high pressure electrical connections between the contact and the pad. The contact points are preferably located on opposite sides of the spring arm and stabilize the contact against twisting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Other objects and features of the invention will become apparent as the description proceeds, especially when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings illustrating the invention, of which there are five sheets of drawings and two embodiments.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top view, broken away, of an interposer assembly according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is an isometric view of a contact used in the interposer assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top view of a substrate with pads for forming electrical connections with the contacts in the interposer assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a view like <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> showing the interposer assembly sandwiched between top and bottom substrates; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of portion of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> showing an alternative construction; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a view like <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> showing the substrates engaging the interposer assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a view like <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> showing wipe traces on the contact pads of the substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a partially broken away view taken along line <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a contact perform; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of a portion of the perform of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> showing a pair of wings; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> showing the wings bent upwardly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing tooling used for punch forming the preform from strip stock; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</cross-reference> are sectional views showing a cantilever contact related to the interposer contact.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The disclosure relates to the interposer assembly of U.S. Pat. No. 6,176,707, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The disclosure also relates to the interposer assembly of Neidich, et al. U.S. patent application for &ldquo;Interposer Assembly,&rdquo; Ser. No. 09/455,989, filed Jun. 28, 2000, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference, in its entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The first embodiment interposer assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a flat dielectric plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> preferably molded from thermoplastic resin and having a plurality of contact passages <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> extending through the thickness of the plate from plate top <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to plate bottom <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is held in each passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The height of plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be as little as 0.048 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Passages <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are elongate in transverse cross section. Each passage includes a wide end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, an opposed narrow end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a uniform width portion <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> adjacent the wide end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and a tapered, reduced width portion <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> adjacent the narrow end. The uniform width portion <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> has opposed parallel walls extending between the top and bottom of the plate and the reduced width portion has inwardly tapered walls extending from portion <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to narrow end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> shallow contact-retention projection <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is formed in each narrow passage end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The projection is defined by flat upper and lower cam surfaces <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> extending from projection tip <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to the top and bottom of plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> respectively. The tip is located equidistant between the top and bottom of the plate. Both cam surfaces slope away from the tip at a shallow angle of about 12 degrees from the vertical. Flat end wall <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> at wide passage end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> extends perpendicularly between the top and bottom of plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a modified interposer assembly plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>similar to plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and having a top cam surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and bottom cam surface (not illustrated) which end a short distance <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> inwardly from the plate top side <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and bottom side (not illustrated). The cam surfaces and short, straight end wall surfaces <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> at the top and bottom sides of the plate extend across the narrow end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of contact passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Plates <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are molded from thermoplastic resin using mold supporting core pins forming passages <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>The tooling supporting the core pins normally extends a very short distance into the mold cavity to prevent the cam surfaces from extending to the top and bottom of the plate. Each straight surface <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> has a vertical extent of about 0.005 inches so that, in practice, the cam surfaces are recessed from the top and bottom of the plate only a very small distance. This recess distance does not effect the operation of the interposer assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed from thin uniform thickness metal strip stock, which may be a beryllium copper, and is preferably plated with a conductive metal, which may be gold or a gold alloy, to reduce contact resistance and prevent oxidation. Contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be made from strip stock having a thickness of 0.0017 inches. This thin stock is difficult to shape accurately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> include a flat central portion or spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, like upper and lower curved and tapered spring arms or beams <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> extend in opposite directions from spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Contact noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are located at the upper and lower ends of the spring arms. Short, straight and tapered retention legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> extending outwardly from the noses and toward each other to rounded ends <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. When contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are unstressed the noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are spaced apart a distance of 0.060 inches, greater than the thickness of plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Spring arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are bent laterally away from central spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in the same direction so that noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are located between the spine and retention leg ends <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> have a maximum width adjacent spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The width of each arm decreases from the spine to nose <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are symmetrical to either side of spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Each spring arm <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> includes a pair of contact points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> adjacent nose <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The contact points are spaced apart on opposite sides of the spring arm a short distance inwardly from the nose and project above the surface of the arm. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the contact points also are located outwardly from the arms to increase the width of the contact adjacent the nose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates preform <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> which is stamped from uniform thickness strip stock and shaped to form contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The preform includes a central portion <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which forms spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and two, like arm or beam sections <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> extending to either side of the central portion which form arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The widths of the arm sections decrease from a maximum at the central portion to minimums at ends <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Rounded projections or wings <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> extend outwardly from the sides of the arm sections between the central portion <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and ends <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates tooling used to stamping preform <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> from thin strip stock <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The strip stock is positioned on anvil <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> with an overlying pressure plate <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> clamping the strip stock to the anvil. Cutters <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, located to either side of the plate and anvil and above strip stock <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, are moved down past the anvil to cut or shear away outer portions <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the strip stock from the portion <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> held between the anvil and pressure plate. Sharing forms sheared edges <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> on held portion <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> with rounded upper corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and sharp, drag lower corners <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. In the drawings, the size of corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is exaggerated for clarity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Stamped preform <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> includes cut edges <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> extending along the sides of both arm sections <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and around the wings or projections <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> on the arm sections. Rounded edge corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> are located on one side of the preform and drag corners <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> are located on the other side of the preform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed from preform <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> by bending the preform about axes parallel to the plane of the preform to form curved spring arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and curved ends <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> at the ends of legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The preform is bent to locate rounded edge corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> on the outside of the contact and drag corners <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> on the inside of the contact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Additionally, during bending of the preform to form the contact, or as an independent step, both projections or wings <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> are bent upwardly relative to the arm sections, around bend lines <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, to form contact points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extending above the spring arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> adjacent to noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates the bent up wings with rounded corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> located above the arm section <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and with the drag corners <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> located outwardly and below the rounded corners. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Contact preform <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> may have a thickness of 0.0017 inches. Metal of this thickness is very hard to handle and shape reliably. The small diameter, rounded corners on the contact points are formed during shearing of the preform from strip stock material without the necessity of physically bending the strip stock. The rounded corners are very small having a transverse radius of curvature of about 0.0006 inches to 0.0010 depending on tool clearance and wear. It would be very difficult to form these small rounded corners by mechanically shaping the preform. The radius of curvature along the length of the corners is about 0.012 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> After bending of preform <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to form contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as described, the contact is preferably plated with a conductive metal which may be gold or a gold alloy to form a plating <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> surrounding the contact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Formed and plated contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are inserted into contact passages <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by positioning each contact to one side of a passage with a contact nose located adjacent the center of the passage, spring arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> adjacent wide passage end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and retention legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> adjacent narrow passage end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The contact is then moved into the passage to bring spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> into engagement with wall <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and the lead retention leg <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> into engagement with the adjacent cam surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. This engagement results because the horizontal distance between the spine and curved ends <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> of legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is greater than the minimum spacing between tip <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and wall <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Continued movement of the contact into the passage elastically stresses the contact to move the leg inwardly and permit movement the leg past the projection to the inserted position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. After the leg passes the projection tip the contact returns to the shape shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. In this position the contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is unstressed and loose in passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Projection <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extends between the ends of the retention legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> to prevent dislodgement of the loose contact from the passage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows loose contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with the retention legs away from the projection. In practice, gravity will shift the contact down in the passage so that the upper leg <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> rests on upper top cam surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. With contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as illustrated, the upper and lower contact noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are located at the top and bottom of the contact. The contact points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are also located at the top and bottom of the contact. Noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> extend across the width of the contact. Projections <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are located on the opposed sides of the contact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In one interposer assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with a thickness of 0.048 inches and contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> formed from uniform thickness strip stock having a thickness of 0.0017 inches the height of the unstressed contacts from nose to nose is 0.060 inches. When the contact is positioned in a contact passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> each contact nose <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> projects a distance 0.006 inches above the top or bottom side of the plate. The contact points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are spaced apart across the width of the contact 0.0115 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Interposer assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is used to establish electrical connections between opposed contact pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> on substrates <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> located to either side of the assembly. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates the contact surface of a substrate <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> with pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the interposer assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> located between substrates <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> with the contact pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> lightly engaging the contact noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and contact points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> on each end of contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> with contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> unstressed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates interposer assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> fully sandwiched between substrates <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> with the contact pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> on the substrates engaging the top and bottom plate surfaces and contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> collapsed into passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. During movement of the substrates onto the plate each contact nose is collapsed 0.006 inches into the passage, the rounded ends of the retention legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are brought into engagement with the upper and lower cam surfaces <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and are moved inwardly along the surfaces to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> adjacent tip <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. As the contact is collapsed, the retention legs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and the spring arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are bent laterally elastically to provide high contact pressure between the ends of the contact and the pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and to wipe the points along the pads. The spring arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and central portion or spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> form an elastic spring system. In this position, contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are held in the passages by the substrates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is collapsed into passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> the ends of arms <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> rotate and engagement between the outer ends of the arms and pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> moves along the arms from noses <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to the adjacent rounded corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> at the tops of the contact points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Compare <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 6</cross-reference>. The rounded edge corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> at the tops of the contact points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> wipe along pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> to form wipe traces <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Each trace <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> extends from a point of initial contact <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> between a point <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the pad to a final contact position <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. The contact points move along traces <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> in a direction away from passage wide end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and toward passage narrow end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The resiliency of the stressed spring system biases the small area rounded corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> against the contact pads under high pressure as the points are moved along traces <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. The contact pressure exerted by the spring system is applied to the pads at the small four rounded corners <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, resulting in redundant high pressure electrical connections between the points and pads. The contact pressures are high because the contact areas are low. High pressure wiped engagement between the points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the pads breaks through debris, oxides or other surface contaminants on the points or on the pads. The rounded corners slide along, but do not cut into the pads. The provision of redundant contacts at each end of contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> increases the reliability of electrical connection between contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> over conventional single area contacts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> During compression of contacts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into passages <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> the two contact arms <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are each bent away from wide passage end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> independently of each other with contact central portion or spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> held on end wall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, although the contact may shift vertically a slight distance in the passage to shift the spine up or down along wide end wall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Each arm <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is stressed essentially independently of the other arm <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> so that the contact pressure at points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> on one end of the contact is provided by elastic deformation of the adjacent spring arm <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and retention leg <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, located to one side of the central portion. Thus, contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes two like spring contacts each located to one side of the central portion and each including a curved tapered spring arm <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a tapered retention leg <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The width of retention leg <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> decreases from nose <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to end <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to permit ready deflection of the leg by the adjacent cam surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Deflection of both the spring arm <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and leg <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> contribute to the spring force holding projections <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> against adjacent pad <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Each of the independent, like spring contacts provides an electrical connection between a contact pad and the spine <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> at the center of contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</cross-reference> illustrate a cantilever spring contact <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> formed from bent uniform thickness strip stock, related to contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The strip stock may have a desired thickness, which may be other than the thickness of contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The contact <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a mounting end <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and a contact end <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. End <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is mounted in substrate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. A curved, tapered spring arm or beam <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> extends upwardly from the substrate and is bent laterally to one side of the mounting end <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The mounting end is connected to a circuit element (not illustrated). Contact <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> connects the circuit element to pad <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> on substrate <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Spring arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> may be identical to spring arm <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and is a beam having a tapered width decreasing from a maximum width at mounting end <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to a minimum width at contact end or end <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. A pair of contact points <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> having upwardly facing rounded edge corners are formed on the opposite sides of arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> at end <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, end <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and contact points <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be identical to arm <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, nose <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and contact points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, previously described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> illustrates substrate <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> located above substrate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and carrying contact pad <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Pad <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> engages end <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and points <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of contact <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> without stressing the contact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Electrical connections are established between pad <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and contact <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> by reducing the distance between substrates <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> so that the spring arm <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is elastically bent laterally and engagement between the contact and the pad shifts from end <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to the rounded corners of spaced contact points <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, in the same way redundant contacts are established between the ends of the spring arms <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and overlying and underlying pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Elastic bending of the spring arm provides high contact pressure engagement between the points <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and pad <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The points are wiped along the pad to form contact traces on the pad like traces <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The wiped, redundant high pressure contacts between the contact and pad assure reliable low resistance electrical connections are established. The spaced apart contact points <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> support contact <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> on pad <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to prevent twisting of the contact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Contact <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> does not include a leg and curved end like retention leg <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and curved end <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> of contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. If desired, contact <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be provided with a leg <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> having a curved end <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, like leg <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and end <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and substrate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may be provided with a cam surface <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, like top cam surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in plate <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Leg <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, end <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and cam surface <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are shown in dashed lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</cross-reference>. During collapse of spring <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> provided with a leg <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and end <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, end <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> engages cam surface <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, leg <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is elastically deformed and increases the contact pressure between points <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and pad <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The spring arm <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> with arm <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and end <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is deformed identically to each half of contact <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as the overlying and underlying substrates <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> are moved together from the position of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> to the position of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> While I have illustrated and described a preferred embodiment of my invention, it is understood that this is capable of modification, and I therefore do not wish to be limited to the precise details set forth, but desire to avail myself of such changes and alterations as fall within the purview of the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What I claim as my invention: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An interposer assembly for forming redundant electrical connections with contact pads on substrates positioned above and below the assembly, said assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a) an insulating plate having top and bottom sides and a plurality of passages extending through the thickness of the plate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a plurality of metal contacts, each contact disposed in one of said passages, each contact including a first pair of spaced contact points at the top side of the plate, a second pair of spaced contact points at the bottom side of the plate, and a spring portion extending between said first pair of contact points and said second pair of contact points, said spring portion spacing said pairs of contact points apart a distance greater than the thickness of the plate when the spring portion is unstressed, wherein each pair of contact points forms redundant electrical connections with a contact pad on a substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein in each contact the contact points of each pair of contact points are spaced laterally across the contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point comprises a rounded corner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact is formed from uniform thickness strip stock having a sheared circumferential edge, and each contact point is located on a corner of said circumferential edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each spring portion includes a central portion and a pair of beams, each beam located between the central portion and a pair of contact points, said beams elastically bendable into said passages. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point is bent to one side of a beam. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point is rounded along the length of the edge corner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said strip stock has a thickness of about 0.0017 inches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said rounded corners have a transverse radius of curvature of about 0.0006 to 0.0010 inches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact is symmetrical to either side of the central portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the plate includes a projection extending into each passage, and each contact includes two retention portions located on opposite sides of a projection to retain the contact in the passage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact includes opposed sheared edges, each contact point comprising a shear rounded edge corner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point comprises a bent projection. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An assembly adapted to be interposed between pairs of spaced metallic pads on substrates for forming electrical connections between the pads, said assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a) a dielectric plate having a top and a bottom, a plurality of spaced passages extending through the thickness of the plate from said top to said bottom thereof, said passages each including opposed interior walls, </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a projection in each passage, each projection extending outwardly from one of said interior walls toward an opposed interior wall and including a first surface facing said plate top and a second surface facing said plate bottom; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) a plurality of metal contacts, each contact disposed in one of said passages, each contact formed from thin sheet metal stock and including a central portion, a pair of beams extending to either side of the central portion, a nose located on the end of each beam, and a retention leg extending inwardly from each nose to an end located away from the central portion, said noses spaced apart a distance greater than the thickness of the plate when the contact is unstressed, each contact being located in a passage with the central portion adjacent an interior wall away from the passage projection and the ends of the retention legs located on opposite sides of the projection so that the projection retains the contact in the passage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) each contact including a pair of laterally spaced contact points adjacent each contact nose; </claim-text>
<claim-text>e) wherein upon compression of the contacts into the passages by opposed contact pads, the beams are stressed, and the contact points on each nose engage and wipe along a pad to form redundant wiped pressure connections with the pad. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said beams are curved. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point is located on an edge of a beam adjacent a nose. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point is located at a corner of a beam edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point comprises a shear-wiped corner of a beam edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said strip stock has a thickness of about 0.0017 inch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said contact points are rounded and have a radius of curvature of about 0.006 inches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point comprises a portion of a contact bent to one side of the remainder of the contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said beams are tapered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said retention legs are tapered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A spring contact for forming redundant electrical connections with a contact pad, said spring contact comprising an elongate metal body including a mounting end, a contact end and a resilient beam located between such ends, the beam extending laterally away from the mounting end to locate the contact end to one side of the mounting end, said contact end including a pair of contact points spaced across the contact end, wherein movement of a contact pad into engagement with contact points flexes the beam and wipes the contact points along the pad to form redundant pressure electrical connections between the contact and pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The spring contact as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point comprises a rounded edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The spring contact as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the spring contact is formed from uniform thickness strip stock having a sheared circumferential edge, and each contact point is located on a corner of said circumferential edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The spring contact as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point is bent to one side of the contact ends. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The spring contact as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point is rounded along the length of the edge corner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. An interposer assembly for forming redundant electrical connections with contact pads on substrates positioned above and below the assembly, said assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a) an insulating plate having top and bottom sides and a plurality of passages extending through the thickness of the plate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a plurality of metal contacts, each contact disposed in one of said passages, each metal contact comprising an integral body formed from uniform thickness strip stock and including a first spring contact as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> and a second spring contact as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, each metal contact including a central portion joining the mounting portions of said spring contacts, the contact portions of said spring contacts facing outwardly of the passage at the top and bottom thereof, the contact portions spaced apart a distance greater than the thickness of the plate when the metal contact is unstressed, wherein the contact points on each contact end form redundant electrical connections with a contact pad on a substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. An interposer assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said beams are curved. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. An interposer assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point comprises a rounded corner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. An interposer assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each rounded corner is located on a sheared edge of the metal contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. An interposer assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point is bent up from one side of a contact end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. An interposer assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each contact point is rounded along the length of the edge corner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of making a spring contact for forming redundant electrical connections with a contact pad, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>a) cutting a preform from a strip of uniform thickness metal stock to form a preform having a circumferential edge and edge corners; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) rounding one edge corner to form a pair of adjacent contact surfaces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) bending the preform to locate the contact surfaces to one side of the preform to form two spaced apart contact points. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> including the step of: 
<claim-text>d) bending the preform away from the contact points to form a resilient beam. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> including the step of: 
<claim-text>e) rounding the edge corners of said contact points along the lengths thereof.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003784A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003784A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003784A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003784A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003784A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003784A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
