<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000589A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000589A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000589A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000589A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000589</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10181721</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020722</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>100036481</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000129</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F16L055/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>138</class>
<subclass>031000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>138</class>
<subclass>030000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Hydropneumatic accumulator</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Norbert</given-name>
<family-name>Weber</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Sulzbach</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Mark S Bicks</name-1>
<name-2>Roylance Abrams Berdo &amp; Goodman</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 600</address-1>
<address-2>1300 19th Street NW</address-2>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20036</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/EP01/00442</doc-number>
<document-date>20010117</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The invention relates to a hydropneumatic accumulator comprising a bellow (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), which, inside the accumulator housing (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), separates a gas chamber (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) from an oil chamber (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and which is fastened with one end thereof to the accumulator housing (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) so that the oil chamber (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) is delimited by the inside of the bellow (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>). Said bellow is sealed on the other free end by means of a closing body (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) that moves according to changes in volume of the gas chamber (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) and of the oil chamber (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>). The hydropneumatic accumulator also comprises a valve (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>), which enables a hydraulic fluid to flow out of and into the oil chamber (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) or which blocks the flow of said hydraulic fluid. The valve can be transferred into its blocking position by the closing body (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) when the closing body (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) undergoes a movement corresponding to an increase in the volume of the gas chamber (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) that exceeds a predetermined maximum value. Said closing body is provided in the shape of a trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) which, with its edge (<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>) located on the open end (<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>), is connected to the assigned free end of the bellow (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>). The trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) extends with its lateral wall (<highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>) along the inside of the metal bellow (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), and the bottom (<highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>) of the trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) is configured as a moveable valve element of the valve (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) that controls the flow of hydraulic fluid. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a hydropneumatic accumulator with a bellows inside the accumulator housing separating a gas space from an oil space, especially a metal bellows which is fastened to the accumulator housing at one of its ends so that the oil space adjoins the interior of the bellows, which is closed at its other, free, end by a closing element which is movable as a function of changes in volume in the gas space and oil space, and with a valve allowing or preventing flow of hydraulic fluid from and into the oil space, a valve which, in the event of movement of the closing element which corresponds to increase in the volume of the gas space exceeding an assigned maximum value, may be transferred to its closing position, the closing element being in the form of a trough, the trough being connected by its edge situated on the open end to the associated free end of the bellows, the side wall of the trough extending along the inside of the bellows, and the bottom of the trough as a movable valve element being in the form of the valve controlling the flow of hydraulic fluid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> It is known that care must be taken to prevent overloading of the bellows in the case of bellows accumulators with rubber or metal bellows. In a conventional accumulator of the type referred to, which uses a metal bellows (see WO 97/46823), in connection with this problem a valve lifter of the valve connected to the oil space is mounted in a position relative to the closing element of the metal bellows such that the closing element, in the form of a flat end plate of the metal bellows, strikes the valve lifter when a desired end position has been reached and displaces it into the locked position of the valve so that escape of hydraulic fluid from the oil space is prevented when this end position of the end plate of the metal bellows is reached. Consequently, when the valve is closed, a pressure is maintained in the oil space of the accumulator, a pressure which corresponds to the gas pressure currently present in the gas space, even if the connected hydraulic system is not under pressure, so that pressure equilibrium prevails on both sides of the metal bellows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Although overloading of the bellows is thereby prevented when in operation of the accumulator the pressure of the hydraulic system connected thereto on the oil side drops, the danger nevertheless continues to exist of damage to the bellows under conditions characterized by excess pressure prevailing on the oil side or by absence of prefill pressure on the gas side. Since the maximum pressure of the gas space volume more or less corresponds to the stroke volume in the case of the conventional accumulator of the type in question, this volume being determined by the movement of the end plate occurring during contraction and expansion of the metal bellows, the length selected for the stroke which the end plate can execute inside the accumulator housing must be of adequate length if a volume of the gas space sufficient for operation of the accumulator is to be made available. Consequently, if gas prefill pressure is absent or excess pressure prevails on the oil side, the prevailing pressure gradient acts on the metal bellows which is fully expanded and accordingly subjected to the greatest mechanical stress. The result is that one must use metal bellows which are either thicker or consist of multiple layers. The resulting disadvantage is sharp increase in rigidity of the spring leading to a relatively poor response characteristic in operation. Multilayer bellows result in increased weight and higher costs. In addition, a smaller stroke is obtained for each turn of the bellows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> GB-A-1 047 983 discloses a generic hydropneumatic accumulator with a bellows inside the accumulator separating a gas space from an oil space. One end of the bellows is fastened to the accumulator housing so that the oil space adjoins the inside of the bellows, while the other, free, end of the bellows is closed by a closing element movable in response to appropriate volume changes in the gas space and oil space. The accumulator also has a valve releasing or blocking flow of hydraulic fluid from or into the oil space, a valve which may be transferred to its blocking position in the event of movement of the closing element corresponding to increase in the volume of the gas space exceeding an assigned value, the trough being connected by its edge situated on its open end to the associated free end of the bellows, the side wall of the trough extending along the inside of the bellows, and the bottom of the trough being in the form of a movable valve element of the valve controlling the flow of hydraulic fluid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> It is not possible with this conventional solution to control the end position of the trough corresponding to the minimum value of the volume of the gas space by means of a valve on the oil side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> On the basis of this state of the art the object of the invention is to develop an accumulator of the generic type in question which is characterized by improved operating characteristics, in particular also in minimum volume areas of the gas space of the accumulator. </paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The goal as formulated in these terms is reached by means of a hydropneumatic accumulator having the features specified in claim 1 in its entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In that, as specified in the descriptive portion of claim 1 a valve lifter fastened to the bottom of the trough is provided which extends from the accumulator housing concentrically with the longitudinal axis and is connected to a second movable valve element which, on movement of the trough exceeding an assigned minimum gas space volume, acts in conjunction with a second valve seat blocking flow of hydraulic fluid into the oil space, the advantageous option is created also of controlling the end position of the trough, which also corresponds to the minimum volume of the gas space, by means of a valve on the oil side. If, in the event of movement of the trough caused by overpressure on the oil side, inflow of hydraulic fluid into the oil space is blocked by movement of the trough by the valve lifter connected to the trough, pressure equilibrium is established on the bellows. When, during operation of the accumulator claimed for the invention, once pressure equilibrium has been established between gas prefill pressure in the gas space and hydraulic pressure in the oil space and the trough forming the element closing the bellows is located between its assigned end positions, in which both valve elements have been lifted from their associated valve seats, and accordingly flow of fluid has not been blocked, the state of pressure equilibrium at the bellows is continued, irrespective of whether the hydraulic pressure of the oil side may drop in relation to the gas prefill pressure (something which results in closing of the valve) or irrespective of how high the hydraulic pressure may rise relative to the gas prefill pressure (something which in turn results in blocking of the valve, so that additional inflow into the oil space is no longer possible). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The structure employed, in which the bellows encloses the exterior of a trough open on the gas side, is advantageous in several respects. Since the whole interior of the trough is available as part of the gas space, an optimal relationship of total size of the accumulator housing to volume of the gas space is achieved. While in the case of the conventional pressure accumulator an adequate gas space volume can be realized only by allowing an adequate path of travel for the end plate of the metal bellows in the accumulator housing, something which results in the overloading problems referred to, in the case of the invention the path of travel corresponding to extension of the bellows may be virtually as small as desired. In other words, the accumulator housing may be designed so that beyond a short path of movement of the trough it forms a mechanical stop, since the whole interior of the trough is available as gas space volume. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In this way not only is the bellows protected from extending too far, since it surrounds the exterior of the trough, under the overpressure prevailing in the gas space the bellows is also supported mechanically over its entire length by the exterior of the trough. This in turn permits build-up of the gas prefill pressure before commencement of operation of the accumulator, that is, before the hydraulic system is connected on the oil side. If the latter is the case and once the operating pressure has been built up in the oil space, pressure equilibrium is maintained on the bellows by the valve controlling flow of hydraulic fluid from the oil space. In that the trough is surrounded externally by the bellows, a very slight &ldquo;dead volume&rdquo; results between trough and bellows, so that only a small amount of hydraulic fluid need be introduced before the gas space is charged, this in turn resulting in saving of weight and costs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Since the bottom of the trough is simultaneously in the form of a movable valve element, an especially compact and simple structure is also obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The trough is preferably in the form of a regular cylinder, and the depth assigned to the trough is such that its bottom serving as valve element acts as a movable round valve disk which operates in conjunction with a valve seat formed on the interior wall of the accumulator housing. Not only does this result in a particularly simple valve structure, but, since the entire surface of the bottom of the trough is available as valve disk, an especially large sealing surface can be obtained when the valve is closed. For example, for this purpose an O-ring may be provided for formation of an annular sealing surface in the radial external marginal area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The valve lifter also performs a control function during the lifting movement of the bellows, so that proper seating of the trough bottom serving as valve element on valve seat and accordingly blocking of the valve are ensured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Since the bellows operates in the state of equilibrium, a light bellows structure may be employed; this results both in weight reduction and in especially good response behavior. </paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A hydropneumatic accumulator with a bellows (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), a metal bellows in particular, separating a gas space (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) from an oil space (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) inside the accumulator housing (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), which bellows (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>) is fastened at one of its ends to the accumulator housing (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) in such a way that the oil space (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) adjoins the inside of the bellows (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), which at its other, free, end is closed by a movable closing element (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) as a function of changes in volume in gas space (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) and oil space (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>), and with a valve (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) releasing or blocking flow of hydraulic fluid from and into the oil space (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) which corresponds to increase in the volume of the gas space (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) exceeding an assigned maximum value and may be transferred to its blocking position by the closing element (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>), the closing element being in the form of a trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>), the trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) being connected to the associated free end of the bellows (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>) by its edge (<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>) situated on the open end (<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>), the side wall (<highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>) of the trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) extending along the inside of the bellows (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), and the bottom (<highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>) of the trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) being in the form of a movable valve element of the valve (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) controlling the flow of hydraulic fluid, characterized in that a valve lifter (<highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>) fastened to the trough bottom (<highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>) is provided which extends from the accumulator housing (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) concentrically with the longitudinal axis (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) and which is connected to a second movable valve element (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>) that operates in conjunction with a second valve seat (<highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>) blocking flow of hydraulic fluid into the oil space (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) on movement of the trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) exceeding an assigned minimum value of the volume of the gas space (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The hydropneumatic accumulator as specified in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the trough (<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) is cylindrical in form and its depth has been determined in such a way that its bottom (<highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>), as a circular movable valve disk, operates in conjunction with a valve seat which is formed on the inner wall (<highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>) of the accumulator housing (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The hydropneumatic accumulator as specified in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the valve seat is mounted concentrically with the central longitudinal axis (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) of the accumulator housing (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) mounted as a rotary element and encloses a passage (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) for hydraulic fluid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The hydropneumatic accumulator as specified in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein sealing surfaces (<highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>) which extend concentrically with the longitudinal axis (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) are provided on the valve disk and valve seat in the area of their external edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The hydropneumatic accumulator as specified in one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein sealing surfaces are formed on the movable valve elements and/or associated valve seats by O-rings (<highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>) seated in annular grooves.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000589A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000589A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
