<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003822A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003822A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003822</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10169789</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-330301</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001030</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B63H021/21</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B63H021/22</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B60K041/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>440</class>
<subclass>084000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Sailing control device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hirotaka</given-name>
<family-name>Kaji</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Shizuoka</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KNOBBE MARTENS OLSON &amp; BEAR LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2040 MAIN STREET</address-1>
<address-2>FOURTEENTH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>IRVINE</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>92614</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/JP01/09194</doc-number>
<document-date>20011019</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">To provide a running control device for a watercraft capable of effecting an easy cruising control of the watercraft even by a beginner, especially allowing a stable running while turning, and capable of reducing cavitation. A running control device <highlight><bold>16 </bold></highlight>for a watercraft with a propulsion device <highlight><bold>15 </bold></highlight>capable of controlling propulsion, comprises a propulsion control section <highlight><bold>17 </bold></highlight>which controls propulsion, based on predetermined input information, said propulsion control section <highlight><bold>17 </bold></highlight>comprising a target propulsion calculation module <highlight><bold>18 </bold></highlight>for determining a target propulsion, based on predetermined input information including at least velocity of said watercraft; and an operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>19 </bold></highlight>for determining the amount of operation of said propulsion device <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, based on predetermined input information so as to obtain the target propulsion determined by said propulsion calculation module <highlight><bold>18. </bold></highlight></paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED CASES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a national phase filing under 35 U.S.C. &sect; 371 of PCT Application No. PCT/JP01/09194, filed Oct. 19, 2001, which claims priority to Japanese Application No. 2000-330301, filed Oct. 30, 2000, the entire contents of which are hereby expressly incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a running control device for a watercraft with a device for electrically controlling the amount of intake air to an engine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In conventional watercrafts, a throttle lever manipulable by a user and a throttle valve provided in an intake passage of a propulsion device constituted by an engine, are mechanically connected to each other with a cable or other mechanical elements. A throttle valve opening is determined uniquely by throttle lever operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, it is possible, as proposed in JP-A-2000-108995, that a throttle controller generates an electrical signal to drive an actuator mounted on a throttle valve so that the relation between throttle lever position and throttle valve opening is set to be non-linear, yet the throttle valve opening is determined uniquely by the throttle lever position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Control of a watercraft is difficult for a beginner, and it takes a veteran driver to operate the watercraft skillfully. For example, when cruising, during which a watercraft runs at a constant speed, specifically in water-skiing, trolling, or the like, the user (driver) should take notice of engine speed and watercraft velocity at all times and fine-tune the throttle opening continuously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> However, the circumstances surrounding a watercraft are not always constant, and the characteristics of ship control change widely depending on various disturbances. For example, the area of submerged portions of the hull changes with changes in weather or sea conditions, the number of crew, the amount of gear, steering operation or trimming operation, or the like, and running resistance changes accordingly, which causes engine speed or watercraft velocity to change every moment even if throttle opening is constant. Controlling a watercraft during cruising in such circumstances while fine-tuning the throttle opening can be burdensome and thus the driver can be distracted especially if he is a beginner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In addition, if velocity and throttle opening are ill-balanced during ship control, a phenomenon called cavitation, where the propeller races due to formation of air bubbles, may occur, which raises engine speed abruptly, resulting in damage to the engine, propeller, or other driving systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> An engine speed control system or a velocity control system can be used for a conventional control device for watercraft cruising. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> One benefit of an engine speed control system is that cavitation is quickly suppressed as soon as it happens. However, when the resistance between the hull and the water changes, a driver should change the target engine speed in order to maintain a constant watercraft speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A benefit of a watercraft velocity control system is that a watercraft can run at a target speed regardless of the change of the resistance to a hull. However, when cavitation occurs, the thrust is reduced which causes the watercraft to slow. The velocity control system then further opens the throttle to compensate for the reduced watercraft velocity, whereby more cavitation is caused. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> While a watercraft is running with an engine speed cruising control system, and if an operation, like turning is performed, which changes the posture of the hull rapidly, the resistance to the hull is increased whereby velocity relative to water is decreased. If a watercraft velocity control system is employed, and the velocity is decreased considerably, a throttle is opened to compensate for the change in watercraft velocity and the probability of the generating cavitation will be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, it is an object of the invention to provide a running control device for a watercraft capable of effecting an easy cruising control of the watercraft even by a beginner, especially, allowing stable running while turning, and preventing cavitation. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve the foregoing object, the invention provides a running control device for a watercraft with a propulsion device capable of controlling propulsion, comprising: a propulsion control section for controlling propulsion, based on predetermined input information, said propulsion control section comprising a target propulsion calculation module for determining a target propulsion based on said predetermined input information, including at least velocity of said watercraft; and an operation amount calculation module for determining the amount of operation of said propulsion device, based on said predetermined input information so as to obtain the target propulsion determined by said target propulsion calculation module. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, a target propulsion is automatically calculated, based on predetermined input information, including velocity, and the amount of operation of the propulsion device is calculated, based on the predetermined input information, so that the calculated target propulsion is obtained. This provides optimum propulsion in response to driving conditions at all times. In this case, since the velocity is included as a parameter for calculation of the target propulsion, it is detected when the velocity is decreased by cavitation, for example, so as to suppress the cavitation by decreasing the amount of propulsion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Also, with this arrangement, if a target velocity for constant speed cruising, for example, is inputted to the engine output control section, this control section calculates a target engine speed corresponding to the target velocity, automatically operates the intake air control device through electrical control according to the target engine speed, and automatically controls engine output so as to maintain the target velocity. The target engine speed may be directly inputted in place of the target velocity. In this case, as in the previous one, the engine output control section automatically operates the intake air control device through electrical control according to the target engine speed, to automatically control engine output. Therefore, the driver need not take notice of the engine speed being maintained through throttling operation, allowing him to concentrate on steering operation, providing easier control of the watercraft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In addition, if cavitation (racing of the propeller) happens, the amount of operation of the intake air control device is calculated to decreased engine speed, so that an immediate action is taken automatically against cavitation, and damage to the engine, propeller, or other driving systems can also be avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> An engine, a motor, or a water jet drive are examples of the above propulsion device. In the case of an engine, the amount of intake air, the amount of fuel injection, and an ignition timing or the like are controlled so that the actual engine speed follows the target engine speed in order to obtain the target propulsion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In the case of an electric motor, the voltage (the current) is controlled so that the actual motor speed follows the target motor speed in order to obtain the target propulsion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In the case of a water jet drive, the amount of intake air, the amount of fuel injection, and an ignition timing or the like are controlled so that the actual engine speed follows the target engine speed in order to obtain the target propulsion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A preferred example of such an arrangement is characterized in that said propulsion device is an engine; and that said running control device comprises an engine output control section for controlling the engine output, based on predetermined input information, using at least one of an intake air control device, an electronically controlled fuel injection device, or an ignition control device, said engine output control section comprising a target engine speed calculation module for determining a target engine speed, based on predetermined input information including at least information on velocity of said watercraft; and an operation amount calculation module for determining the amount of operation of said engine output control section, based on predetermined input information, so as to obtain the target engine speed determined by said target engine speed module. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, an engine is used as a propulsion device. Engine output is controlled by using an intake air control device such as a throttle valve, an electronically controlled fuel injection device such as a magnetic, e.g. solenoid-driven, fuel injection valve (an injector), or an ignition control device constituted by an ignition coil or the like. A target engine speed is calculated, based on predetermined input information including information on velocity, and an amount of operation of output control is calculated, based on predetermined input information so as to obtain the target engine speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A preferred example of such an arrangement is characterized in that said target engine speed calculation module determines the target engine speed derived from at least velocity among information on velocity, acceleration, engine speed, trim angle, pitch angle, and user&apos;s input by hand, and at least one of steering angle and rolling angle as input information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, a turning condition is judged by detecting a steering angle or a rolling angle corresponding to a handle operation in addition to information on velocity which allows a stable running control while turning and prevents cavitation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In addition, by selectively using several kinds of information on a watercraft including information such as the calculated or inputted target engine speed and the current engine speed, the amount of operation of a throttle valve can be calculated properly such that engine speed follows the target engine speed, for example, based on the difference between the target engine speed and the current engine speed. In this case, control may be made using other information as a means of adjusting the gain of engine speed control, such as a riding feeling-oriented control in which the gain is decreased when steering angle is small, or a following-up characteristic-oriented control in which the gain is increased when the steering angle is large. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Still another arrangement is characterized in that said target engine speed calculation module calculates the target engine speed based on a fuzzy rule, or &ldquo;fuzzy logic.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, the setting of the fuzzy rule is based on the amount of driving operation of an experienced driver and the operation according to the fuzzy rule facilitates a stable and proper operation by a beginner as if by an experienced driver. Especially, the best amount of operation can be easily set by using the fuzzy rule when the running condition and the best amount of operation corresponding to it is non-linear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> That is, skill or knowledge of an experienced driver is incorporated in the fuzzy rule to facilitate proper control of a watercraft by a beginner. In this case, a neural network or a Cerebellar Model Arithmetic Computer (CMAC) may be utilized. Also, a learning system may be formed which learns a control method of a skilled driver to update rules, maps, or control routines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Still another arrangement is characterized in that said target engine speed calculation module decreases the correction of the target engine speed as a steering angle increases from the a straight-ahead position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, as the steering angle is increased, that is, in the state of a small turn, the correction of the target engine speed is decreased so as to always facilitate a stable running while turning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Still another arrangement is characterized in that said target engine speed calculation module decreases the correction of the target engine speed as a rolling angle increases from a striaght ahead position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, as the rolling angle is increased, that is, in the state of a small turn, the correction of the engine speed is decreased so as to always facilitate a stable running while turning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Still another arrangement is characterized in that said operation amount calculation module determines the amount of operation of said engine output control section from at least a target engine speed and engine speed, among target engine speed, engine speed, velocity, acceleration, trim angle, and pitch angle, and at least one of the steering angle and rolling angle as an input. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, the amount of operation can be controlled in response to the difference between the target engine speed and the actual engine speed and information on the steering angle or the rolling angle are added to judge the turning condition so as to control to facilitate a stable running while turning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Still another example of the arrangement is characterized in that said operation amount calculation module calculates the amount of operation of said engine output control device based on a fuzzy rule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, the setting of the fuzzy rule is based on the amount of operation of an experienced driver and the operation according to the fuzzy rule facilitates a stable and proper operation by a beginner like that by an experienced driver. Especially, the best amount of operation can be easily set by using a fuzzy rule when the running condition and the best amount of operation corresponding to it is nonlinear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Still another arrangement is characterized in that said operation amount calculation module increases the amount of operation as a steering angle is increased from the straight-ahead position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, as the steering angle is increased, that is, in the state of a small turn, the amount of operation is increased so as to compensate for a larger resistance at the time of a small turn in order to always facilitate a stable running while turning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Still another arrangement is characterized in that said operation amount calculation module increases the amount of operation as a rolling angle is increased from the horizontal position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, as the rolling angle is increased, that is, in the state of a small turn, the amount of operation is increased so as to compensate for a larger resistance at the time of a small turn in order to always facilitate a stable running while turning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Another arrangement is characterized in that said intake air control device is an electronic throttle valve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> According to this arrangement, a reliable intake air control can be achieved using an electronic throttle valve in association with an electronically controlled potentiometer, or the like.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a running control device for an outboard motor equipped with an electronic throttle valve; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a basic block diagram of a running control device of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram of the running control device of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram of the running control device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram of an electronic throttle valve control section of the running control device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is graph of correction rate based on steering angle; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flowchart, showing control operations of the electronic throttle valve control section of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a block diagram of an electronic throttle valve control section of another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> shows acceleration and velocity deviation membership functions; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> shows a fuzzy rule for calculation of the target engine speed based on the acceleration and velocity deviation membership functions shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference> shows an amount of connection of engine speed and engine speed deviation membership functions; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</cross-reference> shows a fuzzy rule for calculation of the electronic throttle valve opening based on the amount of connection of engine speed and engine speed deviation membership functions shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a running control device of another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a block diagram of the running control device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a flowchart, showing control operations of the electronically controlled valve control section of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Now, an embodiment of the invention will be described below with reference to the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a running control device according to the invention incorporated in an outboard motor with an electronic throttle valve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> An outboard motor <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is mounted on a transom of a hull <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of a watercraft through a trim driving device (cylinder) <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. In an intake pipe (not shown) of an engine <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the outboard motor <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is provided an electronic throttle valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, which is connected to a running control device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. To the running control device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is inputted information on engine speed detected from the engine, and information on velocity, acceleration, steering angle, and target velocity inputted through a user by hand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In such an arrangement, the running control device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> calculates, as described below, an amount of operation of the electronic throttle valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> such that engine speed is obtained for a target watercraft velocity, based on the input information, and drives the electronic throttle valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> according to this amount of operation to automatically control engine output for running at a fixed target velocity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a basic block diagram of a running control device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> relating to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The running control device <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for a watercraft which is equipped with a propulsion device <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> capable of controlling propulsion, comprises a propulsion control section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> which controls propulsion, based on predetermined input information. The propulsion control section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> comprises a target propulsion calculation module <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for determining a target propulsion, based on predetermined input information including at least velocity of said watercraft, and an operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> for determining the amount of operation of said propulsion device <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, based on predetermined input information, such that the target propulsion determined by said propulsion calculation module <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Data in the input information are detected data of a working condition of the propulsion device <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> such as watercraft velocity or engine speed, external environment data such as atmospheric temperature or atmospheric pressure, and the data on user&apos;s amount of operation such as the amount of operation of a throttle. These data are inputted through an interface <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at the input side to the propulsion control section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The data on the amount of operation calculated in the propulsion control section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is outputted through an interface <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> at the output side to the propulsion device <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a running control device constructed in accordance with at least one aspect of the invention. This embodiment is one in which the invention is applied to a small watercraft with an outboard engine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> This running control device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is comprised of an engine output control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> provided on a hull, and adapted to drive, for control, a device provided on the outboard engine for electrically controlling the amount of intake air (intake air control device <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>: for example, an electronic throttle valve) and other engine output related devices such as a fuel injection device <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and ignition device <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. To the running control device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are inputted a signal a of the information on the external environments, a signal b of the information on the amount of user operation, and a signal c of the information on the conditions of the outboard engine through an interface <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> (input section). The information on the external environments is detected information on atmospheric temperature and atmospheric pressure. The information on the amount of user operation includes amount of throttling operation, amount of steering operation, and input on the target watercraft velocity. The conditions of the outboard engine include watercraft velocity, acceleration, engine speed, temperature of the cooling water, throttle valve opening, trim angle and posture of the watercraft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The engine output control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises a target engine speed calculation module <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> for determining target engine speed, based on predetermined input information, and an engine output operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for determining the amount of operation of the intake air control device <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> such that engine speed follows the target engine speed determined by the target engine speed calculation module. The engine output operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further calculates the amount of fuel injection of the fuel injection device <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and ignition timing of the ignition device <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and determines the amount of its driving operation to maintain the target engine speed. At this time, trim angle to be driven by the trim driving device (not shown) can also be calculated so as to determine the amount of its driving operation. Other driving devices (not shown) for controlling devices such as the intake air control device <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the fuel injection device <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the outboard motor <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are driven, for control, through an interface <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (at the output section), based on the amount of operation of the intake air control device <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, or the like, determined by the engine output operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, so as to obtain the target engine speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Thus, the target engine speed calculation module, for example, is arranged such that it calculates a target engine speed for a constant speed running, while the engine output operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> calculates an amount of operation of the intake air control device <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> such that actual engine speed follows the target engine speed, and the intake air control device <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is driven by this amount of operation. Therefore, automatic running at a constant speed can be achieved without need of a user manipulating an operating lever (throttle) of the intake air control device <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In addition, if engine speed rises sharply beyond the target engine speed when cavitation happens, the engine output operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> drives the intake air control device <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to decrease an amount of intake air, so that cavitation can be suppressed promptly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram of the running control device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The running control device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is provided with an electronic throttle valve control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A (corresponding to the engine output control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). The electronic throttle control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A includes a target engine speed calculation module <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> for calculating target engine speed in response to the information on target watercraft velocity inputted by a user, and an electronic throttle valve opening calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A (corresponding to the engine output operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) for calculating opening of the electronic throttle valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> such that actual engine speed equivalent to the target engine speed is obtained, and drives the electronic throttle valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by the amount of operation of the calculated electronic throttle valve opening. Thus, intake air for the target engine speed is supplied, so that engine output for the running at the target watercraft velocity is achieved, providing automatic cruising control at a constant speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram of the electronic throttle valve control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The target engine speed calculation module <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is provided with a fuzzy reasoning system <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which calculates the amount of correction of the target engine speed according to a fuzzy rule based on a watercraft velocity deviation and acceleration. While the amount of correction of the target engine speed is calculated by the fuzzy reasoning system <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a correction rate calculation module <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> calculates a correction rate based on a steering angle, and the correction rate is multiplied by the above amount of correction of the target engine speed so as to obtain the data on the target engine speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> A deviation of the engine speed is calculated according to the difference between the data on the target engine speed. The data on the actual engine speed. The data on the deviation of the target engine speed and the data on the amount of correction of the engine speed are inputted to the fuzzy reasoning system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> which is equipped in the electronic throttle valve opening calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A. The fuzzy reasoning system <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> calculates the amount of correction of the electronic throttle valve opening based on the above input data. While the amount of correction of the electronic throttle valve opening is calculated, a correction rate calculation module <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> calculates a correction rate based on a steering angle, and the correction rate is multiplied by the above amount of correction of the electronic throttle valve opening so as to obtain the data on the electronic throttle valve opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a graph, showing the above correction rates. The horizontal axis shows the steering angle, &ldquo;0&rdquo; corresponds to the neutral position, and &ldquo;1&rdquo; corresponds to the maximum position of the steering angle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The solid line &ldquo;a&rdquo; indicates the correction rate used by the correction rate calculation module <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in the target engine speed calculation module <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. With this solid line &ldquo;a&rdquo;, correction rate is less than 1, and the larger the steering angle is, the smaller the correction rate is. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The dotted line &ldquo;b&rdquo; indicates the correction rate used by the correction rate calculation module <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> in the electronic throttle valve opening calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. With this dotted line &ldquo;b&rdquo;, correction rate is more than 1, and the larger the steering angle is, the larger the correction rate is. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flowchart of the running control operation according to the above running control device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> First, a target watercraft velocity is set by a user (step <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). This target watercraft velocity may be any value determined by the user, or may be selected from among a plurality of predetermined values provided by a manufacturer at shipment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Then, an initial value of a target engine speed is set (step <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). In this case, if the current watercraft velocity is in the vicinity of the target watercraft velocity, the current target engine speed is set as the initial value of the target engine speed. If the current velocity is not in the vicinity of the target watercraft velocity, a predetermined initial value of the target engine speed is used. The initial value of the target engine speed may be any value determined by a user, or may be selected from among a plurality of predetermined values provided by a manufacturer at shipment. With these initial values as references, feedback control is performed, based on the difference between the initial value and the measured current engine speed, such that engine speed follows the target engine speed, as described later. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Then, a correction rate for a target engine speed is calculated, based on the steering angle, according to the solid line &ldquo;a&rdquo; of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> as mentioned above (step <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). Then, a correction rate for an electronic throttle valve opening is calculated according to the dotted line &ldquo;b&rdquo; (step <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Then, a target engine speed (step <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) and an opening of an electronic throttle valve is calculated (step <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) using these correction rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Then, an electronic throttle valve is driven, for control, based on the calculated data on the opening of an electronic throttle valve (step <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>). In the next step <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, it is determined if the user has terminated the running control. If the running control has not been terminated, then steps <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are repeated. If the running control is terminated, the driving mode returns to the normal driving mode (step <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a block diagram of another embodiment of a running control device according to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> This embodiment is one in which the data on the steering angle is inputted to fuzzy reasoning systems <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> respectively instead of correction rate calculation modules <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> in the example of above mentioned <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> so as to calculate a target engine speed and an opening of the electronic throttle valve. Other structures and working effects of this embodiment are the same as those of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an illustration of a fuzzy rule for calculation of the target engine speed mentioned above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> From membership functions shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> deduction values of velocity deviation and acceleration are determined, which are applied to the fuzzy rule of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> to determine a weighted mean, so as to calculate the amount of correction of the target engine speed (difference between the current engine speed and the target engine speed). Watercraft velocity deviation (difference between the actual watercraft velocity and the target watercraft velocity) of the membership functions is determined from a detected value of the actual watercraft velocity, and acceleration from the detected value by calculation. Four values corresponding to PL and PS on the positive side and NL and NS on the negative side are determined from the membership functions, based on the velocity deviation and the acceleration, and these four values are weighted by the corresponding four values in the fuzzy rule of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> to calculate a mean value. Thus, the amount of correction of the target engine speed is obtained. Each value of the fuzzy rule is set, for example, based on skilled driver&apos;s experience or knowledge. Therefore, for a velocity detected, an optimum amount of correction of the target engine speed corresponding to the velocity and providing an amount of operation equivalent to the operation by the skilled driver can be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an illustration of a fuzzy rule through which the amount of operation of throttle opening is determined, based on the amount of correction of the target engine speed obtained in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> As in the case of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, an engine speed deviation (difference between the target engine speed and the actual engine speed) is obtained from the detected value of the engine speed. An amount of correction of the engine speed is obtained from the detected value of the engine speed by calculation. From these values of membership functions, processing weighted by the fuzzy rule of (B) is performed to obtain the amount of correction of the throttle valve opening. This amount of correction forms an amount of operation for changing the current throttle valve opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> As described above, control of the electronic throttle valve allows control of the amount of intake air, and thus engine speed is controlled so as to follow the target engine speed, thereby effecting a velocity control such that the watercraft velocity follows the target watercraft velocity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> In small ships with outboard motors, or small ships or small planing watercraft having engines mounted thereon, environmental conditions change drastically due to change in weather or climate, and the resistance to the hull changes widely depending on the number of crew, loadings, and steering angle or trim setting, so that the relation between watercraft velocity and engine speed varies from moment to moment. Therefore, it is difficult for a driver, and particularly beginners, to maintain a constant speed through throttle manipulation, that is, the driver needs to use a difficult ship control technique which necessitates a lot of skill. In order to cope with this problem, in the embodiment as described above, the electronic throttle valve control section of the running control device is constituted by a target engine speed calculation module and an electronic throttle valve opening calculation module. Therefore, the driver is able to run the watercraft at a constant speed without excessive throttle manipulation, and to control the watercraft while concentrating on steering without being distracted by the need for throttle manipulation. Thus, a remarkable effect can be achieved of lightening the burden on the user to control the watercraft, effecting stable running as well as improved stability during ship control, and further of preventing cavitation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a structural diagram of another embodiment of a running control device according to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> This embodiment is one in which a trim driving device is shown in a block in the outboard motor of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> mentioned above (In fact, a trim driving device is equipped in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). A trim angle can be detected from the trim driving device <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The other structures and working effects of this embodiment are the same as those of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a block diagram of the running control device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> The running control device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is provided with the electronic throttle valve control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A (corresponding to the engine output control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>). The electronic throttle control section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A includes the target engine speed calculation module <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> for calculating target engine speed in response to the information on target velocity inputted by a user, and the electronic throttle valve opening calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A (corresponding to the engine output operation amount calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>) for calculating opening of the electronic throttle valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> such that actual engine speed equivalent to the target engine speed is obtained, and drives the electronic throttle valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by the amount of operation of the calculated electronic throttle valve opening. Thus, intake air for the target engine speed is supplied, so that engine output for the running at the target velocity is achieved, providing automatic cruising control at a constant speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a flowchart of the running control operation according to the running control device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> First, a target watercraft velocity is set by a user (step S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). This target velocity may be any value determined by the user, or may be selected from among a plurality of values provided by a manufacturer at shipment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Then, an initial value of a target engine speed is set (step S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). In this case, if the current watercraft velocity is in the vicinity of the target watercraft velocity, the current target engine speed is set as the initial value of the target engine speed. If the current watercraft velocity is not in the vicinity of the target velocity, a predetermined initial value of the target engine speed is used. The initial value of the target engine speed may be any value determined by a user, or may be selected from among a plurality of values provided by a manufacturer at shipment. With these initial values as references, feedback control is performed, based on the difference between the initial value and the measured current engine speed, such that engine speed follows the target engine speed, as described later. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Next, the target engine speed is calculated by the target engine speed calculation module <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference>) (step S<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). The target engine speed calculation module is constituted by a fuzzy reasoning system, adopting, for example, a simplified reasoning method as the reasoning method, deduces the amount of correction of the target engine speed from difference between the target velocity and the current velocity, and acceleration, as input, and outputs the sum of the current target engine speed and the amount of correction of the target engine speed, as a new target engine speed. A fuzzy rule table of this fuzzy reasoning system is designed, based on skilled driver&apos;s knowledge on ship control, and the fuzzy rule in the simplified reasoning method is represented by real values (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> mentioned above). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Next, an electronic throttle valve opening is calculated, based on this target engine speed (step S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). This electronic throttle valve opening calculation module <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>), like the target engine speed calculation module, is constituted by a fuzzy reasoning system, adopting a simplified reasoning method as the reasoning method, deduces the amount of electronic throttle valve opening from a difference between the target engine speed and the current engine speed, and the amount of correction of engine speed per unit time, as input, and outputs the sum of the current electronic throttle opening and the amount of correction of electronic throttle valve opening, as a new electronic throttle valve opening (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> mentioned above). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> The electronic throttle valve is driven, for control, such that its opening coincides with the electronic throttle valve opening calculated in this way (step S<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). In this case, in addition to the control of the electronic throttle valve, the fuel ignition device <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, ignition device <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and trim driving device <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> may also be driven, for control, by calculating the respective amounts of operation, based on the target engine speed corresponding to the target velocity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> It is then determined if the user has disabled the running control (step <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>). If the user has not disabled the running control then steps <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> If the user disables the running control (step S<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>), the electronic throttle valve opening changes gradually to an opening specified by the throttle (throttle lever), and thereafter, normal ship control by the throttle lever is restored (step S<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>). In this case, since the throttle lever is set at a fixed position without manipulation during running control, the throttle valve is moved to an opening corresponding to the position of the throttle lever at the time of disablement of running control. Therefore, if there is a large difference between the throttle valve opening and the opening indicated by the throttle lever at the time of removal of the control, an abrupt output change is effected, preventing stable running. Thus, throttle opening at the time of disablement of running control is detected to calculate the difference between the actual throttle valve opening and the throttle opening, and the throttle valve is driven, for control, such that it is moved slowly to an opening indicated by the throttle lever. The throttle lever opening may be detected from time to time during running control to be stored as information on throttle opening, and upon transition to normal running control, this throttle opening information may be read out, together with other stored information, to perform opening control of the throttle valve as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, as described above, information on watercraft velocity and acceleration are inputted, the target engine speed is determined, based on these pieces of input information, and the amount of correction of the electronic throttle valve opening is determined such that engine speed follows the target engine speed. The invention is not limited to this embodiment, but the target engine speed calculation module, for example, may be arranged such that input by a user is outputted as the target engine speed without alteration. Specifically, if the target engine speed calculation module is arranged such that the target engine speed can be determined uniquely from throttle opening, this makes it possible to maintain any engine speed desired by a user, and cavitation can also be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> Also, the engine output operation amount calculation module may be arranged such that its gain is adjusted in response to steering angle. Specifically, in the case where an electronic throttle valve opening calculation module constituted by proportional-differential controls is used, if steering angle is small (in the state of straight-ahead running), a riding feeling-oriented control of small engine speed variation can be performed by adjusting differential gain, and if steering angle is large (in the state of turning), a following-up characteristic-oriented control of small target engine speed deviation is performed by adjusting proportional gain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> In the case where the target engine speed is inputted directly, engine speed is controlled as in the previous case of the target velocity being inputted, so that cavitation can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> Although the foregoing embodiment has been exemplified by a watercraft with an outboard motor incorporating an electronic throttle valve control device, the invention is not limited to this outboard motor, but may be applied, for example, to an inboard or an inboard-outboard motor of a watercraft with an electronic throttle valve, or a water vehicle such as a water bike or other small planing-type watercraft with an electronic throttle valve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> If the running control device described above is applied to cruising control devices for watercrafts, they can be categorized into the following three systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> (1) Cruising control similar to that of an automobile: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> 1. Summary: after the watercraft is accelerated to a velocity desired by the driver, cruising control is performed with the velocity at which the switch is activated, as a target velocity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> 2. Component: electronic throttle valve, fuel injection device, ignition device, switch, and the like </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> 3. Details of control: a target engine speed is calculated from input velocity and acceleration, and the electronic throttle valve, fuel injection valve and ignition timing are controlled such that engine speed follows the target engine speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> 4. Input information to the target engine speed calculation module: as main information, information on velocity and acceleration, and as sub-information, information on amount of steering operation, trim angle, posture, atmospheric temperature, atmospheric pressure, cooling water temperature, and the like </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> 5. Effect: the driver is able to maintain the target velocity without touching a throttle lever. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> (2) Cruising control unique to watercrafts (Part 1): </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> 1. Summary: when the cruising control switch is pressed in any condition (for example, during stoppage), cruise control is performed with the watercraft velocity set by the driver through target velocity input means, as a target watercraft velocity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> 2. Component: electronic throttle valve, fuel injection device, ignition device, target velocity input means (lever, terminal), switch, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> 3. Details of control: a target engine speed is calculated from input velocity and acceleration, and the electronic throttle valve, fuel injection valve and ignition timing are controlled such that engine speed follows the target engine speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> 4. Input information to the target engine speed calculation module: as main information, information on velocity and acceleration, and as sub-information, information on amount of steering operation, trim angle, posture, atmospheric temperature, atmospheric pressure, cooling water temperature, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> 5. Effect: the driver is able to accelerate the watercraft from the state of stoppage to the target velocity and to maintain the velocity without touching a throttle lever. Cavitation can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> (3) Cruising control unique to watercrafts (Part 2): </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> 1. Summary: The driver inputs a target engine speed corresponding to a constant running speed directly, instead of a target velocity. The target engine speed can be changed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> 2. Component: electronic throttle valve, fuel injection device, ignition device, target engine speed input means (lever, dial), switch, and the like </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> 3. Details of control: a target engine speed is calculated from the amount of operation of the target engine speed input means, and the electronic throttle valve, fuel injection valve and ignition timing are controlled such that engine speed follows the target engine speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> 4. Input information to the target engine speed calculation module: as main information, information on amount of lever operation, and as sub-information, information on velocity, acceleration, amount of steering operation, trim angle, posture, atmospheric temperature, atmospheric pressure, cooling water temperature, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> 5. Effect: as a result that an engine speed specified by the driver is maintained, running at any constant speed can be effected while cavitation is prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Effect of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> In the invention as described above, if a target watercraft velocity for a constant running speed, or an engine speed corresponding to this target velocity, for example, is inputted to the engine output control section (electronic throttle valve control section), this control section automatically operates the intake air control device (electronic throttle valve) through electrical control according to this target, and automatically controls engine output so as to maintain the target velocity. Therefore, the driver need not take notice of the engine speed being maintained through throttling operation, allowing him to concentrate on steering, providing easier control of the watercraft. Especially, stability in running while turning is improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> In addition, if cavitation (racing of the propeller) occurs, the amount of operation of the intake air control device is calculated to decrease engine speed, so that an immediate action is taken automatically against cavitation, and any damages to the engine, propeller, or other driving system can be avoided. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Explanation of Symbols </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>: running control device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>: engine output control section </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A: electronic throttle valve control section </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>: outboard motor </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>: intake air control device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>: interface </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>: fuel injection device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>: ignition device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>: trim driving device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>: target engine speed calculation module </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>: engine output operation amount calculation module </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A: electronic throttle valve opening calculation module </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>: interface </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>: electronic throttle valve </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>: full </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>: engine </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>: propulsion device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>: running control section </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>: propulsion control section </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>: target propulsion calculation module </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>: operation amount calculation module </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>: I/F </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>: I/F </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>: fuzzy reasoning system </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>: correction rate calculation module </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>: fuzzy reasoning system </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>: correction rate calculation module </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A running control device for a watercraft with a propulsion device having controllable propulsion, comprising: 
<claim-text>a propulsion control section for controlling propulsion, based on predetermined input information, said propulsion control section comprising 
<claim-text>a target propulsion calculation module for determining a target propulsion, based on predetermined input information including at least velocity of said watercraft; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation amount calculation module for determining the amount of operation of said propulsion device, based on predetermined input information, such that the target propulsion determined by said propulsion calculation module is obtained. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said propulsion device is an engine, and said running control device comprising 
<claim-text>an engine output control section for controlling engine output using at least one of an intake air control device for electrically controlling the amount of intake air to the engine, an electrically controlled fuel injection device, and an ignition control device, said engine output control section comprising, a target engine speed calculation module for determining a target engine speed, based on predetermined input information, including information at least on velocity of said watercraft; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an operation amount calculation module for determining the amount of operation of said engine output control section, based on predetermined input information, such that the target engine speed determined by said target engine speed calculation module is obtained. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said target engine speed calculation module determines the target engine speed from information at least on velocity of information on velocity, acceleration, engine speed, trim angle, pitch angle, and hand operated input by a user, and at least one of steering angle and rolling angle, as input information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, wherein said target engine speed calculation module determines the target engine speed based on a fuzzy rule. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, wherein said target engine speed calculation module decreases the amount of correction of the target engine speed as steering angle increases from the neutral position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, wherein said target engine speed calculation module decreases the amount of correction of the target engine speed as rolling angle increases from the neutral position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said operation amount calculation module determines the amount of operation of said engine output control section from information at least on target engine speed and engine speed of information on target engine speed, engine speed, velocity, acceleration, trim angle, pitch angle, and at least one of steering angle and rolling angle, as input information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, wherein said operation amount calculation module calculates the amount of operation of said engine output control section, based on a fuzzy rule. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, wherein said operation amount calculation module increases the amount of operation as steering angle increases from the neutral position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, wherein said operation amount calculation module increases the amount of operation as rolling angle increases from the neutral position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The running control device set forth in any of claims <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein said intake air control device is an electronic throttle valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030003822A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
