<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003488A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003488A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003488A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003488A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003488</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10149256</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020610</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>60169615</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19991208</filing-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>60239106</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001011</filing-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>C12Q001/68</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C07H021/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12N009/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12P021/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12N005/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>006000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>197000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>069100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>320100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>325000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>536</class>
<subclass>023200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Regulation of human mitochondrial deformylase</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shyam</given-name>
<family-name>Ramakrishnan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Brighton</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BANNER &amp; WITCOFF</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1001 G STREET N W</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1100</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/EP00/12110</doc-number>
<document-date>20001201</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Reagents which regulate human mitochondrial deformylase and reagents which bind to human mitochondrial deformylase gene products can be used to regulate cell proliferation, particularly in diseases such as cancer and other forms of neoplasia. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to the area of regulation of cell proliferation. More particularly, the invention relates to the regulation of human mitochondrial deformylase activity to increase or decrease cell proliferation. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Traditional methods of treating diseases characterized by aberrant cell proliferation, such as cancer, involve agents which inhibit rapid cell division. Rapidly dividing cells require functional mitochondria to support cell division and maintenance. Thus, agents which inhibit mitochondrial protein synthesis have been used to treat cancer. Such methods also affect non-cancer cells which divide rapidly, however, which can result in unpleasant and potentially serious side effects. Thus, there is a need in the art for methods of regulating cell proliferation for the treatment of cancer and other proliferation-related diseases which will avoid or minimize the side effects associated with traditional treatment methods. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The invention is based on the identification of a human mitochondrial deformylase. Based on in this identification the invention provides: 1) isolated mitochondrial deformylase protein or a biological active derivative thereof, 2) isolated nucleic acid molecules that encode the mitochondrial deformylase, 3) methods of isolating allelic variants of the mitochondrial deformylase protein and gene and 4) methods of identifying cells and tissues that express the mitochondrial deformylase gene/protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the invention to provide reagents and methods of regulating cell proliferation and treating disease characterized by aberrant cell proliferation. These and other objects of the invention are provided by one or more of the embodiments described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> One embodiment of the invention is a method of screening for agents which decrease proliferation of a cell. A test compound is contacted with a polypeptide. The polypeptide comprises an amino acid sequence selected from the group consisting of amino acid sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:2, the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:2, amino acid sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:4, the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:4, amino acid sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:6, and the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:6. Binding of the test compound to the polypeptide is detected. A test compound which binds to the target polypeptide is identified as a potential agent for decreasing proliferation of the cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the invention is a method of screening for agents which regulate proliferation of a cell. A test compound is contacted with a polypeptide comprising an amino acid sequence selected from the group consisting of SEQ ID NOS:2, 4 and 6. A deformylase activity of the polypeptide is detected. A test compound which decreases the deformylase activity of the polypeptide relative to deformylase activity in the absence of the test compound is identified as a potential agent for decreasing proliferation of a cell. A test compound which increases the deformylase activity of the polypeptide relative to deformylase activity in the absence of the test compound is identified as a potential agent for increasing proliferation of a cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the invention is a method of screening for agents which decrease proliferation of a cell. A test compound is contacted with a product of a polynucleotide comprising a nucleotide sequence selected from the group consisting of nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:1, the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:1, nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:3, the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:3, nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:5, and the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:5. Binding of the test compound to the product is detected. A test compound which binds to the product is identified as a potential agent for decreasing proliferation of the cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Even another embodiment of the invention is a method of reducing proliferation of a cell. A cell is contacted with a reagent which specifically binds to a product encoded by a polynucleotide. The polynucleotide comprises a nucleotide sequence selected from the group consisting of nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:1, the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:1, nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:3, the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:3, nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:5, and the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:5. Proliferation of the cell is thereby decreased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The invention thus provides reagents and methods for regulating cell proliferation, particularly proliferation of neoplastic cells.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. BLASTP alignment of the partial human human mitochondrial deformylase protein (SEQ ID NO:4) with the putative full-length human mitochondrial deformylase protein as predicted by the Genescan algorithm (SEQ ID:6). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Output of the Genescan algorithm: Analysis of human genomic sequence (AC026474) and prediction of the gene structure of the human mitochondrial deformylase gene</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> All technical terms used herein have the same meaning as is commonly used by those skilled in the art to which the present invention belongs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Nucleotide sequence&rdquo; as used herein refers to an oligonucleotide, nucleotide or polynucleotide sequence, and fragments or portions thereof, and to DNA or RNA of genomic or synthetic origin which may be double-stranded or single-stranded whether representing the sense or the antisense strand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;under stringent conditions&rdquo; as used herein includes, but is not limited to, the condition of 65&deg; C. for 10 to 2.0 hours in a solution containing 6&times;SSC, 1% sodium lauryl sulfate, 100 &mgr;g/ml salmon sperm DNA and 5&times;Denhardt&apos;s solution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Similarly, an amino acid sequence as used herein refers to peptide or protein sequences or portions thereof. &ldquo;Amino acid sequences wherein a substitution, deletion, addition, or transposition of one to several amino acid residue (s) is made&rdquo; refers to modifications of the amino acid sequence that do not abolish the biological activity of the protein or protein fragment. Substitutions of the amino acid sequence may be &ldquo;conservative&rdquo;, when substituted amino acids have similar structural or chemical properties, e.g., replacement of leucine with isoleucine, or, more rarely, &ldquo;non-conceservative&rdquo;, when the structural or chemical properties of the exchanged amino acids are different, e.g. replacement of glycine with tryptophan. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Functional equivalent&rdquo; in connection with nucleic acids are derivatives of these nucleic acids which have the same function, that is it codes for the same or a quite similar protein. &ldquo;Functional equivalent&rdquo; in connection with proteins are derivatives or fragments of that protein which still have the same or quite the same biological function. An enzyme for example reacts with the same substrate and a receptor binds the same ligand. A derivative of a protein is a protein which can have additions, deletions, transitions and/or substitutions of amino acids compared to the disclosed sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> It is a discovery of the present invention that regulators of human mitochondrial deformylase can be used to treat diseases characterized by aberrant cell proliferation, such as cancer. Mitochondrial deformylase cleaves the formyl group from nascent formyl-methionine peptides in the following reaction: N-formyl-Met-peptide&plus;H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O&reg; formate&plus;N-met-peptide (see Meinnel et al., <highlight><italic>Biochimie </italic></highlight>75, 1061-75, 1993, for a discussion of the related bacterial enzyme, peptide deformylase). Inhibition of mitochondrial deformylase according to the invention can affect protein production in rapidly dividing cells without significantly affecting protein production in normal cells. This decrease in mitochondrial protein production in rapidly dividing cancer cells leads to a decrease in proliferation of the cancer cells. Alternatively, according to the invention, cell proliferation can be increased by increasing mitochondrial deformylase activity. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Mitochondrial Deformylase Polypeptides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides according to the invention comprise an amino acid sequence as shown in SEQ ID NO:2, 4 or 6 or amino acid sequences wherein a substitution, deletion, addition or transposition of one to several amino acid residue(s) is made in SEQ ID NO:2, 4 or 6 or a biologically active variant of an amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:2, 4 or 6, as defined below. The undefined amino acids in SEQ ID NOS:2 and 4 represent the positions of stop codons introduced into SEQ ID NOS:1 and 3 (which encode SEQ ID NOS:2 and 4, respectively) by sequencing errors. A mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide of the invention can be a portion of a mitochondrial deformylase molecule, a full-length mitochondrial deformylase molecule, or a fusion protein comprising all or a portion of a mitochondrial deformylase molecule. Preferably, a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide comprises the HEXXH motif (SEQ ID NO:7), which is typical of the active site of zinc-dependent metallopeptidases, including mitochondrial deformylase. Most preferably, a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide has a deformylase activity. Deformylase activity is the removal of the formyl group from nascent formyl-methionine-peptides and is preferably measured as described in Adams, <highlight><italic>J. Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>33, 571-89, as modified by Meinnel &amp; Blanquet, <highlight><italic>J. Bacteriol. </italic></highlight>177, 1883-87 (1995), or WO 99/57097 (see also Examples 2 and 5, below). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Biologically Active Variants </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Mitochondrial deformylase variants which retain a mitochondrial deformylase activity, i.e., are biologically active, also are mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides. Preferably, naturally or non-naturally occurring mitochondrial deformylase variants have amino acid sequences which are at least about 50, preferably about 75, 90, 96, or 98% identical to amino acid sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:2, 4 or 6. Percent identity between a putative mitochondrial deformylase variant and the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:2, 4 or 6 can be determined, for example, using the Blast2 alignment program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Variations in percent identity can be due, for example, to amino acid substitutions, insertions, or deletions. Amino acid substitutions are defined as one for one amino acid replacements. They are conservative in nature when the substituted amino acid has similar structural and/or chemical properties. Examples of conservative replacements are substitution of a leucine with an isoleucine or valine, an aspartate with a glutamate, or a threonine with a serine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Amino acid insertions or deletions are changes to or within an amino acid sequence. They typically fall in the range of about 1 to 5 amino acids. Guidance in determining which amino acid residues can be substituted, inserted, or deleted without abolishing biological or immunological activity can be found using computer programs well known in the art, such as DNASTAR software. Whether an amino acid change results in a biologically active mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can readily be determined by assaying for mitochondrial deformylase activity, as described, for example, in Adams, <highlight><italic>J. Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>33, 571-89, as modified by Meinnel &amp; Blanquet, <highlight><italic>J. Bacteriol. </italic></highlight>177, 1883-87 (1995), or WO 99/57097 (see also Examples 2 and 5, below). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Fusion Proteins </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Fusion proteins can comprise at least 6, 10, 20, 50, 75, 100, 150, or 200 or more contiguous amino acids of SEQ ID NO:2 or at least 6, 10, 20, 50, 75, 100, or 150 or more contiguous amino acids of SEQ ID NO:4 or at least 6, 10, 20, 50, 75, 100, or 150 or more contiguous amino acids of SEQ ID NO:6. Fusion proteins are useful for generating antibodies against mitochondrial deformylase amino acid sequences and for use in various assay systems. For example, fusion proteins can be used to identify proteins which interact with portions of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, including its active site. Physical methods, such as protein affinity chromatography, or library-based assays for protein-protein interactions, such as the yeast two-hybrid or phage display systems, can also be used for this purpose. Such methods are well known in the art and can also be used as drug screens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> A mitochondrial deformylase fusion protein comprises two protein segments fused together by means of a peptide bond. The first protein segment comprises at least 6, 10, 20, 50, 75, 100, 150, or 200 or more contiguous amino acids of SEQ ID NO:2 or at least 6, 10, 20, 50, 75, 100, or 150 or more contiguous amino acids of SEQ ID NO:4 or at least 6, 10, 20, 50, 75, 100, or 150 or more contiguous amino acids of SEQ ID NO:6. Preferably, a fusion protein comprises the active site of a mitochondrial deformylase molecule. Contiguous mitochondrial deformylase amino acids for use in a fusion protein can be selected from the amino acid sequences shown in SEQ ID NO:2, 4 or 6 or from a biologically active variant of that sequence, such as those described above. The first protein segment can also comprise full-length mitochondrial deformylase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The second protein segment can be a full-length protein or a protein fragment or polypeptide. Proteins commonly used in fusion protein construction include &bgr;-galactosidase, &bgr;-glucuronidase, green fluorescent protein (GFP), autofluorescent proteins, including blue fluorescent protein (BFP), glutathione-S-transferase (GST), luciferase, horseradish peroxidase (HRP), and chloramphenicol acetyltransferase (CAT). Additionally, epitope tags are used in fusion protein constructions, including histidine (His) tags, FLAG tags, influenza hemagglutinin (HA) tags, Myc tags, VSV-G tags, and thioredoxin (Trx) tags. Other fusion constructions can include maltose binding protein (MBP), S-tag, Lex a DNA binding domain (DBD) fusions, GAL4 DNA binding domain fusions, and herpes simplex virus (HSV) BP16 protein fusions. A fusion protein can also be engineered to contain a cleavage site located between the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide-encoding sequence and the heterologous protein sequence, so that the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be cleaved and purified away from the heterologous moiety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A fusion protein can be synthesized chemically, as is known in the art. Preferably, a fusion protein is produced by covalently linking two protein segments or by standard procedures in the art of molecular biology. Recombinant DNA methods can be used to prepare fusion proteins, for example, by making a DNA construct which comprises coding sequences selected from SEQ ID NO:1, 3 or 5 (encoding SEQ ID NOS:2, 4 and 6, respectively) in proper reading frame with nucleotides encoding the second protein segment and expressing the DNA construct in a host cell, as is known in the art. Many kits for constructing fusion proteins are available from companies such as Promega Corporation (Madison, Wis.), Stratagene (La Jolla, Calif.), Clontech (Mountain View, Calif.), Santa Cruz Biotechnology (Santa Cruz, Calif.), MBL International Corporation (MIC; Watertown, Mass.), and Quantum Biotechnologies (Montreal, Canada; 1-888-DNA-KITS). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Identification of Species Homologs </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Species homologs of human mitochondrial deformylase can be obtained using mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides (described below) to make suitable probes or primers to screening cDNA expression libraries from other species, such as mice, monkeys, or yeast, identifying cDNAs which encode homologs of mitochondrial deformylase, and expressing the cDNAs as is known in the art. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Mitochondrial Deformylase Polynucleotides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide comprises a coding sequence for at least a portion of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. For example, nucleotide sequences of mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides which encode the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides shown in SEQ ID NOS:2, 4 and 6 are shown in SEQ ID NOS:1 (AL045195), 3 (AI859289) and 5, respectively. Further cDNA sequences that were identified as partial mitochondrial deformylase genes are accessible through the EMBL database with the accession numbers: AI859289, AI765656, AW452869, AA831012, AW131443, AI394056, AW305385, AI363505, AI990860, AI651000, AA648991, AA714004, AA516472, AI991677, AI823498, AA112466, AI684882, AW001656, AA928208, A1623289, AI636515, AA746387, R42230 und AA715557. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Degenerate nucleotide sequences encoding amino acid sequences of human mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides, as well as homologous nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50, preferably about 75, 90, 96, or 98% identical to the nucleotide sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5, are also mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides. Percent sequence identity between the sequences of two polynucleotides is determined using computer programs such as ALIGN which employ the FASTA algorithm, using an affine gap search with a gap open penalty of &minus;12 and a gap extension penalty of &minus;2. Complementary DNA (cDNA) molecules, species homologs, and variants of human mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides which encode biologically active mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides also are mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Identification of Variants and Homologs of Mitochondrial Deformylase Polynucleotides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Variants and homologs of polynucleotides comprising a nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5 also are mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides. Typically, homologous mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide sequences can be identified by hybridization of candidate polynucleotides to known mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides under stringent conditions, as is known in the art. For example, using the following wash conditions&mdash;2&times;SSC (0.3 M NaCl, 0.03 M sodium citrate, pH 7.0), 0.1% SDS, room temperature twice, 30 minutes each; then 2&times;SSC, 0.1% SDS, 50&deg; C. once, 30 minutes; then 2&times;SSC, room temperature twice, 10 minutes each&mdash;homologous sequences can be identified which contain at most about 25-30% basepair mismatches. More preferably, homologous nucleic acid strands contain 15-25% basepair mismatches, even more preferably 5-15% basepair mismatches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Species homologs of the mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides disclosed herein also can be identified by making suitable probes or primers and screening cDNA expression libraries from other species, such as mice, monkeys, or yeast. Human variants of mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides can be identified by screening human cDNA expression libraries. It is well known that the T<highlight><subscript>m </subscript></highlight>of a double-stranded DNA decreases by 1-1.5&deg; C. with every 1% decrease in homology (Bonner et al., <highlight><italic>J. Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>81, 123 (1973). Variants of human mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides or mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides of other species can therefore be identified, for example, by hybridizing a putative homologous mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide with a polynucleotide having the nucleotide sequence of SEQ ID NO:1, 3 or 5 to form a test hybrids, comparing the melting temperature of the test hybrid with the melting temperature of a hybrid comprising a polynucleotide having SEQ ID NO:1, 3 or 5 and a polynucleotide which is perfectly complementary to SEQ ID NO:1, 3 or 5, and calculating the number or percent of basepair mismatches within the test hybrid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Nucleotide sequences which hybridize to the nucleotide sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5 or their complements following stringent hybridization and/or wash conditions are also mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides. Stringent wash conditions are well known and understood in the art and are disclosed, for example, in Sambrook et al., MOLECULAR CLONING: A LABORATORY MANUAL, 2d ed., 1989, at pages 9.50-9.51. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Typically, for stringent hybridization conditions a combination of temperature and salt concentration should be chosen that is approximately 12-20&deg; C. below the calculated T<highlight><subscript>m </subscript></highlight>of the hybrid under study. The T<highlight><subscript>m </subscript></highlight>of a hybrid between the mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:1, 3 or 5 and a polynucleotide sequence which is at least about 50, preferably about 75, 90, 96, or 98% identical to SEQ ID NO:1, 3 or 5 can be calculated, for example, using the equation of Bolton and McCarthy, <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci U.S.A. </italic></highlight>48, 1390 (1962):</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>T</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>&equals;81.5&deg; C.&minus;16.6(log<highlight><subscript>10</subscript></highlight>&lsqb;Na<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>&rsqb;)&plus;0.41(%G&plus;C)&minus;0.63(%formamide)&minus;600/<highlight><italic>l</italic></highlight>),</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>where l&equals;the length of the hybrid in basepairs.</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Stringent wash conditions include, for example, 4&times;SSC at 65&deg; C., or 50% formamide, 4&times;SSC at 42&deg; C., or 0.5&times;SSC, 0.1% SDS at 65&deg; C. Highly stringent wash conditions include, for example, 0.2&times;SSC at 65&deg; C. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preparation of Mitochondrial Deformylase Polynucleotides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> A naturally occurring mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide can be isolated free of other cellular components such as membrane components, proteins, and lipids. Polynucleotides can be made by a cell and isolated using standard nucleic acid purification techniques, or synthesized using an amplification technique, such as PCR, or by using an automatic synthesizer. Methods for isolating polynucleotides are routine and are known in the art. Any such technique for obtaining a polynucleotide can be used to obtain isolated mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides. For example, restriction enzymes and probes can be used to isolate polynucleotide fragments which comprise nucleotide sequences encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. Isolated polynucleotides are in preparations which are free or at least 70, 80, or 90% free of other molecules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Mitochondrial deformylase cDNA molecules can be made with standard molecular biology techniques, using mitochondrial deformylase mRNA as a template. Mitochondrial deformylase cDNA molecules can thereafter be replicated using molecular biology techniques known in the art and disclosed in manuals such as Sambrook et al. (1989). An amplification technique, such as the polymerase chain reaction (PCR), can be used to obtain additional copies of subgenomic polynucleotides of the invention, using either human genomic DNA or cDNA as a template. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, synthetic chemistry techniques can be used to synthesize mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotides. The degeneracy of the genetic code allows alternate nucleotide sequences to be synthesized which will encode a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide having, for example, the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:2, 4 or 6 or a biologically active variant of those sequences. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Obtaining Full-Length Mitochondrial Deformylase Polynucleotides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The partial sequences of SEQ ID NOS:1 and 3 and the putative full-length sequence of SEQ ID NO:5 can be used to verify experimentally the corresponding fill length gene from which they are derived. The partial sequences can be nick-translated or end-labeled with <highlight><superscript>32</superscript></highlight>P using polynucleotide kinase using labeling methods known to those with skill in the art (BASIC METHODS IN MOLECULAR BIOLOGY, Davis et al., eds., Elsevier Press, N.Y., 1986). A lambda library prepared from human tissue can be directly screened with the labeled sequences of interest or the library can be converted en masse to pBluescript (Stratagene Cloning Systems, La Jolla, Calif. 92037) to facilitate bacterial colony screening (see Sambrook et al., MOLECULAR CLONING: A LABORATORY MANUAL, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press (1989, pg. 1.20). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Both methods are well known in the art. Briefly, filters with bacterial colonies containing the library in pBluescript or bacterial lawns containing lambda plaques are denatured, and the DNA is fixed to the filters. The filters are hybridized with the labeled probe using hybridization conditions described by Davis et al., 1986. The partial sequences, cloned into lambda or pBluescript, can be used as positive controls to assess background binding and to adjust the hybridization and washing stringencies necessary for accurate clone identification. The resulting auto-radiograms are compared to duplicate plates of colonies or plaques; each exposed spot corresponds to a positive colony or plaque. The colonies or plaques are selected, expanded and the DNA is isolated from the colonies for further analysis and sequencing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Positive cDNA clones are analyzed to determine the amount of additional sequence they contain using PCR with one primer from the partial sequence and the other primer from the vector. Clones with a larger vector-insert PCR product than the original partial sequence are analyzed by restriction digestion and DNA sequencing to determine whether they contain an insert of the same size or similar as the mRNA size determined from Northern blot Analysis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Once one or more overlapping cDNA clones are identified, the complete sequence of the clones can be determined, for example after exonuclease III digestion (McCombie et al., <highlight><italic>Methods </italic></highlight>3, 33-40, 1991). A series of deletion clones are generated, each of which is sequenced. The resulting overlapping sequences are assembled into a single contiguous sequence of high redundancy (usually three to five overlapping sequences at each nucleotide position), resulting in a highly accurate final sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Various PCR-based methods can be used to extend the nucleic acid sequences encoding the disclosed portions of human mitochondrial deformylase to detect upstream sequences such as promoters and regulatory elements. For example, restriction-site PCR uses universal primers to retrieve unknown sequence adjacent to a known locus (Sarkar, <highlight><italic>PCR Methods Applic. </italic></highlight>2, 318-322, 1993). In particular, genomic DNA is first amplified in the presence of primer to a linker sequence and a primer specific to the known region. The amplified sequences are then subjected to a second round of PCR with the same linker primer and another specific primer internal to the first one. Products of each round of PCR are transcribed with an appropriate RNA polymerase and sequenced using reverse transcriptase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Inverse PCR also can be used to amplify or extend sequences using divergent primers based on a known region (Triglia et al., <highlight><italic>Nucleic Acids Res. </italic></highlight>16, 8186, 1988). Primers can be designed using commercially available software, such as OLIGO 4.06 Primer Analysis software (National Biosciences Inc., Plymouth, Minn.), to be 22-30 nucleotides in length, to have a GC content of 50% or more, and to anneal to the target sequence at temperatures about 68&deg;-72&deg; C. The method uses several restriction enzymes to generate a suitable fragment in the known region of a gene. The fragment is then circularized by intramolecular ligation and used as a PCR template. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Another method which may be used is capture PCR which involves PCR amplification of DNA fragments adjacent to a known sequence in human and yeast artificial chromosome DNA (Lagerstrom et al., <highlight><italic>PCR Methods Applic. </italic></highlight>1, 111-119, 1991). In this method, multiple restriction enzyme digestions and ligations may also be used to place an engineered double-stranded sequence into an unknown fragment of the DNA molecule before performing PCR. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Another method which may be used to retrieve unknown sequences is that of Parker et al., <highlight><italic>Nucleic Acids Res. </italic></highlight>19, 3055-3060 (1991). Additionally, PCR, nested primers, and PROMOTERFINDER libraries (Clontech, Palo Alto, Calif.) can be used to walk genomic DNA (Clontech, Palo Alto, Calif.). This process avoids the need to screen libraries and is useful in finding intron/exon junctions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> When screening for full-length cDNAs, it is preferable to use libraries that have been size-selected to include larger cDNAs. Also, random-primed libraries are preferable, in that they will contain more sequences which contain the 5&prime; regions of genes. Use of a randomly primed library may be especially preferable for situations in which an oligo d(T) library does not yield a full-length cDNA. Genomic libraries may be useful for extension of sequence into 5&prime; non-transcribed regulatory regions. Commercially available capillary electrophoresis systems can be used to analyze the size or confirm the nucleotide sequence of sequencing or PCR products. In particular, capillary sequencing may employ flowable polymers for electrophoretic separation, four different fluorescent dyes (one for each nucleotide) which are laser activated, and detection of the emitted wavelengths by a charge coupled device camera. Output/light intensity can be converted to electrical signal using appropriate software (e.g. GENOTYPER and Sequence NAVIGATOR, Perkin Elmer), and the entire process from loading of samples to computer analysis and electronic data display can be computer controlled. Capillary electrophoresis is especially preferable for the sequencing of small pieces of DNA which might be present in limited amounts in a particular sample. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Obtaining Mitochondrial Deformylase Polypeptides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides can be obtained, for example, by purification from human cells, by expression of mitochondrial deformylase poly-nucleotides, or by direct chemical synthesis. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Protein Purification </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides can be purified from human cells, preferably using the method of Meinnel &amp; Blanquet, <highlight><italic>J. Bacteriol. </italic></highlight>175, 7737-40 (1993), as modified by Meinnel &amp; Blanquet (1995). A purified mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is separated from other compounds which normally associate with the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide in the cell, such as certain proteins, carbohydrates, or lipids. A preparation of purified mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides is at least 80% pure; preferably, the preparations are 90%, 95%, or 99% pure. Purity of the preparations can be assessed by any means known in the art, such as SDS-polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Expression of Mitochondrial Deformylase Polynucleotides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> To express a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide can be inserted into an appropriate expression vector, i.e., a vector which contains the necessary elements for the transcription and translation of the inserted coding sequence. Methods which are well known to those skilled in the art may be used to construct expression vectors containing sequences encoding mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides and appropriate transcriptional and translational control elements. These methods include in vitro recombinant DNA techniques, synthetic techniques, and in vivo genetic recombination. Such techniques are described, for example, in Sambrook et al. (1989) and Ausubel et al., CURRENT PROTOCOLS IN MOLECULAR BIOLOGY, John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, N.Y, 1989. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> A variety of expression vector/host systems may be utilized to contain and express sequences encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. These include, but are not limited to: microorganisms such as bacteria transformed with recombinant bacteriophage, plasmid, or cosmid DNA expression vectors; yeast transformed with yeast expression vectors; insect cell systems infected with virus expression vectors (e.g., baculovirus); plant cell systems transformed with virus expression vectors (e.g., cauliflower mosaic virus, CaMV; tobacco mosaic virus, TMV) or with bacterial expression vectors (e.g., Ti or pBR322 plasmids); or animal cell systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The control elements or regulatory sequences are those non-translated regions of the vector&mdash;enhancers, promoters, 5&prime; and 3&prime; untranslated regions&mdash;which interact with host cellular proteins to carry out transcription and translation. Such elements may vary in their strength and specificity. Depending on the vector system and host utilized, any number of suitable transcription and translation elements, including constitutive and inducible promoters, may be used. For example, when cloning in bacterial systems, inducible promoters such as the hybrid lacZ promoter of the BLUESCRIPT phagemid (Stratagene, LaJolla, Calif.) or pSPORT1 plasmid (Life Technologies) and the like may be used. The baculovirus polyhedrin promoter may be used in insect cells. Promoters or enhancers derived from the genomes of plant cells (e.g., heat shock, RUBISCO; and storage protein genes) or from plant viruses (e.g., viral promoters or leader sequences) may be cloned into the vector. In mammalian cell systems, promoters from mammalian genes or from mammalian viruses are preferable. If it is necessary to generate a cell line that contains multiple copies of a nucleotide sequence encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, vectors based on SV40 or EBV may be used with an appropriate selectable marker. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In bacterial systems, a number of expression vectors may be selected depending upon the use intended for the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. For example, when a large quantity of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is needed for the induction of antibodies, vectors which direct high level expression of fusion proteins that are readily purified may be used. Such vectors include, but are not limited to: multifunctional <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>cloning and expression vectors such as BLUESCRIPT (Stratagene), in which the sequence encoding the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide may be ligated into the vector in frame with sequences for the amino-terminal Met and the subsequent 7 residues of &bgr;-galactosidase so that a hybrid protein is produced, pIN vectors (Van Heeke &amp; Schuster, <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>264, 5503-5509, 1989. pGEX vectors (Promega, Madison, Wis.) may also be used to express foreign polypeptides as fusion proteins with glutathione S-transferase (GST). In general, such fusion proteins are soluble and can easily be purified from lysed cells by adsorption to glutathione-agarose beads followed by elution in the presence of free glutathione. Proteins made in such systems may be designed to include heparin, thrombin, or factor XA protease cleavage sites so that the cloned polypeptide of interest can be released from the GST moiety at will. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In the yeast <highlight><italic>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</italic></highlight>, a number of vectors containing constitutive or inducible promoters such as alpha factor, alcohol oxidase, and PGH may be used. For reviews, see Ausubel et al. (1989) and Grant et al., <highlight><italic>Methods Enzymol. </italic></highlight>153, 516-544, 1987. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> In cases where plant expression vectors are used, the expression of sequences encoding mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides can be driven by any of a number of promoters. For example, viral promoters such as the 35S and 19S promoters of CaMV may be used alone or in combination with the omega leader sequence from TMV (Takamatsu <highlight><italic>EMBO J. </italic></highlight>6, 307-311, 1987). Alternatively, plant promoters such as the small subunit of RUBISCO or heat shock promoters may be used (Coruzzi et al., <highlight><italic>EMBO J. </italic></highlight>3, 1671-1680, 1984; Broglie et al., <highlight><italic>Science </italic></highlight>224, 838-843, 1984; and Winter et al., <highlight><italic>Results Probl. Cell Differ. </italic></highlight>17, 85-105, 1991). These constructs can be introduced into plant cells by direct DNA transformation or pathogen-mediated transfection. Such techniques are described in a number of generally available reviews (see, for example, Hobbs or Murry, in McGRAW HILL YEARBOOK OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, McGraw Hill, New York, N.Y., pp. 191-196, 1992). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> An insect system may also be used to express a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. For example, in one such system Autographa californica nuclear polyhedrosis virus (AcNPV) is used as a vector to express foreign genes in <highlight><italic>Spodoptera frugiperda </italic></highlight>cells or in Trichoplusia larvae. Sequences encoding mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides can be cloned into a non-essential region of the virus, such as the polyhedrin gene, and placed under control of the polyhedrin promoter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Successful insertion of mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides will render the polyhedrin gene inactive and produce recombinant virus lacking coat protein. The recombinant viruses may then be used to infect, for example, <highlight><italic>S. frugiperda </italic></highlight>cells or Trichoplusia larvae in which mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides may be expressed (Engelhard et al., (1994) <highlight><italic>Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>91, 3224-3227, 1994). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> A number of viral-based expression systems can be utilized in mammalian host cells. In cases where an adenovirus is used as an expression vector, sequences encoding mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides can be ligated into an adenovirus transcription/translation complex consisting of the late promoter and tripartite leader sequence. Insertion in a non-essential E1 or E3 region of the viral genome may be used to obtain a viable virus which is capable of expressing mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide in infected host cells (Logan &amp; Shenk, <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>81, 3655-3659, 1984). In addition, transcription enhancers, such as the Rous sarcoma virus (RSV) enhancer, may be used to increase expression in mammalian host cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Human artificial chromosomes (HACs) may also be employed to deliver larger fragments of DNA than can be contained and expressed in a plasmid. HACs of 6 to 10M are constructed and delivered via conventional delivery methods (liposomes, polycationic amino polymers, or vesicles) for therapeutic purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Specific initiation signals may also be used to achieve more efficient translation of sequences encoding mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides. Such signals include the ATG initiation codon and adjacent sequences. In cases where sequences encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, its initiation codon, and upstream sequences are inserted into the appropriate expression vector, no additional transcriptional or translational control signals may be needed. However, in cases where only coding sequence, or a fragment thereof, is inserted, exogenous translational control signals including the ATG initiation codon should be provided. Furthermore, the initiation codon should be in the correct reading frame to ensure translation of the entire insert. Exogenous translational elements and initiation codons may be of various origins, both natural and synthetic. The efficiency of expression may be enhanced by the inclusion of enhancers which are appropriate for the particular cell system which is used (see Scharf et al., <highlight><italic>Results Probl. Cell Differ. </italic></highlight>20, 125-162, 1994). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> A host cell strain can be chosen for its ability to modulate the expression of the inserted sequences or to process the expressed protein in the desired fashion. Such modifications of the polypeptide include, but are not limited to, acetylation, carboxylation, glycosylation, phosphorylation, lipidation, and acylation. Post-translational processing which cleaves a &ldquo;prepro&rdquo; form of the protein may also be used to facilitate correct insertion, folding and/or function. Different host cells which have specific cellular machinery and characteristic mechanisms for post-translational activities (e.g., CHO, HeLa, MDCK, HEK293, and W138), are available from the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC; 10801 University Boulevard, Manassas, Va. 20110-2209) and may be chosen to ensure the correct modification and processing of the foreign protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Stable expression is preferred for long-term, high-yield production of recombinant proteins. For example, cell lines which stably express mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides may be transformed using expression vectors which may contain viral origins of replication and/or endogenous expression elements and a selectable marker gene on the same or on a separate vector. Following the introduction of the vector, cells may be allowed to grow for 1-2 days in an enriched medium before they are switched to a selective medium. The purpose of the selectable marker is to confer resistance to selection, and its presence allows growth and recovery of cells which successfully express the introduced sequences. Resistant clones of stably transformed cells may be proliferated using tissue culture techniques appropriate to the cell type. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Any number of selection systems may be used to recover transformed cell lines. These include, but are not limited to, the herpes simplex virus thymidine kinase (Wigler et al., <highlight><italic>Cell </italic></highlight>11, 223-32, 1977) and adenine phosphoribosyltransferase (Lowy et al., <highlight><italic>Cell </italic></highlight>22, 817-23, 1980) genes which can be employed in tk<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> or aprt<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> cells, respectively. Also, antimetabolite, antibiotic, or herbicide resistance can be used as the basis for selection; for example, dhfr confers resistance to methotrexate (Wigler et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>77, 3567-70, 1980); npt, confers resistance to the aminoglycosides, neomycin and G-418 (Colbere-Garapin et al., <highlight><italic>J. Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>150, 1-14, 1981), and als or pat confer resistance to chlorsulfuron and phosphinotricin acetyltransferase, respectively (Murry, supra). Additional selectable genes have been described, for example, trpB, which allows cells to utilize indole in place of tryptophan, or hisD, which allows cells to utilize histinol in place of histidine (Hartman &amp; Mulligan, <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>85, 8047-51, 1988). Visible markers such as anthocyanins, &bgr;-glucuronidase and its substrate GUS, and luciferase and its substrate luciferin, can be used to identify transformants and to quantify the amount of transient or stable protein expression attributable to a specific vector system (Rhodes et al., <highlight><italic>Methods Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>55, 121-131, 1995). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Although the presence of marker gene expression suggests that the mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide is also present, its presence and expression may need to be confirmed. For example, if a sequence encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is inserted within a marker gene sequence, transformed cells containing sequences which encode a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be identified by the absence of marker gene function. Alternatively, a marker gene can be placed in tandem with a sequence encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide under the control of a single promoter. Expression of the marker gene in response to induction or selection usually indicates expression of the mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, host cells which contain a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide and which express a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be identified by a variety of procedures known to those of skill in the art. These procedures include, but are not limited to, DNA-DNA or DNA-RNA hybridizations and protein bioassay or immunoassay techniques which include membrane, solution, or chip-based technologies for the detection and/or quantification of nucleic acid or protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The presence of a polynucleotide sequence encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be detected by DNA-DNA or DNA-RNA hybridization or amplification using probes or fragments or fragments of polynucleotides encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. Nucleic acid amplification-based assays involve the use of oligonucleotides selected from sequences encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide to detect transformants which contain a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> A variety of protocols for detecting and measuring the expression of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, using either polyclonal or monoclonal antibodies specific for the polypeptide are known in the art. Examples include enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), radioimmunoassay (RIA), and fluorescence activated cell sorting (FACS). A two-site, monoclonal-based immunoassay utilizing monoclonal antibodies reactive to two non-interfering epitopes on a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is preferred, but a competitive binding assay can be employed. These and other assays are described, among other places, in Hampton et al., SEROLOGICAL METHODS: A LABORATORY MANUAL, APS Press, St Paul, Minn., 1990) and Maddox et al., <highlight><italic>J. Exp. Med. </italic></highlight>158,1211-1216,1983). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> A wide variety of labels and conjugation techniques are known by those skilled in the art and may be used in various nucleic acid and amino acid assays. Means for producing labeled hybridization or PCR probes for detecting sequences related to polynucleotides encoding mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides include oligolabeling, nick translation, end-labeling or PCR amplification using a labeled nucleotide. Alternatively, the sequences encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, or any fragments thereof may be cloned into a vector for the production of an mRNA probe. Such vectors are known in the art, are commercially available, and may be used to synthesize RNA probes in vitro by addition of an appropriate RNA polymerase such as T7, T3, or SP6 and labeled nucleotides. These procedures may be conducted using a variety of commercially available kits Amersham Pharmacia Biotech, Promega, and US Biochemical. Suitable reporter molecules or labels, which may be used for ease of detection, include radionuclides, enzymes, fluorescent, chemiluminescent, or chromogenic agents as well as substrates, cofactors, inhibitors, magnetic particles, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Host cells transformed with nucleotide sequences encoding mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides may be cultured under conditions suitable for the expression and recovery of the protein from cell culture. The protein produced by a transformed cell may be secreted or contained intracellularly depending on the sequence and/or the vector used. As will be understood by those of skill in the art, expression vectors containing polynucleotides which encode mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides may be designed to contain signal sequences which direct secretion of mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides through a prokaryotic or eukaryotic cell membrane. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Other constructions may be used to join sequences encoding mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides to nucleotide sequence encoding a polypeptide domain which will facilitate purification of soluble proteins. Such purification facilitating domains include, but are not limited to, metal chelating peptides such as histidine-tryptophan modules that allow purification on immobilized metals, protein A domains that allow purification on immobilized immunoglobulin, and the domain utilized in the FLAGS extension/affinity purification system (Immunex Corp., Seattle, Wash.). The inclusion of cleavable linker sequences such as those specific for Factor XA or enterokinase (Invitrogen, San Diego, Calif.) between the purification domain and mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides may be used to facilitate purification. One such expression vector provides for expression of a filsion protein containing mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides and a nucleic acid encoding 6 histidine residues preceding a thioredoxin or an enterokinase cleavage site. The histidine residues facilitate purification on IMAC (immobilized metal ion affinity chromatography as described in Porath et al., <highlight><italic>Prot. Exp. Purif. </italic></highlight>3, 263-281, 1992) while the enterokinase cleavage site provides a means for purifying mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides from the fusion protein. A discussion of vectors which contain fusion proteins is provided in Kroll et al., <highlight><italic>DNA Cell Biol. </italic></highlight>12, 441-453, 1993). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Chemical Synthesis </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, sequences encoding a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide may be synthesized, in whole or in part, using chemical methods well known in the art (see Caruthers et al., <highlight><italic>Nucl. Acids Res. Symp. Ser. </italic></highlight>215-223, 1980; Horn et al. <highlight><italic>Nucl. Acids Res. Symp. Ser. </italic></highlight>225-232, 1980). Alternatively, the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide itself may be produced using chemical methods to synthesize the amino acid sequence of the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, or a fragment thereof. For example, peptide synthesis can be performed using various solid-phase techniques (Roberge et al., <highlight><italic>Science </italic></highlight>269, 202-204, 1995) and automated synthesis may be achieved, for example, using the ABI 431A Peptide Synthesizer (Perkin Elmer). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In addition to recombinant production, fragments of mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides may be produced by direct peptide synthesis using solid-phase techniques (Merrifield, <highlight><italic>J. Am. Chem. Soc. </italic></highlight>85, 2149-2154, 1963). Protein synthesis may be performed using manual techniques or by automation. Automated synthesis may be achieved, for example, using Applied Biosystems 431A Peptide Synthesizer (Perkin Elmer). Various fragments of mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides may be chemically synthesized separately and combined using chemical methods to produce the full length molecule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The newly synthesized peptide may be substantially purified by preparative high performance liquid chromatography (e.g., Creighton, PROTEINS: STRUCTURES AND MOLECULAR PRINCIPLES, WH Freeman and Co., New York, N.Y., 1983). The composition of the synthetic peptides may be confirmed by amino acid analysis or sequencing (e.g., the Edman degradation procedure; see Creighton, supra). Additionally, the amino acid sequence of the polypeptide or any part thereof may be altered during direct synthesis and/or combined using chemical methods with sequences from other proteins, or any part thereof, to produce a variant polypeptide. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Production of Altered Mitochondrial Deformylase Polypeptides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> As will be understood by those of skill in the art, it may be advantageous to produce mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide-encoding nucleotide sequences possessing non-naturally occurring codons. For example, codons preferred by a particular prokaryotic or eukaryotic host can be selected to increase the rate of protein expression or to produce an RNA transcript having desirable properties, such as a half-life which is longer than that of a transcript generated from the naturally occurring sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The nucleotide sequences disclosed herein can be engineered using methods generally known in the art in order to alter mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide-encoding sequences for a variety of reasons, including but not limited to, alterations which modify the cloning, processing, and/or expression of the gene product. DNA shuffling by random fragmentation and PCR reassembly of gene fragments and synthetic oligonucleotides may be used to engineer the nucleotide sequences. For example, site-directed mutagenesis may be used to insert new restriction sites, alter glycosylation patterns, change codon preference, produce splice variants, introduce mutations, and so forth. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Antibodies </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Any type of antibody known in the art can be generated to bind specifically to an epitope of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. ,,Antibody&rdquo; as used herein includes intact immunoglobulin molecules, as well as fragments thereof, such as Fa, F(ab&prime;)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and Fv, which are capable of binding an epitope of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. Typically, at least 6, 8, 10, or 12 contiguous amino acids are required to form an epitope. However, epitopes which involve non-contiguous amino acids may require more, e.g., at least 15, 25, or 50 amino acids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> An antibody which specifically binds to an epitope of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be used therapeutically, as well as in immunochemical assays, including but not limited to Western blots, ELISAs, radioimmunoassays, immunohistochemical assays, immunoprecipitations, or other immunochemical assays known in the art. Various immunoassays can be used to identify antibodies having the desired specificity. Numerous protocols for competitive binding or immunoradiometric assays are well known in the art. Such immunoassays typically involve the measurement of complex formation between an immunogen and an antibody which specifically binds to the immunogen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Typically, an antibody which specifically binds to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide provides a detection signal at least 5-, 10-, or 20-fold higher than a detection signal provided with other proteins when used in such immunochemical assays. Preferably, antibodies which specifically bind to mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides do not detect other proteins in immunochemical assays and can immunoprecipitate a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide from solution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides can be used to immunize a mammal, such as a mouse, rat, rabbit, guinea pig, monkey, or human, to produce polyclonal antibodies. If desired, the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be conjugated to a carrier protein, such as bovine serum albumin, thyroglobulin, and keyhole limpet hemocyanin. Depending on the host species, various adjuvants can be used to increase the immunological response. Such adjuvants include, but are not limited to, Freund&apos;s adjuvant, mineral gels (e.g., aluminum hydroxide), and surface active substances (e.g. lysolecithin, pluronic polyols, polyanions, peptides, oil emulsions, keyhole limpet hemocyanin, and dinitrophenol). Among adjuvants used in humans, BCG (bacilli Calmette-Guerin) and <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium parvum </italic></highlight>are especially preferable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Monoclonal antibodies which specifically bind to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be prepared using any technique which provides for the production of antibody molecules by continuous cell lines in culture. These techniques include, but are not limited to, the hybridoma technique, the human B-cell hybridoma technique, and the EBV-hybridoma technique (Kohler et al., <highlight><italic>Nature </italic></highlight>256, 495-497, 1985; Kozbor et al., <highlight><italic>J. Immunol. Methods </italic></highlight>81, 31-42, 1985; Cote et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>80, 2026-2030, 1983; Cole et al., <highlight><italic>Mol. Cell Biol. </italic></highlight>62, 109-120, 1984). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> In addition, techniques developed for the production of ,,chimeric antibodies,&rdquo; the splicing of mouse antibody genes to human antibody genes to obtain a molecule with appropriate antigen specificity and biological activity can be used (Morrison et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>81, 6851-6855, 1984; Neuberger et al., <highlight><italic>Nature </italic></highlight>312, 604-608, 1984; Takeda et al., <highlight><italic>Nature </italic></highlight>314, 452-454, 1985). Monoclonal and other antibodies can also be ,,humanized&rdquo; in order to prevent a patient from mounting an immune response against the antibody when it is used therapeutically. Such antibodies may be sufficiently similar in sequence to human antibodies to be used directly in therapy or may require alteration of a few key residues. Sequence differences between, for example, rodent antibodies and human sequences can be minimized by replacing residues which differ from those in the human sequences, for example, by site directed mutagenesis of individual residues, or by grating of entire complementarity determining regions. Alternatively, one can produce humanized antibodies using recombinant methods, as described in GB 2188638B. Antibodies which specifically bind to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can contain antigen binding sites which are either partially or fully humanized, as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,565,332. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, techniques described for the production of single chain antibodies may be adapted, using methods known in the art, to produce single chain antibodies which specifically bind to mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides. Antibodies with related specificity, but of distinct idiotypic composition, may be generated by chain shuffling from random combinatorial immunoglobin libraries (Burton, <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>88, 11120-23, 1991). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Single-chain antibodies can also be constructed using a DNA amplification method, such as the polymerase chain reaction (PCR), using hybridoma cDNA as a template (Thirion et al., 1996, <highlight><italic>Eur. J. Cancer Prev. </italic></highlight>5, 507-11). Single-chain antibodies can be mono- or bispecific, and can be bivalent or tetravalent. Construction of tetravalent, bispecific single-chain antibodies is taught, for example, in Coloma &amp; Morrison, 1997, <highlight><italic>Nat. Biotechnol. </italic></highlight>15, 159-63. Construction of bivalent, bispecific single-chain antibodies is taught inter alia in Mallender &amp; Voss, 1994, <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>269, 199-206. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> A nucleotide sequence encoding a single-chain antibody can be constructed using manual or automated nucleotide synthesis, cloned into an expression construct using standard recombinant DNA methods, and introduced into a cell to express the coding sequence, as described below. Alternatively, single-chain antibodies can be produced directly using, for example, filamentous phage technology. Verhaar et al., 1995, <highlight><italic>Int. J. Cancer </italic></highlight>61, 497-501; Nicholls et al., 1993, <highlight><italic>J. Immunol. Meth. </italic></highlight>165, 81-91. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Antibodies which specifically bind to mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides also can be produced by inducing in vivo production in the lymphocyte population or by screening immunoglobulin libraries or panels of highly specific binding reagents as disclosed in the literature (Orlandi et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>86, 3833-3837, 1989; Winter et al., <highlight><italic>Nature </italic></highlight>349, 293-299, 1991). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Other types of antibodies can be constructed and used therapeutically in methods of the invention. For example, chimeric antibodies can be constructed as disclosed in WO 93/03151. Binding proteins which are derived from immunoglobulins and which are multivalent and multispecific, such as the ,,diabodies&rdquo; described in WO 94/13804, can also be prepared. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Antibodies of the invention can be purified by methods well known in the art. For example, antibodies can be affinity purified by passing the antibodies over a column to which a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is bound. The bound antibodies can then be eluted from the column, using a buffer with a high salt concentration. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Antisense Oligonucleotides </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Antisense oligonucleotides are nucleotide sequences which are complementary to a specific DNA or RNA sequence. Once introduced into a cell, the complementary nucleotides combine with natural sequences produced by the cell to form duplexes and block either transcription or translation. Preferably, an antisense oligonucleotide is at least 8 nucleotides in length, but can be at least 11, 12, 15, 20, 25, 30, 35, 40, 45, or 50 or more nucleotides long. Longer sequences can also be used. Antisense oligonucleotide molecules can be provided in a DNA construct and introduced into a cell as described above to decrease the level of mitochondrial deformylase gene products in the cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Antisense oligonucleotides can be deoxyribonucleotides, ribonucleotides, peptide nucleic acids (PNAs; described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,714,331), locked nuleic acids (LNAs; described in WO 99/14226), or a combination of them. Oligonucleotides can be synthesized manually or by an automated synthesizer, by covalently linking the 5&prime; end of one nucleotide with the 3&prime; end of another nucleotide with non-phosphodiester internucleotide linkages such alkylphosphonates, phosphorothioates, phosphorodithioates, alkylphosphonothioates, alkylphosphonates, phosphoramidates, phosphate esters, carbamates, acetamidate, carboxymethyl esters, carbonates, and phosphate triesters. See Brown, <highlight><italic>Meth. Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>20, 1-8, 1994; Sonveaux, <highlight><italic>Meth. Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>26, 1-72, 1994; Uhlmann et al., <highlight><italic>Chem. Rev. </italic></highlight>90, 543-583, 1990. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Modifications of mitochondrial deformylase gene expression can be obtained by designing antisense oligonucleotides molecules which will form duplexes to the control, 5&prime; or regulatory regions of the mitochondrial deformylase encoding gene. Oligonucleotides derived from the transcription initiation site, e.g., between positions &minus;10 and &plus;10 from the start site, are preferred. Similarly, inhibition can be achieved using &ldquo;triple helix&rdquo; base-pairing methodology. Triple helix pairing is useful because it causes inhibition of the ability of the double helix to open sufficiently for the binding of polymerases, transcription factors, or chaperons. Recent therapeutic advances using triplex DNA have been described in the literature (Gee et al., in Huber &amp; Carr, MOLECULAR AND IMMUNOLOGIC APPROACHES, Futura Publishing Co., Mt. Kisco, N.Y., 1994). The complementary sequence or antisense molecule may also be designed to block translation of mRNA by preventing the transcript from binding to ribosomes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Precise complementarity is not required for successful duplex formation between an antisense oligonucleotide and the complementary sequence of a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide. Antisense molecules which comprise, for example, 2, 3, 4, or 5 or more stretches of contiguous nucleotides which are precisely complementary to a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide, each separated by a stretch of contiguous nucleotides which are not complementary to adjacent mitochondrial deformylase nucleotides, can provide targeting specificity for mitochondrial deformylase mRNA. Preferably, each stretch of contiguous nucleotides is at least 4, 5, 6, 7, or 8 or more nucleotides in length. Non-complementary intervening sequences are preferably 1, 2, 3, or 4 nucleotides in length. One skilled in the art can easily use the calculated melting point of an antisense-sense pair to determine the degree of mismatching which will be tolerated between a particular antisense oligonucleotide and a particular mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Antisense oligonucleotides can be modified without affecting their ability to hybridize to a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide. These modifications can be internal or at one or both ends of the antisense molecule. For example, internucleoside phosphate linkages can be modified by adding cholesteryl or diamine moieties with varying numbers of carbon residues between the amino groups and terminal ribose. Modified bases and/or sugars, such as arabinose instead of ribose, or a 3&prime;, 5&prime;-substituted oligonucleotide in which the 3&prime; hydroxyl group or the 5&prime; phosphate group are substituted, can also be employed in a modified antisense oligonucleotide. These modified oligonucleotides can be prepared by methods well known in the art. See, e.g., Agrawal et al., <highlight><italic>Trends Biotechnol. </italic></highlight>10, 152-158, 1992; Uhlmann et al., <highlight><italic>Chem. Rev. </italic></highlight>90, 543-584, 1990; Uhlmann et al., <highlight><italic>Tetrahedron. Lett. </italic></highlight>215, 3539-3542, 1987. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Ribozymes </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Ribozymes are RNA molecules with catalytic activity. See, e.g., Cech, <highlight><italic>Science </italic></highlight>236, 1532-1539; 1987; Cech, <highlight><italic>Ann. Rev. Biochem. </italic></highlight>59, 543-568; 1990, Cech, <highlight><italic>Curr. Opin. Struct. Biol. </italic></highlight>2, 605-609; 1992, Couture &amp; Stinchcomb, <highlight><italic>Trends Genet. </italic></highlight>12, 510-515, 1996. Ribozymes can be used to inhibit gene function by cleaving an RNA sequence, as is known in the art (e.g., Haseloff et al., U.S. Pat. No. 5,641,673). The mechanism of ribozyme action involves sequence-specific hybridization of the ribozyme molecule to complementary target RNA, followed by endonucleolytic cleavage. Examples include engineered hammerhead motif ribozyme molecules that can specifically and efficiently catalyze endonucleolytic cleavage of specific nucleotide sequences. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The coding sequence of a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide can be used to generate ribozymes which will specifically bind to mRNA transcribed from the mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide. Methods of designing and constructing ribozymes which can cleave other RNA molecules in trans in a highly sequence specific manner have been developed and described in the art (see Haseloff, J. et al. <highlight><italic>Nature </italic></highlight>334, 585-591, 1988). For example, the cleavage activity of ribozymes can be targeted to specific RNAs by engineering a discrete &ldquo;hybridization&rdquo; region into the ribozyme. The hybridization region contains a sequence complementary to the target RNA and thus specifically hybridizes with the target (see, for example, Gerlach et al., EP 321,201). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Specific ribozyme cleavage sites within a mitochondrial deformylase RNA target are initially identified by scanning the target molecule for ribozyme cleavage sites which include the following sequences: GUA, GUU, and GUC. Once identified, short RNA sequences of between 15 and 20 ribonucleotides corresponding to the region of the target RNA containing the cleavage site may be evaluated for secondary structural features which may render the oligonucleotide inoperable. The suitability of candidate targets may also be evaluated by testing accessibility to hybridization with complementary oligonucleotides using ribonuclease protection assays. The nucleotide sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS: 1, 3 and 5 provide a source of suitable hybridization region sequences. Longer complementary sequences can be used to increase the affinity of the hybridization sequence for the target. The hybridizing and cleavage regions of the ribozyme can be integrally related; thus, upon hybridizing to the target RNA through the complementary regions, the catalytic region of the ribozyme can cleave the target. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Ribozymes can be introduced into cells as part of a DNA construct, as is known in the art and described above. Mechanical methods, such as microinjection, liposome-mediated transfection, electroporation, or calcium phosphate precipitation, can be used to introduce the ribozyme-containing DNA construct into cells in which it is desired to decrease mitochondrial deformylase expression, as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, if it is desired that the cells stably retain the DNA construct, it can be supplied on a plasmid and maintained as a separate element or integrated into the genome of the cells, as is known in the art. The DNA construct can include transcriptional regulatory elements, such as a promoter element, an enhancer or UAS element, and a transcriptional terminator signal, for controlling transcription of ribozymes in the cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> As taught in Haseloff et al., U.S. Pat. No. 5,641,673, ribozymes can be engineered so that ribozyme expression will occur in response to factors which induce expression of a target gene. Ribozymes can also be engineered to provide an additional level of regulation, so that destruction of mRNA occurs only when both a ribozyme and a target gene are induced in the cells. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Screening Methods </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> The invention provides methods for identifying modulators, i.e., candidate or test compounds which bind to mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides or polynucleotides and/or have a stimulatory or inhibitory effect on, for example, expression or activity of the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or polynucleotide, so as to increase or decrease proliferation of the cell. Decreased proliferation is useful for treating neoplastic cells, including both benign and malignant (cancer) cells. Increased proliferation may be desired, for example, to treat diseases characterized by low numbers of particular cell types, such as AIDS, or for increasing numbers of a cell population in vitro. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> The invention provides assays for screening test compounds which bind to or modulate the activity of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide. A test compound preferably binds to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or polynucleotide. More preferably, a test compound decreases a mitochondrial deformylase activity of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or expression of a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide by at least about 10, preferably about 50, more preferably about 75, 90, or 100% relative to the absence of the test compound. Even more preferably, the test compound decreases or increases proliferation of a cell, such as a neoplastic cell, by at least about 10, preferably about 50, more preferably about 75, 90, or 100% relative to proliferation of the cell in the absence of the test compound. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Test Compounds </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Test compounds can be obtained using any of the numerous approaches in combinatorial library methods known in the art, including but not limited to, biological libraries, spatially addressable parallel solid phase or solution phase libraries, synthetic library methods requiring deconvolution, the ,,one-bead one-compound&rdquo; library method, and synthetic library methods using affinity chromatography selection. The biological library approach is limited to polypeptide libraries, while the other four approaches are applicable to polypeptide, non-peptide oligomer or small molecule libraries of compounds. See Lam, <highlight><italic>Anticancer Drug Des. </italic></highlight>12, 145, 1997. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Examples of methods for the synthesis of molecular libraries can be found in the art, for example in DeWitt et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. </italic></highlight>90, 6909, 1993; Erb et al. <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad Sci. U.S.A. </italic></highlight>91, 11422, 1994; Zuckermann et al., <highlight><italic>J. Med. Chem. </italic></highlight>37, 2678, 1994; Cho et al., <highlight><italic>Science </italic></highlight>261, 1303, 1993; Carell et al., <highlight><italic>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. </italic></highlight>33, 2059, 1994; Carell et al., <highlight><italic>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. </italic></highlight>33, 2061; and in Gallop et al., <highlight><italic>J. Med. Chem. </italic></highlight>37, 1233, 1994. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Libraries of compounds may be presented in solution (see, e.g., Houghten, <highlight><italic>Biotechniques </italic></highlight>13, 412-421, 1992), or on beads (Lam, <highlight><italic>Nature </italic></highlight>354, 82-84, 1991), chips (Fodor, <highlight><italic>Nature </italic></highlight>364, 555-556, 1993), bacteria or spores (Ladner, U.S. Pat. No. 5,223,409), plasmids (Cull et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. </italic></highlight>89, 1865-1869, 1992) or on phage (Scott &amp; Smith, <highlight><italic>Science </italic></highlight>249, 386-390, 1990; Devlin, <highlight><italic>Science </italic></highlight>249, 404-406, 1990); Cwirla et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. </italic></highlight>97, 6378-6382, 1990; Felici, <highlight><italic>J. Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>222, 301-310,1991; and Ladner, U.S. Pat. No. 5,223,409). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">High Throughput Screening </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Test compounds are preferably screened for the ability to bind to mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides or polynucleotides or to affect mitochondrial deformylase activity or mitochondrial deformylase gene expression using high throughput screening. Using high throughput screening, many discrete compounds can be tested in parallel so that large numbers of test compounds can be quickly screened. The most widely established techniques utilize 96-well microtiter plates. The wells of the microtiter plates typically require assay volumes that range from 50 to 500 ml. In addition to the plates, many instruments, materials, pipettors, robotics, plate washers and plate readers are commercially available to fit the 96-well format to a wide range of homogeneous and heterogeneous assays. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, ,,free format assays,&rdquo; or assays that have no physical barrier between samples, can be used. For example, an assay using pigment cells (melanocytes) in a simple homogeneous assay for combinatorial peptide libraries is described by Jayawickreme et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. </italic></highlight>19, 1614-18 (1994). The cells are placed under agarose in petri dishes, then beads that carry combinatorial compounds are placed on the surface of the agarose. The combinatorial compounds are partially released the compounds from the beads. Active compounds can be visualized as dark pigment areas because, as the compounds diffuse locally into the gel matrix, the active compounds cause the cells to change colors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Another example of a free format assay is described by Chelsky, &ldquo;Strategies for Screening Combinatorial Libraries: Novel and Traditional Approaches,&rdquo; reported at the First Annual Conference of The Society for Biomolecular Screening in Philadephia, Pa. (Nov. 7-10, 1995). Chelsky placed a simple homogenous enzyme assay for carbonic anhydrase inside an agarose gel such that the enzyme in the gel would cause a color change throughout the gel. Thereafter, beads carrying combinatorial compounds via a photolinker were placed inside the gel and the compounds were partially released by UV-light. Compounds that inhibited the enzyme were observed as local zones of inhibition having less color change. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> Yet another example is described by Salmon et al., <highlight><italic>Molecular Diversity </italic></highlight>2, 57-63 (1996). In this example, combinatorial libraries were screened for compounds that had cytotoxic effects on cancer cells growing in agar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> Another high throughput screening method is described in Beutel et al., U.S. Pat. No. 5,976,813. In this method, test samples are placed in a porous matrix. One or more assay components are then placed within, on top of, or at the bottom of a matrix such as a gel, a plastic sheet, a filter or other forms of easily manipulated solid support. When samples are introduced to the porous matrix they diffuse sufficiently slowly such that the assays can be performed without the test samples running together. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Binding Assays </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> For binding assays, the test compound is preferably a small molecule which binds to and occupies the active site of the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide thereby making the active site inaccessible to substrate such that normal biological activity is prevented. Examples of such small molecules include but are not limited to small peptides or peptide-like molecules. In binding assays, either the test compound or the target polypeptide can comprise a detectable label, such as a fluorescent, radioisotopic, or enzymatic label, such as horseradish peroxidase, alkaline phosphatase, or luciferase. Detection of a test compound which is bound to the target polypeptide can then be accomplished, for example, by direct counting of radioemmission or by scintillation counting, or by determination of conversion of an appropriate substrate to product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, binding of a test compound to a target polypeptide can be determined without labeling either of the interactants. For example, a microphysiometer can be used to detect binding of a test compound with the target polypeptide. A microphysiometer (e.g., Cytosensor&Ocirc;) is an analytical instrument that measures the rate at which a cell acidifies its environment using a light-addressable potentiometric sensor (LAPS). Changes in this acidification rate can be used as an indicator of the interaction between a test compound and a target polypeptide. (McConnell et al., <highlight><italic>Science </italic></highlight>257, 1906-1912, 1992). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> In yet another aspect of the invention, a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be used as a &ldquo;bait protein&rdquo; in a two-hybrid assay or three-hybrid assay (see, e.g., U.S. Pat. No. 5,283,317; Zervos et al., <highlight><italic>Cell </italic></highlight>72, 223-232, 1993; Madura et al., <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>268, 12046-12054, 1993; Bartel et al., <highlight><italic>Biotechniques </italic></highlight>14, 920-924, 1993; Iwabuchi et al., <highlight><italic>Oncogene </italic></highlight>8, 1693-1696, 1993; and Brent W094/10300), to identify other proteins (captured proteins) which bind to or interact with the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide and modulate its activity </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> The two-hybrid system is based on the modular nature of most transcription factors, which consist of separable DNA-binding and activation domains. Briefly, the assay utilizes two different DNA constructs. In one construct, the gene that codes for a protein of the invention is fused to a gene encoding the DNA binding domain of a known transcription factor (e.g., GAL4). In the other construct, a DNA sequence, from a library of DNA sequences, that encodes an unidentified protein (&ldquo;prey&rdquo; or &ldquo;sample&rdquo;) is fused to a gene that codes for the activation domain of the known transcription factor. If the &ldquo;bait&rdquo; and the &ldquo;prey&rdquo; proteins are able to interact in vivo to form an protein-dependent complex, the DNA-binding and activation domains of the transcription factor are brought into close proximity. This proximity allows transcription of a reporter gene (e.g., LacZ) which is operably linked to a transcriptional regulatory site responsive to the transcription factor. Expression of the reporter gene can be detected, and cell colonies containing the functional transcription factor can be isolated and used to obtain the cloned gene which encodes the protein which interacts with the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Determining the ability of a test compound to bind to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can also be accomplished using a technology such as real-time Bimolecular Interaction Analysis (BIA). Sjolander &amp; Urbaniczky, <highlight><italic>Anal. Chem. </italic></highlight>63, 2338-2345, 1991, and Szabo et al., <highlight><italic>Curr. Opin. Struct. Biol. </italic></highlight>5, 699-705, 1995. BIA is a technology for studying biospecific interactions in real time, without labeling any of the interactants (e.g., BIAcore&trade;). Changes in the optical phenomenon surface plasmon resonance (SPR) can be used as an indication of real-time reactions between biological molecules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> It may be desirable to immobilize either the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or the test compound to facilitate separation of bound from unbound forms of one or both of the interactants, as well as to accommodate automation of the assay. Thus, either the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or the test compound is bound to a solid support. Suitable solid supports include, but are not limited to, glass or plastic slides, tissue culture plates, microtiter wells, tubes, silicon chips, or particles such as beads, including but not limited to latex, polystyrene, or glass beads. Any method known in the art can be used to attach the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or test compound to a solid support, including use of covalent and non-covalent linkages, passive absorption, or pairs of binding moieties attached respectively to the polynucleotide and the solid support. Test compounds are preferably bound to the solid support in an array, so that the location of individual test compounds can be tracked. Binding of a test compound to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be accomplished in any vessel suitable for containing the reactants. Examples of such vessels include microtiter plates, test tubes, and microcentrifuge tubes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is a fusion protein comprising a domain that allows the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide to be bound to a solid support. For example, glutathione-S-transferase fusion proteins can be adsorbed onto glutathione sepharose beads (Sigma Chemical, St. Louis, Mo.) or glutathione derivatized microtiter plates, which are then combined with the test compound or the test compound and the non-adsorbed mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, and the mixture incubated under conditions conducive to complex formation (e.g., at physiological conditions for salt and pH). Following incubation, the beads or microtiter plate wells are washed to remove any unbound components and binding of the interactants is determined either directly or indirectly, for example, as described above. Alternatively, the complexes can be dissociated from the solid support before binding is determined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> Other techniques for immobilizing proteins on a solid support also can be used in the screening assays of the invention. For example, either a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or a test compound can be immobilized utilizing conjugation of biotin and streptavidin. Biotinylated mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides or test compounds can be prepared from biotin-NHS(N-hydroxysuccinimide) using techniques well known in the art (e.g., biotinylation kit, Pierce Chemicals, Rockford, Ill.) and immobilized in the wells of streptavidin-coated 96 well plates (Pierce Chemical). Alternatively, antibodies which specifically bind to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or a test compound, but which do not interfere with a desired binding site, such as the active site of the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, can be derivatized to the wells of the plate, and unbound target or protein trapped in the wells by antibody conjugation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Methods for detecting such complexes, in addition to those described above for the GST-immobilized complexes, include immunodetection of complexes using antibodies which specifically bind to the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide or test compound, as well as enzyme-linked assays which rely on detecting a mitochondrial deformylase activity of the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> Screening for test compounds which bind to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide also can be carried out in an intact cell. Any cell which expresses a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide can be used in a cell-based assay system. The mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide can be naturally occurring in the cell or can be introduced using techniques such as those described above. Either a primary culture or an established cell line, including neoplastic cell lines such as the colon cancer cell lines HCT116, DLD1, HT29, Caco2, SW837, SW480, and RKO, breast cancer cell lines 21-PT, 21-MT, MDA-468, SK-BR3, and BT-474, the A549 lung cancer cell line, and the H392 glioblastoma cell line, can be used. An intact cell is contacted with a test compound. Binding of the test compound to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is determined as described above, after lysing the cell to release the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide-test compound complex. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Mitochondrial Deformylase Assays </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> Test compounds also can be tested for the ability to increase or decrease a mitochondrial deformylase activity of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. Mitochondrial deformylase activity is preferably measured using the method described in Adams, <highlight><italic>J. Mol. Biol. </italic></highlight>33, 571-89, as modified by Meinnel &amp; Blanquet, <highlight><italic>J. Bacteriol. </italic></highlight>177, 1883-87 (1995), or WO 99/57097 (see also Examples 2 and 5, below). Mitochondrial deformylase activity can be measured after contacting either a purified mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, a cell extract, or an intact cell with a test compound. A test compound which decreases mitochondrial deformylase activity by at least about 10, preferably about 50, more preferably about 75, 90, or 100% is identified as a potential agent for decreasing cell proliferation. A test compound which increases mitochondrial deformylase activity by at least about 10, preferably about 50, more preferably about 75, 90, or 100% is identified as a potential agent for increasing cell proliferation. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Mitochondrial Deformylase Gene Expression </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, test compounds which increase or decrease mitochondrial deformylase gene expression are identified. A mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide is contacted with a candidate compound and the expression of an RNA or protein product of the mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide is determined. The level of expression of appropriate mRNA or protein in the presence of the candidate compound is compared to the level of expression of mRNA or protein in the absence of the candidate compound. The candidate compound can then be identified as a modulator of expression based on this comparison. For example, when expression of mRNA or protein is greater in the presence of the candidate compound than in its absence, the candidate compound is identified as a stimulator or enhancer of the mRNA or protein expression. Alternatively, when expression of the mRNA or protein is less in the presence of the candidate compound than in its absence, the candidate compound is identified as an inhibitor of the mRNA or protein expression. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> The level of mRNA or protein expression in the cells can be determined by methods well known in the art for detecting mRNA or protein. Either qualitative or quantitative methods can be used. The presence of protein products of the disclosed genes can be determined, for example, using a variety of techniques known to the art, including immunochemical methods such as radioimmunoassay, Western blotting, and immunohistochemistry. Alternatively, protein synthesis can be determined in vivo, in a cell culture, or in an in vitro translation system by detecting incorporation of labeled amino acids into a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Such screening can be carried out either in a cell-free assay system or in an intact cell. Any cell which expresses a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide can be used in a cell-based assay system. The mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide can be naturally occurring in the cell or can be introduced using techniques such as those described above. Either a primary culture or an established cell line, including neoplastic cell lines such as the colon cancer cell lines HCT116, DLD1, HT29, Caco2, SW837, SW480, and RKO, breast cancer cell lines 21-PT, 21-MT, MDA-468, SK-BR3, and BT-474, the A549 lung cancer cell line, and the H392 glioblastoma cell line, can be used. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Pharmaceutical Compositions </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> An additional embodiment of the invention relates to the administration of a pharmaceutical composition, in conjunction with a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier, for any of the therapeutic effects discussed above. Such pharmaceutical compositions may comprise a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide, antibodies which specifically bind to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, or mimetics, agonists, antagonists, or inhibitors of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. In a preferred embodiment, the pharmaceutical composition comprises an antibody which specifically binds to a polypeptide comprising an amino acid sequence selected from the group consisting of amino acid sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:2, the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:2, amino acid sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:4, the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:4 amino acid sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:6, and the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:6. In a further preferred embodiment, the pharmaceutical composition comprises an antisense RNA or a ribozyme which is complementary to an RNA transcribed from a polynucleotide comprising a nucleotide sequence selected from the group consisting of nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:1, the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:1, nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:3, the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:3, nucleotide sequences which are at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:5, and the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:5. In this context, the term ,,antisense RNA or a ribozyme&rdquo; also comprises DNA sequences encoding said antisense RNA or ribozyme and which are, preferably, inserted in an expression vector which is useful for gene therapy. Such vectors are well known to the person skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> The compositions may be administered alone or in combination with at least one other agent, such as stabilizing compound, which may be administered in any sterile, biocompatible pharmaceutical carrier, including, but not limited to, saline, buffered saline, dextrose, and water. The compositions may be administered to a patient alone, or in combination with other agents, drugs or hormones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> The pharmaceutical compositions utilized in this invention may be administered by any number of routes including, but not limited to, oral, intravenous, intramuscular, intra-arterial, intramedullary, intrathecal, intraventricular, transdermal, subcutaneous, intraperitoneal, intranasal, enteral, topical, sublingual, or rectal means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> In addition to the active ingredients, these pharmaceutical compositions may contain suitable pharmaceutically-acceptable carriers comprising excipients and auxiliaries which facilitate processing of the active compounds into preparations which can be used pharmaceutically. Further details on techniques for formulation and administration may be found in the latest edition of REMINGTON&apos;S PHARMACEUTICAL SCIENCES (Maack Publishing Co., Easton, Pa.). Pharmaceutical compositions for oral administration can be formulated using pharmaceutically acceptable carriers well known in the art in dosages suitable for oral administration. Such carriers enable the pharmaceutical compositions to be formulated as tablets, pills, dragees, capsules, liquids, gels, syrups, slurries, suspensions, and the like, for ingestion by the patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> Pharmaceutical preparations for oral use can be obtained through combination of active compounds with solid excipient, optionally grinding a resulting mixture, and processing the mixture of granules, after adding suitable auxiliaries, if desired, to obtain tablets or dragee cores. Suitable excipients are carbohydrate or protein fillers, such as sugars, including lactose, sucrose, mannitol, or sorbitol; starch from corn, wheat, rice, potato, or other plants; cellulose, such as methyl cellulose, hydroxypropylmethyl-cellulose, or sodium carboxymethylcellulose; gums including arabic and tragacanth; and proteins such as gelatin and collagen. If desired, disintegrating or solubilizing agents may be added, such as the cross-linked polyvinyl pyrrolidone, agar, alginic acid, or a salt thereof, such as sodium alginate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> Dragee cores may be used in conjunction with suitable coatings, such as concentrated sugar solutions, which may also contain gum arabic, talc, polyvinylpyrrolidone, carbopol gel, polyethylene glycol, and/or titanium dioxide, lacquer solutions, and suitable organic solvents or solvent mixtures. Dyestuffs or pigments may be added to the tablets or dragee coatings for product identification or to characterize the quantity of active compound, i.e., dosage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> Pharmaceutical preparations which can be used orally include push-fit capsules made of gelatin, as well as soft, sealed capsules made of gelatin and a coating, such as glycerol or sorbitol. Push-fit capsules can contain active ingredients mixed with a filler or binders, such as lactose or starches, lubricants, such as talc or magnesium stearate, and, optionally, stabilizers. In soft capsules, the active compounds may be dissolved or suspended in suitable liquids, such as fatty oils, liquid, or liquid polyethylene glycol with or without stabilizers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Pharmaceutical formulations suitable for parenteral administration may be formulated in aqueous solutions, preferably in physiologically compatible buffers such as Hanks&apos; solution, Ringer&apos;s solution, or physiologically buffered saline. Aqueous injection suspensions may contain substances which increase the viscosity of the suspension, such as sodium carboxymethyl cellulose, sorbitol, or dextran. Additionally, suspensions of the active compounds may be prepared as appropriate oily injection suspensions. Suitable lipophilic solvents or vehicles include fatty oils such as sesame oil, or synthetic fatty acid esters, such as ethyl oleate or triglycerides, or liposomes. Non-lipid polycationic amino polymers may also be used for delivery. Optionally, the suspension may also contain suitable stabilizers or agents which increase the solubility of the compounds to allow for the preparation of highly concentrated solutions. For topical or nasal administration, penetrants appropriate to the particular barrier to be permeated are used in the formulation. Such penetrants are generally known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> The pharmaceutical compositions of the present invention may be manufactured in a manner that is known in the art, e.g., by means of conventional mixing, dissolving, granulating, dragee-making, levigating, emulsifying, encapsulating, entrapping, or lyophilizing processes. The pharmaceutical composition may be provided as a salt and can be formed with many acids, including but not limited to, hydrochloric, sulfuric, acetic, lactic, tartaric, malic, succinic, etc. Salts tend to be more soluble in aqueous or other protonic solvents than are the corresponding free base forms. In other cases, the preferred preparation may be a lyophilized powder which may contain any or all of the following: 1-50 mM histidine, 0.1%-2% sucrose, and 2-7% mannitol, at a pH range of 4.5 to 5.5, that is combined with buffer prior to use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> After pharmaceutical compositions have been prepared, they can be placed in an appropriate container and labeled for treatment of an indicated condition. Such labeling would include amount, frequency, and method of administration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> The determination of a therapeutically effective dose is well within the capability of those skilled in the art. A therapeutically effective dose refers to that amount of active ingredient which increases or decreases cell proliferation relative to cell proliferation which occurs in the absence of the therapeutically effective dose. Cell proliferation can be measured, inter alia, by counting dividing cells microscopically or by measuring the incorporation of <highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>H-thymidine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> For any compound, the therapeutically effective dose can be estimated initially either in cell culture assays or in animal models, usually mice, rabbits, dogs, or pigs. The animal model may also be used to determine the appropriate concentration range and route of administration. Such information can then be used to determine useful doses and routes for administration in humans. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> Therapeutic efficacy and toxicity may be determined by standard pharmaceutical procedures in cell cultures or experimental animals, e.g., ED<highlight><subscript>50 </subscript></highlight>(the dose therapeutically effective in 50% of the population) and LD<highlight><subscript>50 </subscript></highlight>(the dose lethal to 50% of the population). The dose ratio of toxic to therapeutic effects is the therapeutic index, and it can be expressed as the ratio, LD<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>/ED<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> Pharmaceutical compositions which exhibit large therapeutic indices are preferred. The data obtained from cell culture assays and animal studies is used in formulating a range of dosage for human use. The dosage contained in such compositions is preferably within a range of circulating concentrations that include the ED<highlight><subscript>50 </subscript></highlight>with little or no toxicity. The dosage varies within this range depending upon the dosage form employed, sensitivity of the patient, and the route of administration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> The exact dosage will be determined by the practitioner, in light of factors related to the subject that requires treatment. Dosage and administration are adjusted to provide sufficient levels of the active moiety or to maintain the desired effect. Factors which may be taken into account include the severity of the disease state, general health of the subject, age, weight, and gender of the subject, diet, time and frequency of administration, drug combination(s), reaction sensitivities, and tolerance/response to therapy. Long-acting pharmaceutical compositions may be administered every 3 to 4 days, every week, or once every two weeks depending on half-life and clearance rate of the particular formulation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> Normal dosage amounts may vary from 0.1 to 100,000 micrograms, up to a total dose of about 1 g, depending upon the route of administration. Guidance as to particular dosages and methods of delivery is provided in the literature and generally available to practitioners in the art. Those skilled in the art will employ different formulations for nucleotides than for proteins or their inhibitors. Similarly, delivery of polynucleotides or polypeptides will be specific to particular cells, conditions, locations, etc. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Therapeutic Indications and Methods </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> This invention further pertains to the use of novel agents identified by the screening assays described above. Accordingly, it is within the scope of this invention to use a test compound identified as described herein in an appropriate animal model. For example, an agent identified as described herein (e.g., a modulating agent, an antisense nucleic acid molecule, a specific antibody, ribozyme, or a protein-binding partner) can be used in an animal model to determine the efficacy, toxicity, or side effects of treatment with such an agent. Alternatively, an agent identified as described herein can be used in an animal model to determine the mechanism of action of such an agent. Furthermore, this invention pertains to uses of novel agents identified by the above-described screening assays for treatments as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> The human mitochondrial deformylase gene provides a therapeutic target for decreasing cell proliferation, in particular for treating cancer or other diseases involving increased levels of cell proliferation. Cancers which can be treated according to the invention include adenocarcinoma, leukemia, lymphoma, melanoma, myeloma, sarcoma, and teratocarcinoma, cancers of the adrenal gland, bladder, bone, bone marrow, brain, breast, cervix, gall bladder, ganglia, gastrointestinal tract, heart, kidney, liver, lung, muscle, ovary, pancreas, parathyroid, penis, prostate, salivary glands, skin, spleen, testis, thymus, thyroid, and uterus. Other proliferative disorders, such as anhydric hereditary ectodermal dysplasia, congenital alveolar dysplasia, epithelial dysplasia of the cervix, fibrous dysplasia of bone, mammary dysplasia, and hyperplasias, for example, endometrial, adrenal, breast, prostate, or thyroid hyperplasias, or pseudoepitheliomatous hyperplasia of the skin, also can be treated with compositions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> The mitochondrial deformylase is of critical importance to both central and peripheral nervous system and is therefore a promising new target for the treatment of nervous system disease, for example in primary and secondary disorders after brain injury, disorders of mood, anxiety disorders, disorders of thought and volition, disorders of sleep and wakefulness, diseases of the motor unit like neurogenic and myopathic disorders, neurodegenerative disorders like Alzheimer&apos;s and Parkinson&apos;s disease, disorders leading to peripheral and chronic pain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> A reagent which affects mitochondrial deformylase activity can be administered to a human cell, either in vitro or in vivo, to reduce mitochondrial deformylase activity. The reagent preferably binds to an expression product of a human mitochondrial deformylase gene. If the expression product is a protein, the reagent is preferably a small molecule or an antibody. For treatment of human cells ex vivo an antibody can be added to a preparation of stem cells which have been removed from the body. The cells can then be replaced in the same or another human body, with or without clonal propagation, as is known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the reagent is delivered using a liposome. Preferably, the liposome is stable in the animal into which it has been administered for at least about 30 minutes, more preferably for at least about 1 hour and even more preferably for at least about 24 hours. A liposome comprises a lipid composition that is capable of targeting a reagent, particularly a polynucleotide, to a particular site in an animal, such as a human. Preferably, the lipid composition of the liposome is capable of targeting to any organ of an animal, such as the lung, liver, spleen, heart brain, lymph nodes, and skin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> A liposome useful in the present invention comprises a lipid composition that is capable of fusing with the plasma membrane of the targeted cell to deliver its contents to the cell. Preferably, the transfection efficiency of a liposome is about 0.5 mg of DNA per 16 nmole of liposome delivered to about 10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>cells, more preferably about 1.0 mg of DNA per 16 nmol of liposome delivered to about 10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>cells, and even more preferably about 2.0 mg of DNA per 16 nmol of liposome delivered to about 10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>cells. Preferably, a liposome is between about 100 and 500 nm, more preferably between about 150 and 450 nm and even more preferably between about 200 and 400 nm in diameter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> Suitable liposomes for use in the present invention include those liposomes standardly used in, for example, gene delivery methods known to those of skill in the art. More preferred liposomes comprise liposomes having a polycationic lipid composition and/or liposomes having a cholesterol backbone conjugated to polyethylene glycol. Optionally, a liposome comprises a compound capable of targeting the liposome to a tumor cell. Such a liposome preferably includes a tumor cell ligand exposed on the outer surface of the liposome. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> Complexing a liposome with a polynucleotide, such as an antisense oligonucleotide or ribozyme, can be achieved using methods which are standard in the art (see, for example, U.S. Pat. No. 5,705,151). Preferably, from about 0.1 mg to about 10 mg of polynucleotide is combined with about 8 nmol of liposomes, more preferably from about 0.5 mg to about 5 mg of polynucleotides are combined with about 8 nmol liposomes, and even more preferably about 1.0 mg of polynucleotides is combined with about 8 nmol liposomes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, antibodies can be delivered to specific tissues in vivo using receptor-mediated targeted delivery. Receptor-mediated DNA delivery techniques are taught in, for example, Findeis et al. <highlight><italic>Trends in Biotechnol. </italic></highlight>11, 202-05, (1993); Chiou et al., GENE THERAPEUTICS: METHODS AND APPLICATIONS OF DIRECT GENE TRANSFER (J. A. Wolff, ed.) (1994); Wu &amp; Wu, <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>263, 621-24, 1988; Wu et al., <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>269, 542-46, 1994; Zenke et al., <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. </italic></highlight>87, 3655-59, 1990; Wu et al., <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>266, 338-42, 1991. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> If single-chain antibodies are used, polynucleotides encoding the antibodies can be constructed and introduced into cells either ex vivo or in vivo using well-established techniques including, but not limited to, transferrin-polycation-mediated DNA transfer, transfection with naked or encapsulated nucleic acids, liposome-mediated cellular fusion, intracellular transportation of DNA-coated latex beads, protoplast fusion, viral infection, electroporation, ,,gene gun,&rdquo; and DEAE- or calcium phosphate-mediated transfection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> Effective in vivo dosages of an antibody are in the range of about 5 mg to about 50 mg/kg, about 50 mg to about 5 mg/kg, about 100 mg to about 500 mg/kg of patient body weight, and about 200 to about 250 mg/kg of patient body weight. For administration of polynucleotides encoding single-chain antibodies, effective in vivo dosages are in the range of about 100 ng to about 200 ng, 500 ng to about 50 mg, about 1 mg to about 2 mg, about 5 mg to about 500 mg, and about 20 mg to about 100 mg of DNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> If the expression product is mRNA, the reagent is preferably an antisense oligonucleotide or a ribozyme. Polynucleotides which express antisense oligonucleotides or ribozymes can be introduced into cells by a variety of methods, as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> Preferably, a reagent reduces expression of a mitochondrial deformylase gene or the activity of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide by at least about 10, preferably about 50, more preferably about 75, 90, or 100% relative to the absence of the reagent. The effectiveness of the mechanism chosen to decrease the level of expression of a mitochondrial deformylase gene or the activity of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide can be assessed using methods well known in the art, such as hybridization of nucleotide probes to mitochondrial deformylase-specific mRNA, quantitative RT-PCR, immunologic detection of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, or measurement of mitochondrial deformylase activity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> Disorders characterized by lowered cell proliferation or a loss of specific cell types, such as Alzheimer&apos;s Disease, AIDS, muscular dystrophy, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, or other muscle wasting diseases, autoimmune diseases, or a disease in which the cell is infected with a pathogen, such as a virus, bacterium, fungus, mycoplasm, or protozoan, can be treated with an agonist or activator of mitochondrial deformylase, to increase cell proliferation. Introduction of a mitochondrial deformylase polynucleotide which expresses a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide, e.g. by gene therapy, also can be used to increase cell proliferation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> In any of the embodiments described above, any of the pharmaceutical compositions of the invention can be administered in combination with other appropriate therapeutic agents. Selection of the appropriate agents for use in combination therapy may be made by one of ordinary skill in the art, according to conventional pharmaceutical principles. The combination of therapeutic agents may act synergistically to effect the treatment or prevention of the various disorders described above. Using this approach, one may be able to achieve therapeutic efficacy with lower dosages of each agent, thus reducing the potential for adverse side effects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> Any of the therapeutic methods described above may be applied to any subject in need of such therapy, including, for example, birds and mammals such as dogs, cats, cows, pigs, sheep, goats, horses, rabbits, monkeys, and most preferably, humans. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> All documents cited in this disclosure are expressly incorporated herein. The above disclosure generally describes the present invention, and all references cited in this disclosure are incorporated by reference herein. A more complete understanding can be obtained by reference to the following specific examples which are provided for purposes of illustration only and are not intended to limit the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Recombinant Expression of a DNA Sequence Encoding a Mitochondrial Deformylase Polypeptide in Yeast Cells (<highlight><italic>Pichia pastoris</italic></highlight>) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> To produce large quantities of a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides in yeast, the <highlight><italic>Pichia pastoris </italic></highlight>expression vector pPICZB (Invitrogen, San Diego, Calif.) is used. The mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide encoding DNA sequence is derived from the nucleotide sequence (SEQ ID NO:5) encoding the amino acid sequence (SEQ ID NO:6). Before insertion into vector pPICZB the DNA sequence is modified by well known methods in such a way that it contains at its 5&prime;-end an initiation codon and at its 3&prime;-end an enterokinase cleavage site, a His6 reporter tag and a termination codon. Moreover, at both termini recognition sequences for restriction endonucleases are added and after digestion of the multiple cloning site of pPICZ B with the corresponding restriciton enzymes the modified mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide encoding DNA sequence is ligated into pPICZB. This expression vector is designed for inducible expression in <highlight><italic>Pichia pastoris</italic></highlight>, expression is driven by a yeast promoter. The resulting pPICZ/md-His6 vector is used to transform the yeast. The yeast is cultivated under usual conditions in 5 1 shake flasks and the recombinantly produced protein isolated from the culture by affinity chromatography (Ni-NTA-Resin) in the presence of 8 M urea. The bound polypeptide is eluted with buffer, pH 3,5, and neutralized. Separation of the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide from the His6 reporter tag is accomplished by site-specific proteolysis using enterokinase (Invitrogen, San Diego, Calif.) according to manufacturer&apos;s instructions. Purified mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is obtained. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 2 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Determination of the Deformylase Activity of the Mitochondrial Deformylase Polypeptide Prepared According to Example 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> In this assay the dipeptide substrate, N-formyl-methionylleucyl-p-nitroaniline (f-ML-pNA) is first deformylated by the deformylase to give the corresponding dipeptide with a free amino terminus, which is a substrate for an aminopeptidase from <highlight><italic>Aeromonas proteolytica </italic></highlight>(Sigma Chemical Company). Sequential action by the aminopeptidase releases p-nitroaniline, a chromophore which can be detected spectrophotometrically. The dipeptide substrate is prepared as described in Wei and Pei 250, (1997), Anal. Biochem., 29-34. Assays are carried out at 23&deg; C. in polystyrene cuvettes which contain 50 mM potassium phosphate, pH 7.0, 100 &mgr;M EGTA, 0 to 200 &mgr;M dipeptide substrate and 0.8 unit Aeromonas aminopeptidase. Reactions are initiated by addition of 10 to 100 &mgr;l (0.1 to 100 &mgr;g) of the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide prepared according to Example 1, diluted in 50 mM HEPES, pH 7.0, containing 100 &mgr;g/ml BSA. Reactions are monitored continuously at 405 nm in a Perkin-Elmer &lgr;3 UV/VIS spectrophotometer, and the initial rates are calculated from the early part of the reaction progression curves (&lt;60s). Reactions at the lowest and highest dipeptide substrate concentration are generally repeated with doubled amount of the aminopeptidase (1.6 U) to insure that the deformylase reaction is rate-limiting in the coupled reaction sequence. The results obtained indicate that the mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide prepared according to Example 1 has deformylase activity. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 3 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Proliferation Inhibition Assay: Antisense Oligonucleotides Suppress the Growth of Cancer Cell Lines </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> The Cell line used for testing is the human colon cancer cell line HCT 116. Cells are cultured in RPMI-1640 with 10-15% fetal calf serum at a concentration of 10,000 cells per milliliter in a volume of 0.5 ml and kept at 37&deg; C. in a 95% air/5% CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>atmosphere. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> Phosphorothioate oligoribonucleotides are synthesized on an Applied Biosystems Model 380B DNA synthesizer using phosphoramidite chemistry. Two sequences of 24 bases are used: (1) 5&prime;-CAG CGA TTT AAA TAC GGA ACA AGG-3&prime; (complementary to the nucleotides at position 1 to 24 of SEQ ID NO:1) and (2) 5&prime;-AAA ATG CAG GTA AGC ATG TGA AAA-3&prime; (complementary to the nucleotides at position 1 to 24 of SEQ ID NO:3), as a control another (random) sequence (3) 5&prime;-TCA ACT GAC TAG ATG TAC ATG GAC-3&prime; is used. Following assembly and deprotection, oligonucleotides are ethanol-precipitated twice, dried, and suspended in phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) at the desired concentration. Purity of these oligonucleotides is tested by capillary gel electrophoresis and ion exchange HPLC. The purified oligonucleotides are added to the culture medium at a concentration of 10 micromolar once per day for seven days. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> The addition of oligonucleotides (1) and (2) for seven days results in significantly reduced expression of the mitochondrial deformylase as determined by Western blotting. This effect is not observed with oligonucleotide (3). After 3 to 7 days, the number of cells is counted using an automatic cell counter. The number of cells in cultures treated with oligonucleotide (3) (expressed at 100%) is compared with the number of cells in cultures treated with oligonucleotides (1) and (2), respectively. The number of cells in cultures treated with oligonucleotides (1) and (2) is not more than 30% of control, indicating that the inhibition of human mitochondrial deformylase has an anti-proliferative effect on cancer cells. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 4 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Proliferation Activation Assay: Cell Lines Transfected with the Mitochondrial Deformylase Gene Increase Growing Rates </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> Standard cell lines suitable for transfection and protein expression as known in the art are cultured under appropriate conditions as described by the suppliers of cell lines, e.g. the ATCC. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> Cells are transfected with expression constructs for the mitochondrial deformylase gene as known in the art. The expression of the protein is induced as known in the art. After 3 to 7 days, the number of cells is counted using an automatic cell counter. The number of cells in cultures with transfected cells is compared with the number of cells in cultures with untransfected cells. The number of cells in cultures which are transfected with the mitochondrial deformylase is more than 30% of control, indicating that the augmentation of human mitochondrial deformylase activity has a proliferative effect on cells. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 5 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Identification of a Test Compound which Binds to a Mitochondrial Deformylase Polypeptide </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> Purified mitochondrial deformylase polypeptides comprising a glutathione-S-transferase protein and absorbed onto glutathione-derivatized wells of 96-well microtiter plates are contacted with test compounds from a small molecule library at pH 7.0 in a physiological buffer solution. The mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide comprises an amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NO:2, 4 or 6. The test compounds comprise a fluorescent tag. The samples are incubated for 5 minutes to one hour. Control samples are incubated in the absence of a test compound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> The buffer solution containing the test compounds is washed from the wells. Binding of a test compound to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide is detected by fluorescence measurements of the contents of the wells. A test compound which increases the fluorescence in a well by at least 15% relative to fluorescence of a well in which a test compound was not incubated is identified as a compound which binds to a mitochondrial deformylase polypeptide. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 6 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Identification of a Test Compound which Decreases Mitochondrial Deformylase Activity </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> Extracts from the human colon cancer cell line HCT116 are contacted with test compounds from a small molecule library in 50 ml of 50 mM HEPES, pH 7.0, and 0.5 M KCl and assayed for mitochondrial deformylase activity as described in Adams (1968), as modified by Meinnel &amp; Blanquet, 1995. Control extracts, in the absence of a test compound, also are assayed. Mitochondrial deformylase activity of the extracts is measured in the presence of 4 mM substrate (Fo-Met-Ala-Ser; Sigma). After incubation at for 5 minutes to 1 hour at 37&deg; C. in 50 mM HEPES (N-2-hydroxyethylpiperazine-N&prime;-2-ethanesulfonic acid sodium salt)-HCl, pH 7.0, and 0.5 M KCl for five minutes, the reaction is stopped with 500 ml of trichlorocetic acid. The samples are centrifuged briefly to remove protein, and 500 ml of supernatant is removed and added to 500 ml of 0.2 M KOH and 0.25 M potassium acetate buffer, pH 5.2 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> A ninhydrin assay according to Moore &amp; Stein, <highlight><italic>J. Biol. Chem. </italic></highlight>211, 907 (1954) is then performed. The color which develops is measured at 350 mm. A test compound which decreases mitochondrial deformylase activity of the extract relative to the control extract by at least 20% is identified as a mitochondrial deformylase inhibitor. Alternatively, determination of deformylase activity is carried out as described in Example 2, above. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 7 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Identification of a Test Compound which Decreases Mitochondrial Deformylase Gene Expression </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> A test compound is administered to a culture of the breast tumor cell line MDA-468 and incubated at 37&deg; C. for 10 to 45 minutes. A culture of the same type of cells incubated for the same time without the test compound provides a negative control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> RNA is isolated from the two cultures as described in Chirgwin et al., <highlight><italic>Biochem. </italic></highlight>18, 5294-99, 1979). Northern blots are prepared using 20 to 30 &mgr;g total RNA and hybridized with a <highlight><superscript>32</superscript></highlight>P-labeled mitochondrial deformylase-specific probe at 65&deg; C. in Express-hyb (ClonTech). The probe comprises at least 11 contiguous nucleotides selected from SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5. A test compound which decreases the mitochondrial deformylase-specific signal relative to the signal obtained in the absence of the test compound is identified as an inhibitor of mitochondrial deformylase gene expression. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 8 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> Treatment of a Breast Tumor with a Reagent which Specifically Binds to a Mitochondrial Deformylase Gene Product </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> Synthesis of antisense mitochondrial deformylase oligonucleotides comprising at least 11 contiguous nucleotide selected from SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5 is performed on a Pharmacia Gene Assembler series synthesizer using the phosphoramidite procedure (Uhlmann et al., <highlight><italic>Chem. Rev. </italic></highlight>90, 534-83, 1990). Following assembly and deprotection, oligonucleotides are ethanol-precipitated twice, dried, and suspended in phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) at the desired concentration. Purity of these oligonucleotides is tested by capillary gel electrophoreses and ion exchange HPLC. Endotoxin levels in the oligonucleotide preparation are determined using the Luminous Amebocyte Assay (Bang, <highlight><italic>Biol. Bull</italic></highlight>. (Woods Hole, Mass.) 105, 361-362, 1953). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> The antisense oligonucleotides are injected directly into the breast tumor in an aqueous medium (an aqueous composition) at a concentration of 0.1-100 mM with a needle. The needle is placed in the tumors and withdrawn while expressing the aqueous composition within the tumor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> The size of the breast tumor is monitored over a period of days or weeks. Additional injections of the antisense oligonucleotides may be given during that time. The size of the breast tumor gradually decreases due to decreased proliferation of the breast tumor cells. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<sequence-cwu id="SEQLST-1">
<number>1</number>
<sequence-list-new-rules>
<s100>
<s160>10 </s160>
</s100>
<s200>
<s210>1 </s210>
<s211>488 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Homo sapiens </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 1 
ccttgttccg tatttaaatc gctgtctcca agtccttttt ccaccagctc agatagcaca     60 
gactttaggc attcctccca ctcagctctc caagtacggt aacctagggc atgtgaacat    120 
cggcgccatt caggagcccc tcgcctttat cctgccaaag agagagacgc ttttcaccct    180 
ggatgaccag gcgctggggc ccgagctcac agctccagca ccagagcctc ccgccgagga    240 
gccacgcctg gagcccgcgg gcccagcctg cccggaggga gggcgagcgg agacgcaggc    300 
cgaaccgccc agcgtggggc cctagccggc gtcccctgcc tccagaacgc gggctggacc    360 
ccaatggaga acaggtggtg tggcaggcga gcgggtgggc agcccgcatc atccagcacg    420 
agatggacca cctgcagggc tgcctgttta ttgacaaaat ggacagcagg acgttcacaa    480 
acgtctat                                                             488 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>2 </s210>
<s211>163 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>Homo sapiens </s213>
<s220>
<s221>VARIANT </s221>
<s222>(1)...(163) </s222>
<s223>Xaa &equals; Any Amino Acid </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 2 
Leu Phe Arg Ile Xaa Ile Ala Val Ser Lys Ser Phe Phe His Gln Leu 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Arg Xaa His Arg Leu Xaa Ala Phe Leu Pro Leu Ser Ser Pro Ser Thr 
            20                  25                  30 
Val Thr Xaa Gly Met Xaa Thr Ser Ala Pro Phe Arg Ser Pro Ser Pro 
        35                  40                  45 
Leu Ser Cys Gln Arg Glu Arg Arg Phe Ser Pro Trp Met Met Thr Arg 
    50                  55                  60 
Arg Trp Gly Pro Ser Ser Gln Leu Gln His Gln Ser Leu Pro Pro Arg 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Ser His Ala Trp Ser Pro Arg Ala Gln Pro Ala Arg Arg Glu Gly Glu 
                85                  90                  95 
Arg Arg Arg Arg Pro Asn Arg Pro Ala Trp Gly Pro Ser Arg Arg Pro 
            100                 105                 110 
Leu Pro Pro Glu Arg Gly Leu Asp Pro Asn Gly Glu Gln Val Val Trp 
        115                 120                 125 
Gln Ala Ser Gly Trp Ala Ala Arg Ile Ile Gln His Glu Met Asp His 
    130                 135                 140 
Leu Gln Gly Cys Leu Phe Ile Asp Lys Met Asp Ser Arg Thr Phe Thr 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Asn Val Tyr 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>3 </s210>
<s211>630 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Homo sapiens </s213>
<s220>
<s221>misc_feature </s221>
<s222>(1)...(630) </s222>
<s223>n &equals; A,T,C or G </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 3 
ttttcacatg cttacctgca tttttaaaga cagctttcag gtatttgggg actacattat     60 
taccaaacct tggctttggg agattataca ggtccgagga actcgtgtct actgcagacg    120 
aatgcaatta ccccaccttc ctccatacag aattgttagg aaatgtccac tcctttgggg    180 
gtgatttttc tcctcaagtt gtagccaaca ttttgtccgt aactgatttc agggcaaaca    240 
tttctgacat cttcctccag ctcagtctgc catgccttgg caatccagtt tcctgtcata    300 
tgcgagccat ccaagttgat gccaagtaag atttgcccag ctcaaagtga aagtgtttgc    360 
gtcttggtat ccggaatcct cagccccagt agcaaagctt tagtcattca ccttcatcca    420 
atagacgttt gtgaacgtcc tgctgtccat tttgtcaata aacaggcagc cctgcaggtg    480 
gtccatctcg tgctggatga tgcgggctgc ccacccgctc gcctgccaca ccacctgttc    540 
tccattgggg tccagccctg agatctgcac cgnctggaag cggggcacgc angccangaa    600 
agccgcgacg ctctcgcagc cctcgggaaa                                     630 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>4 </s210>
<s211>210 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>Homo sapiens </s213>
<s220>
<s221>VARIANT </s221>
<s222>(1)...(210) </s222>
<s223>Xaa &equals; Any Amino Acid </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 4 
Phe Pro Glu Gly Cys Glu Ser Val Ala Ala Phe Xaa Ala Cys Val Pro 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Arg Phe Gln Xaa Val Gln Ile Ser Gly Leu Asp Pro Asn Gly Glu Gln 
            20                  25                  30 
Val Val Trp Gln Ala Ser Gly Trp Ala Ala Arg Ile Ile Gln His Glu 
        35                  40                  45 
Met Asp His Leu Gln Gly Cys Leu Phe Ile Asp Lys Met Asp Ser Arg 
    50                  55                  60 
Thr Phe Thr Asn Val Tyr Trp Met Lys Val Asn Asp Xaa Ser Phe Ala 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Thr Gly Ala Glu Asp Ser Gly Tyr Gln Asp Ala Asn Thr Phe Thr Leu 
                85                  90                  95 
Ser Trp Ala Asn Leu Thr Trp His Gln Leu Gly Trp Leu Ala Tyr Asp 
            100                 105                 110 
Arg Lys Leu Asp Cys Gln Gly Met Ala Asp Xaa Ala Gly Gly Arg Cys 
        115                 120                 125 
Gln Lys Cys Leu Pro Xaa Asn Gln Leu Arg Thr Lys Cys Trp Leu Gln 
    130                 135                 140 
Leu Glu Glu Lys Asn His Pro Gln Arg Ser Gly His Phe Leu Thr Ile 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Leu Tyr Gly Gly Arg Trp Gly Asn Cys Ile Arg Leu Gln Xaa Thr Arg 
                165                 170                 175 
Val Pro Arg Thr Cys Ile Ile Ser Gln Ser Gln Gly Leu Val Ile Met 
            180                 185                 190 
Xaa Ser Pro Asn Thr Xaa Lys Leu Ser Leu Lys Met Gln Val Ser Met 
        195                 200                 205 
Xaa Lys 
    210 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>5 </s210>
<s211>732 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Homo sapiens </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 5 
atggcccggc tgtggggcgc gctgagtctt tggccactgt gggcggccgt gccgtggggc     60 
ggggcggcag ccgtcggtgt ccgggcttgc agctccacgg ccgccccgga cggcgtcgag    120 
ggcccggcgc tgcggcgctc ctattggcgc cacctgaggc gtctggtgct gggtcctccc    180 
gaaccgccgt tctcgcacgt gtgccaagtc ggggacccgg tgctgcgcgg cgtggcggcc    240 
ccggtggagc gggcgcagct aggcgggccc gagctgcagc ggctgacgca acggctggtc    300 
caggtgatgc ggcggcggcg ctgcgtgggc ctaagcgcgc cgcagctggg ggtgccgcgg    360 
caggtgctgg cgctggagct ccccgaggcg ctgtgtcggg agtgcccgcc ccgccagcgc    420 
gcgctccggc aaatggagcc cttccccctg cgcgtgttcg tgaaccccag cctgcgagtg    480 
cttgacagcc gcctggtcac ctttcccgag ggctgcgaga gcgtcgccgg cttcctggcc    540 
tgcgtgcccc gcttccaggc ggtgcagatc tcagggctgg accccaatgg agaacaggtg    600 
gtgtggcagg cgagcgggtg ggcagcccgc atcatccagc acgagatgga ccacctgcag    660 
ggctgcctgt ttattgacaa aatggacagc aggacgttca caaacgtcta ttggatgaag    720 
gtgaatgact aa                                                        732 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>6 </s210>
<s211>243 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>Homo sapiens </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 6 
Met Ala Arg Leu Trp Gly Ala Leu Ser Leu Trp Pro Leu Trp Ala Ala 
 1               5                  10                  15 
Val Pro Trp Gly Gly Ala Ala Ala Val Gly Val Arg Ala Cys Ser Ser 
            20                  25                  30 
Thr Ala Ala Pro Asp Gly Val Glu Gly Pro Ala Leu Arg Arg Ser Tyr 
        35                  40                  45 
Trp Arg His Leu Arg Arg Leu Val Leu Gly Pro Pro Glu Pro Pro Phe 
    50                  55                  60 
Ser His Val Cys Gln Val Gly Asp Pro Val Leu Arg Gly Val Ala Ala 
65                  70                  75                  80 
Pro Val Glu Arg Ala Gln Leu Gly Gly Pro Glu Leu Gln Arg Leu Thr 
                85                  90                  95 
Gln Arg Leu Val Gln Val Met Arg Arg Arg Arg Cys Val Gly Leu Ser 
            100                 105                 110 
Ala Pro Gln Leu Gly Val Pro Arg Gln Val Leu Ala Leu Glu Leu Pro 
        115                 120                 125 
Glu Ala Leu Cys Arg Glu Cys Pro Pro Arg Gln Arg Ala Leu Arg Gln 
    130                 135                 140 
Met Glu Pro Phe Pro Leu Arg Val Phe Val Asn Pro Ser Leu Arg Val 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Leu Asp Ser Arg Leu Val Thr Phe Pro Glu Gly Cys Glu Ser Val Ala 
                165                 170                 175 
Gly Phe Leu Ala Cys Val Pro Arg Phe Gln Ala Val Gln Ile Ser Gly 
            180                 185                 190 
Leu Asp Pro Asn Gly Glu Gln Val Val Trp Gln Ala Ser Gly Trp Ala 
        195                 200                 205 
Ala Arg Ile Ile Gln His Glu Met Asp His Leu Gln Gly Cys Leu Phe 
    210                 215                 220 
Ile Asp Lys Met Asp Ser Arg Thr Phe Thr Asn Val Tyr Trp Met Lys 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Val Asn Asp 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>7 </s210>
<s211>5 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>Artificial Sequence </s213>
<s220>
<s223>zinc-dependent metalloprotease motif </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 7 
His Glu Xaa Xaa His 
 1               5 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>8 </s210>
<s211>24 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Homo sapiens </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 8 
cagcgattta aatacggaac aagg                                            24 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>9 </s210>
<s211>24 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Homo sapiens </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 9 
aaaatgcagg taagcatgtg aaaa                                            24 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>10 </s210>
<s211>24 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Artificial Sequence </s213>
<s220>
<s223>random oligonucleotide </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 10 
tcaactgact agatgtacat ggac                                            24
</s400>
</sequence-list-new-rules>
</sequence-cwu>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A substantially purified human mitochondrial deformylase 
<claim-text>a) consisting essentially of the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID NO:6 and fragments thereof; or </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) of an amino acid sequence wherein a substitution, deletion, addition or transpostion of one to several amino acid residue(s) is made in SEQ ID NO:6. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An isolated and purified polynucleotide encoding the mitochondrial deformylase of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, a degenerate variant thereof, or a nucleotide sequence which is complementary thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An isolated and purified polynucleotide consisting essentially of the sequence of SEQ ID NO:5, a conservative substitution variant thereof, active fragments, or functional equivalents thereof, or a nucleotide sequence which is complementary thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An isolated and purified cDNA or RNA comprising of the sequence of SEQ ID NO:5, a conservative substitution variant thereof, active fragments, or functional equivalents thereof, or a nucleotide sequence which is complementary thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A polynucleotide which hybridizes under stringent conditions to the polynucleotide sequence of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A hybridization probe comprising at least 10 contiguous nucleotides selected from SEQ ID NO:2. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An expression vector containing the polynucleotide sequence of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A host cell containing the expression vector of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method for producing a polypeptide comprising SEQ ID NO:6, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>a) culturing the host cell of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> under conditions suitable for the expression of the polypeptide; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) recovering the polypeptide from the host cell culture. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method for detection of polynucleotides in a biological sample comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>a) hybrizing a polynucleotide consisting of SEQ ID NO:1, SEQ ID NO:3 or SEQ ID:5 or a complement of any of them to nucleic acid material of a biological sample, thereby forming a hybridization complex; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) detecting said hybridization complex; wherein the presence of said complex correlates with the presence of the polynucleotide consiting of SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 and 5 in said biological sample. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein before hybridization, the nucleic acid material of the biological sample is amplified. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method for the detection of an expression product of the polynucleotide of SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5 comprising the steps of 
<claim-text>contacting a biological sample with a reagent which specifically interacts with the expression product and </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting the interaction. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The expression product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> being a polynucleotide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The expression product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> being a peptide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A diagnostic kit comprising the reagents of one of the claims <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method of screening for agents which can regulate the activity of human mitochondrial deformylase, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>contacting a test compound with a polypeptide comprising an amino acid sequence which is at least about 52% identical to the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID NOS:2; 4 or 6 and </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting binding of the test compound to the polypeptide, wherein a test compound which binds to the polypeptide is identified as a potential therapeutic agent for regulating the activity of human mitochondrial deformylase. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of contacting is in a cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cell is in vitro. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of contacting is in a cell-free system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the polypeptide comprises a detectable label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the test compound comprises a detectable label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the test compound displaces a labeled ligand which is bound to the polypeptide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the polypeptide is bound to a solid support. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the test compound is bound to a solid support. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A method of screening for agents which regulate an activity of human mitochondrial deformylase, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>contacting a test compound with a polypeptide comprising an amino acid sequence which is at least about 52% identical to the amino acid sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:2, 4 or 6; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a mitochondrial deformylase activity of the polypeptide, wherein a test compound which increases the mitochondrial deformylase activity is identified as a potential therapeutic agent for increasing the activity of the human mitochondrial deformylase, and wherein a test compound which decreases the mitochondrial deformylase activity of the polypeptide is identified as a potential therapeutic agent for decreasing the activity of the human mitochondrial deformylase. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of contacting is in a cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cell is in vitro. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of contacting is in a cell-free system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method of screening for agents which regulate an activity of human mitochondrial deformylase, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>contacting a test compound with a product encoded by a polynucleotide which comprises a nucleotide sequence which is at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5 or complements theretof; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting binding of the test compound to the product, wherein a test compound which binds to the product is identified as a potential therapeutic agent for regulating the activity of human mitochondrial deformylase. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the product is a polypeptide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the product is RNA. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A method of reducing activity of human mitochondrial deformylase, comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>contacting a cell with a reagent which specifically binds to a product encoded by a polynucleotide comprising a nucleotide sequence which is at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5, whereby the activity of human mitochondrial deformylase is reduced. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the product is a polypeptide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reagent is an antibody. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the product is RNA. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reagent is an antisense oligonucleotide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reagent is a ribozyme. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cell is in vitro. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cell is in vivo. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A purified reagent that specifically binds to and modulates activity of the polypeptide of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reagent is identified by the method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A pharmaceutical composition, comprising: 
<claim-text>a reagent which specifically binds to a product encoded by a polynucleotide comprising a nucleotide sequence which is at least about 50% identical to the nucleotide sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:1, 3 or 5, wherein said reagent is identified by the method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The pharmaceutical composition of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reagent is an antibody. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The pharmaceutical composition of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reagent is an antisense oligonucleotide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The pharmaceutical composition of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reagent is a ribozyme. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A pharmaceutical composition, comprising: 
<claim-text>an expression construct encoding a polypeptide comprising the amino acid sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:2, 4 or 6; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A method for treating neoplastic disease comprising administering to a subject in need of such treatment an effective amount of the reagent of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. A preparation of antibodies which specifically binds to a polypeptide consisting essentially of the amino acid sequences shown in SEQ ID NOS:2, 4 or 6. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The preparation of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the antibodies are polyclonal. The preparation of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the antibodies are monoclonal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003488A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003488A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
