<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003708A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003708A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003708A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003708A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003708A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003708A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003708A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003708A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003708A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003708A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003708</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10227325</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020823</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/4763</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>622000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>637000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Creation of subresolution features via flow characteristics</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10227325</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020823</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09944483</doc-number>
<document-date>20010830</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6479378</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09944483</doc-number>
<document-date>20010830</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09333796</doc-number>
<document-date>19990615</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6365489</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Philip</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Ireland</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Nampa</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TRASK BRITT</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 2550</address-1>
<city>SALT LAKE CITY</city>
<state>UT</state>
<postalcode>84110</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An integrated circuit having at least one electrical interconnect for connecting at least two components and a process for forming the same are disclosed. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation of application Ser. No. 09/944,483, filed Aug. 30, 2001, pending, which is a continuation of application Ser. No. 09/333,796, filed Jun. 15, 1999, now U.S. Pat. No. 6,365,489, issued Apr. 2, 2002.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to the manufacture of silicon integrated circuits (ICs). More specifically, the present invention relates to integrated circuits utilizing an electrical interconnect system in multi-level conductor-type integrated circuits of high component density and the processes for making the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. State of the Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In recent years with increasing component density of very large scale integrated circuits, it has become necessary to develop multi-level conductor technologies to provide the required number of electrical interconnects between both active and passive devices fabricated on silicon substrates using state of the art planar processing. These multi-level conductor technologies are also alternatively referred to as multi-level metal (MLM) processing. But as used herein, multi-level conductor (MLC) processing is generic to either metal deposition, polycrystalline silicon deposition, or polysilicon deposition used in the formation of conductive interconnecting paths at different levels or planes formed on an integrated circuit substrate, such levels or planes containing previously formed active and passive devices located therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As generally understood in the art and as used herein, a &ldquo;level&rdquo; including a conductor or metallization is added atop a semiconductor substrate by growing or depositing an insulating layer, such as silicon dioxide or silicon nitride, over a previously formed underlayer of metal and forming an opening or &ldquo;via&rdquo; in this insulating layer for receiving a conductor or metallization to extend therethrough from another conductor or metallization subsequently formed as an upper layer deposited on the surface of the insulating layer. Thus, the mere addition of a single &ldquo;level&rdquo; of conductor over a previously formed conductive pattern will include the process steps of (1) the formation of an insulating layer, (2) the formation of a photoresist etch mask on the surface of the insulating layer, (3) the exposure of the etch mask to a selected etchant to create a via in the insulating layer, (4) the removal of the photoresist etch mask, and (5) deposition of an additional layer of metallization or polysilicon in order to provide an electrical interconnect through the previously formed via in the dielectric layer and conductor connected thereto located on the insulating layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A number of prior art electrical interconnect systems and processes for the formation thereof have been used in the integrated circuit art, but none such as the electrical interconnect systems of the present invention. For example, U.S. Pat. No. 5,001,079 discloses a method of manufacturing a semiconductor device by forming insulating side walls with voids below overhangs. This method illustrates insulating material layers of silicon oxide, silicon nitride or silicon oxynitride which are deposited by plasma enhanced chemical vapor deposition (CVD), a process known in the art, for the formation of overhanging portions thereof having voids thereinbetween. Such voids are subsequently etched to expose gently sloping portions for further insulation to be added therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,278,103 illustrates a method for the controlled formation of voids in doped glass dielectric films wherein the doped glass may include boron phosphorous silicate (BPSG) deposited in predetermined thicknesses. BPSG is used for its dielectric properties, its melting point, and for deposition by CVD processes. The controlled formation of voids in the BPSG is used to minimize the effect of parasitic capacitance between conductors located therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,166,101 illustrates another method for forming a BPSG layer on a semiconductor wafer using predetermined CVD deposition and plasma-assisted CVD deposition processes to form void-free BPSG layers over stepped surfaces of a semiconductor wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> As current semiconductor device performance requirements continue to increase component packing densities of the semiconductor device, this, in turn, increases the complexity and cost of multi-level conductor formation processes requiring further levels of conductors to multi-level conductor integrated circuits. This typically results in lower wafer processing yields, affects semiconductor device reliability, and increases production costs for such semiconductor devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> What is needed and not illustrated in the prior art described herein are multi-level conductor interconnections and processes for the manufacture thereof in integrated circuit semiconductor devices wherein the electrical interconnections and the density thereof is increased without the addition of another &ldquo;level&rdquo; of circuitry for conductors or metallization to the semiconductor device. This increased density of multi-level conductor interconnections without the addition of at least one additional &ldquo;level&rdquo; further requires the use of areas of the integrated circuit semiconductor device not presently used for electrical interconnection, requires the use of improved oxide formation and conductor formation processes for maximizing component packing density on each layer of the semiconductor device, and requires minimizing the number of individual process steps for manufacturing. The present invention described hereinafter is directed to such requirements while allowing for the substantially simultaneous formation of electrical interconnections. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the present invention, a semiconductor device comprises a substrate, a plurality of conductive strips located on said substrate extending along at least a portion of the length of the substrate, a layer of doped glass formed over the substrate and plurality of conductive strips, the layer of doped glass having an elongated passageway formed therein between the conductive strips, and a conductive material located in the elongated passageway located between the conductive strips forming at least one electrical interconnect through the layer of doped glass to electrically connect at least two components of the integrated circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the present invention, an integrated circuit semiconductor device having regions comprises a semiconductor substrate, a plurality of conductive strips, a layer of dielectric material covering portions of the semiconductor substrate and the conductive strips located thereon, the dielectric material including an elongated passageway located therein extending between adjacent conductive strips of the plurality of conductive strips, a conductive material located in the elongated passageway of the dielectric material, and at least one electrical interconnect formed between the two regions of the integrated circuit semiconductor device by a portion of the conductive material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention also includes a process for forming electrical interconnections in integrated circuit semiconductor devices by creating subresolution features between the circuitry thereof using doped glass. The process of the present invention includes forming adjacent conductive strips on a substrate surface, depositing a doped glass layer over at least a portion of the adjacent conductive strips and a portion of the surface of the substrate having a thickness proportional to the spacing of the adjacent conductive strips, flowing the doped glass layer around the conductive strips located on the surface of the substrate to form at least one elongated passageway coextensive with a portion of the length of the conductive strips, reflowing the deposited doped glass layer to smooth the doped glass layer and to position the at least one elongated passageway, forming at least one opening in the reflowed doped glass layer in the at least one elongated passageway, and filling the at least one elongated passageway formed in the reflowed doped glass layer with a conductive material through the at least one opening and along at least a portion of the length of the elongated passageway to produce at least one electrical interconnect between at least two regions of the integrated circuit.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>C are a series of abbreviated isometric views illustrating the formation of at least one elongated passageway which is formed and filled to create at least one electrical interconnect in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D are a series of abbreviated schematic cross-sectional views taken along an X-axis direction or plane of the embodiment in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>C showing the device&apos;s structure and fabrication process in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D are a series of abbreviated schematic cross-sectional views taken along a Y-axis direction or plane of the embodiment in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D showing the device&apos;s structure and fabrication process in accordance with the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a plan view of an embodiment of the present invention showing a typical interconnect scheme utilizing the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be better understood when the drawings are taken in conjunction with the detailed description of the invention hereinafter.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in sequence in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 4</cross-reference>, the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the present invention includes at least two regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> or at least two components further described hereinbelow. The integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the present invention is also provided in combination or as a system of inter-level electrical interconnections in other embodiments. The integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> comprises a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a plurality of adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> located on the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a layer of dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> covering at least portions of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> located in an elongated passageway <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, of the dielectric material, and at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. In other embodiments of the present invention, the plurality of adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> comprises either a plurality of adjacent conductive strips or at least two adjacent conductive strips. In other embodiments of the present invention, the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> comprises at least one elongated conductor formed of a suitable conductive material. Also, in other embodiments of the present invention, the layer of dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is at least one layer of doped glass as described hereinbelow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 3D</cross-reference>, is formed of suitable materials known in the art, such as silicon. The semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes an upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> upon which levels of conductive strips, circuitry, and components are constructed through known processes using lithographic techniques known in the art. The semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> supports the components hereinafter described being suitable for multi-level metal (MLM) processing or multi-level conductor (MLC) processing as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The plurality of adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, at least a pair of conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 4</cross-reference>, is disposed on and is operatively connected to the substrate surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Each adjacent conductive strip <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is constructed of either polysilicon conductors or other suitable materials known in the art. The conductive strips have a length <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> measured from one end <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to an opposite end (not shown). As is known in the art, the plurality of adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be formed by suitable chemical vapor deposition (CVD) processes (i.e. low pressure CVD), by sputtering, etc. Chemical vapor deposition is a well-known, preferred method of deposition providing coverage of exterior surfaces, inner surfaces, and contact openings that can be used to form insulative and conductive layers as will be further discussed below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> As shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 3D</cross-reference>, the layer of dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is deposited over the substrate upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and over and around the plurality of adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Additional layers of dielectric material (not shown) can also be deposited following the deposition and reflow of the layer shown in the figures. These processes are accomplished again by processes known in the art, such as CVD (i.e. low pressure, plasma-enhanced, etc.) as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The layer of dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> can be selected from the group of materials comprising borophosphosilicate glass (BPSG), borosilicate glass (BSG), phosphosilicate glass (PSG), silicon dioxide, and others known in the art. However, any desired suitable layer of material may be used as the dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment of the present invention, BPSG is used as the doped glass dielectric layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> as described below. BPSG provides an excellent dielectric material with a melting point made significantly lower than that of regular glass or other dielectric materials, allowing it to be used in a high temperature reflow process which melts and smooths the BPSG surface <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> without damaging other semiconductor components of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The dielectric layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> (i.e., BPSG layer) is deposited on the plurality of conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to a deposited thickness <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> sufficient to create at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1C through 3D</cross-reference>. It is critical that the deposited thickness <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> be proportional to a spacing <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> defined between at least two of the plurality of adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as is taught in U.S. Pat. No. 5,278,103 to Mallon et al., which is incorporated herein by reference, to illustrate the controlled formation of voids in BPSG layer and formation processes therefor. If the deposited thickness <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is not sufficiently thick to be proportional to this spacing <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, an open channel-type groove is formed (not shown) instead of the elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Additionally, if the adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are spaced too far apart, it is not possible for the deposited thickness <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the deposited dielectric layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> to overlap to form the elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, or void. If the spacing of the conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is too great, the thickness dimension <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> required may be so large as to defeat the purpose of having inter-level connections in the first place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, or void, in the dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is formed by at least one set of opposing, contoured, merging dielectric surfaces <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> overhanging the substrate surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> until the surfaces contact. The formation of the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 1C</cross-reference> as the dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is deposited to the desired thickness <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> during a CVD process or other suitable process. The opposing, contoured, merging dielectric surfaces <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are located between at least two of the plurality of adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, as shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1C through 3D</cross-reference>, to define the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> located therein. The elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is substantially enclosed within the layer of dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> along the length <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in a direction substantially parallel to the plurality of adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and has at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> leading into the elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is required for the formation of the electrical interconnect system discussed hereafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> further comprises conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> substantially filling an elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> through the at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> as is shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2C through 2D</cross-reference> and drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3C through 4</cross-reference>. The conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is selected from the group of materials comprising doped polysilicon, pure metals, metals, alloys thereof, and metal silicides, and other suitable materials known in the art. It is contemplated that the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> be deposited and formed by chemical vapor deposition (CVD) or by any other suitable process known in the art allowing the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to form in the substantially closed passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the at least one elongated passageway, located within the dielectric material/doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and to form simultaneously with processes forming metallization interconnections <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Finally, the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, or subresolution feature referred to as such since the electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is too small to be formed by conventional lithographic techniques, as shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2C through 2D</cross-reference> and drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3C through 4</cross-reference>, is formed between at least two of the regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> by the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> substantially filling the elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> formed through the layer of dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> as described herein. As the chemical vapor deposition (CVD), or other suitable process, forms the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, the conductive material deposits on an inner surface <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, thereby creating the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which, in turn, forms at least one additional &ldquo;level&rdquo; for semiconductor component interconnection while maximizing the component package density of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. This &ldquo;level&rdquo; then is capable of being located in or proximate to the plane <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the corresponding adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference>. In a preferred embodiment, the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> can be located between corresponding adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and is capable of receiving the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> simultaneously with forming an interconnection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> at the least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> thereby satisfies the needs in the art by connecting the regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> in at least one level of a multi-level integrated circuit semiconductor device structure <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) to form multi-level electrical interconnections approximately simultaneously formed therein with metallization or other processes used to form interconnection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated that in other embodiments, at least two elongated passageways <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> can be located between adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and are capable of receiving the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to form the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and to thereby create additional semiconductor component interconnections, depending upon the requirements of the circuitry of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> illustrates an oxide layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> formed and located between the layer of dielectric material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and the plurality of adjacent, substantially parallel conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to form an additional insulating surface using processes known in the art. The oxide layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> can be a low temperature deposited oxide layer formed by CVD processes, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1C through 3D</cross-reference>, can be formed in the contoured, merging dielectric surfaces <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> at the ends of the plurality of adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> prior to or during the reflow process due to the properties of the dielectric layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and its deposition on and around the corresponding adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can then be connected to at least one via <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> which can be formed using conventional masking and etching processes. The at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can also be formed by the direct connection of the at least one via <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> to the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> formed by processes known in the art. The connection of the at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to the at least one via <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> directs the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> into the elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> simultaneously with the fabrication process to form interconnection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Also, drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2D and 3D</cross-reference> illustrate that the top level of interconnection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be masked and etched using conventional processes to form any desired pattern <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> needed above the adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for receiving external contacts to the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is directed substantially parallel to the plurality of conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the multi-level electrical interconnections are directed in parallel and perpendicular directions to the plurality of conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to connect the at least two components in at least two levels of the multi-level integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. This inter-level electrical interconnect, therefore, can be used to connect components, for example, in one region <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> to components in another region <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> without requiring a separate additional &ldquo;level&rdquo; of MLC metallization. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a typical topographical layout with the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> extending between a contact pad <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and a contact pad <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The contact pad <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> may typically be connected to an underlying external polysilicon line <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, whereas the right side contact pad <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> may typically be connected to an underlying contact pad <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The exemplary topographical layout in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> may further include additional polysilicon conductors <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, as well as a metal conductive strip <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> extending from one end of the polysilicon strip <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> to another lower contact pad <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>. Some elongated passageways, such as the passageway <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, may not be used at all, and other conductors, such as crossover conductor <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may cross over the entire area without making any contact with any of the conductive strips shown therein. Drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is representative of a conventional integrated circuit topographical layout in which the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> contained therein (the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>) are extended by a length dimension between contact pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to make electrical contact between various spaced-apart components within the integrated circuit structure of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the contact pads <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> are the lowermost regions in the integrated circuit (IC) structure and may be diffusions, depositions, or ion-implanted regions which serve as the source and drain for MOS transistors in the silicon substrate. Moving vertically upward from the lowermost regions and with respect to &ldquo;levels,&rdquo; the figure shows the conductive strips <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and then the crossover conductors <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> which are at the same level of and are formed with the rectangularly shaped enclosed regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> which surround the two vertical contact pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Thus, end nodes or termination points <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to the enclosed heavily doped regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, respectively, and then the two vertical contact pads <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> continue this electrical path from the polysilicon conductor <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> to the MOS transistor contact pad <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the MOS transistor contact pad <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> is connected up through the vertical interconnect <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and through the metal conductive strip <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and then down through the vertical interconnect <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to the lower level polysilicon conductor <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. Illustrated in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> extending between the nodes <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and making use of the inter-level path to extend between the interconnect level of the conductors <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, the interconnect level of crossover conductors <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and the heavily doped rectangular enclosed regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The present invention also includes a process for forming electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in integrated circuit semiconductor devices <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> by creating the subresolution features <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in a doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, or insulating layer, using the layer&apos;s flow characteristics. The features <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> are referred to as subresolution features as they are too small in dimension to be accurately formed by the lithographic techniques used to form the circuitry of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. The process, described sequentially in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 3D</cross-reference>, comprises (1) forming adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> having a space <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> therebetween of suitable dielectric material on a surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by processes known in the art, such as photolithography, etching, implanting, diffusion, CVD, and metallization. For example, adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be formed having a height of 3000-4000 angstroms high and having a spacing of 0.5-1.0 microns from center to center of the adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Next in the process, a doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, or insulating layer, is deposited over the adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the substrate surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to a thickness <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> proportional to the spacing <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> therebetween the conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to form coated strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and coated substrate surfaces <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Chemical vapor deposition processes, such as plasma enhanced CVD, low pressure CVD, or other deposition processes, are used to deposit the doped glass layer. Opposing, contoured dielectric surfaces <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the deposited doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> are merged around the coated strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and over the corresponding coated substrate surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to form at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> running coextensive with a length <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of the coated conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> For example, with the ranges of dimensions given herein for the conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> using CVD processes, a first layer of BPSG having appropriate concentration percentages of boron and phosphorus and having a thickness of 10,000-15,000 angstroms will properly coat and cause merging surfaces <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to form the desired at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, or void, in the doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. Typical concentration percentages will range from 3-5 weight percent Boron concentration and 3-6 weight percent phosphorus concentration. If a higher density is required and lower reflow/annealing temperatures are required, then the percentage concentration of Boron should be increased above 5% so that reflow temperatures can drop below 800&deg; C. The use of processes such as CVD and the flow characteristics of the doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, such as BPSG, create the ability to form the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and, when filled with conductive material, the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The deposited doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is then reflowed by processes known in the art in order to smooth the surface <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> of deposited doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> without substantially affecting the position of the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> within the doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. For example, the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> can be formed directly in line with and between corresponding adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as long as a sufficient coated substrate surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> covers the substrate surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, or the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> can be offset so as to be formed above the plane <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in a manner similar to that illustrated in drawing FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D. Reflow or annealing processes, especially for BPSG layers, are typically performed at a temperature of about 900&deg; C. and will smooth the surface for later depositions. These processes also contemplate the use of rapid thermal processing for the recrystallization of surface films. Reflowing results in a position of the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> at a distance from the conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the coated substrate therebetween sufficient to prevent damage to the coated substrate surfaces <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> when the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is formed. The reflowing process results allow for sufficient insulation between conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> so as to prevent interference or electrical shortages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Next in the process, at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is formed in the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> due either to the flow characteristics of the doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and the structure of the adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> during the reflow process or due to the creation of at least one via <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> heretofore described. Finally, the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is filled with a conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> through the at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and along the length <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> thereof to produce at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, or subresolution feature, between at least two regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. This filling process for the conductive material <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> includes using CVD processes (i.e. low pressure CVD) or other processes known in the art and as discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> If further doped glass layers (not shown) are required, then at least one more doped glass layer (not shown) can be deposited and smoothed as described herein over the first deposited and reflowed doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> using CVD and high temperature reflow processes known in the art. Such a high temperature process typically occurs at a temperature between 600&deg; C. and 800&deg; C. In addition, if an oxide layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is required, then the oxide layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> can be deposited over the spaced and formed adjacent conductive strips <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> prior to the act of depositing the doped glass layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> as shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C, the oxide layer <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> having a height of approximately 2000 angstroms and deposited by low pressure CVD processes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> During the process of filling the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> as shown in drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2B through 2D</cross-reference> and drawing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3B through 3D</cross-reference> with a conductive material, the at least one via <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is connected to the at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to direct the conductive material thereinto and to elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> by suitable processes, such as CVD, simultaneously while forming interconnection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. This simultaneous filling-formation process simplifies the fabrication process. As discussed above, the at least one opening <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can also be formed by the connection of the at least one via <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> prior to filling the at least one elongated passageway <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. These process acts thereby form multi-level electrical interconnections by approximately or substantially simultaneously connecting the at least one electrical interconnect <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> with the at least two regions <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> in at least one level of the integrated circuit semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. Further conventional processes, such as etching, are used to shape and form the component pattern structures <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, depending upon the requirements of the circuitry of the integrated semiconductor device <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> It will also be appreciated by one of ordinary skill in the art that one or more features of any of the illustrated embodiments may be combined with one or more features from another to form yet another combination within the scope of the invention as described and claimed herein. Thus, while certain representative embodiments and details have been shown for purposes of illustrating the invention, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various changes in the invention disclosed herein may be made without departing from the scope of the invention, which is defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A process for forming electrical interconnects for integrated circuits formed on a substrate having at least one surface for forming integrated circuits thereon, said substrate for a semiconductor device comprising: 
<claim-text>forming spaced adjacent conductive strips on said surface of said substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a doped glass layer over said spaced adjacent conductive strips and said substrate surface to a thickness proportional to said spacing for forming coated strips and coated surfaces of said substrate, said doped glass layer selected from the group consisting of borophosphosilicate glass, borosilicate glass, phosphosilicate glass, and silicon dioxide; </claim-text>
<claim-text>merging at least portions of opposing contoured surfaces of said deposited doped glass layer around at least portions of said coated strips and over at least portions of said coated surfaces of said substrate for forming at least one elongated passageway running coextensive with at least a portion of said length of said coated strips; </claim-text>
<claim-text>reflowing said deposited doped glass layer for smoothing said deposited doped glass layer and for positioning said at least one elongated passageway; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least one opening in said at least one elongated passageway; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>filling at least a portion of said at least one elongated passageway with a conductive material through said at least one opening and along at least a portion of said length for producing at least one electrical interconnect between at least two regions of at least one integrated circuit of said integrated circuits. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said spaced adjacent conductive strips comprise polysilicon conductors and said conductive material is selected from the group consisting of doped polysilicon, metals, alloys, and metal silicides. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising depositing and densifying at least one more doped glass layer over said doped glass layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising depositing an oxide layer over said spaced adjacent conductive strips prior to said depositing said doped glass layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said filling comprises connecting at least one via to said at least one opening for directing said conductive material into said at least one elongated passageway simultaneously with metallization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said forming said at least one opening comprises connecting at least one via to said at least one elongated passageway for directing said conductive material into said at least one elongated passageway simultaneously with metallization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising forming multi-level electrical interconnections by approximately simultaneously connecting said at least one electrical interconnect with said at least two regions in at least one level of at least one integrated circuit of said integrated circuits during metallization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said doped glass layer is deposited and formed by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said spaced adjacent conductive strips comprise strips deposited and formed by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one more doped glass layer comprises a layer deposited and formed by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oxide layer comprises an oxide layer deposited and formed by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said conductive material fills said at least one elongated passageway during a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said conductive material fills said at least one elongated passageway by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said conductive material fills said at least one elongated passageway by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said conductive material fills said at least one elongated passageway by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reflowing positions said at least one elongated passageway at a distance from said coated surface of said substrate and said coated strips sufficient for preventing damage to said coated substrate surfaces and said coated strips during the formation of said at least one electrical interconnect is produced. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A process for forming electrical interconnects in integrated circuits located on a portion of a substrate having a surface for use as a semiconductor device comprising: 
<claim-text>forming adjacent conductive strips on said surface of said substrate, each said conductive strip having a surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing an insulating layer over at least a portion of a strip of surface of said adjacent conductive strips and on said surface of said substrate located between said adjacent conductive strips for forming coated surfaces of each said strip and coated surfaces of said substrate, said insulating layer deposited to a thickness for forming at least one elongated passageway having at least one opening, said at least one elongated passageway being located between and running along a portion of the lengthwise distance of said adjacent conductive strips above said coated surfaces of said substrate, said insulating layer selected from the group consisting of borophosphosilicate glass, borosilicate glass, phosphosilicate glass, and silicon dioxide; </claim-text>
<claim-text>reflowing said deposited insulating layer for smoothing said insulating layer and for positioning said at least one elongated passageway; and p<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> depositing a conductive material into said at least one opening using a chemical vapor deposition process and extending throughout at least a portion of said at least one elongated passageway for forming an electrical interconnect extending therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said insulating layer comprises an insulation layer deposited and formed by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said adjacent conductive strips are constructed of polysilicon conductors and said conductive material is selected from the group consisting of doped polysilicon, metals, alloys, and metal silicides, said adjacent conductive strips being formed by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising depositing and densifying at least one more insulating layer over said deposited and reflowed insulating layer, said at least one more insulating layer being deposited by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising depositing an oxide layer over said adjacent conductive strips prior to said depositing said insulating layer by a chemical vapor deposition process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said depositing said conductive material further comprises connecting at least one via to said at least one opening for directing said conductive material into said at least one elongated passageway approximately simultaneously with metallization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising forming said at least one opening by connecting at least one via to said at least one elongated passageway for directing said conductive material into said at least one elongated passageway approximately simultaneously with metallization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising forming multi-level electrical interconnections by approximately simultaneously connecting each said electrical interconnect with at least two regions in at least one level of said integrated circuits during metallization. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reflowing said insulating layer positions said at least one elongated passageway at a distance from said surfaces of said coated substrate and said coated conductive strips sufficient for preventing damage to said coated substrate surfaces and said coated adjacent conductive strips during the formation of each said electrical interconnect. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The process of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said depositing said insulating layer continues until said thickness is proportional to a spacing between said adjacent conductive strips.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3D</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003708A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003708A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003708A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003708A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003708A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
