<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004824A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004824A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004824A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004824A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004824A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004824A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004824A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004824A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004824A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004824A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004824</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09898232</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F017/60</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>705</class>
<subclass>026000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and system for customized mail piece production utilizing a data center</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Uday</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Joshi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Wilton</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<family-name>Mould</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Greenwich</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Pitney Bowes Inc.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>35 Waterview Drive</address-1>
<address-2>P.O. Box 3000</address-2>
<city>Shelton</city>
<state>CT</state>
<postalcode>06484-8000</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system and method for preparing mail pieces is disclosed. A business provides one or more designs for a mail piece to a data center, which converts the designs to a format suitable for viewing via an on-line network connection utilizing a browser. A custom Web site for the business is created and accessed by the business&apos;s employees. A defined design for a mail piece is selected, information to be included on the mail piece is provided, and a mailing list is provided to the data center. Multiple requests for mailings are combined by the data center into a single print run and arranged in a presort sequence to allow for postal discounts. The aggregated mailing is printed, and the entire mailing is mailed by the data center. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention disclosed herein relates generally to mail piece production, and more particularly to a system and method for producing mail pieces for direct mail advertising utilizing a data center. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In today&apos;s highly competitive business world, advertising to customers, both potential and previous, is a necessity. A business bears the expenses of advertising to inform, persuade or remind target buyers of the business&apos; goods, services or goodwill, with the ultimate goal being that an advertisement will result in the sale of the goods or services. Additionally, many businesses desire to thank customers for recent purchases and offer additional related goods or services to the customer, thereby promoting customer loyalty. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> One method for such advertising is by direct mail. There are many different ways a business, both large and small, can conduct an advertising campaign using direct mailings. Suppose, for example, a large company has multiple satellite offices or franchises located in different geographic areas, but requires each office to utilize the same style and look for its advertising to retain a single corporate identity. Typically, the company&apos;s marketing department will design a standard mailing and make the design files available to the sales representatives in each of the satellite offices. The sales representative will select a design, customize the file by adding contact information, and print the desired number of copies. Alternatively, the sales representative may also use a commercial printing service to print the mailing. Once the mailing has been printed, the sales representative must address the mailing and apply the proper postage to produce a finished mail piece. The finished mail piece can then be sent to the intended recipient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> There are problems, however, with the generation and sending of conventional direct mailings as described above. For example, there is the risk that a sales representative will make unauthorized changes to the design of the mail piece before printing, thereby removing any uniformity in design between the different satellite offices. Additionally, the printing of the mailing by the sales representative may be time consuming, and the quality of the finished mail piece is limited by the performance of the equipment upon which the mail piece is printed. Additionally, a small number of mailings each year may not justify the expense of maintaining the mailing, shipping and printing equipment in house. While the use of a commercial printing service can eliminate the need to maintain such equipment and ensure a high quality product, the use of such a service may be cost prohibitive, especially for a mailing that does not contain a large number of pieces. Furthermore, the sales representative may not be able to take advantage of postal discounts for mailing rates if the mailing is not pre-sorted or does not contain a sufficient number of pieces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Thus, there exists a need for an economical and efficient method and system for mail piece production that reliably controls the format and design of the mail pieces. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention alleviates the problems associated with the prior art and provides a system and method for businesses to prepare mail pieces for direct mailings in which the format and design of the mail pieces are centrally controlled and preparation of the mail pieces is both economical and time efficient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, a business provides one or more designs for a mail piece to a data center. The business defined designs are converted to a format suitable for viewing via an on-line network connection utilizing a browser. A custom Web site for the business is created, which is accessible by the business&apos;s employees. The employees can select a business defined mail piece design for a mailing, provide additional information to be included on each of the mail pieces in the mailing, and upload a recipient mailing list to the data center or specify targeting criteria for a recipient mailing list provided by the data center. Multiple requests for mailings, from the same business or from different businesses, that are received by the data center within a predetermined time period are combined by the data center into a single print run and presorted to allow for postal discounts. The mail pieces are printed, and the entire mailing is mailed by the data center. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> By utilizing the system of the present invention, a business can maintain central control over the look and style of mailings sent by branch offices or franchises, thereby maintaining corporate uniformity. The use of a Web site and the data center provides easy access for any authorized employee to request a mailing. Additionally, by combining requests for mailings from multiple parties, the aggregated mailing can qualify for postal discounts, thereby reducing the costs to each of the parties. Furthermore, the use of the data center for printing the mail pieces provides higher quality finished mail pieces.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects and advantages of the present invention will be apparent upon consideration of the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with accompanying drawings, in which like reference characters refer to like parts throughout, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates in block diagram form a system according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates in block diagram form a data center according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates in flow diagram form a process for implementing mail piece production according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates in flow diagram form a process for ordering a mailing according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates in flow diagram form a process for preparing and sending mail pieces according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In describing the present invention, reference is made to the drawings, wherein there is seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> an interactive system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for producing direct mailings according to the present invention. System <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> operatively coupled to a network, such as, for example, the Internet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is preferably operated as a Web server that is accessible by remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> via the Internet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. It should be understood that while only one remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is illustrated, system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may actually include numerous remote computers. System <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also include a server <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> operated by a business that is also operatively coupled to the Internet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes and executes a Web browser software application, which allows the remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to access Hypertext Markup Language (HTML) Web pages and other data on various Web servers, such as data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and server <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> therefore provides access to data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for the production of mail pieces as will be further described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, there is shown a data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> according to the present invention. Data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a microprocessor <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> for controlling operation of the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and production of mail pieces. Data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of data bases <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>n </italic></highlight>used to store information relative to a specific business or company, such as, for example, business A, business Bb and business N. Each data base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>n </italic></highlight>includes Web pages accessible via remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Each Web page is based on a design for a mail piece submitted by the business. Alternatively, each data base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>n </italic></highlight>includes stored component information that is used to dynamically assemble a Web page when requested via remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Thus, for example, business A will submit one or more designs or components for a design for the look and style of a mail piece to data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The designs from business A will be converted into a format suitable for viewing on-line, such as, for example, an GIF image, via a Web browser, and stored in data base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Business B and business N will similarly supply their own designs for mail pieces to data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, which will be converted into a format suitable for viewing on-line and stored in data base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>n, </italic></highlight>respectively. As noted above, the Web pages created by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can be accessed and viewed by a remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> via the Internet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> also includes a printer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for printing the direct mail pieces. Printer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is preferably a high performance printer, such as, for example, a digital printer. Printer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is operatively coupled to microprocessor <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> which controls the printing of graphics and text as defined by user selections from the Web pages referenced above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The operation of the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be described with respect to the flow charts illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, in step <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> a business, such as, for example, business A of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, prepares a design for one or more mail pieces that its sales representatives are authorized to use. Preferably, the mail pieces are postcards having printing on one or both sides, but could also be any other type of print media. For clarity, the operation of system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be described with respect to business A; however, it should be understood that other businesses, such as, for example, business B and business N, will operate similarly. The design will include, for example, features such as color, font style and size, graphics, corporate logos, banners, placement of predefined information fields, i.e., contact information, customized information, etc. Since each design is centrally created and approved by the business, such as, for example, by the corporate marketing department, the business is assured of maintaining uniformity of the design of mailings, regardless of the business location from which the mailings are sent. However, the use of the predefined information fields for entry of customized information allows each mail piece to be customized while still maintaining the uniformity of the overall design. In addition, new designs can be easily introduced and made immediately available to all locations of a business simply by submitting the new designs to the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, obsolete designs can be easily withdrawn from use, without the risk of obsolete designs being used after their removal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, the business created designs are sent to the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. This can be performed either manually, or, alternatively, electronically. Additionally, data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be further adapted to allow designs to be created on-line when accessed by an authorized party. Thus, for example, a user authorized by business A could access data base <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> via remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and select or provide components to create a new design for a mail piece. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> converts the designs received from the business into a format that is suitable for viewing on-line via a Web browser. Preferably, the format is a Web page that is created by a table-driven Active Server Pages (ASP) scripting environment that can combine HTML, scripts and reusable components to create dynamic Web pages, thereby enabling a single application to generate different looking Web sites for different businesses. The created Web pages can be viewed from a remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> that is running a Web browser software application. In step <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> creates a custom Web site for business A that includes the Web pages created by converting the mailing designs in step <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The custom Web site is identified by a unique uniform resource locator (URL). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> method for selecting a direct mailing according to the present invention is illustrated in flow diagram form. In step <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, the custom Web site created for business A in step <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is accessed by a user desiring to generate and send a direct mailing. The user could be, for example, a sales representative or marketing department employee desiring to send any type of promotional mailing. The user accesses the Web site via remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and Internet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> by entering the URL for the custom Web site for business A created by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. As noted above, remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes and executes a Web browser software application, which allows the remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to access Hypertext Markup Language (HTML) Web pages and other data on various Web servers, such as data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the user could log into a Web site maintained by business A on the server <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for business A, and click on a link provided therein to connect to the Web site created and maintained by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The user would then be redirected through the Internet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Optionally, access to the Web site created by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for business A could be controlled by requiring a user identification as well as a password to access the Web site. A predetermined list of authorized users, identified by a user identification and password, would be provided from business A to data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In this manner, only users authorized by business A will have access to the Web site maintained by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and can request generation of a direct mailing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Once the user has accessed the Web site for business A maintained by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and, if necessary, supplied a proper user identification and password, the user can preview, via remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the Web pages created by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> from the designs supplied by business A. In step <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, one of the business defined designs for a mail piece is selected by the user. Once the mail piece has been selected, if there are sections of the mail piece that allow for customized information to be printed, in step <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> it is determined if the user desires to add customized information to the mail piece. Such customized information could include, for example, specific items on sale, personal messages to be included on the mail piece, or any other type of information that is unique to this mailing. If in step <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> it is determined that the user desires to add customized information, then in step <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> the user is prompted to enter the customized information. It should be understood that this information must fit within the parameters defined for the custom information field, i.e., the maximum number of characters that can be placed into the custom information area on the mail piece is predefined and cannot be modified by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Once the customized information has been entered in step <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>, or if the user did not desire to add customized information in step <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> or the mail piece selected by the user in step <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> does not have a field for entering customized information, then in step <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> the user is prompted to enter his contact information. The contact information will be printed on the mail piece in a predefined field and can include, for example, the user&apos;s name, office address, telephone and facsimile numbers, e-mail address or other location identification, store hours, etc. that will assist the mail piece recipient in contacting the user if so desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, the user is prompted to enter a recipient mailing list for the mail piece selected in step <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. The mailing list can be uploaded from remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by the user, or the mailing list can be input by the user to data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> via remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the mailing list can be selected from a list maintained by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Such lists maintained by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> could be from previous mailings by the user, or supplied by business A. Additionally, the user could specify a targeting criteria for a list maintained by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Such targeting criteria could include, for example, a specific geographic area, previous customers, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Once the recipient mailing list has been selected, downloaded or entered by the user in step <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, in step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> the data center calculates the cost of printing the mailing, based on the number of mail pieces to be printed, and requests billing information from the user. Such billing information could include, for example, a purchase order number if the invoice is to be sent to the business A, credit card information if the user will pay for the mailing directly, or any other type of information necessary to effectuate the billing process as agreed to by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and business A. Also in step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the user is requested to input contact information to which a confirmation message will be sent upon actual printing and sending of the mailing from data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Once the billing information has been entered, the user can review all of the selections made and make any changes or modifications as desired. The user will then be prompted to submit the complete order to data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and a confirmation of the submitted order is returned to remote computer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> by data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> confirming receipt of the order and indicating that the order will be printed and mailed within a predetermined time period, preferably within 2-3 days of the order. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As illustrated above, the ordering of a mailing can be performed from any remote terminal <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> having Internet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> access, thereby allowing users the freedom to generate a mailing from any location. Additionally, the entire process of ordering a mailing can be performed in only a matter of minutes, thereby saving time for the user, since everything needed for the production of a promotional mailing is provided on one Web site, in a single workflow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, there is shown in flow diagram form the operation of the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In step <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is in a receive orders mode, i.e., data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> receives orders for mailings from any of the businesses A-N. In step <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>, it is determined if a predetermined period of time has elapsed since data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> processed orders. Preferably, the period of time is approximately two to three days. If in step <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> it is determined that the predetermined period of time has not elapsed, the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> continues in the receive orders mode in step <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Once the predetermined period of time has elapsed, data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will begin to process the mail piece orders and in step <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> all of the mail piece orders received during the previous receive order mode period will be aggregated into a single printing run. In step <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight>, all of the mail pieces in the aggregated orders are sequences in a presorted order based on addressing information provided in step <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. In accordance with the present invention, since the entire mailing is one large mailing formed of an aggregation of smaller individual mailings, it is possible to take advantage of postage discounts for the presorted aggregated mailing. Therefore, the aggregated mailing will have a lower postage cost per mail piece than each of the individual smaller mailings, thereby reducing the cost of such direct mailings for each business. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, all of the mail pieces in the aggregated orders are printed utilizing printer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Because printer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is a high performance printer, preferably each mail piece is a blank print media, and the entire mail piece, including text and graphics, is dynamically inserted into the print stream and printed on the mail piece. Thus, it is not necessary for any of the businesses A-N to provide data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with stock mail pieces that already have pre-printed graphics or text, since printer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is capable of printing the entire design of the mail piece. This will also reduce the total cost of the mailing for each business, and eliminate any left-over pre-printed stock should a design of a mail piece become obsolete and no longer used. Specifically, in step <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, the design for each mail piece is printed on one or both sides of a postcard, along with the customized information, if any, provided in step <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>, the contact information provided in step <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and the recipient address culled from the recipient mailing list provided in step <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The use of the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to print the mailing eliminates the need for each business to maintain its own high performance printer. Additionally, the costs to each business A-N associated with printing a mailing utilizing data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will be less than if a commercial printing service was used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight>, the appropriate postage is applied to each mail piece to create a finished mail piece. Postage indicia can be printed by printer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, if desired, and in included as part of the printing of the mail pieces in step <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. In step <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>, each finished mail piece is sent to its respective intended recipient via physical mail, such as, for example, by the United States Post Office (USPS) or any other postal service. In step <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight>, a confirmation of the sending of the ordered mail pieces is sent to the user that requested the order utilizing the information input by the user in step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Thus, according to the present invention, a system and method is provided for businesses to prepare mail pieces for direct mailings in which the format and design of the mail pieces are centrally controlled, thereby eliminating the risk of unwanted changes to the design and content of the mail piece design. Additionally, the Web site maintained by the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is accessible via any remote computer with Internet access. The actual ordering of the mailing can be done in a matter of minutes, since everything needed for the production of a promotional mailing is provided on one Web site, in a single workflow, including selection from a catalog of business approved designs, customization of the mail pieces, targeted lists, printing, addressing, mailing, postage discounts and payment. The high performance printers utilized by the data center <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to prepare the mail pieces ensures high quality printing and professional appearance. Furthermore, by aggregating several smaller individual mailings into a single large mailing, postal discounts can be utilized, thereby reducing the overall costs of each of the mailings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> While preferred embodiments of the invention have been described and illustrated above, it should be understood that these are exemplary of the invention and are not to be considered as limiting. Additions, deletions, substitutions, and other modifications can be made without departing from the spirit or scope of the present invention. Accordingly, the invention is not to be considered as limited by the foregoing description but is only limited by the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for generating a mailing comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>receiving a design for at least one mail piece; </claim-text>
<claim-text>converting said design to a viewable format, said viewable format being viewable from a remote computer via a network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving an order for a plurality of pieces of said at least one mail piece from said remote computer via said network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>combining said order with at least one other order for a plurality of pieces of a different mail piece to produce a single print run; </claim-text>
<claim-text>printing each of said plurality of pieces of said at least one mail piece and said plurality of pieces of said different mail piece of said single print run on a corresponding print medium to produce a plurality of finished mail pieces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>mailing said plurality of finished mail pieces. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said network is the Internet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of receiving an order further comprises: 
<claim-text>receiving contact information, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said contact information is printed on each of said plurality of said at least one mail piece. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of receiving an order further comprises: 
<claim-text>receiving a recipient mailing list including a plurality of names, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a respective one of said plurality of names is printed on a corresponding one of said plurality of pieces of said at least one mail piece. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of receiving an order further comprises: 
<claim-text>receiving customized information to be printed on at least one of said plurality of pieces of said at least one mail piece. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said print medium is a post card having a first and second side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of printing further comprises: 
<claim-text>printing on said first and second side of said postcard. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of combining further comprises: 
<claim-text>arranging said single print run in a presort sequence. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of receiving a design further comprises receiving a design for at least one mail piece from a first business, and wherein said different mail piece is designed by a second business. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method for preparing a plurality of mail pieces comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>receiving a first design for a mail piece from a first business; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a second design for a mail piece from a second business; </claim-text>
<claim-text>converting said first design and said second design to a viewable format, said viewable format being viewable from a remote computer via a network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving an order for a plurality of mail pieces having said first design from a first remote computer via said network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving an order for a plurality of mail pieces having said second design from a second remote computer via said network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>combining said orders for said plurality of mail pieces having said first design and said second design to produce a single print run; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>printing each of said plurality of mail pieces of said orders for said plurality of mail pieces having said first design and said second design in said single print run on a corresponding print medium to produce a plurality of finished mail pieces. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>applying postage to each of said finished mail pieces; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>mailing each of said finished mail pieces. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of combining further comprises: 
<claim-text>arranging said single print run in a presort sequence. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said steps of receiving an order for a plurality of pieces of said first design and said second design further comprise: 
<claim-text>receiving respective contact information, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said respective contact information is printed on each of said plurality of pieces of said order for said first design and said second design. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A system for producing a mailing including a plurality of mail pieces, said system comprising: 
<claim-text>a data center, said data center receiving a first design for a mail piece from a first business and a second design for a mail piece from a second business and converting said first design and said second design to a respective viewable format, said data center being operatively coupled to a network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first remote computer coupled to said network, said first remote computer communicating with said data center via said network to view said viewable format for said first design and provide an order for a plurality of mail pieces having said first design; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second remote computer coupled to said network, said second remote computer communicating with said data center via said network to view said viewable format for said second design and provide an order for a plurality of mail pieces having said second design, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said data center combines said orders for said plurality of mail pieces having said first design and said second design to produce a single print run and prints each of said plurality of mail pieces of said orders for said plurality of mail pieces having said first design and said second design in said single print run on a corresponding print medium to produce a plurality of finished mail pieces. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said network is the Internet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said viewable format is a Web page. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said data center arranges said single print run in a presort sequence.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004824A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004824A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004824A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004824A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004824A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
