<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000638A1-20030102-M00001.NB SYSTEM "US20030000638A1-20030102-M00001.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030000638A1-20030102-M00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000638A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000638A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000638A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000638A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000638A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000638</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10157411</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020529</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B32B031/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B32B031/28</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>156</class>
<subclass>272200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method of bonding a stack of layers by electromagnetic induction heating</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60297137</doc-number>
<document-date>20010608</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>H.</middle-name>
<family-name>Booske</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Madison</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Keith</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Thompson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Madison</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yogesh</given-name>
<middle-name>B.</middle-name>
<family-name>Gianchandani</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Reid</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Cooper</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Madison</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>WISCONSIN ALUMNI RESEARCH FOUNDATION</organization-name>
<address>
<address-1>614 WALNUT STREET</address-1>
<city>MADISON</city>
<state>WI</state>
<postalcode>53705</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BOYLE FREDRICKSON NEWHOLM STEIN &amp; GRATZ, S.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>250 E. WISCONSIN AVENUE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1030</address-2>
<city>MILWAUKEE</city>
<state>WI</state>
<postalcode>53202</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of bonding multiple layers is provided. The method includes the steps of stacking the multiple layers on top of each other and volumetrically heating the stack of multiple layers to a predetermined temperature. It is preferred that the stack is heated by electromagnetic induction. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application Serial No. 60/297,137, filed Jun. 8, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<federal-research-statement>
<heading lvl="1">REFERENCE TO GOVERNMENT GRANT </heading>
<paragraph-federal-research-statement id="P-0002"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention was made with United States government support awarded by the US Civilian Research &amp; Development Foundation, No. RE1-2065. The United States has certain rights in this invention.</paragraph-federal-research-statement>
</federal-research-statement>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to the bonding of multiple layers, and in particular, to a method of bonding a stack of multiple layers through electromagnetic induction heating. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND AND SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In the past decade, silicon-silicon bonding has received increasing use in the fabrication of micromechanical structures and power electronics. Silicon-silicon bonding is also a candidate technology for manufacturing silicon-on-insulator (SOI) wafers, which are attractive for high speed digital microelectronics. By way of example, in metal-oxide-semiconductor (MOS) transistors fabricated on SOI wafers, the parasitic capacitance associated with source and drain junctions is minimal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In the bonding process, the polished surfaces of the silicon wafers to be bonded are pressed together at moderate temperatures to form an initial pre-bond. To complete the bond and achieve full strength, the wafers require baking at approximately 1000&deg; Celsius. Conventionally, this is done in large furnaces, which require long ramp times, consume large amounts of power, and have significant manufacturing footprints. The resultant high thermal budget limits process flexibility, making process integration difficult. In addition, furnaces lack the flexibility to adapt to unconventional bonding requirements such as multi-wafer stacks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It can be appreciated that silicon bonding through electromagnetic induction heating (EMIH) overcomes many conventional limitations. Heretofore, the use of electromagnetic radiation for wafer bonding has been limited. Since it has been assumed that silicon is transparent to electromagnetic radiation because of its small imaginary dielectric response, intermediate glue layers of metal were used to absorb the radiation. In reality, however, the ohmic response of silicon to an oscillating magnetic flux can be used to directly heat the silicon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is a primary object and feature of the present invention to provide a method of bonding a stack of silicon wafers which is simpler and less expensive than prior methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is a further object and feature of the present invention to provide a method of bonding a stack of silicon wafers which consumes less power than prior methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> It is a still further object and feature of the present invention to provide a method of bonding a stack of silicon wafers which bonds the wafers in a shorter time period than prior methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, a method of bonding multiple layers is provided. The method includes the steps of stacking the multiple layers on top of each other and generating an electromagnetic field which intersects the stack of the multiple layers. The electromagnetic field heats the multiple layers to a predetermined temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The method may include the additional step of providing a resonant cavity extending along a longitudinal axis. The cavity has length which is adjustable along the axis. The stack of multiple layers is positioned in the cavity at a predetermined location where the intensity of the electromagnetic field is maximized. The length of the cavity may be adjusted to a user selected length to vary the electromagnetic field. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The step of generating the electromagnetic field may include injecting microwave radiation into the cavity and tuning the microwave radiation to minimize reflections from the cavity. Alternatively, the step of generating the electromagnetic field may include the step of generating a magnetic field which intersects the stack of multiple layers. The magnetic field may be generated by providing a conducting material and passing a current through the conducting material at a predetermined frequency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated to preheat the stack of multiple layers to a coupling temperature so as to initiate the bonding of the multiple layers. It is preferred that the coupling temperature be between 20&deg; and 200&deg; Celsius and the predetermined temperature be between 800&deg; and 1100&deg; Celsius. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The multiple layers may be cleaned prior to stacking the multiple layers to facilitate the bonding of the layers in a stack. The layers are cleaned first in a NaOH:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius, followed by a H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius. In addition, the step of cleaning the multiple layers may also include the additional steps of dipping the layers in dilute (100:1) HF to remove any residual oxide layer; rinsing the layers in deionized water; and spinning the layers completely dry to minimize the amount of residual moisture thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a further aspect of the present invention, a method of bonding multiple layers is provided. The method includes the steps of stacking the multiple layers on top of each other and volumetrically heating the stack of multiple layers to a predetermined temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A resonant cavity extending along a longitudinal axis is provided and an electromagnetic field is generated therein. The cavity has length which is adjustable along the axis to vary the electromagnetic field. The stack of multiple layers is positioned in the cavity at a predetermined location where the intensity of the electromagnetic field is maximized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The electromagnetic field may be generated by injecting microwave radiation into the cavity and by tuning the microwave radiation to minimize reflections from the cavity. Alternatively, the electromagnetic field may be generated by generating a magnetic field which intersects the stack of multiple layers. The magnetic field may be generated by providing a conducting material and passing a current through the conducting material at a predetermined frequency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated to preheat the stack of multiple layers to a coupling temperature so as to initiate the bonding of the multiple layers. It is preferred that the coupling temperature be between 20&deg; and 200&deg; Celsius and the predetermined temperature be between 800&deg; and 1100&deg; Celsius. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The multiple layers may be cleaned prior to stacking the multiple layers to facilitate the bonding of the layers in a stack. The layers are cleaned first in a NaOH:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius, followed by a H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius. In addition, the step of cleaning the multiple layers may also include the additional steps dipping in dilute (100:1) HF (hydrogen floride) to remove any residual oxide layer; rinsing the layers in deionized water; and spinning the layers completely dry to minimize the amount of residual moisture thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a still further aspect of the present invention, a method of bonding multiple layers is provided. The layers are cleaned in a NaOH:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius, followed by a H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius. The cleaned multiple layers are brought into contact together to form a stack that is volumetrically heated to a predetermined temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The step of cleaning the multiple layers may also include the additional steps dipping in dilute (100:1) HF to remove any residual oxide layer; rinsing the layers in deionized water; and spinning the layers completely dry to minimize the amount of residual moisture thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A generally cylindrical resonant cavity extending along a longitudinal axis is provided and an electromagnetic field is generated therein. The cavity has length which is adjustable along the axis to vary the electromagnetic field. The stack of multiple layers is positioned in the cavity at a predetermined location where the intensity of the electromagnetic field is maximized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The electromagnetic field may be generated by injecting microwave radiation into the cavity and by tuning the microwave radiation to minimize reflections from the cavity. Alternatively, the electromagnetic field may be generated by generating a magnetic field which intersects the stack of multiple layers. The magnetic field may be generated by providing a coil winding and passing a current through the coil winding at a predetermined frequency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated to preheat the stack of multiple layers to a coupling temperature so as to initiate the bonding of the multiple layers. It is preferred that the coupling temperature be between 20&deg; and 200&deg; Celsius and the predetermined temperature be between 800&deg; and 1100&deg; Celsius.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The drawings furnished herewith illustrate a preferred construction of the present invention in which the above advantages and features are clearly disclosed as well as others which will be readily understood from the following description of the illustrated embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In the drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic view of a structure for the electromagnetic induction heating of a plurality of silicon wafers in accordance with the method of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic view of an alternate structure for the electromagnetic induction heating of a plurality of silicon wafers in accordance with the method of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a second, schematic view of the alternate structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> It can be appreciated that electromagnetic induction heating (EMIH) is a unique application of Faraday&apos;s and Ampere&apos;s laws. When a silicon wafer is exposed to oscillating magnetic fields, currents&mdash;more specifically electrons and holes&mdash;are induced to flow within the wafer (Faraday&apos;s law). These electrons, through collisions with the lattice, give up their energy by heating the wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Predicting the magnitude of these induced currents, however, requires a more detailed analysis of Faraday&apos;s and Ampere&apos;s laws. The currents induced in highly conducting materials, e.g. copper, re-induce a magnetic field that partially or completely interferes destructively with the incident field. This is commonly known as shielding or skin-depth. Conversely, the lack of free carriers in insulating materials, e.g. quartz, precludes any flow of current and allows the incident field to penetrate through the material. Semi-conductors fall in between these two extremes and therefore have the potential for significant field penetration that induces substantial currents throughout the volume of the wafer. This enables the possibility for substantial and volumetric heating, rather than just surface heating. This can be illustrated best by a self-consistent solution of Ampere&apos;s and Faraday&apos;s laws that obtains a first order description of induced current density and the subsequent power absorbed:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<math>
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>P</mi>
            <mrow>
              <mi>A</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>B</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>S</mi>
            </mrow>
          </msub>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mfrac>
              <mrow>
                <mi>&pi;</mi>
                <mo>&it;</mo>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
                </mstyle>
                <mo>&it;</mo>
                <msup>
                  <mi>a</mi>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </msup>
                <mo>&it;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <msubsup>
                    <mi>t</mi>
                    <mi>w</mi>
                    <mn>3</mn>
                  </msubsup>
                  <mo>/</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <msup>
                        <mi>&delta;</mi>
                        <mn>4</mn>
                      </msup>
                      <mo>&it;</mo>
                      <mi>&sigma;</mi>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mn>1</mn>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <msup>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <msub>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mi>w</mi>
                      </msub>
                      <mo>/</mo>
                      <mi>&delta;</mi>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                  <mn>4</mn>
                </msup>
              </mrow>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <msubsup>
              <mi>H</mi>
              <mn>0</mn>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </msubsup>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>,</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>&delta;</mi>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <msqrt>
            <mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mn>2</mn>
                <mo>/</mo>
                <mi>&omega;</mi>
              </mrow>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>&mu;</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>&sigma;</mi>
            </mrow>
          </msqrt>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00001" file="US20030000638A1-20030102-M00001.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00001" wi="216.027" he="21.12075" file="US20030000638A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> wherein: &sgr; is conductivity; t<highlight><subscript>w </subscript></highlight>is thickness; &dgr; is skin depth; co is frequency; &mgr; is permeability; &ldquo;a&rdquo; is radius; and H<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>is the incident magnetic field. It is inferable from Equation (1) that the absorbed power increases with conductivity, &sgr;, until a peak absorption point is reached at which point the power decreases and asymptotes to zero. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The strong dependence of power absorption on conductivity adds an elusive element to the heating of silicon because of the non-linear relationship between temperature and conductivity in a silicon wafer. As is known, conductivity is the product of mobility and carrier density. However, both these terms, mobility and carrier density, have opposing relationships with respect to temperature. Mobility decreases with temperature due to an increased collision frequency that impedes the flow of carriers. Carrier density increases with temperature as the increased thermal energy moves more carriers from the valence band into the conduction band; thereby increasing the intrinsic carrier concentration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> It can be appreciated that conductivity initially decreases with temperature&mdash;as collisions impede carrier mobility&mdash;until the temperature exceeds &tilde;100&deg; Celsius. At such point, the increase in intrinsic carriers overcomes the loss in mobility and conductivity increases monotonically with temperature. As a result, a conductivity valley exists just above room temperature (50-125&deg; Celsius). This creates, due to the strong dependence of power absorption on conductivity, the possibility of an absorption valley which prevents the wafer from heating beyond 100&deg; Celsius. Once beyond this point, conductivity increases with temperature and power absorption increases with conductivity. This creates a runaway heating effect that results in extremely rapid temperature ramp rates. Further, above 500&deg; Celsius, the intrinsic carrier concentration becomes much greater than the background doping; consequently, the intrinsic carriers, not the specific wafer doping, dominate conductivity. Consequently, above 500&deg; Celsius wafer heating becomes independent of the initial substrate doping, and silicon wafers of various room temperature conductivities heat in an identical fashion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> cylindrical resonant chamber for electromagnetic induction heating a plurality of layers such as silicon wafers is generally designated by the reference numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Resonant chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> defines a cavity <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> having a predetermined diameter d and an adjustable height h. Height h of cavity <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is adjusted by moving adjustable top <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> which, in turn, allows a user to tune in specific modes, for reasons hereinafter described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Resonant chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is operatively connected to magnetron <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by a waveguide <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Magnetron <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> converts electrical energy to microwave radiation such that magnetron <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may provide microwaves to cavity <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> within resonant chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through waveguide <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. As is known, magnetron <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is capable of generating microwaves having frequencies between 100 MHz and 10 GHz. However, it is contemplated as being within the scope of the present invention to replace magnetron <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> with an alternate microwave generator in order to provide microwaves having frequencies of up to 30 GHz. Radial tuner <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is positioned in the interior of waveguide <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to minimize reflected power. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> A plurality of layers such as silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is positioned on hollow quartz cylinders <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> within cavity <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of resonant chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> adjacent cavity bottom <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> thereof. Silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are positioned just above cavity bottom <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to ensure that the silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are in a magnetic field maximum. Since the electromagnetic energy absorbed by silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is directly proportional to the magnetic field intensity, the uniformity of the magnetic field pattern in cavity <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for the various modes in the plane of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can have a strong influence on the uniformity of the heating of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. As such, adjustable top <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of resonant chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned by a user to tune in specific modes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In order to heat silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> utilizing EMIH, intense electromagnetic fields must be used to induce currents to flow through silicon wafer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Magnetron <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> provides cavity <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with microwaves, as heretofore described, such that highly energetic electrons collide with the lattice of the silicon, transferring energy to the lattice in the form of heat. As the temperature of the silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> rises, additional electrons move into the conduction band and are available to flow as current, thereby increasing the power absorbed by silicon wafers. This process continues until radiation losses equal the power absorbed, forcing a steady state operating point. As described, silicon wafers 20 can be rapidly ramped to temperatures in the range of 800&deg; to 1100&deg; Celsius, and preferably above 1000&deg; Celsius, so as to bond the plurality of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> together. It is contemplated to create the bond between the silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are ramped to 1000&deg; C. at a rate of 125&deg; C./sec, soaked at 1000&deg; Celsius for 5 minutes, and cooled to room temperature in &ap;5 seconds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> It can be appreciated that temperature measurement in the presence of intense electromagnetic fields is difficult under the best circumstances. In order to obtain such temperature measurement, an optical pyrometer or light-pipe <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, calibrated to the specific emissivity of silicon in the temperature range of interest (800-1100&deg; Celsius), is fed through the bottom <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of resonant chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Light pipe <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> allows the temperature to be accurately measured without perturbing the field patterns. In addition, light-pipe <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be used to obtain localized spatial measurements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, an alternate structure for electromagnetic induction heating a plurality of silicon wafers is generally designated by the reference numeral <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Structure <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes a radio frequency power generator <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> operatively connected to a radio frequency antenna <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. In the preferred embodiment, radio frequency antenna <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> takes the form a copper coil winding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> A plurality of layers such as silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are stacked upon each other and are positioned on a plurality of ceramic support rods <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> just below (e.g. 2.5 centimeters) radio frequency antenna <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Ceramic support rods <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> may be heated in any conventional manner to a user desired temperature between 20&deg; and 200&deg; Celsius, and preferably 150&deg; Celsius, in order to preheat silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to such point as to initiate coupling of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In operation, frequency power generator <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> provides current at a frequency less than 300 MHz through radio frequency antenna <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to induce magnetic field <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and electric field <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Fields <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> induce highly energetic electrons collide with the lattice of the silicon, transferring energy to the lattice in the form of heat. As the temperature of the silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> rises, additional electrons move into the conduction band and are available to flow as current, thereby increasing the power absorbed by silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. This process continues until radiation losses equal the power absorbed, forcing a steady state operating point. As described, silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be rapidly ramped to temperatures in the range of 800&deg; to 1100&deg; Celsius, and preferably above 1000&deg; Celsius, so as to bond the plurality of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> together. As heretofore described, to create the bond between the plurality of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are ramped to 1000&deg; Celsius at a rate of 125&deg; C./sec, soaked at 1000&deg; Celsius for 5 minutes, and cooled to room temperature in &ap;5 seconds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In order to obtain such temperature measurement, an optical pyrometer or light pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, calibrated to the specific emissivity of silicon in the temperature range of interest (800-1100&deg; Celsius), is positioned adjacent silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Light pipe is operatively connected to various sensor electronics <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> by optical fiber <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. Sensor electronics <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> process the signals received from light pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> such that light pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> may be used to the temperature to be accurately measure the temperature of the silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> without perturbing the field patterns. In addition, light pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> may be used to obtain localized spatial measurements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Surface preparation is an important step in conventional wafer bonding, as well as, in EMIH bonding. Poor surface preparation can result in voids, particularly when rapid temperature ramps are used. During the heating process, adsorbed water trapped between the wafer surfaces quickly vaporizes and expands, increasing local pressures along the bond interface. This pressure can force the surfaces of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> apart, creating voids in an otherwise uniform bond. Furthermore, the oxygen present in the water may react locally with the silicon surface to form silicon dioxide, making uneven the surface over which the bond is formed. In extreme cases, silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may delaminate during the temperature ramp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In order to minimize the possibility of void formation along the bond interfaces of the plurality of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be cleaned prior to EMIH. The silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are first cleaned in a NaOH:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius, followed by a H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius, and finally dipped in dilute (100:1) HF to remove any residual oxide layer. Silicon wafers may then be rinsed in deionized water and spun completely dry to minimize the amount of residual moisture on the surfaces of the silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Once dry, silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are immediately pressed together, and thereafter, bonded together as heretofore described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated to clean the silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in other manners including, but are not limited to, oxygen plasma or hydrogen plasma treatments followed by a vigorous rinse in deionized water. It is intended for the cleaning of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to remove particulates and contaminants from the surface of silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and to condition such surfaces for optimal bonding prior to the stacking the silicon wafers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> While the method of the present invention has been described in connection with silicon-silicon bonding, it can be appreciated that other types of bonding, such as silicon-on-insulator bonding, are contemplated without deviating from the scope of the present invention. Further, the bonding of materials such as Germanium and Si&mdash;Ge hybrid materials are contemplated as being within the scope of the present invention. As such, it can be appreciated that various modes of carrying out the invention are contemplated as being within the scope of the following claims particularly pointing out and distinctly claiming the subject matter which is regarded as the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of bonding multiple layers, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>stacking the multiple layers on top of each other; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>generating an electromagnetic field which intersects and heats the multiple layers to a predetermined temperature. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a resonant cavity extending along a longitudinal axis, the cavity having length which is adjustable along the axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the stack of multiple layers in the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the stack of multiple layers are positioned within the cavity at a predetermined location wherein the intensity of the electromagnetic field is maximized. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of adjusting the length of cavity to a user selected length to vary the electromagnetic field. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of generating electromagnetic fields includes injecting microwave radiation into the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of tuning the microwave radiation to minimize reflections from the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of generating the electromagnetic field includes the step of generating a magnetic field which intersects the stack of multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of generating a magnetic field includes the steps of providing a conducting material and passing a current at a predetermined frequency through the conducting material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the predetermined frequency is less than 300 MHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of preheating the stack of multiple layers to a coupling temperature so as to initiate bonding of the multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the coupling temperature is between 20&deg; and 200&deg; Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the predetermined temperature is between 800&deg; and 1100&deg; Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the additional step of cleaning the multiple layers prior to stacking the multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of bringing the multiple layers into contact after the step of stacking the multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of cleaning the multiple layers includes the steps: 
<claim-text>depositing each of the multiple layers in a NaOH:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing each of the multiple layers in a H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of cleaning the multiple layers includes the additional steps: 
<claim-text>dipping each of the multiple layers in dilute (100:1) HF; </claim-text>
<claim-text>rinsing each of the multiple layers in deionized water; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>spinning the multiple layers completely dry. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method of bonding multiple layers, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>stacking the multiple layers on top of each other; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>volumetrically heating the stack of multiple layers to a predetermined temperature. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of heating the stack of multiple layers includes the step of generating an electromagnetic field which intersects the stack of the multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a resonant cavity extending along a longitudinal axis, the cavity having length which is adjustable along the axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the stack of multiple layers in the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the stack of multiple layers are positioned within the cavity at a predetermined location wherein the intensity of the electromagnetic field is maximized. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of adjusting the length of cavity to a user selected length to vary the electromagnetic field. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of generating electromagnetic fields includes injecting microwave radiation into the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of tuning the microwave radiation to minimize reflections from the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of heating the stack of multiple layers includes the step of generating a magnetic field which intersects the stack of multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of generating the magnetic field includes the steps of providing a conducting material and passing a current at a predetermined frequency through the conducting material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the wherein the predetermined frequency is less than 300 MHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of preheating the stack of multiple layers to a coupling temperature so as to initiate bonding of the multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the coupling temperature is between 20&deg; and 200&deg; Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the predetermined temperature is between 800&deg; and 1100&deg; Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the additional step of cleaning the multiple layers prior to stacking the multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of bringing the multiple layers into contact after the step of stacking the multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of cleaning the multiple layers includes the steps: 
<claim-text>depositing each of the multiple layers in a NaOH:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing each of the multiple layers in a H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of cleaning the multiple layers includes the additional steps: 
<claim-text>dipping each of the multiple layers in dilute (100:1) HF; </claim-text>
<claim-text>rinsing each of the multiple layers in deionized water; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>spinning the multiple layers completely dry. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the stack of multiple layers is heated by electromagnetic induction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A method of bonding multiple layers, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>depositing each of the multiple layers in a NaOH:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing each of the multiple layers in a H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>:H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O (5:1) solution at 80&deg; Celsius; </claim-text>
<claim-text>pressing the multiple layers together to form a stack; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>volumetrically heating the stack to a predetermined temperature. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of heating the stack includes the step of generating an electromagnetic field which intersects the stack. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a resonant cavity extending along a longitudinal axis, the cavity having length which is adjustable along the axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the stack in the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the stack is positioned within the cavity at a predetermined location wherein the intensity of the electromagnetic field is maximized. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of adjusting the length of cavity to a user selected length to vary the electromagnetic field. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of generating the electromagnetic field includes injecting microwave radiation into the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of tuning the microwave radiation to minimize reflections from the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of heating the stack includes the step of generating a magnetic field which intersects the stack of multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of generating the magnetic field includes the steps of providing a conducting material and passing a current at a predetermined frequency through the conducting material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the predetermined frequency is less than 300 MHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> comprising the additional step of preheating the stack to a coupling temperature so as to initiate bonding of the multiple layers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the coupling temperature is between 200 and 200&deg; Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the predetermined temperature is between 800&deg; and 1100&deg; Celsius. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the stack is heated by electromagnetic induction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the additional step of cleaning the multiple layers by: 
<claim-text>dipping each of the multiple layers in dilute (100:1) HF; </claim-text>
<claim-text>rinsing each of the multiple layers in deionized water; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>spinning the multiple layers completely dry.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000638A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000638A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
