<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000872A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000872A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000872A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000872A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000872A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000872A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000872A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000872A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000872</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10187421</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>1018427</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>NL</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B07C005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>209</class>
<subclass>577000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>250</class>
<subclass>559460</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus for checking products with labels</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Petrus</given-name>
<middle-name>Antonius, J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Alberts</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Hengelo</city>
<country-code>NL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HOFFMANN &amp; BARON, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>6900 JERICHO TURNPIKE</address-1>
<city>SYOSSET</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>11791</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method for checking products with labels, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="2">a product is formed and is provided on one side, in particular an outer side, with a label which, at least in fitted condition, forms at least one closed surface; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0003" lvl="2">the product is brought between a light source and a light-sensitive device; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0004" lvl="2">with the light-sensitive device, the pattern and/or intensity of light originating from the light source and falling through the product, in particular through and/or alongside the label, is measured; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0005" lvl="2">wherein the light-sensitive device produces a rejection signal if the pattern and/or the intensity do not agree with a pre-set pattern and/or intensity. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method for checking products with labels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> It is known to provide products with decorations by providing labels thereon. These labels may be adhered to the inside or outside of a product or, preferably, are provided by in-mold labeling technique. These labels moreover, besides providing the decoration, typically afford protection of goods to be packaged in the products, for instance from the influence of light. In this connection it is highly important for the labels to be fitted in the correct manner. In substantially rectangular holder-shaped products, often labels are used that in flat condition have roughly the shape of a Maltese cross, that is, a central surface having four adjoining cross surfaces. The central surface is then placed against the bottom of the holder, the cross surfaces against the four side surfaces of the holder. The cross surfaces must adjoin each other accurately along the ribs of adjacent side surfaces, such that no light can pass between these surfaces and, moreover, any decorations continue across the ribs. If this has been achieved to an insufficient extent, the products are rejected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Commonly, products are inspected visually. To that end, the products in a production line are looked at by quality inspectors, who remove poorly labeled products from the production line. In more advanced methods, cameras with pattern recognition means are used. The labels are then provided with printings recognizable to the pattern recognition means, which printings can be compared with pre-inputted patterns. In case of insufficient agreement, the product involved is removed. These known methods have the drawback that they are particularly labor-intensive and moreover lead to an undesirably high percentage of errors. In the known method, the use of the pattern recognition means moreover leads to the drawback that only specific patterns are recognizable. Furthermore, for this purpose, a relatively large number of cameras must be used, which is costly and involves susceptibility to trouble. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The invention has for its object to provide a method of the type described in the opening paragraph, in which the above drawbacks of the known methods are avoided, while retaining the advantages thereof. To that end, a method according to the invention is characterized by the measures according to claim 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In a method according to the invention, use is made of a light source and light-sensitive means to trace any errors in a product with a label. It has been found that with a method according to the invention errors can be traced particularly fast and accurately. In the method, moreover, use can be made of simple light-sensitive means. Especially if use is made of both measurement of light falling through and of pattern recognition, a particularly high accuracy can be achieved. Moreover, by means of a rejection signal other parts of the same or a different apparatus may be controlled, for instance discharge means for rejected products or means for positioning the labels. Thus, an optimally automated method can be obtained for manufacturing and checking products with labels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The invention further relates to an apparatus for checking products with labels. According to the invention, such an apparatus is characterized by the features according to claim 7. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In an apparatus according to the invention, use is made of a light source and light-sensitive means to trace any errors in a product with a label. It has been found that with an apparatus according to the invention errors can be traced very fast and accurately and use can be made of simple light-sensitive means. Especially if use is made of both measurement of light falling through and pattern recognition, a particularly high accuracy can be achieved. Moreover, by means of a rejection signal, other parts of the same or a different apparatus may be controlled, for instance discharge means for rejected products or means for positioning the labels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An apparatus according to the invention is particularly suitable for checking in-mold labeled injection molded products to be used as packages, with both the bottom and the longitudinal walls labeled, and the labels having edge portions adjoining each other, in particular adjacent the ribs of the holder. An apparatus according to the invention is preferably provided with a table having an opening against which or over which the holder can be placed by an open side thereof, the table being provided with an abutment edge around the opening to provide a substantially light-tight seal between the holder and the table. Thus, the desired light-tightness of the holder can be checked particularly fast. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> An apparatus according to the invention is preferably provided with a discharge device controlled on the basis of the presence or absence of a rejection signal for a respective product. Thus, products can be automatically conveyed further for later use or be discharged if the labels have not been provided in the correct manner or if other defects are established. The products are preferably supplied by means of belt conveyer means and picked up and displaced within the apparatus with the aid of suction means, at least reduced pressure means, such as suction cups, or the like. By these means, the products can be picked up and displaced simply, rapidly, and accurately, without damage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> An apparatus according to the invention is preferably of such design that at least two products can be handled simultaneously, in particular can be checked simultaneously. Also, the apparatus may be of such design that in each case two juxtaposed feeding and discharge means make use of a checking apparatus disposed between them and comprising the at least one light source and light-sensitive device. Furthermore, it is then preferred that the apparatus be of modular construction, such that it can be easily and rapidly adapted to other types of products. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Further advantageous embodiments of an apparatus and a method according to the invention are described in the subclaims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> To clarify the invention, exemplary embodiments of an apparatus and a method according to the invention will be elucidated in more detail with reference to the drawing. In the drawing: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a label in flat condition; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> diagrammatically shows, in perspective elevation, a holder provided with a label according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> diagrammatically shows, in perspective elevation, a portion of a label fitted in the right condition; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> diagrammatically shows, in perspective elevation, a portion of an incorrectly fitted label; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> diagrammatically shows, in top plan view, an apparatus according to the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> diagrammatically shows, in side elevation, an apparatus according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In this description, the same or corresponding parts have the same or corresponding reference numerals. In this description, by way of example, a holder, for instance a tub of butter, with a label is shown. It will be clear, however, that all kinds of other products can also be checked in the same manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows, in flat condition, a label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for use on a holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comprises a substantially rectangular central surface <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and four cross surfaces <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>extending therefrom, so that the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is somewhat in the shape of a Maltese cross. The holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises a bottom surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and four side walls <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, to some extent diverging from the bottom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> may, for instance, be provided on one side with an adhesive layer and be adhered to the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, with the central surface <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> being adhered to the bottom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the holder and the cross surfaces <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>being adhered to the respective side walls <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. Preferably, however, the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is provided in a mold cavity (not shown), after which the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is injection molded against the label, in a known manner with in-mold labeling technique, so that an integral connection is obtained between the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The cross surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has a side edge <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the cross surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>has a side edge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, which side edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> meet in an angular point <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the central surface <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows, in perspective elevation, a corner of the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> with a label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> provided thereon, with the angular point <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> coinciding with a corner <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The cross surfaces <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are folded against the side walls <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, such that the longitudinal edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the respective side surfaces <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>touch each other along the ribs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. In a comparable manner, the other cross surfaces <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>are folded against the respective side walls <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, so that the longitudinal edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> thereof lie against each other. The rib <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is thus no longer visible. Provided on the outer sides of the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is a printing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, for instance lines or text (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, this printing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> continues across the ribs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> from one cross surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the adjacent cross surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. If the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has been fitted correctly, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, for instance a continuous pattern <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is thus obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the same corner <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the holder, on which, however, the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has been provided incorrectly. Visible between the side edge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the cross surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and the side wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the cross surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is the rib <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> as well as an uncovered part of the side wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The printing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, in particular the lines, do not continue across the rib <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, so that an unwanted pattern is obtained. The position of the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> on the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be checked with an apparatus according to the invention, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The apparatus <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> according to the invention is shown in part in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, comprising two feed-through paths <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for feeding through products, such as the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. For clarity&apos;s sake, the holders <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are omitted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, whilst the apparatus <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is shown diagrammatically of the apparatus <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, specifically the left-hand path <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>will be described. The right-hand path <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>B is substantially identical thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The apparatus <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> comprises first feeding means <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, a table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> linking up with the leading end <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the first feeding means <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, as well as discharge means <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, comprising a valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, arranged on the side of the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> remote from the first feeding means <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and conveying means <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> placed therebelow, in particular a conveyor belt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The first feeding means <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> have a conveying direction T in the direction of the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the conveyor belt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> has a conveying direction K approximately at right angles to the conveying direction T. Connected on the side of the valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> remote from the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are second discharge means <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the first feeding mean <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the second discharge means <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are designed as two circular conveyor belts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> extending side by side, on which holders <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be supported. The holders <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, are arranged upside down, that is, with the bottom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> directed upwards, remote from the belt <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The belt elements <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> have been passed around guide wheels <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is centrally provided with an opening <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, around which extends a groove <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> in which a longitudinal edge <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be received with a proper fit, such that a substantially light-tight seal is obtained between the groove <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, at least the table <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, and the longitudinal edge <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> has an outwardly bent longitudinal edge <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, as known, for instance, in tubs of (low-fat) margarine, on which longitudinal edge <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> a lid (not shown) can be placed. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> this edge is omitted, for clarity&apos;s sake. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is placed on rails <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> by way of rollers <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, such that the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can be rolled in a direction S, at right angles to the conveying direction T. Provided between the tables <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the paths <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, between the rails <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, is a light box <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> in sectional view. Included in the light box <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is a light source <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, for instance a tubular lamp <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> the distance between the underside of the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the light box <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is represented as being relatively large. In reality, the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> will preferably move closely above the light box <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. During use, the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can be moved with the opening <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> above the tubular lamp <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, for instance by driving one of the rollers <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> with a motor <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, such that light from the light source <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> can reach through the opening <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> into the inner space of a holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> supported on the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Light from the light source <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> will fall through the side walls <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the bottom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and in some measure through the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. There will be a difference between the light falling through parts of the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> covered by the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and parts not covered by the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Especially relevant here is the difference in light falling through correctly fitted labels <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, in particular between the longitudinal edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and incorrectly fitted labels, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, so that space exists between the longitudinal edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and light shines through the uncovered part of the side wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Provided between the paths <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is a light-sensitive device <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, in the embodiment shown in the form of three cameras <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. It is also possible to use different numbers of cameras, possibly just one camera centrally above the light box <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The cameras are connected via suitable cable work <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> to a central control unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, with which, in a manner to be described hereinafter, inter alia the valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be controlled, as well as the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and transport means <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, with which a holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be picked up and placed on the table or can be picked up from the table and placed on the valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> or the second discharge means <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, depending on signals to be described hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> With the light-sensitive device <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, during use, a holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> placed between the light source <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and the light-sensitive device <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can be checked, whereby light from the light source <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> shining through the holder can be observed, yielding an image which can be compared by means of the control unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> with a previously inputted image or pattern matching a holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the subject type on which the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has been fitted correctly, as shown, for instance, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Moreover, permissible tolerances may be inputted in the control unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, for instance a quantity of light failing between longitudinal edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that is considered permissible. In the event of a deviation from the desired image that is greater than is considered permissible, the control unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> produces a signal which can be designated as rejection signal. With this signal, the valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be controlled. This valve can be opened on the basis of a rejection signal, such that a rejected holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, that is, a holder whose image observed by the light-sensitive device <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> deviates unduly from the desired image, can pass the valve and be received in the discharge device <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, so that it can be carried off by the belt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, for instance for recycling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Provided above each path <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is a transfer device <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> supported by guide rails <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> extending in the conveying direction T. The transfer device <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> carries piston-cylinder assemblies <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> provided with suction cups <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> which, by means of the piston-cylinder assemblies <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, can be placed against the product <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, in particular the bottom <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, whereupon a reduced pressure can be generated in the suction cups <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> to pick up the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. To that end, the piston-cylinder assemblies <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the suction cups <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are connected via a line <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> with a pneumatic device <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. After the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> has been seized with the suction cups <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, it can be lifted from the feeding means <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and be transferred to the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with the transfer device <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. There the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> will be released and with the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> be moved in the direction S to above the tubular lamp <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. In that position, the tubular lamp <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is switched on, and with the light-sensitive device <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> an image of light passing through the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, in particular through and alongside the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, is recorded and transmitted to the central control unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, in which the image is compared with the desired image. Next, the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is moved back into the path <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, where the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is picked up again with the transfer device <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and is moved further in the direction T, at least to above the valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. If on the basis of this holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> a rejection signal has been produced by the central control unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, the valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is controlled to open and the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is released above the thus created opening, so that it falls onto the belt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and can be carried off for recycling. If on the basis of this holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> no rejection signal is produced, or possibly an acceptance signal, then the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is moved further by means of the transfer device <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> to above the second discharge means <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and set down thereon, so that the holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be passed further for further processing, for instance to be filled, at least stacked for further use. It will be clear, for that matter, that cracks or other imperfections in the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can also be observed with an apparatus according to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> It is preferred that with the light-sensitive device <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> not only an image of transmitted light is formed, but also that by means of pattern recognition the labeling is examined and is compared with a desired labeling image. Thus the printing of the label <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be checked as well, as a second check. If the correct printing, at least the correct condition of the printing, has not been obtained, likewise a rejection signal can be produced, with the consequences described earlier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> It is preferred that at least two transfer devices <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> are provided, one after the other in the conveying direction T, with which at the same time a holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be picked up from the first feeding means <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and a holder <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be picked up from the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the two holders can be moved at the same time, one to the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the other to the valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> or the second discharge means <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, depending on the presence or absence of the rejection signal. Thus, a large number of holders can be checked still faster. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The invention is by no means limited to the exemplary embodiments shown in the description and the drawing. Many variations thereof are possible within the scope of the invention outlined by the claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> For instance, the discharge device may be designed in many ways, with the valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> possibly omitted. For instance, in the event of a rejection signal, holders may be blown away from the second discharge means or be put away beside the second discharge means in a different manner. In the condition shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, two paths <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, b </italic></highlight>are shown, allowing the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the left-hand path <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the table of the right-hand path <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to be alternately moved above the light source <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> for alternately testing holders. However, it is, of course, also possible for each path <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> to be provided with a light source. Also, the light source <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> could be arranged directly below the path <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, in which case, however, a different arrangement of the light-sensitive device <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is to be chosen to avoid collision of the transfer device <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and the light-sensitive device <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Also, holders <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may, for instance, be moved over the light box <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> directly with a belt conveyor, such as the first feeding means <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, so that the holders can be moved directly between the light source and the light-sensitive device. Additionally, for instance the light box, at least the light source, may be arranged for movement in vertical direction, so that it can be moved closely below or even into the holder. Furthermore, the light source may be placed above and the light-sensitive device below the path, or on opposite sides thereof, while the position of the tested products may be simply adjusted. It will be clear that with an apparatus according to the invention, also differently shaped products, for instance flat products, may be tested, in all of which cases a desired image can be stored in the control unit <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> for comparison with a current observed image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> These and many comparable variations are understood to fall within the scope of the invention outlined by the claims. </paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for checking products with labels, wherein: 
<claim-text>a product is formed and is provided on one side, in particular an outer side, with a label which, at least in fitted condition, forms at least one closed surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the product is brought between a light source and a light-sensitive device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>with the light-sensitive device, the pattern and/or intensity of light originating from said light source and falling through the product, in particular through and/or alongside the label, is measured; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the light-sensitive device produces a rejection signal if said pattern and/or said intensity do not agree with a pre-set pattern and/or intensity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein on the basis of said rejection signal a discharge device is energized for leading the respective product out of a product stream, in particular to a recycling unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said discharge device comprises at least one valve, which, in closed condition, allows said product stream to pass and, on the basis of said rejection signal, is controlled to open, such that said product on the basis of which said rejection signal has been produced, falls out of the product stream, after which the at least one valve is controlled to close again. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the products are holder-shaped and are provided with said at least one label by in-mold labeling technique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the products are moved over the light source, and the light-sensitive device comprises at least one camera, with which at least one pattern of light from the light source failing through openings in the label can be recognized for comparison with a comparative pattern stored in the light-sensitive device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the products are fed and discharged in a first direction, the products are moved out of the product stream in lateral direction with respect to said first direction to a position between said light source and said light-sensitive device, and after measurement are returned to the product stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for checking products with labels, comprising: 
<claim-text>feeding means for feeding products provided on at least one side, in particular an outer side, with a label which, at least in fitted condition, forms at least one closed surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a light source and a light-sensitive device, as well as positioning means for positioning a product between the light source and the light-sensitive device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>recognition means for comparing a pattern of light originating from said light source and falling through the product, in particular through and/or alongside the label, measured with the light-sensitive device, with a reference pattern stored in the recognition means; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein signaling means are provided for producing a rejection signal if said pattern does not agree with a pre-set pattern. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the feeding means comprise suction means for picking up products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, wherein the positioning means comprise at least one movable table for bringing the products between the light source and the light-sensitive device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the table comprises at least one opening, as well as abutment means surrounding said at least one opening for sealing abutment against a product, such that during use light from the light source failing through the at least one opening can reach the light-sensitive device only through said product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An apparatus according to any one of claims <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein the feeding means comprise belt-shaped conveying means which connect to the positioning means and can support the products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An apparatus according to any one of claims <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, wherein a discharge device is provided, controllable on the basis of said rejection signal, between a first position in which a product can pass the discharge device if no rejection signal is produced and a second position in which a product is received in the discharge device if a rejection signal is produced. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the discharge device comprises at least one valve, movable between a first closed position and a second open position; wherein a product is movable from a set-up position over the valve when the valve is in the first position or along the valve into the discharge device when the valve is in the second position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein suction means are provided for displacing a product to above or beyond said valve, depending on said rejection signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An apparatus according to any one of claims <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, wherein the means are provided for simultaneously checking at least two products.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000872A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000872A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000872A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000872A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
