<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003384A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003384A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003384</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10178234</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020625</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-198744</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03B027/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G03F009/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G03C005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>430</class>
<subclass>022000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>430</class>
<subclass>030000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>355</class>
<subclass>018000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Aligning method, exposure method, exposure apparatus, and device manufacturing method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tai</given-name>
<family-name>Hoshi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Canon Kabushiki Kaisha</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>FITZPATRICK CELLA HARPER &amp; SCINTO</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>30 ROCKEFELLER PLAZA</address-1>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10112</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">According to an aligning method, positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate are measured, measurement values are statistically processed, and a master and the substrate are aligned. When a plurality of measurement marks exist in a shot, measurement marks to be used for alignment are selected from them independently of each other. An alignment measurement sample shot which is not adversely affected by a shot size is selected, so an alignment precision is improved. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an aligning method, exposure method, and exposure apparatus used for manufacturing various types of devices, e.g., a semiconductor element such as an IC or LSI, a display element such as a liquid crystal panel, a detection element such as a magnetic head, and an image sensing element such as a CCD, and a device manufacturing method. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> For example, in a photolithography process for manufacturing a semiconductor element and the like, an exposure apparatus for transferring a pattern on a master (mask or reticle) onto a substrate (wafer or glass plate) coated with a photoresist is used. Recently, a reduction projection exposure apparatus which is advantageous in terms of resolution and aligning precision has been used. Usually, a semiconductor element is manufactured by forming multilevel circuit patterns on a plurality of shot regions arrayed on a substrate by using different masters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A shot array comprised of a plurality of shots arranged on the substrate will be called a shot layout. The shot layout is formed by considering the size of the substrate, the sizes of the shot regions, the sizes of the chip regions, and the like. A necessary number of shots selected from the shot layout in order to overlay circuits for forming the multilevel circuits described above are called sample shots. The sample shots are usually selected automatically. As a sample shot selecting method, methods disclosed in Japanese Patent Laid-Open Nos. 63-232324 and 63-232325 are known. The sample shot selecting method is important in overlay accuracy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, concerning selection of the sample shots, when an arbitrary number of shots are specified, the arbitrary number is arithmetically processed from the shot layout described above on the basis of the central coordinates of the shots arranged in the shot layout. As in the conventional case, when the shot size is comparatively small and the required precision is comparatively moderate, the shot center and an alignment measurement mark position which is used for actual overlaying can be treated to be identical while causing no problems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In recent years, the size of the semiconductor element increases, a region (angle of field) that can be exposed by one shot is widened in order to improve the productivity, and requirement for improving the overlay accuracy has become stricter. Thus, an adverse influence produced by treating the shot center and the alignment measurement mark position to be identical becomes no longer negligible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, measurement marks are arranged for each measurement direction (X and Y directions) (X-direction marks are arranged along a transverse scribing line and Y-direction marks are arranged along a vertical scribing line), so a measurement error is minimized. However, in order to improve the productivity, marks with which the measurement time can be shortened, i.e., measurement marks with which both the X and Y directions can be measured simultaneously, are employed. Also, in order to correct the shot shape, multi-point measurement marks are arranged within the shot. This makes it difficult to improve the precision when sample shot selection is performed in the conventional manner by treating the shot center and the measurement mark position to be identical. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As described above, in conventional sample shot selection for performing overlaying, the arithmetic process is performed on the basis of the shot center. On the shot layout, even if the sample shots can be arranged in the vicinities of positions at the equal distance from the substrate center, when the positions of actual alignment measurement marks arranged in the shot do not correspond to the shot center, the measurement mark positions are deviated from the substrate center. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In fact, the overlaying measurement marks in the shot are rarely arranged at the shot center, and are usually formed in scribing line regions arranged between shots. Even if the centers of selected sample shots can be arranged at the equal distance from the substrate center, for example, the X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement mark positions are displaced from the shot center by half the shot size at minimum. This appears as a deviation amount from the substrate center. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In an ideal state, this deviation amount does not adversely affect the overlay accuracy. In fact, however, a measurement error caused depending on the coating uniformity of the resist, and a position detection error such as expansion/contraction of the substrate which is caused by annealing of the substrate exist. When these errors exist and the deviation of measurement mark positions from the substrate center is present, an error occurs in a correction amount obtained by a statistical process, to adversely affect the overlay accuracy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> For example, assume that X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement marks are used. When the shot size is 20 mm and a substrate magnification component produced by manufacturing process factors is 5 ppm, a shift component produced by the overlaying measurement value is about 50 nm when compared to a case with no substrate magnification component. This cannot be neglected when compared to a recent required overlay accuracy of 30 nm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> It is known that the measurement error caused depending on the coating uniformity of the resist, and expansion/contraction of the substrate which is caused by annealing of the substrate occur radially from the substrate center and equally concentrically due to the manufacturing process. Also, the expansion/contraction in the radial direction varies in accordance with the manufacturing process and the density of the circuit pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In order to decrease an influence to the overlay accuracy caused by the manufacturing process factors, the present invention has as its object to provide an automatic selecting method for alignment measurement sample shots which is not adversely affected by the shot size. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The present invention has been proposed to solve the conventional problems, and has as its object to provide an aligning method, an exposure apparatus employing the alignment method, and a device manufacturing method employing the exposure apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve the above object, an aligning method, an exposure apparatus employing the alignment method, and a device manufacturing method employing the exposure apparatus according to the present invention are characterized mainly by the following steps and arrangements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> More specifically, in an aligning method according to the present invention, an aligning method of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, wherein when a plurality of measurement marks exist related a shot, measurement marks to be used for alignment are selected therefrom independently of each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In an aligning method according to the present invention, an aligning method of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, wherein a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate on the basis of the shot positions or the positions of the measurement marks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In an aligning method according to the present invention, an aligning method of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, wherein a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate on the basis of distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In an aligning method according to the present invention, an aligning method of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, wherein a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate so as to be distributed in the vicinities of positions with which distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks are equal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Preferably, in any one of the above aligning methods, when the necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from the plurality of shots on the substrate, distances between a center of the substrate and the measurement marks are calculated, allowable values of differences in distance between the center of the substrate and the measurement marks are input for all the marks or for each mark, and whether the allowable values are satisfied is checked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> An exposure apparatus according to the present invention comprises an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by the alignment unit, wherein when a plurality of measurement marks exist in a shot, the alignment unit selects measurement marks to be used for alignment therefrom independently of each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> An exposure apparatus according to the present invention comprises: an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by the alignment unit, wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer on the basis of the shot positions or the positions of the measurement marks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> An exposure apparatus according to the present invention comprises: an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by the alignment unit, wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer on the basis of distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> An exposure apparatus according to the present invention comprises: an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by the alignment unit, wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer so as to be distributed in the vicinities of positions with which distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks are equal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> An exposure method according to the present invention comprises: the aligning step of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and the projecting and exposing step of projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned in the aligning step, wherein when a plurality of measurement marks exist in a shot, measurement marks to be used for alignment are selected therefrom independently of each other in the aligning step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> An exposure method according to the present invention comprises: the aligning step of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and the projecting and exposing step of projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned in the aligning step, wherein in the aligning step, a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate on the basis of the shot positions or the positions of the measurement marks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> An exposure method according to the present invention comprises: the aligning step of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and the projecting and exposing step of projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned in the aligning step, wherein in the aligning step, a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate on the basis of distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> An exposure method according to the present invention comprises: the measuring step of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and the projecting and exposing step of projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned in the aligning step, wherein in the aligning step, a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate so as to be distributed in the vicinities of positions with which distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks are equal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> A device manufacturing method according to the present invention comprises the steps of: installing a plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses including an exposure apparatus at a factory; and manufacturing a semiconductor device by using the plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses, the exposure apparatus comprising an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, and a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by the alignment unit, wherein when a plurality of measurement marks exist in a shot, the alignment unit selects measurement marks to be used for alignment therefrom independently of each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A device manufacturing method according to the present invention comprises the steps of: installing a plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses including an exposure apparatus at a factory; and manufacturing a semiconductor device by using the plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses, the exposure apparatus comprising an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, and a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by the alignment unit, wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer on the basis of the shot positions or the positions of the measurement marks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> A device manufacturing method according to the present invention comprises the steps of: installing a plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses including an exposure apparatus at a factory; and manufacturing a semiconductor device by using the plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses, the exposure apparatus comprising an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, and a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by the alignment unit, wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer on the basis of distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> A device manufacturing method according to the present invention comprises the steps of: installing a plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses including an exposure apparatus at a factory; and manufacturing a semiconductor device by using the plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses, the exposure apparatus comprising an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, and a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by the alignment unit, wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer so as to be distributed in the vicinities of positions with which distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks are equal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Other features and advantages of the present invention will be apparent from the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which like reference characters designate the same or similar parts throughout the figures thereof.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of the specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a view showing an alignment unit according to an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a view showing a layout within a shot of measurement marks (X- and Y-direction independent measurement marks); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a view showing a layout within a shot of measurement marks (X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement marks); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a view showing a layout of sample shots for overlaying when the X- and Y-direction independent measurement marks according to the present invention are used; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a view showing a layout of sample shots for overlaying when the X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement marks according to the present invention are used; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flow chart for determining sample shot selection; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing a semiconductor device manufacturing process; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a detailed flow chart of the wafer process of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows a layout of sample shots for overlaying when conventional X- and Y-direction independent measurement marks are used; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> shows a layout of sample shots for overlaying when conventional X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement marks are used; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a view showing the schematic arrangement of an exposure apparatus incorporating an alignment unit according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments of the present invention will now be described in detail in accordance with the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> &lt;First Embodiment&gt;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows an alignment unit according to the present invention. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, reference symbol R denotes a retile; and W, a wafer. Reference numeral <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> denotes a projection lens, and reference symbol S denotes an alignment optical system. Of the constituent elements of the alignment optical system S, reference numeral <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> denotes an alignment illumination unit; <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a beam splitter; <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, an alignment scope; and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, an image sensing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Illumination light from the alignment illumination unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> irradiates a mark on the wafer W through the beam splitter <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and projection lens <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The image of the mark is formed on the image sensing device <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> through the projection lens <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, beam splitter <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and alignment scope <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An A/D converter <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> converts an image sensing signal from the image sensing device <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> into a digital signal. The digital signal is accumulated by an accumulator <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and subjected to position detection by a position detector <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Position measurement information of the respective marks are statistically processed by a controller <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and converted into grid information indicating the position, magnification, and rotation of the wafer W as a whole. A stage driver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> drives an X-Y stage <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> on the basis of this information to move the wafer W. Reference numeral <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> denotes a storage for storing information necessary for the process. A so-called TTL type alignment unit which detects a mark on the wafer W through the projection lens <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has been described. Alternatively, an off-axis alignment unit may be used instead. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As examples of the layout in the shot according to the present invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a layout within a shot of X- and Y-direction independent measurement marks, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a layout within a shot of X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement marks. Reference numeral <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> denotes an X-direction measurement mark; <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a Y-direction measurement mark; and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, an X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement mark. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a view showing a layout of sample shots for overlaying when conventional X- and Y-direction independent measurement marks are used, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a view showing a layout of sample shots for overlaying when the X- and Y-direction independent measurement marks according to the present invention are used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a view showing a layout of sample shots for overlaying when conventional X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement marks are used, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a view showing a layout of sample shots for overlaying when the X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement marks according to the present invention are used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>, reference numerals D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to D<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> denote conventional positions of sample shots. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>, deviation amounts of a measurement mark from the wafer center are indicated by Ox and Oy. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, reference numerals A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to A<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> denote sample shots for X-direction measurement; and B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to B<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, sample shots for Y-direction measurement. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, reference numerals C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to C<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> denote sample shots for X/Y-direction simultaneous measurement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The present invention is constituted by the first stage of calculating, when selecting a sample shot, measurement mark position coordinates on the wafer from shot position coordinates and measurement mark position coordinates within a shot, the second stage of selecting a sample shot on the basis of the information on the measurement mark position coordinates on the wafer, and the third stage of checking whether or not the mark position coordinates of the selected shot are within checking information input in advance. These stages will now be described individually. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Regarding calculation of the measurement mark position of the first stage, for example, when the measurement marks arranged in the shot are X- and Y-direction independent marks, the position coordinates of a sample shot candidate or of the measurement marks of all the shots are calculated from the mark layout within the shot shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> and the shot layout within a wafer shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The measurement marks are calculated from the shot position coordinates and the measurement mark position coordinates within the shot. When the mark coordinate position within the wafer is directly obtained in advance, its coordinates may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In the second stage, of the measurement mark coordinate positions present within the wafer, those which are in the vicinities of positions at the equal distance from the wafer center are selected, and that shot which has these measurement marks is selected as a sample shot. In the case of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the X- and Y-direction marks are arranged such that their coordinate positions are at the equal distance from the wafer center. In an actual case, however, the shot layout within the wafer, the size of the shot, and the measurement mark position within the shot vary, and it is impossible to arrange all the measurement marks at the equal distance from the wafer center. For this reason, selectable measurement mark coordinate positions are prioritized or conditions such as a measurement mark layout allowable range are added to them, and sample shot selection is performed, so sample shot selection can be performed practically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The sample shots shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> are selected completely independently in the X- and Y-directions. When compared to a case wherein X- and Y-direction measurement marks related one shot are used, different shots are selected for the respective measurement marks. Consequently, a stage driving distance for alignment measurement increases, which may decrease the throughput. In view of this, the middle point between the X and Y mark coordinates may be used as average coordinates for selecting the same sample shot in the X and Y direction as the measurement mark coordinates, or as the weighted position of the X and Y coordinates (X and Y barycentric coordinates). Then, sample shot selection more advantageous than conventional one can be performed without decreasing the throughput. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In the third stage, whether the measurement mark position coordinates of the sample shot selected in the second step is effective is checked. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, first, an allowable deviation amount of the measurement mark position is input as Ax and Ay in accordance with a necessary precision (S<highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>). Deviations of the measurement mark coordinates of the sample shot selected in the second stage are calculated for the respective measurement marks based on the distances from the wafer center which are already calculated in the second stage (S<highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight>). These deviations are defined as &Dgr;X and &Dgr;Y that satisfy: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&Dgr;<highlight><italic>X&gE;&Dgr;x</italic></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&Dgr;<highlight><italic>Y&gE;&Dgr;y</italic></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(2) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> If the conditions (1) and (2) are not satisfied (S<highlight><bold>630</bold></highlight>&mdash;No), this state is determined as a sample shot abnormality, and the operator is prompted to change the conditions. The operator changes the number of sample shots and the coordinates of other measurement marks (S<highlight><bold>640</bold></highlight>), and performs sample shot selection again (S<highlight><bold>650</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> If the allowable deviation amounts can be input for each measurement mark, it is effective in sample shot selection when the required precision differs between the X and Y directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> If the conditions (1) and (2) are satisfied (S<highlight><bold>630</bold></highlight>&mdash;Yes), the process is ended. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, the shot center and the measurement shot position are treated to be identical (a deviation of the measurement mark from the substrate center occurs, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>). In contrast to this, as described above, since the measurement marks are arranged in the vicinities of positions at the equal distance from the wafer center, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, no deviation occurs. Therefore, a measurement error caused by the process, which occurs radially from the wafer center, does not adversely affect the overlay accuracy, and the precision is improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Selection of measurement marks at the equal distance from the wafer center has been described. Alternatively, the measurement marks may be selected in accordance with other conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> &lt;Exposure Apparatus Incorporating Alignment Unit&gt;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a view showing the schematic arrangement of an exposure apparatus incorporating the alignment unit described above. In this exposure apparatus, a master (reticle, mask) <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> held by a master stage <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is illuminated by an illumination optical system <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. A pattern on the master <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> is projected onto a substrate (wafer) <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> on a substrate stage (wafer stage) <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> through a projection optical system <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, thereby exposing the substrate <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>. The alignment unit is adopted in alignment of the master <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> and substrate <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>, and the alignment process is performed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> In this manner, with the exposure apparatus incorporating the alignment unit according to the present invention, alignment of the master and substrate can be performed at high precision, so the exposure performance of the exposure apparatus can be improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> &lt;Device Manufacturing Method Using Exposure Apparatus&gt;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of a device manufacturing method using an exposure apparatus to which the alignment unit as described above is applied will be described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows the manufacturing flow of a semiconductor device (a semiconductor chip such as an IC or LSI, a liquid crystal panel, a CCD, a thin film magnetic head, a micromachine, and the like). In step S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (design circuit), a device pattern is designed. In step S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (fabricate mask), a mask as a mater on which the designed pattern is formed is fabricated. In step S<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> (manufacture wafer), a wafer is manufactured by using a material such as silicon. In step <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> (wafer process) called a pre-process, an actual circuit is formed on the wafer by lithography using the prepared mask and wafer. In step S<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> (assembly) called a post-process, a semiconductor chip is formed by using the wafer fabricated in step S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and includes processes such as an assembly process (dicing and bonding) and packaging process (chip encapsulation). In step S<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> (inspection), inspections such as the operation confirmation test and durability test of the semiconductor device manufactured in step <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are conducted. The semiconductor device is completed through these steps, and is shipped (step S<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows the detailed flow of the above wafer process. In step S<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (oxidation), the surface of the wafer is oxidized. In step S<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (CVD), an insulating film is formed on the wafer surface. In step S<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> (form electrode), an electrode is formed on the wafer by vapor deposition. In step S<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (implant ion), ions are implanted in the wafer. In step S<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> (resist processing), a photosensitive agent is applied to the wafer. In step S<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (exposure), the above-mentioned exposure apparatus or method exposes the circuit pattern of the mask to the wafer. In step S<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> (developing), the exposed wafer is developed. In step S<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (etching), the resist is etched except for the developed resist image. In step S<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> (remove resist), an unnecessary resist after etching is removed. These steps are repeated to form multiple circuit patterns on the wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> According to this embodiment, in the repeated processes, a high overlay accuracy can be obtained during exposure (step S<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>), as described above, so the semiconductor device manufacturing efficiency can be improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> As has been described above, according to the present invention, high-precision overlaying which is not adversely influenced by the manufacturing process can be performed. Since the overlaying operation is not adversely affected by the manufacturing process, the shift component of the overlaying operation in the process condition confirming operation performed at the beginning of a batch process (a group of substrates that are processed continuously at once under the same process conditions) becomes stable. Hence, the process condition confirming operation can be reduced or eliminated, thereby improving the productivity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> As many apparently widely different embodiments of the present invention can be made without departing from the spirit and scope thereof, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the specific embodiments thereof except as defined in the claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An aligning method of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, 
<claim-text>wherein when a plurality of measurement marks exist related a shot, measurement marks to be used for alignment are selected therefrom independently of each other. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An aligning method of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, 
<claim-text>wherein a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate on the basis of the shot positions or the positions of the measurement marks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An aligning method of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, 
<claim-text>wherein a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate on the basis of distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An aligning method of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, 
<claim-text>wherein a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate so as to be distributed in the vicinities of positions with which distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks are equal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from the plurality of shots on the substrate, distances between a center of the substrate and the measurement marks are calculated, allowable values of differences in distance between the center of the substrate and the measurement marks are input for all the marks or for each mark, and whether the allowable values are satisfied is checked. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from the plurality of shots on the substrate, distances between a center of the substrate and the measurement marks are calculated, allowable values of differences in distance between the center of the substrate and the measurement marks are input for all the marks or for each mark, and whether the allowable values are satisfied is checked. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from the plurality of shots on the substrate, distances between the center of the substrate and the measurement marks are calculated, allowable values of differences in distance between the center of the substrate and the measurement marks are input for all the marks or for each mark, and whether the allowable values are satisfied is checked. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An exposure apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by said alignment unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when a plurality of measurement marks exist in a shot, said alignment unit selects measurement marks to be used for alignment therefrom independently of each other. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An exposure apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by said alignment unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer on the basis of the shot positions or the positions of the measurement marks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An exposure apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by said alignment unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer on the basis of distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An exposure apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by said alignment unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer so as to be distributed in the vicinities of positions with which distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks are equal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An exposure method comprising: 
<claim-text>the aligning step of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the projecting and exposing step of projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned in the aligning step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when a plurality of measurement marks exist in a shot, measurement marks to be used for alignment are selected therefrom independently of each other in the aligning step. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An exposure method comprising: 
<claim-text>the aligning step of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the projecting and exposing step of projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned in the aligning step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein in the aligning step, a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate on the basis of the shot positions or the positions of the measurement marks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An exposure method comprising: 
<claim-text>the aligning step of measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the projecting and exposing step of projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned in the aligning step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein in the aligning step, a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate on the basis of distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An exposure method comprising: 
<claim-text>the measuring step of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the projecting and exposing step of projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned in the aligning step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein in the aligning step, a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment are selected from a plurality of shots on the substrate so as to be distributed in the vicinities of positions with which distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks are equal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A device manufacturing method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>installing a plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses including an exposure apparatus at a factory; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>manufacturing a semiconductor device by using the plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the exposure apparatus comprising 
<claim-text>an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by said alignment unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when a plurality of measurement marks exist in a shot, the alignment unit selects measurement marks to be used for alignment therefrom independently of each other. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A device manufacturing method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>installing a plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses including an exposure apparatus at a factory; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>manufacturing a semiconductor device by using the plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the exposure apparatus comprising 
<claim-text>an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by said alignment unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer on the basis of the shot positions or the positions of the measurement marks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A device manufacturing method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>installing a plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses including an exposure apparatus at a factory; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>manufacturing a semiconductor device by using the plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the exposure apparatus comprising 
<claim-text>an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by said alignment unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer on the basis of distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A device manufacturing method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>installing a plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses including an exposure apparatus at a factory; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>manufacturing a semiconductor device by using the plurality of semiconductor manufacturing apparatuses, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the exposure apparatus comprising 
<claim-text>an alignment unit for measuring positions of measurement marks at a plurality of shot positions on a substrate, statistically processing measurement values, and aligning a master and the substrate, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a projection exposure unit for projecting and exposing a pattern of the master onto the substrate aligned by said alignment unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the alignment unit selects a necessary number of shots to be used for alignment from a plurality of shots on the wafer so as to be distributed in the vicinities of positions with which distances between a center of the substrate and the positions of the measurement marks are equal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003384A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
