<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002027A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002027A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002027</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896230</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01N033/48</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>356</class>
<subclass>039000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Optical detection system for flow cytometry</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bernard</given-name>
<middle-name>Steven</middle-name>
<family-name>Fritz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Eagan</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HONEYWELL INTERNATIONAL INC.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>101 COLUMBIA ROAD</address-1>
<address-2>P O BOX 2245</address-2>
<city>MORRISTOWN</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>07962-2245</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An optical detection system for flow cytometry that uses two or more light sources positioned laterally at different distances from a central axis of a flow stream for providing light through different parts of the flow stream. One or more lenses are used to focus the light from the two or more light sources through the flow stream and onto a common focal point or region on the opposite side of the flow stream. One or more light detectors are then placed at, near or around the common focal point or region. A processor or the like receives at least one output signal from the one or more light detectors to analyze and determine selected characteristics of the flow stream. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED CO-PENDING APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This Application is related to co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/630,927 to Cabuz et al., filed Aug. 2, 2000, and entitled &ldquo;OPTICAL DETECTION SYSTEM FOR FLOW CYTOMETRY&rdquo;, which is incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to flow cytometers. More particularly, the present invention relates to optical detection systems for flow cytometer systems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Flow cytometry is a technique that is used to determine certain physical and chemical properties of microscopic biological particles by sensing certain optical properties of the particles. Flow cytometry is currently used in a wide variety of applications including hematology, immunology, genetics, food science, pharmacology, microbiology, parasitology and oncology. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In flow cytometry, the microscopic biological particles of a sample fluid are arranged in single file in a core stream, typically using hydrodynamic focusing. The particles are then individually interrogated by an optical detection system. The optical detection system provides a light beam, which is scattered by each particle to produce a scatter profile. The scatter profile is analyzed by measuring the light intensity at both small and larger scatter angles. Certain physical and/or chemical properties of each particle can then be determined from the scatter profile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Conventional cytometer systems use a single light source such as a laser to interrogate each particle. The light beam is often focused to an elongated shape that covers the uncertainty in particle position due to misalignment and variations in the width of the core stream. A limitation of using a single light source is that the particle position and variations in the width of the core stream cannot be directly detected. Misalignments in particle position and variations in the width of the core stream can be indicators of improper core formation. Because there may be no direct way of monitoring the characteristics of the core stream, improper core formation may go undetected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> This limitation may be further compounded because the single laser source configuration often does not provide a constant illumination intensity across the flow channel. As such, particles that pass more toward the edge of the core stream may not be as illuminated as particles that pass near the center. As a result, the sensitivity and accuracy of the system may vary depending on the lateral position of the particle through the focused elongated shape beam. Since there may be no easy way of detecting the lateral position of each particle, the variations in sensitivity and accuracy may go undetected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Another limitation of using a single light source is that the velocity of each particle cannot be directly determined. Particle velocity is often an important parameter in estimating the particle size from light scatter signals. In conventional flow cytometry systems, the velocity of each particle is extrapolated from the pump flow rates. Accordingly, to accurately gauge the velocity of each particle, the pumps must be very precise, the tolerance of the cytometer flow chambers must be tightly controlled, no fluid failures such as leaks can occur, and no obstructions such as microbubbles can be introduced to disturb the flow or core formation. Satisfying these constraints can add significant complexity and cost to the flow cytometer system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention overcomes many of the disadvantages of the prior art by providing an optical detection system that uses two or more light sources positioned laterally at different distances from a central axis of a flow stream for providing light through different parts of the flow stream. One or more lenses are used to focus the light from the two or more light sources through the flow stream and onto a common focal point or region on the opposite side of the flow stream. One or more light detectors are then placed at, near or around the common focal point or region. A processor or the like may then receive at least one output signal from the one or more light detectors to analyze and determine selected characteristics of the flow stream. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In one illustrative embodiment of the present invention, an array of light sources and an array of lenses are used to illuminate a flow stream. To focus the light from each of the light sources through the flow stream to a common focal point or region on the opposite side of the flow stream, the pitch of the lens array is slightly different than the pitch of the light source array. This creates an offset between the optical axis of each lens and the corresponding light source, and this offset varies across the arrays. The various offsets are preferably set so that each lens focuses the light from the corresponding light source onto the common focal point or region on the opposite side of the flow stream. A multiple annular zoned detector is then positioned at, near or around the common focal point or region to measure the incident intensity distribution over various angular zone regions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Blood cells or other particles present in the flow channel tend to diffract or scatter the light out of the central zone of the annular zoned detector and onto outer annular detector zones. Analysis of the signal strength produced by the various annular zones can be used to determine certain physical and/or chemical properties of each particle passing through the flow channel. Such an analysis can be used to determine, for example, if a particle is present in the flow stream, the speed and alignment of the particle within the flow stream, and in many cases, the type of particle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In one illustrative application, the optical detection system of the present invention may be used in conjunction with a portable cytometer system for detecting, for example, neutrophils and/or lymphocytes white blood cells in a blood sample. By examining the scatter distribution of each of the particles, the portable cytometer may identify and count the neutrophils and lymphocytes in the blood sample, and provide a clear infection warning with differentiation between viral and bacterial causes. Many other applications are also contemplated.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Other objects of the present invention and many of the attendant advantages of the present invention will be readily appreciated as the same becomes better understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in connection with the accompanying drawings, in which like reference numerals designate like parts throughout the figures thereof and wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an illustrative portable cytometer in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the illustrative portable cytometer of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a more detailed schematic diagram showing the portable cytometer of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with the cover not yet depressed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a more detailed schematic diagram showing the portable cytometer of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with the cover depressed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing the formation of a flow stream by the hydrodynamic focusing block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an array of light sources, an array of lenses and a cross sectional view of an annular zoned detector; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an illustrative diagram of a top frontal view of the annular zoned detector of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an array of light sources positioned along an axis that is angularly offset by about ninety degrees relative to the central axis of a flow channel and a single annular zoned detector positioned on the opposite side of the flow stream; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing two arrays of light sources, each positioned along an axis that is angularly offset by about ninety degrees relative to the central axis of a flow channel, and two annular zoned detectors positioned on the opposite side of the flow stream; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing two separate arrays of light sources, each positioned along an axis that is angularly offset by less than ninety degrees relative to the central axis of the flow stream, with two annular zoned detectors; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an illustrative graph representing the intensity distribution of light striking an annular detector when no particle is present in the flow channel; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is an illustrative graph representing the intensity distribution of light striking the annular detector when a particle is present in the flow channel.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an illustrative portable cytometer in accordance with the present invention. The portable cytometer is generally shown at <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and includes a housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a removable or replaceable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The illustrative housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and a hinge <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> that attaches the base <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The base <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes an array of light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, associated optics and the necessary electronics for operation of the cytometer. The cover <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a manual pressurizing element, pressure-chambers with control microvalves, and an array of light detectors <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> preferably receives a sample fluid via a sample collector port <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A cap <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may be used to protect the sample collector port <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> when the removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is not in use. The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> preferably performs blood dilution, red cell lysing, and hydrodynamic focusing for core formation. The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be constructed similar to the fluidic circuits available from Micronics Technologies, some of which are fabricated using a laminated structure with etched channels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is inserted into the housing when the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is in the open position. The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may include holes <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for receiving registration pins <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the base <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, which help provide alignment and coupling between the different parts of the instrument. The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> also preferably includes a transparent flow stream window <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which is in alignment with the array of the light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and light detectors <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. When the cover is moved to the closed position, and the system is pressurized, the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> provides controlled pressures to pressure receiving ports <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>in the removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via pressure providing ports <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> To initiate a test, the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is lifted and a new cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is placed and registered onto the base <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A blood sample is introduced into the sample collector <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is closed and the system is manually pressurized. Once pressurized, the instrument performs a white blood cell cytometry measurement. The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> provides blood dilution, red cell lysing, and hydrodynamic focusing for core formation. The light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, light detectors <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and associated control and processing electronics perform differentiation and counting of white blood cells based on light scattering signals. Rather than using a hinged construction for the housing <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, it is contemplated that a sliding cartridge slot or any other suitable construction may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the illustrative portable cytometer of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As above, the base <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may include an array of light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, associated optics and the necessary control and processing electronics <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> for operation of the cytometer. The base <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may also include a battery <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for powering the cytometer. The cover <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is shown having a manual pressurizing element <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, pressure-chambers <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>with control microvalves, and an array of light detectors <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may receive a sample fluid via the sample collector port <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. When pressurized by the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> performs blood dilution, red cell lysing, and hydrodynamic focusing for core formation in a preferred embodiment. Once formed, the core is provided down a flow stream path <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, which passes the flow stream window <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The array of light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and associated optics in the base provide light through the core stream via the flow stream window <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The array of light detectors receive scattered and non-scattered light from the core, also via the flow stream window <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> receives output signals from the array of detectors, and differentiates and counts selected white blood cells that are present in the core stream. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a more detailed schematic diagram showing the portable cytometer of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> not yet depressed. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a more detailed schematic diagram showing the portable cytometer of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with the cover depressed. The cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is shown having a manual pressurizing element <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, pressure-chambers <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, and control microvalves generally shown at <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The array of light sources and detectors are not shown in these Figures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> There are three pressure chambers <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, one for each fluid to be pressurized. In the illustrative embodiment, pressure chamber <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>provides pressure to a blood sample reservoir <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, pressure chamber <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provides pressure to a lyse reservoir <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, and pressure chamber <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>provides pressure to a sheath reservoir <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The size and shape of each pressure chamber <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>may be tailored to provide the desired pressure characteristics to the corresponding fluid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Pressure chamber <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>includes a first pressure chamber <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and a second pressure chamber <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. A first valve <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is provided between the first pressure chamber <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and the second pressure chamber <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> for controllably releasing the pressure in the first pressure chamber <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to a second pressure chamber <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. A second valve <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, in fluid communication with the second pressure chamber <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, controllably vents the pressure in the second pressure chamber <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Each valve is preferably an array of electrostatically actuated microvalves that are individually addressable and controllable, as described in, for example, co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/404,560, entitled &ldquo;ADDRESSABLE VALVE ARRAYS FOR PROPORTIONAL PRESSURE OR FLOW CONTROL&rdquo;, and incorporated herein by reference. Pressure chambers <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>include similar valves to control the pressures applied to the lyse reservoir <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and sheath reservoir <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, respectively. Alternatively, each valve may be an array of electrostatically actuated microvalves that are pulse modulated with a controllable duty cycle to achieve a controlled &ldquo;effective&rdquo; flow or leak rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> has pressure receiving ports <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>for receiving the controlled pressures from the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The controlled pressures are provided to the blood reservoir <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, lyse reservoir <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and sheath reservoir <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, as shown. The lyse reservoir <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and sheath reservoir <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> are preferably filled before the removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is shipped for use, while the blood reservoir <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is filled from sample collector port <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A blood sample may be provided to the sample collector port <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and through capillary action, the blood sample is sucked into the blood reservoir <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Once the blood sample is in the blood reservoir <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be closed and the system may be pressurized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> A flow sensor is provided in-line with each fluid prior to hydrodynamic focusing. Each flow sensor <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> measures the velocity of the corresponding fluid. The flow sensors are preferably thermal anemometer type flow sensors, and more preferably microbridge type flow sensor. Microbridge flow sensors are described in, for example, U.S. Pat. No. 4,478,076, U.S. Pat. No. 4,478,077, U.S. Pat. No. 4,501,144, U.S. Pat. No. 4,651,564, U.S. Pat. No. 4,683,159, and U.S. Pat. No. 5,050,429, all of which are incorporated herein by reference. An output signal from each flow sensor <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is provided to controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> opens the first valve <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> when the velocity of the blood sample drops below a first predetermined value and opens the second valve <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> when the velocity of the blood sample increases above a second predetermined value. Valves <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> operate in a similar manner to control the velocities of the lyse and sheath fluids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> During operation, and to pressurize the system, the manual pressurizing element <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is depressed. In the example shown, the manual pressurizing element <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> includes three plungers, with each plunger received within a corresponding one of the first pressure chambers. The plungers create a relatively high non-precision pressure in the first pressure chambers. Lower, controlled pressures are built in the secondary chambers by opening the first valves <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, which produce a controllable leak into the secondary chambers. If too much pressure builds up in the secondary pressure chambers, the corresponding vent valves <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are opened to relieve the pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> When closing the cover <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the normally open first valves <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are closed while the vent valves <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are open. When a predetermined pressure P is achieved in the first pressure chambers, the vent valves <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are closed, and the first valves <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are opened to build a lower pressure P&prime; in the secondary pressure chambers. The controlled pressure in the secondary pressure chambers provide the necessary pressures to the fluidic circuit of the removable cartridge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to produce fluid flow for the blood, lyse and sheath. The velocity of the fluid flow is then measured by the downstream flow sensors <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Each flow sensor provides an output signal that is used by the controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to control the operation of the corresponding first valve and vent valve to provide a desired and constant flow rate for each fluid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Downstream valves generally shown at <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may also be provided. Controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may close downstream valves <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> until the system is pressurized. This may help prevent the blood, lyse and sheath from flowing into the fluid circuit before the circuit is pressurized. In another embodiment, downstream valves <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are opened by mechanical action when the cover is closed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing the formation of a flow stream and core by the hydrodynamic focusing block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The hydrodynamic focusing block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> receives blood, lyse and sheath at controlled velocities from the fluid driver. The blood is mixed with the lyse, causing the red blood cells to be removed. This is often referred to as red cell lysing. The remaining white blood cells are provided down a central lumen <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, which is surrounded by sheath fluid to produce a flow stream <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The flow stream <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes a core stream <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> surrounded by the sheath fluid <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. The dimensions of the channel are reduced as shown so that the blood cells <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> are in single file. The velocity of the sheath fluid is preferably about 9 times that of the core stream <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. However, the velocity of the sheath fluid and core stream <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> preferably remain sufficiently low to maintain laminar flow in the flow channel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Light emitters <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and associated optics are preferably provided adjacent one side of the flow stream <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Light detectors <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are provided on another side of the flow stream <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> for receiving the light from the light emitters <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the flow stream <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The output signals from the light detectors <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are provided to controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, wherein they are analyzed to identify and/or count selected white blood cells in the core stream <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the blood cells <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> are white blood cells. In other preferred embodiments, the blood cells may include neutrophils and/or lymphocytes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a diagram showing an illustrative embodiment of the present invention. A lens array <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is positioned between a light source array <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Each lens in the lens array <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be a microlens. The microlenses may be any type of lens including, for example, refractive lenses, diffractive lenses, etc. An annular detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, with a center zone <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and outer zones <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, is positioned on the opposite side of the flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> from the light source array <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. A first lens <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is positioned relative a first light source <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>such that the central focal axis <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the lens <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is offset by a distance &ldquo;d,&rdquo; from the light source central axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. A second lens <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is positioned relative a second light source <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>such that the central focal axis <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the lens <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is offset by a distance &ldquo;d<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&rdquo; from the light source central axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The offset distances between the central focal axis of each lens and the corresponding light source central axis preferably changes across the array such that the light rays emitted by each light source is focused onto a common point or region <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> on the annular detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the common focal point <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may appear on the annular detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> at or about the center of the central zone <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Because the lens array <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and the light source array <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> are adapted to focus the light rays onto a common point or region <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, no beam shaping optics may be required on the detector side. This may reduce the complexity and cost of the device. Furthermore, particles that pass through the flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may produce a simple rotationally symmetric scattering signature, which can be much easier to process at the detector than non-rotationally symmetric scattering signatures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The light source array <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is preferably an array of lasers such as Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers (VCSEL) fabricated on a common substrate. Because of their vertical emission, VCSELs are ideally suited for packaging in compact instruments such as a portable cytometer. Preferably, the VCSELs are &ldquo;red&rdquo; VCSELs that operate at wavelengths that are less than the conventional 850 nm, and more preferably in the 670 nm to 780 nm range. Red VCSELs may have a wavelength, power and polarization characteristic that is ideally suited for scatter measurements. Other light sources may be used including, for example, Light Emitting Diodes (LEDs) or any other type of light source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a frontal view of the annular detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The illustrative annular detector has several zones, including a central zone <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and several annular shaped outer zones <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. The first zone <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which is located just outside of the central zone <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, may be an annular shaped light detector used for detecting forward angle scattering (FALS) produced by one or more particles in the flow stream. The second zone <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which is positioned outside of the first zone <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, may be an annular shaped light detector used for detecting the small angle scattering (SALS) produced by one or more particles in the flow stream. Other annular shaped light detectors <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>may be positioned outside of the central detector <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the first two annular shaped outer detectors <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to detect other scatter angles, as desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing a linear array of light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (indicated by &ldquo;&plus;&rdquo; signs) positioned along an axis that is angularly offset by about ninety degrees relative to the central axis of flow of a flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> also shows a single annular shaped zoned detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> positioned on the opposite side of the flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are designed with lenses as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> so that the light emitted from the array of light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will have a common focal point or region on the central ring <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> of the detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the array of light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are positioned and spaced to provide a substantially constant light intensity across the width of the flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Using a linear array of lasers offers a number of important advantages over the single light source configuration. For example, a linear array of lasers may be used to determine the lateral alignment of the path of the particles in the core steam. One source of uncertainty in the alignment of the particle stream is the width of the core flow, which leads to statistical fluctuations in the particle path position. These fluctuations can be determined from analysis of the detector data and can be used by the controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) to adjust the valves of the fluid driver in order to change the relative pressures that are applied to the sample fluid and the supporting fluids to change the alignment of the selected particles in the flow stream. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> To determine the lateral alignment of the particles in the fluid stream <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the particles pass through the light produced by the linear array of VCSELs. The particles produce a different scatter profile at the detector when the cells are not properly aligned. The relative strengths of the signals at the detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> can be used by the controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to determine when the particle path is centered in the flow stream. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing two linear arrays of light sources, each positioned along an axis that is angularly offset by about ninety degrees relative to the central axis of flow of a flow channel. Each array of light sources has an annular zoned detector positioned on the opposite side of the flow stream. More specifically, a first flow sensor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> has an array of light sources <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (indicated as &ldquo;&plus;&rdquo; signs) and an annular shaped detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> having a center ring <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and outer rings <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. A second flow sensor <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, which is located either upstream or downstream of the first flow sensor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, includes an array of light sources <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> (indicated as &ldquo;&plus;&rdquo; signs) and an annular shaped detector <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. In the illustrative embodiment, the annular shaped detector <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of the second flow sensor <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> only has a center ring or region <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In preferred embodiments, the first flow sensor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is used to measure, for example, the FALS and SALS produced by one or more particles in the flow stream <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The first flow sensor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may also be used to determine the lateral alignment of the path of the particles in the core stream. The second flow sensor <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is used in conjunction with first flow sensor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to measure the velocity of the particles passing through flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> To determine the velocity of each particle, the system may measure the time required for each particle to pass between the first detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and the second detector <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. For example, and with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9, a</cross-reference> particle may pass detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and then detector <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. By measuring the time required for the particle to travel from detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to detector <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, and by knowing the distance from detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to detector <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, the controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can calculate the velocity of the particle in the flow stream. This would be an approximate velocity measurement. This is often referred to as a time-of-flight measurement. Once the velocity is known, the time of travel through the light beam of the first or second flow sensors <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (a few microseconds) may provide a measure of particle length and size. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> It is contemplated that the particle velocity can also be used to help control the fluid driver. To reduce the size, cost and complexity of the present invention, the replaceable cartridge of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> may be manufactured from a plastic laminate or molded parts. While such manufacturing techniques may provide inexpensive parts, they are typically less dimensionally precise and repeatable, with asymmetrical dimensions and wider tolerance cross-sections. These wider tolerances may produce variations in particle velocity, particularly from cartridge to cartridge. To help compensate for these wider tolerances, the time-of-flight measurement discussed above can be used by the controller or processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to adjust the controlled pressures applied to the blood, lyse and sheath fluid streams such that the particles in the core stream have a relatively constant velocity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> To further evaluate the particle size, it is contemplated that laser beams may be focused both along the particle path and across the particle path. Additionally, multiple samples across the particle may be analyzed for texture features, to correlate morphological features to other particle types. This may provide multiple parameters about particle size that may help separate particle types from one another. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing two linear arrays of light sources along an axis that is angularly offset by less than ninety degrees relative to the central axis of the flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. This embodiment is similar to that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, but each of the flow sensors <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> are rotated relative to the central axis of the flow channel. One advantage of this embodiment is that the effective spacing of the light sources, as viewed by a particle, may be less than that provided by the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. This may allow a more uniform illumination intensity across the flow channel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an illustrative graph representing the intensity distribution of light striking the annular detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> with no particle in the flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. This graph shows a classic airy diffraction intensity distribution. Most of the diffraction pattern intensity is concentrated in a central zone, as shown by the center peak <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. A first outer peak <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and a second outer peak <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> can also be observed from the graph. The first and second outer peaks <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> are of substantially lesser magnitude than the first peak <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, but are large enough to be noted on the graph. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is an illustrative graph representing the intensity distribution of light striking the annular detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> when a particle is present in the flow channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. A central peak <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, a first outer peak <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, and a second outer peak <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> are shown. This graph demonstrates that, while the central peak <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> is similar in magnitude to the central peak <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the comparative difference between the central peak <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> and the first outer peak <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is of different magnitude than the comparative difference between central peak <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> and first outer peak <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> also demonstrates that the second outer peak <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> is relatively farther away from the central peak <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> than the second outer peak <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> is from the center peak <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. These graphs also demonstrate the rotational symmetry of the light scatter signature that occurs in the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The graphs in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference> represent data that, in preferred embodiments, is collected by the annular detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. This data is then sent to a processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) to perform various data processing functions. Possible functions include, but are not limited to, flow alignment, blood cell counting, identification of foreign objects, blood cell identification, flow speed, and identification of neutrophils and/or lymphocytes white blood cells. In a preferred embodiment, the ratio of annular zone signal strengths that are detected by the various zones in the detector <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> can be used to determine whether a blood cell is present and/or the type of blood cell present. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Having thus described the preferred embodiments of the present invention, those of skill in the art will readily appreciate that the teachings found herein may be applied to yet other embodiments within the scope of the claims hereto attached. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system for analyzing predetermined characteristics of a flow stream, the flow stream having a central axis along the direction of flow, the optical detection system comprising: 
<claim-text>two or more spaced light sources positioned on a first side of the flow stream for providing light through the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>lens means positioned on the first side of the flow stream for focusing the light from each of the two or more light sources to a common focal point or region located on a second opposite side of the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>light receiving means for receiving the light from the two or more light sources, and for providing at least one signal in response thereto, at least a portion of the light receiving means located at or near the common focal point or region of the lens means; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing means for receiving the at least one signal from the light receiving means and for using the at least one signal for analyzing the predetermined characteristics of the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the two or more light sources are positioned laterally at different distances from the central axis of the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the two or more light sources are Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers (VCSELs). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the VCSELs operate in the red spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the two or more light sources are Light Emitting Diodes (LEDs). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two or more light sources are an array of light sources. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lens means includes two or more microlenses, one for each of the two or more light sources. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each microlens is laterally offset relative to the corresponding light source so that the light provided by each light source is focused onto the common focal point or region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light receiving means includes a centrally located light detector positioned at the common focal point or region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light receiving means includes a first annular shaped light detector positioned around the centrally located light detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first annular shaped light detector is used for detecting the forward angle scattering (FALS) produced by one or more particles in the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the one or more particles include white blood cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the white blood cells include neutrophils and/or lymphocytes white blood cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light receiving means includes a second annular shaped light detector positioned around the first annular shaped light detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second annular shaped light detector is used for detecting the small angle scattering (SALS) produced by one or more particles in the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the one or more particles include white blood cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the white blood cells include neutrophils and/or lymphocytes white blood cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light receiving means includes at least one other annular shaped light detector positioned around the second annular shaped light detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two or more spaced light sources are positioned along a light source axis that is angularly offset relative to the central axis of flow of the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light source axis is angularly offset by about 90 degrees relative to the central axis of flow of the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light source axis is angularly offset by less than 90 degrees relative to the central axis of flow of the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two or more spaced light sources collectively provide a substantially constant light intensity across the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light that is provided through the flow stream is used for determining the velocity of one or more particles in the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light that is provided through the flow stream is used for determining the size of one or more particles in the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two or more light sources include a first set of light sources positioned along a first light source axis and a second set of light sources positioned along a second light source axis, wherein the second light source axis is located downstream or upstream of the first light source axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein light receiving means includes a first detector and a second detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lens means includes a first set of microlenses associated with the first set of light sources and a second set of microlenses associated with the second set of light sources. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first set of microlenses are adapted to focus the light from the first set of light sources to a first common focal point or region, and the second set of microlenses are adapted to focus the light from the second set of light sources to a second common focal point or region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first detector of the light receiving means has a centrally located light detector positioned at the first common focal point or region and the second detector of the light receiving means has a centrally located light detector positioned at the second common focal point or region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first detector includes at least one annular shaped light detector positioned around the centrally located light detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second detector includes at least one annular shaped light detector positioned around the centrally located light detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second detector does not include an annular shaped light detector around the centrally located light detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first set of light sources and the first detector are used to detect the alignment of the flow of one or more particles relative to the central axis of the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first set of light sources and the first detector are used to detect the speed of one or more particles in the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first set of light sources and the first detector are used to detect the size of one or more particles in the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second set of light sources and the second detector are used in conjunction with the second set of light sources and the second detector to determine the speed of one or more particles in the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. An optical detection system for analyzing predetermined characteristics of a flow stream, the flow stream having a central axis along the direction of flow, the optical detection system comprising: 
<claim-text>one or more spaced light sources positioned on a first side of the flow stream for providing light through the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>lens means positioned on the first side of the flow stream for focusing the light from each of the one or more light sources to a common focal point or region located on a second opposite side of the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>light receiving means for receiving the light from the one or more light sources, and for providing at least one signal in response thereto, at least a portion of the light receiving means located at or near the common focal point or region of the lens means; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing means for receiving the at least one signal from the light receiving means and for using the at least one signal for analyzing the predetermined characteristics of the flow stream. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A method for analyzing predetermined characteristics of a flow stream, the flow stream having a central axis along the direction of flow, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing light from a first side of the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>focusing the light to a common focal point or region located on a second opposite side of the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the light at or near the common focal point or region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the predetermined characteristics of the flow stream by analyzing the light that is received at or near the common focal point or region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light is received at the common focal point or region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light is received along an annulus that surrounds the common focal point or region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light is received along two or more annuli that surround the common focal point or region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A method for determining the alignment of one or more particles in a flow stream relative to a central axis of the flow stream, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>activating two or more light sources positioned on a first side of the flow stream for providing light through the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>focusing the light from each of the two or more light sources to a common focal point or region located on a second opposite side of the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring an output response of a detector, wherein at least a portion of the detector is positioned at or near the common focal point or region, the output response providing an indication of the alignment of the one or more particles in the flow stream; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the alignment of the one or more particles in the flow stream by examining the output response of the detector. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A method for determining the velocity of one or more particles in a flow stream, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>activating two or more upstream light sources at an upstream position of the flow stream to provide light through the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>focusing the light from each of the at least two or more upstream light sources to a first common focal point or region behind the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring an output response of an upstream detector that receives the light from the two or more upstream light sources; </claim-text>
<claim-text>activating two or more downstream light sources at a downstream position of the flow stream to provide light through the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>focusing the light from each of the at least two or more downstream light sources to a second common focal point or region behind the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring an output response of a downstream detector that receives the light from the two or more downstream light sources; </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a change in the output response of the at least one upstream detector when a particle passes between the at least two upstream light sources and the upstream detector; </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a change in the output response of the downstream detector when the same particle passes between the at least two downstream light sources and the downstream detector; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a time lag between the change in output response of the upstream detector and the change in output response of the downstream detector, the time lag being related to the speed of the particle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A method for determining the small angle scattering (SALS) produced by one or more particles in a flow stream, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>activating two or more light sources to provide light through the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>focusing the light provided by the two or more light sources to a common focal point or region behind the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the light from the one or more light sources using a light detector, the light detector adapted to detect a scatter pattern of light; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the SALS produced by the one or more particles by examining the scatter pattern detected by the light detector. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light detector has at least two detector regions, including a first annular region surrounded by a second annular region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the SALS component is detected by the second annular region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. A method for determining the small angle scattering (FALS) produced by one or more particles in a flow stream, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>activating two or more light sources to provide light through the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>focusing the light provided by the two or more light sources to a common focal point or region behind the flow stream; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the light from the one or more light sources using a light detector, the light detector adapted to detect a scatter pattern of light; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the FALS produced by the one or more particles by examining the scatter pattern detected by the light detector. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light detector has at least two detector regions, including a first annular region surrounded by a second annular region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the FALS component is detected by the first annular region.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002027A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
