<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005304A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005304A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005304</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10165104</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020606</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04L009/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>713</class>
<subclass>176000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Marking articles using a covert digitally watermarked image</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60296308</doc-number>
<document-date>20010606</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60310914</doc-number>
<document-date>20010808</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60311160</doc-number>
<document-date>20010809</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Nabil</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lawandy</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>North Kingstown</city>
<state>RI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jeffrey</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Conroy</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Rumford</city>
<state>RI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Andrei</given-name>
<family-name>Smuk</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Providence</city>
<state>RI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HARRINGTON &amp; SMITH, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>4 RESEARCH DRIVE</address-1>
<city>SHELTON</city>
<state>CT</state>
<postalcode>06484-6212</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A marking system that includes forming at least one marking in or on an article, wherein the image formed is not visible to the unaided human observer, and further contains at least one digital watermark. The digitally watermarked image comprises emissive and photoabsorptive portions. The digitally watermarked image is applied using a substance reactive to a predetermined excitation source, and exposure to ultraviolet light. Other traditional techniques, such as printing with fluorescent inks may be used in combination. The digitally watermarked image is subsequently observable upon exposure to the predetermined excitation source. The digitally watermarked image may be observed and decoded by appropriately configured detection systems, wherein the information obtained may be used for purposes including, but not limited to, authentication and security of the article or information contained within the article. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &sect;119(e) to U.S. Provisional Patent Application Serial No. 60/296,308, filed Jun. 6, 2001; U.S. Provisional Patent Application Serial No. 60/310,914, filed Aug. 8, 2001; U.S. Provisional Patent Application Serial No. 60/311,160, filed Aug. 9, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a method and apparatus for marking and authenticating articles, such as documents, currency, credit cards, passports, product labeling and packaging and other types of objects. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Valuable items such as negotiable instruments, art work, etc., are susceptible to theft and counterfeiting. With respect to documents in particular, the advancement of color copier technology has made it fairly easy to create a color copy of any document, including currency, using commonly available equipment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> One security device for verifying an article&apos;s authenticity is a digital watermark. Digital watermarks or similar signatures typically use semantic information associated with the protected article, such as alphanumeric characters, physical features, etc. or other related information such as ownership information. These watermarks or signatures are typically kept with or incorporated into, the item to be protected. For example, a watermark may be printed within the substrate of a negotiable instrument including information regarding the value and the originator of the instrument. As another example, digital watermarking techniques may be used for both still and video images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Various digital watermarking techniques are known for both still and video images. For example, reference may be had to U.S. Pat. No. 6,343,138 B1, entitled &ldquo;Security Documents with Hidden Digital Data&rdquo;, issued Jan. 29, 2002. This patent discloses embedding a visible digital watermark into a video signal or a still image. Another example of use of digital watermarks with documents is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,243,480 B1, entitled &ldquo;Digital authentication of analog documents,&rdquo; issued Jun. 5, 2001. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> There are many techniques that are used to embed additional information in a digital image. One example is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,359,985, entitled a &ldquo;Procedure for marking binary coded data sets,&rdquo; issued Mar. 19, 2002. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> One technique involves separately coding an image and a watermark image on an article using a pseudo random number generator and a discrete cosine transform (DCT) to term coded blocks, one of the image to be watermarked and the other of the watermark itself. The DCT coefficients representing the coded watermark block and the coded image block are then added together to form a combined block to digitally watermark the image. For example, as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,037,984, entitled a &ldquo;Method and Apparatus for Encoding a Watermark into a Digital Image or Image Sequence,&rdquo; issued Mar. 14, 2000, an image or sequence of images is watermarked using a conventional DCT unit and quantizer by generating an array of quantized DCT coefficients and watermarking the array by selecting certain DCT coefficients and replacing them with zero values. In the aforementioned patent, the array is further processed by a watermark inserter that replaces the zero valued coefficients with predefined watermark coefficients, and the coefficients form a watermarked array of DCT coefficients that constitutes a watermarked image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Other common and known techniques for providing authentication of articles is through the use of invisible markings. One method is by printing in inks that are clear under normal illumination but emit visible fluorescent wavelengths upon ultraviolet (UV) excitation. One common technique is to use invisible ink to print security marks or information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> For documents with visible markings, it is very easy to copy or scan a document into a PC using scanning and printing technologies. In some instances, there is no way to tell if a reproduction is an original document. Even if the original document is coded with a visible code, once scanned, the code could be reproduced on the counterfeit document. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> By using an invisible code or message on the document, for example &ldquo;Original document&mdash;Do not copy&rdquo;, a scanner using visible light would not see the invisible ink. Another security feature of invisible codes recognizes that it may be difficult to reproduce the invisible ink for printing illegitmate copies. Typically, the formulation of such ink is difficult to duplicate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another patent, U.S. Pat. No. 6,269,169 B1, &ldquo;Secure Document Reader And Method Therefor,&rdquo; issued Jul. 31, 2001, discloses an apparatus and a method for reading documents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Additional approaches to providing authentication use fluorescent markings and more sophisticated printing methods, such as printing with visible graphics. Of interest to the teaching of this invention is U.S. Pat. No. 6,373,965, &ldquo;Apparatus And Methods For Authentication Using Partially Fluorescent Graphic Images And OCR Characters&rdquo;, issued Apr. 16, 2002 discloses a system combining a source of ultraviolet light with apparatus for capturing and recognizing either graphic images or characters, or both. In this patent either a visible sub-image, or a fluorescent sub-image, or a combination image, may further contain steganographic (digital watermark) information that is encoded and inserted using conventional techniques. The digital watermark information may be similarly encoded and inserted into visible and/or fluorescent sub-portions and or recombined OCR characters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Techniques for hiding information in an invisible fashion also include the use of various frequency bands in document security design. These optical techniques exploit the limitations of digital copiers and scanners by use of fine line printing patterns that use screen angle modulation of lines (SAM) and micro screen angle modulation techniques. For example, a protected document that includes background printed background matter and line pattern printed warning indicia is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 4,582,346, entitled &ldquo;Document Security System,&rdquo; issued on Apr. 15, 1986. U.S. Pat. No. 5,171,040, entitled &ldquo;Copy-Invalidating Document&rdquo; issued on Dec. 15, 1992 discloses printing a pattern of warning indicia that is merged by human sensory perception with its background, but is distinguished and reproduced by xerographic copying as a result of the employment of two different screen values for the indicia and the background within and beyond the reproductive capability of the copier machine. U.S. Pat. No. 5,297,815, entitled &ldquo;Security Printed Documents&rdquo; issued Mar. 29, 1994, discloses a security document that provides an indication of when copied by a photocopy machine through the use of a background pattern and warning matter interspersed with blank areas of a substrate to provide a distinct intermeshed pattern so the warning printed is indistinguishable by the human eye. As methods of detecting and defeating security devices, such as digital watermarks, have become more sophisticated, there is a growing need for advancements in markings that provide additional security. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Disclosed herein are methods and apparatus for covertly marking an article with a digitally watermarked image that is not visible to the unaided observer. Also disclosed is an object that carries a normally invisible digitally watermarked image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> An aspect of this invention involves the discreet incorporation of security information into the appearance of an object. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of this invention is the use of substances reactive to a predetermined excitation source as a coating over an article. The coating is optically variable, that is, an image formed in or with the coating appears at wavelengths outside of the visible region, and is not visible to the unaided observer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> An image that contains a digital watermark is provided on the surface of an object. The image contains a digital watermark that appears at wavelengths that are outside of the visible region of the electromagnetic spectrum. A variety of embodiments of images and digital watermarks are disclosed. Multiple watermarked images may be used for a single article, where the actual scheme selected is dependent upon, among other things, the needs of the user. The ability of an image to carry information in the form of a digital watermark provides for the discreet incorporation of information and application of security techniques. The digital watermark may carry a variety of information, including information useful for as examples, the authentication of the article, and/or decryption of information related to or contained within the article. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The image and watermark may be incorporated through techniques that include printing with UV light. Combinations of coating materials and exposure techniques may be used to control the appearance of the image and the digital watermark. Other methods for incorporating an image and digital watermark include traditional techniques, such as printing. Portions of the coating may be photoabsorptive. For example, portions of the coating may absorb ultraviolet light. Thus, the digital watermark may be characterized by regions that are emissive, and other regions that are photoabsorptive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> A coating material may be used in some embodiments that is responsive to any one of a number of predetermined excitation sources, or stimuli. Possible stimuli include, but are not limited to, wavelengths of light, thermal energy, humidity, pressure, and chemical sources. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The image may be observed by various techniques, such as the introduction of a fluorescent background with proper illumination, or through more sophisticated means. More sophisticated means for imaging include, for example, a charge coupled device (CCD) with proper sources of illumination. The imaging device may be connected with a processor to decipher watermark information.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> For the present invention to be understood clearly and readily practiced, the present invention will be described in conjunction with the following figures, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts a digital watermark incorporated in a coating on an optical information medium according to an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates transmission spectra of one particular lacquer at different curing times; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a transmission spectra of polycarbonate substrate before and after UV exposure; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows an exemplary bar code having a digital watermark; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a schematic diagram of a detection system to identify and authenticate items in accordance with an embodiment the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a block diagram of a detector array according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A-B, collectively referred to herein as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, is a schematic illustration of application of coatings. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> depicts an image printed with a reactive substance. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> depicts an image printed with a reactive substance, with an overlay coating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an illustration of an optical media with an information bearing marking inscribed in the clamping area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an illustration of the use of multiple digital watermarks in a credit card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an illustration of multiple digital watermarks in registration with each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-C, collectively referred to as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, is an illustration of a split image.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that the figures and descriptions of the present invention have been simplified to illustrate elements that are relevant for a clear understanding of the present invention while eliminating, for purposes of clarity, other elements. For example, certain details relating to technologies for creating and embedding digital watermarks, such as automated or manual techniques, are not described herein. Those of ordinary skill in the art will recognize, however, that these and other elements may be desirable in a typical digital watermarking algorithm. A discussion of such elements is not provided because such elements are well known in the art and because they do not facilitate a better understanding of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Disclosed herein are methods and apparatus for incorporating an image (also referred to herein as a &ldquo;marking&rdquo; or as a &ldquo;mark&rdquo;) containing a digital watermark (also referred to herein as a &ldquo;watermark&rdquo;) into or onto an article, where the marking and the watermark are only partially visible to an unaided observer, or they are invisible to the unaided observer. As referred to herein, it is generally considered that &ldquo;visible&rdquo; images and marks appear at wavelengths between about 400 nm to about 700 nm. &ldquo;Invisible&rdquo; images and marks may appear at wavelengths above the visible spectrum (above about 700 nm), which is herein referred to for purposes herein the infrared region, or IR; or, invisible images and marks may appear at wavelengths below the visible spectrum (downward from about 400 nm), in what is referred to herein the ultraviolet region, or UV. &ldquo;Normally invisible,&rdquo; as used herein, refers to the visibility of a marking without the introduction of an external stimulus. Thus, it can be appreciated that an invisible image that becomes visible only upon exposure to a stimulus, for example, UV light, is &ldquo;normally invisible.&rdquo; Additionally, invisible markings may appear at various wavelengths simultaneously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The &ldquo;unaided observer&rdquo; may be a human and/or a detection system. A degree of authentication may occur by the human observer, where the human observer is possessed by the ability to verify the presence of an image, and may be able to verify certain characteristics related to the image. Detection systems have improved capabilities over a human observer, and may detect additional features of a mark, such as the presence and content of a digital watermark. Typically, a human observer is not able to detect a digital watermark, and additionally, the human observer will not be able to decipher a digital watermark without the aid of a detection system. However, the covert nature of the markings disclosed herein require that a detection system be &ldquo;appropriately configured&rdquo; in order to detect and decipher the marking. For example, characteristics of an &ldquo;appropriately configured&rdquo; detection system include, but are not limited to, illumination at proper wavelengths, and possession of digital watermarking algorithm information in order to decipher a digital watermark. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Invisible images may be observed through use of various intermediate mechanisms. For example, UV absorptive markings may be observed through the introduction of fluorescent materials that are emissive in the visible region. As an alternate example, an image may be observed in the IR region through use of equipment, such as a charge coupled device, appropriately configured to detect IR wavelengths. One skilled in the art will realize that many embodiments are possible, where images that are not visible to the unaided observer may viewed in the visible region, or through use of appropriately configured detection equipment presenting a visible portrayal of the image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The image may include various conventions for presentation of data, including, but not limited to, data code symbologies, such as a bar code, graphics, text, alphanumeric, and digital watermarks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method for processing an article to embed auxiliary data and the subsequent extraction and use of such data. In accordance with embodiments described herein, an image containing a multi-bit marking may be embedded directly or printed on the article, such as a security document, an optical storage media, or other article. Hardware or software systems can then read the marking, for example, to identify and authenticate the subject article. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The watermark is encoded within the image, and becomes part of the image. The watermark preferably cannot be detected or removed without prior knowledge of the specifics of the watermark. While the changes manifested by the incorporation of the watermark are generally too slight to be visible to the human eye, when a marked image appears, they are easily and consistently recognizable by, for example, a digital image scanner or a charge-coupled device where after recognition and imaging the marking is extracted interpreted and verified by, for example, a software algorithm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The Marking </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> One non-limiting embodiment of the teachings herein describe use of a coating for application to an article, for example, an optical information medium such as a CD-ROM (compact disc, read-only-memory) or DVD (digital versatile disc). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows an exemplary article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, such as an optical information media, that includes a coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> that is supportive of an image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, also referred to herein as a &ldquo;marking.&rdquo; The marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> contains a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the invention, the marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> is invisible, or substantially invisible, to the unaided observer. The coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may have absorption properties such that it does not absorb a &ldquo;readout&rdquo; wavelength or wavelengths, such as those wavelengths used to read a CD-ROM or a DVD. The coating is applied in a manner that is consistent with the teachings herein, and the image and mark are likewise subsequently applied to the coating in a manner consistent with the teachings herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> While the teachings herein are frequently described in the context of an optical information medium such as a CD-ROM or a DVD, the use of these articles is considered to be illustrative and is not limiting of the invention. It should be understood that the invention includes any article suitable for receiving a coating in accordance with these teachings. For example, the invention may be used to provide for marking of securities, product packages, labels, notes of currency, identification, credit cards, diplomas, passports, licenses, windshields, documents, and other items. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, a marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> are formed through deposition of a coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may be formed of, for example, a fluorescent ink. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> may include, e.g., text information, such as a word or words, graphic information, such as a logo or barcode, or any other suitable information. According to a preferred embodiment, marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> includes embedded information (also called &ldquo;coding information&rdquo;) and/or authentication signatures included in the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. For example, a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may contain distribution chain or manufacturer specific information, the date of manufacture, the country of origin, the authorized distribution channel, or any other information that may be informative or useful about the article. It also might contain a hash value of the semantic information printed on the article for use in comparison for forgery detection. Thus, the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> may also carry additional information in a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> that may not be discernable without knowledge of digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> and the ability to read the information included therein. Such indiscernible information may be useful for various applications, for instance with respect to the anti-diversion of branded products. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> According to another embodiment, coding information for a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may be generated from one or more physical characteristics or attributes of article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. The coding information may be used as an input to the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. For example, the coding information may include attributes of the information recorded on article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> such as the number of recorded titles, the author, the playtime of the CD or DVD, copyright dates, a serial number, an indication of the content owner, etc. Such physical characteristics may be directly or indirectly observable. For example, the characteristics included in the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> preferably require processing by a suitably programmed digital data processor with appropriate sensors, detectors, illumination sources, etc. in order to be detected and decoded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may be created using any of a number of methods. One example of a method for creating digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may include using the coding information as a seed or a pseudo-random number generator where the random number is used as a hash or some other one-way function for generating digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. Another technique may include using the coding information, the output of a pseudo-random number generator, and any other appropriate information as distinct inputs to an algorithm including a discrete cosine transform to form a digitally watermarked image. In another embodiment, one or more of the various inputs to the digital watermarking algorithm may be used as a key to &ldquo;unlock&rdquo; or otherwise obtain information included in digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, or other information, such as information within the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> By whatever means created, and as was noted above, the digitally watermarked image or marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> is invisible or substantially invisible to the unaided observer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The Coating </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> is formed of a substance that is reactive to a predetermined excitation source. A variety of materials may be used; the actual material selected depends upon, among other things, the needs of the user regarding a particular application. Examples of excitation sources, include, but are not limited to, illumination with electromagnetic radiation, including certain wavelengths of light; chemical; thermal; pressure; and, humidity. Once applied, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> does not significantly interfere with the use or functionality of the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. For example, in the case of optical media <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> does not interfere with the readout laser mechanism, and the recovery of data from the optical media <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Techniques for applying coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may include, but are not limited to, printing, spraying, rolling, silk-screening, painting, or any other technique suitable for applying the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> as described herein. Coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may be processed or applied in a manner to exhibit the marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. According to an embodiment, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> can be printed, photo-bleached with a mask, engraved and/or ablated to exhibit the marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. According to another embodiment, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may be processed to exhibit the marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> by directly writing with a laser or any other suitable laser writing technique. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may be colored or colorless to the eye, and may be fluorescent under certain electromagnetic radiation. According to an embodiment, coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> includes compounds such as metal chelates, fluorescent dyes or laser dyes. According to other embodiments, coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> includes organic phosphors or inorganic phosphors. For example, coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may include an inorganic phosphor such as silver doped zinc sulfide (Ag:ZnS). According to another embodiment in which coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> is fluorescent, coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may include a thermoplastic resin and an insoluble fluorescent pigment in a suitable carrier. According to a further embodiment, the pigment may include a dye dissolved in a plastic material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> According to an embodiment, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may be applied to an optical information medium <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> (for example, the play side). In this embodiment, readout light wavelengths for the optical information medium <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> may include wavelengths of about 400 nm, about 440 nm, about 630 nm, about 650 nm, about 780 nm, or any other readout wavelength, or combination of wavelengths, that may be employed to read information from optical information medium <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. Those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may be applied to either the &ldquo;play&rdquo; or &ldquo;non-play&rdquo; side of optical information medium <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may have any desired thickness, provided the thickness does not interfere with the readout of optical information medium <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> when applied to the readout side of medium <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. The coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may be observable at any wavelength, other than wavelengths that would be substantially interfering with the readout mechanism of the optical information medium <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> According to embodiments where the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> is fluorescent, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may absorb electromagnetic radiation either at ultraviolet (UV), visible, near infrared (IR), or longer wavelengths. The fluorescent coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may emit wavelengths in any one of UV, near UV, near IR or IR regions. According to another embodiment, where the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> is a colorless fluorescent coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>, the marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> may only appear under illumination with a predetermined source, such as a UV light source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Printing with UV Light </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The disclosed technique of invisible, or substantially invisible, printing by UV light is based on several mechanisms. One mechanism recognizes the property of some materials to become more absorbing of UV light due to progressive exposure of the material to UV light. This property is exhibited by a number of polymers and glasses, and is attributed to photogeneration of defects that contribute to the absorption in the UV region of the electromagnetic spectrum (called the &ldquo;defect generation mechanism&rdquo;). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates the effect of this mechanism, showing the transmission spectra of a polycarbonate substrate before and after exposure to intense UV light produced by Xenon RC-747&trade; pulsed lamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In addition to the defect generation mechanism, another mechanism is possible, such as in the case of photocurable polymers. As UV light leads to polymerization of a monomeric coating, the total UV exposure will determine the degree of polymerization of the material, and therefore, its optical properties including UV absorption in particular. Thus, exposure of a partially cured film to UV light results in higher degree of polymerization, which accounts for the difference in UV absorption compared to the original less-cured material (called the &ldquo;curing time mechanism&rdquo;). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the effect of this mechanism, showing the transmission spectra of a 19-&mgr;m-thick layer of Sony Chemicals lacquer SK6400 cured by UV light of a Xenon RC-747&trade; pulsed lamp with total exposure times of three seconds and one minute. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Due to either of the aforementioned mechanisms, selective UV exposure of some areas of certain substrates result in the formation of latent contrast between the exposed and virgin parts of the substrate. In one embodiment, this contrast becomes visible by placing a fluorescent layer under the substrate and illuminating a polymeric substrate with longwave UV or &ldquo;black&rdquo; light. Higher absorption of the illumination by the previously exposed areas of the substrate results in lower excitation levels of the underlying fluorescent layer and, consequently, lower brightness of the fluorescence, thereby producing a visible contrast. The substrate is assumed to be at least partially transmissive to the UV excitation and fluorescent emission. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Latent contrast formation is also possible using a further mechanism, called photobleaching that induces modification of the optical properties of a target molecule by irradiation of the target with UV. This technique may be practiced in a host polymer, provided the host is supportive of irradiation with UV. In one embodiment, a UV sensitive fluorescent additive is used as a target molecule, where the additive is mixed into a UV transparent polymer. In this embodiment, irradiation of the substrate with UV provides for modification of the optical properties of the fluorescent additive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Latent contrast may be achieved by using the three methods alone, or in combination. For example, fluorescent pigment may be intermixed with a coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> that carries the invisible print according to an embodiment of the present invention. This technique can be used for making invisible markings <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> on the read out surfaces of optical discs such as CDs and DVDs. A clear polymer impregnated with a fluorescent additive is applied to the read out surface of an optical disc <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> by spin-coating and, subsequently, is cured. According to such an embodiment, coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> is uniform and transparent in the visible and near-IR regions of the spectrum and, therefore, produces no interference with the read out laser beam. At this point in the manufacturing process, the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> produces uniform fluorescence across the entire coated area. A desired marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> may be transferred onto the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> by the above mechanisms of photoinduced UV absorption, and/or by photobleaching. The transfer may be achieved through UV irradiation using, for example, a photomask or by a direct laser writing process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Any of the above-mentioned mechanisms may be used to fabricate an image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> containing a watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. For example, a gray-scale image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> encoded with a watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> is printed on a UV-transparent substrate, with gray-scale print providing spatially variable attenuation for the UV radiation in accordance with the desired watermarked image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, thereby providing a photomask for subsequent transfer of the contrast onto a fluorescent polymeric substrate <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. Exposure of the fluorescent polymer to an intense UV-source through the prepared photomask results in transfer of the watermarked image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> onto the fluorescent polymer as a latent contrast. This latent contrast can be visualized, for example, via fluorescence under low-intensity UV radiation or &ldquo;black&rdquo; light and the watermarked image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> read out and decoded. Since digital watermarking supports inversion of contrast, either a positive or a negative photomask can be used, with the final fluorescent contrast being respectively negative or positive, while preserving the encoded watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. An example of a system that is supportive of this technique is the SysCop&trade; system available from MediaSec Technologies of Providence, R.I. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> depicts embodiments of markings <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> with digital watermarks <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A, a</cross-reference> marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> with a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> is printed onto a substrate using a substance that is reactive to an excitation source. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> depicts a marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> that is visible when illuminated with wavelengths of UV light. For convenience, the area of the marking over the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is identified from the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> side of the marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. The coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> absorbs light in the UV region, thereby causing a fluorescent emission in the visible region. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> depicts another embodiment, where the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> is further embellished with another coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>A, where a portion <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>A has been irradiated with UV light. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>B, the portion of the second coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> provides photoabsorption of wavelengths of UV light, thereby providing a perception of an image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> that is modified from the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> that appears in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an illustration of an embodiment where information has been transferred onto an optical media <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the optical media <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is a CD or DVD, which has a central clamping area <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> that is not used for the storage of data. The central clamping area <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> is substantially transparent. In this embodiment, an image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> includes a watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, which is formed in the clamping area <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> through use of a photomask, or any other suitable technique. The marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> was previously transferred in a predetermined pattern according to the needs of the user. In this embodiment, viewing of the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and the mark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> involves placing the optical media <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> over a fluorescent background <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight>. The fluorescent background <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> is independent of the optical media <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, and is supplied to provide contrast when exposed to UV light. UV light may be supplied by a low intensity UV light supply <highlight><bold>415</bold></highlight>. Once the optical media <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is placed over the fluorescent background <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> and exposed to UV light from the UV light supply <highlight><bold>415</bold></highlight>, the latent contrast from the UV exposure becomes apparent and the information bearing marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> becomes visible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> According to another embodiment of the present invention, a fluorescent polymeric layer is applied between the halves of a DVD <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. The latent image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> is produced on the read out side (also called the &ldquo;label side&rdquo;) by selective exposure of the DVD <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> to intense UV light through a photomask or by direct writing with a UV laser. Subsequent &ldquo;black&rdquo; light illumination generates a visible contrast fluorescence pattern. In this embodiment, the fluorescent layer is attached to the substrate <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> that is carrying the invisible print. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Latent contrast may be used alone or in combination with other techniques to create or enhance a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. In the embodiments where latent contrast is included in the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> is characterized by portions that are at least partially absorptive of UV. Examples include, but are not limited to, embodiments such as the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference>; and other embodiments where exposure to UV may be used to create shading and/or other effects. Further embodiments make use of photobleaching, where the fluorescent dye used in an invisible watermark is modified. In these embodiments, a UV laser may be used to enhance the marking, and provide for degrees of detail or control that may not be achievable through traditional techniques for application of fluorescent ink. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> It may therefore be realized by one of ordinary skill in the art, that the cooperation of ultraviolet irradiation and other techniques can provide for a degree of refinement in invisible images not otherwise attainable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Detection </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> A detector in combination with an excitation source may be used to read or display the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. The detector-source combination may be, for example, a handheld reader with a self contained UV source, such as a xenon flash source. The reader may also include a CCD pixel array and a display. One suitable type of detector is known as VeriCam&trade;, available from Spectra Systems of Providence, R.I. According to another embodiment, the reader may include a visible light scanner to convert the image to a digitized form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, a bar code symbology may be impregnated with a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows an example of such a bar code <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. Barcode <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> may be implemented using any suitable symbology including, without limitation, 3 of 9, I2 of 5, Code 128, UPC, 2-D, and 3-D symbologies. In addition to being encrypted with digitally watermarked information, bar code <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> can be made to contain a pass key to allow reading of bar code <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> itself. If the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> is not read, a properly designed terminal will not read bar code <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. The watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may be incorporated, for example, as a digitally embedded imprint in the bit pattern or noise of a digital image of the bar code <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Software technologies may be used to embed the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> such that it is recoverable using software or other automated or manual techniques. The digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may also include additional information that may be decoded by using a key to &ldquo;unlock&rdquo; data, for example, data included in another digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, or data within the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. The digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, and the other information that may be embedded in the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, is robust to image deformations, rotations, copying, multiple renderings, conversions, and other manipulations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> With respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the decoding or identification of coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may employ imaging of the coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> and/or the unique marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> as well as the detection of fluorescent emission or color if present. This can be achieved, for example, by using a microscope system coupled to a monolithic spectrometer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment may use a narrow band filtered detection system including CCD camera-based devices. Use of these, and other appropriately configured detection systems may provide for observation of markings <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> that are not otherwise visible to the unaided observer. Such systems may be used, among other things, to detect an image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, and to present a copy of the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> to a user, wherein the copy is provided by a device presenting the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> in the visible region. For example, an image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> that appears in the ultraviolet or the infrared region may be viewed using appropriate equipment that includes a detector configured to detect in the appropriate region, connected with image processing equipment and a display monitor, wherein the display monitor provides for viewing of the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> by the human observer. However, the slight variations in the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> that compose the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may, or may not, become apparent. In this manner, as one example, images <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> that were otherwise undetectable to a human observer become observable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows an exemplary detection system <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the present invention. A source of radiation <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is directed on article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> to be examined, such as a CD-ROM, DVD, or other suitable type of optically encoded medium. Source <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> may generate any type of radiation, such as UV radiation, that is suitable for detecting coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> included on article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> and/or watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> or any appropriate attributes of article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. Article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> may be mounted on a positioning device <highlight><bold>425</bold></highlight> to locate article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> for irradiation. Positioning device <highlight><bold>425</bold></highlight> may include a conveyor or any other type of device suitable for transporting or locating the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> for irradiation. Detection system <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may also include a detector array <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight>, such as a CCD camera or other suitable detection device with appropriate support circuitry <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> for detecting an image of article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> and watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. Detector array <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> may be fixed, moveable or handheld. Source <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and detector array <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> may also comprise positioning devices (not shown) for locating these devices for optimum performance. Detector array <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> may be capable of detecting the spectral content of any emissions, in addition to any other physical characteristics of watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> or article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> for identification and authentication of article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. Control circuitry <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> directs the activity of system <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, and in particular controls source <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, positioning device <highlight><bold>425</bold></highlight>, detector array <highlight><bold>436</bold></highlight> and support circuitry <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>. It is also within the scope or the invention to use a simple handheld reader, such as the one described above, as a detection system <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> According to an embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> detector array <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> includes an optical section <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> for focusing received emissions within detector array <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight>, an array of sensors <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> for detecting the emissions, and a filter section <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight> for allowing only the frequencies of interest to impinge on sensors <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight>. Optical section <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> may include a microscope system or any other system suitable for magnifying or otherwise focusing the image of article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> and/or any emissions from item <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> within the detector array <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight>. The sensor array <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> may include any array of sensors suitable for detecting the emissions and/or physical characteristics of article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> such as, for example, a diode array, a CCD array, etc. The sensor array <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> may be a one dimensional linear array that is scanned relative to the marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, or it may be a two dimensional area array that provides for &ldquo;snap shot&rdquo; imaging. Using this arrangement, the output of the detector array <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> is analyzed to detect the characteristics of and thereby interpret watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> and/or coating <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> so as to identify and authenticate article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, such as by obtaining plural bit data contained in the digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Further Embodiments </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> A variety of embodiments of the invention disclosed herein is possible. One skilled in the art will recognize that the embodiments disclosed herein are illustrative of features of this invention, and are not limiting of the invention. One skilled in the art will also recognize that many variations of this invention are achievable without deviation from the spirit of this invention. Among other things, the needs of the user play a role in the determination of the actual scheme used. Examples of further embodiments are thus now provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Multiple images <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> containing watermarks <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may be used to mark a single article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. Images <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> may be disposed upon the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> with a distinct relationship to each other. For example, an image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> could be overlapping, concentric, in registration with, or offset by some predetermined value from, another image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. The positioning of images <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> relative to each other, or on an article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, may be used to provide additional information to a user. In another example, a first image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may be not be apparent at visible wavelengths, while a second image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may appear at visible wavelengths. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Images <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> may be used in cooperation with one another. For example, the first image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, once detected may be used to locate the second image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>C depict an example of a &ldquo;split&rdquo; image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference> depicts one compliment <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>L of the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, which may be referred to for convenience as a &ldquo;left handed&rdquo; portion. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference> depicts the right handed compliment <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>R of the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11C</cross-reference> depicts the image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, after a processor has assembled the left and right images <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. A &ldquo;split&rdquo; image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> may be used, which contains a portion of a total image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and/or watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, where the complimentary portion is contained in a complimentary image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, or multiples of images <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>. The split image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> may be reconstructed into a single image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, among other means, by use of a processing system that is appropriately configured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments, the information contained in a digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> is used in some relationship to other digital watermarks <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> incorporated with the article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. For example, one digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may be used as a key to another digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. provides and example of this embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9, a</cross-reference> first image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A is not visible to a human observer under normal illumination with visible wavelengths. Information contained in the watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A may be used for an authentication of a bank card <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, where the presence of the watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A, or information contained within the watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A, is compared to corresponding features of an authentic version of the mark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A. Once authenticated, the detection and authentication system that is used to detect the mark is directed to a second invisible image <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> and digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>B. In this embodiment, the second watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>B may carry additional information, such as a decryption key used to gain access to a bank card system. In another embodiment, a first digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A may be observed by detection systems using visible light to excite the materials, which thereby causes the substrate materials to fluoresce in the IR region. In this embodiment, the second digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>B may be observed by detection systems using non-visible light, such as ultraviolet light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> In one variation of this embodiment, the second digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>B is formed of a material that may be imaged at a predetermined IR wavelength. A component of the detection system is configured to detect a narrow band of IR wavelengths containing the predetermined wavelength. In this example, the second watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>B may contain information needed by the user, such as, for example, encoded biometric data for verification of identity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, another embodiment involves use of digital watermarks <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> in registration with each other. For example, a visible digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A is applied to an article <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, with a second and invisible digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>B applied in registration with the first digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A. As an alternate embodiment, the first digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A and the second digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>B may be included in concentric images with varied appearance. In these embodiments, the first digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>A may appear when illuminated by a predetermined first band of wavelengths, for example in the UV region, and the second digital watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>B may appear when illuminated by a predetermined second band of wavelengths, for example in the IR region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> It is easily recognizable by one of ordinary skill in the art that many embodiments may be realized. For example, one may vary aspects such as, but not limited to, the wavelength at which a watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> may appear, the number of watermarks <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> in use, placement of watermarks <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, the information contained in a watermark <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight>, and the use of watermarks <highlight><bold>435</bold></highlight> as sources of various information, such as keys for access to other information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> In some embodiments of these teachings other stimuli may be used to make a normally invisible marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> become visible, such as but not limited to, at least one of the application of heat, a change in humidity, a change in pressure, or the application of one or more chemical agents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Preferably, after the stimulus is removed, the marking <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> one more becomes invisible, or substantially invisible, to the unaided observer, the observer being either a human or machine observer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> It can thus be appreciated that while the invention has been particularly shown and described with respect to preferred embodiments thereof, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that changes in form and details may be made therein without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An object comprising at least one digitally watermarked image, said digitally watermarked image being normally invisible and comprising a material that causes said digitally watermarked image to become detectable due at least in part to an optically absorptive property of said digitally watermarked image when exposed to a predetermined excitation source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The object as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said digitally watermarked image includes a data code symbology comprising at least one of a bar code, a graphic, text, and alphanumeric characters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The object as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said digitally watermarked image comprising at least one digital watermark is disposed upon said article in a coating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The object as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating comprises at least one of a polymeric material, a monomeric material, a metal chelate, an organic phosphor, an inorganic phosphor, a fluorescent dye and a laser dye. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The object as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said digitally watermarked image comprises information for purposes comprising at least one of authentication of said article, providing a relationship to said article, providing access to a digital watermark, providing access to said article, providing access to information contained within said article, and providing a key for decrypting encrypted information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The object as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said digitally watermarked image comprises a decryption key. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The object as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said object comprises one of an optical media, a security document, a note of currency, a product package, a label, an identification, and a credit card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An article comprising a marking, the marking comprising: 
<claim-text>a first digitally watermarked image, said digitally watermarked image being normally invisible and comprising a material that causes said digitally watermarked image to become detectable due at least in part to an optically absorptive property of said digitally watermarked image when exposed to a predetermined excitation source; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second digitally watermarked image disposed upon said article, wherein said second digitally watermarked image is substantially observable to the unaided observer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first digitally watermarked image is in registration with said second digitally watermarked image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first digitally watermarked image is offset from said second digitally watermarked image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first digitally watermarked image is concentric with said second digitally watermarked image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first digitally watermarked image and said second digitally watermarked image each comprise at least a complimentary portion of a complete digitally watermarked image of said marking. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of said digitally watermarked images comprises information for purposes comprising at least one of authentication of said article, providing a relationship to said article, providing access to a digital watermark, providing access to said article, providing access to information contained within said article, and providing a key for decrypting encrypted information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of said watermarks comprises a decryption key. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An article comprising a marking, the marking comprising: 
<claim-text>a first digitally watermarked image, said digitally watermarked image being normally invisible and comprising a material that causes said digitally watermarked image to become detectable due at least in part to an optically absorptive property of said digitally watermarked image when exposed to a first predetermined excitation source; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one second digitally watermarked image, said second digitally watermarked image being normally invisible and comprising a material that causes said second digitally watermarked image to become detectable when exposed to a second predetermined excitation source. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first digitally watermarked image is in registration with said at least one second digitally watermarked image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first digitally watermarked image is offset from said at least one second digitally watermarked image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first digitally watermarked image is concentric with said at least one second digitally watermarked image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first digitally watermarked image is overlapping with said at least one second digitally watermarked image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of said digitally watermarked images comprises information for purposes comprising at least one of authentication of said article, providing a relationship to said article, providing access to a digital watermark, providing access to said article, providing access to information contained within said article, and providing a key for decrypting encrypted information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An article as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first predetermined excitation source and said second predetermined excitation source comprise one of a same excitation source or two excitation sources. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a mark on an article, comprising: 
<claim-text>selecting a marking for said article; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing said article to ultraviolet light for applying at least one digitally watermarked image of said marking to said article, wherein said at least one digitally watermarked image is not substantially observable to the unaided observer, and said at least one digitally watermarked image being observable upon exposure to a predetermined excitation source. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein exposing is preceded by applying a coating to said article. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said coating comprises at least one of a polymeric material, a monomeric material, a metal chelate, an organic phosphor, an inorganic phosphor, a fluorescent dye and a laser dye. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein applying comprises at least one of printing, spraying, rolling, silk screening and painting. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein applying comprises use of at least one of a positive photomask, a negative photomask, and a UV laser. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein applying comprises applying a portion of said mark in a first image, and at least one complimentary portion of said mark in at least one second image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A method of examining an article containing a mark, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing an article having said mark, said mark comprising at least one digitally watermarked image, said digitally watermarked image being normally invisible and comprising a material that causes said digitally watermarked image to become detectable due at least in part to an optically absorptive property of said digitally watermarked image when exposed to a predetermined excitation source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing said article to said predetermined excitation source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting said at least one digital watermark in accordance with at least a partial absorption of UV light; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>decoding said at least one digital watermark. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said predetermined excitation source comprises at least one of a source of certain wavelengths of electromagnetic radiation, a source of a chemical agent, a source of thermal energy, a source of pressure, and source of humidity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said predetermined excitation source comprises at least one of ultraviolet light, visible light, and infrared light. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein detecting comprises using at least one of a charge coupled device and a visible light scanner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein detecting comprises using a hand held device comprising a detector and said predetermined excitation source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein detecting comprises at least one of an array of ultraviolet light sensors and an array of infrared light sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>comparing at least one said digital watermark to predetermined authentication information for said article; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>verifying authenticity of said article based upon the comparison. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising, when said article&apos;s authenticity has been verified, enabling access to information contained in said article. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>using information from said at least one digital watermark to decrypt further information, wherein said further information is included in at least one of another mark and said article. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one digitally watermarked image comprises a first complimentary digitally watermarked image and a second complimentary digitally watermarked image, the method further comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a complete digitally watermarked image from a combination of said first complimentary digitally watermarked image and said second complimentary digitally watermarked image.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030005304A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
