<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004637A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004637A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004637</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10169694</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020703</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-375321</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001208</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01C021/28</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>701</class>
<subclass>207000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>701</class>
<subclass>208000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Position information identifier providing system, and position information identifier transmitting method and device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shinya</given-name>
<family-name>Adachi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kanagawa</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>PEARNE &amp; GORDON LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>526 SUPERIOR AVENUE EAST</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1200</address-2>
<city>CLEVELAND</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>44114-1484</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/JP01/10749</doc-number>
<document-date>20011207</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">This invention provides a system for aiding information providing services utilizing position information identifiers, which is a position information identifier providing system including information providing means (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) for providing to a receiving device (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) containing a database (<highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>) of position information identifiers and a database (<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>) of a digital map, only the information using said position information identifiers; and position information identifier information providing means (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) for providing only updated position information identifier information to said receiving device, in addition to said information providing means. The system is capable of supplementarily supporting a scheme of providing information by using the position information identifier. The burden imposed on the map data manufacturer, such as the maintenance and after-sales service, which result from the updating of the position information identifier, is lightened. Further, there is no need of transmitting the new and old position information identifiers redundantly to the VICS information. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a system for providing updating information of a position information identifier, which defines a road position, to an on-board device or the like, a method for transmitting the position information identifier in that case, and a device for executing the method. More particularly, the invention aids a system for providing traffic information by using the position information identifier. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Recently, the vehicle carrying thereon an on-board navigation device rapidly increases its number. The on-board navigation device contains digital map database, and receives information by a VICS (vehicle information communication system), which provides traffic congestion information or traffic accident information, through media such as FM multiplex broadcasting, or radio or optical beacon, displays a congested or accident position on a map, and adds those pieces of information to the condition and executes a route search process based on the condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The digital map database is currently prepared by several companies in Japan. The map data contains errors as the fatality of the scale map. Those errors contained in the map data are different for each company. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In the transmission of traffic information, e.g., the position of a traffic accident on the on-board navigation device, if the longitude and latitude data representative of that position is solely presented, the on-board navigation device mistakenly recognizes a position on a different road as the accident position, depending on some types of the digital map database contained therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To avoid such an unexactness of the information transmission, in the VICS information, road positions are designated by using position information identifiers, such as node numbers assigned to nodes, e.g., intersections, link numbers assigned to the links each between adjacent nodes or the like. In the digital map database of every company, the intersections and roads are stored in association with node numbers and link numbers. Accordingly, each road position described in terms of the VICS information may uniquely be specified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The position information identifier is defined according to predetermined rules. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), each node has a node number, which is uniquely assigned to and indicates the node. A link number of a road &ldquo;c&rdquo; located between a node &ldquo;a&rdquo; (node number&equals;1111) and another node &ldquo;b&rdquo; (node number 3333) is assigned &ldquo;11113333&rdquo; in which the large node number &ldquo;3333&rdquo; follows the small node number &ldquo;1111&rdquo;. A curve of the road is approximated by a polygonal line, apexes of the polygonal line are set as interpolating points, the node &ldquo;a&rdquo; of the small node number is designated as an interpolating point (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), and the node &ldquo;b&rdquo; is designated as the final interpolating point, and the interpolating points located between the nodes &ldquo;a&rdquo; and &ldquo;b&rdquo; are sequentially numbered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), in a case where a new road is constructed and another node &ldquo;d&rdquo; (node number&equals;4444) is provided anew, the old link number &ldquo;11113333&rdquo; is substituted by a new line number 11114444 assigned to a link &ldquo;f&rdquo; between the nodes &ldquo;a&rdquo; and &ldquo;d&rdquo;, and another new link number &ldquo;33334444&rdquo; assigned to a link &ldquo;e&rdquo; between the nodes &ldquo;d&rdquo; and &ldquo;b&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Updating information of the position information identifier is recorded into a recording medium, and distributed to the related map data manufacturing companies, from a distribution source. Each company modifies the company&apos;s map data on the basis of the updated position information identifier. Some companies accept a customer&apos;s request of modifying the map data as the after-sales service to the map data sold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In the VICS information, even after the position information identifier is updated, traffic information containing both the position information identifier after updated and the position information identifier before updated is provided for a predetermined period of time, while taking the on-board navigation devices containing the digital map data before updated into consideration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Road construction and alteration will be carried out continuously in the future, and the position information identifier will be updated repeatedly. Accordingly, the money as invested into the maintenance and after-sales service by the map data manufacturers, is extremely large. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the VICS information, it is necessary to send the new and old position information identifiers redundantly. Therefore, to maintain the information providing system, which utilizes the position information identifiers, much cost is taken in various forms, such as economic burden to prepare its data, and data transmission inefficiency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, an object of the present invention is to provide a system for aiding the information providing service utilizing the position information identifiers, and a method and apparatus for transmitting position information identifiers in that system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the invention, there is provided a position information identifier providing system, which includes: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> 1) information providing means for providing to a receiving device containing a database of position information identifiers and a database of a digital map, only the information using said position information identifiers; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> 2) position information identifier information providing means for providing only updated position information identifier information to said receiving device, in addition to said information providing means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, there is provided a method for transmitting to a receiving device containing a database of position information identifiers and a database of a digital map, information on said position information identifier as updated, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> wherein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> 1) information on said position information identifier and coordinate row information of nodes and interpolating points, both constituting said position information identifier, is transmitted to said receiving device, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> 2) said receiving device executes a map matching process to determine a position on said digital map, which corresponds to said position information identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> According to still another aspect, there is provided a position information identifier transmitter for generating and transmitting position information identifier transmitting information containing information on a position information identifier and coordinate row information of nodes and interpolating points, both constituting said position information identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> According to still another aspect of the invention, there is provided a receiving device which contains a database on a position information identifier and a database on a digital map, and receives information using said position information identifier and displays a position on a digital map, which corresponds to said position information identifier, the improvement being characterized in that </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> 1) said receiving device receives information of an updated position information identifier and position information identifier transmitting information containing information on a position information identifier and coordinate row information of nodes and interpolating points, both constituting said position information identifier, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> 2) said receiving device stores said position information identifier into said position information identifier database, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> 3) said receiving device carries out a map matching process by using said coordinate row information to thereby determine a position of said position information identifier on a digital map. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The system of the invention is capable of supplementarily supporting a scheme of providing information by using the position information identifier. The burden imposed on the map data manufacturer, such as the maintenance and after-sales service, which result from the updating of the position information identifier, is lightened. Further, there is no need of transmitting the new and old position information identifiers redundantly to the VICS information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Where the position information identifier transmitting method of the invention is employed, if different digital map data is used, the receiving side device reliably makes the correspondence between the position information identifier and the position on the digital map</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing an arrangement of a position information identifier providing system, which is an embodiment of the present invention, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a data configuration of position information identifier information provided in the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a data configuration of supplementary information provided in the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a data configuration of accident information, which is provided as traffic information in the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a data configuration of traffic congestion information, which is provided as traffic information in the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flow chart showing operations at respective portions in the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a first application of the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a second application of the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a third application of the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a position information identifier in the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another position information identifier in the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a diagram showing yet another position information identifier in the embodiment system, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a diagram showing an application other than the transmission of the updated position information identifier in the embodiment system, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) are diagrams for explaining the updating of the position information identifier.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BEST MODES FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> A system of an embodiment according to the invention, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, is made up of media <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for providing various pieces of traffic information by using position information identifiers, a position information identifier transmitting device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for providing information of the position information identifiers per se, and a receiving side device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> which receives traffic information from the media <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and receives position information identifier information from the position information identifier transmitting device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The position information identifier transmitting device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a new position information identifier database A <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, a digital map database A <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a position information identifier transmitting information generating part <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> for generating transmitting information of position information identifiers, and a position information identifier information transmitting part <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for transmitting generated information of position information identifiers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The receiving side device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes a position information identifier database B <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, a digital map database B <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, a position information identifier information receiving part <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> which receives position information identifier information from the position information identifier transmitting device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, an information reflection judging part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which judges the position information identifiers and selects those position information identifiers needed by the receiver unit, a map matching part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> which executes a map matching process to determine a position of the position information identifier on the digital map, traffic information receiving parts <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for receiving traffic information from media, a traffic-information generating position computing part <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> which computes a position where an event, such as traffic accident or traffic congestion, occurs, from the information received, and a digital map display part <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> which displays the position where the event occurs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The receiving side device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is mounted on a vehicle. Traffic information are provided by media, such as a traffic information providing channel (channel A) of ground wave digital broadcasting as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> and a beacon as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. Information on the position information identifier is provided by a position information identifier information providing channel (channel B) of the ground wave digital broadcasting, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows operating procedures of the position information identifier transmitting device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the traffic information transmitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the receiving side device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The following operation is performed in the position information identifier transmitting device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>: The position information identifier transmitting information generating part <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> selects a new position information identifier (e.g., link data) from the position information identifier database A <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, or selects information of an position information identifier containing a position of or designated by the receiver unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>: The position information identifier transmitting information generating part acquires coordinate values (longitude/latitude) of nodes and interpolating points, which constitute the position information identifier, from the digital map database A <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and generates a coordinate row. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>: The position information identifier transmitting information generating part further acquires supplementary information indicating the attributes of the nodes and the links each between adjacent nodes, from the digital map database A <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The supplementary information includes information on road type code, road number, the number of connection links at the intersection node, and connection link angles of the connection links and others. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>: When a configuration of an array of interpolating points may be approximated by a function, the array configuration is expressed by the function, whereby the coordinate row data is compressed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>: When the interpolating points are linearly arrayed, the interpolating points are thinned to compress the coordinate row data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>: The coordinate value of the first node in the coordinate row is expressed by the absolute coordinate. The coordinate values of the second and subsequent nodes (or interpolating points) are expressed, to compress the data amount, by the relative coordinate in a manner that a difference between the coordinate value of the first node and the coordinate value of the preceding node (or the interpolating point). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>: Information (link number) of the position information identifier and information of the coordinate row or the supplementary information are formatted into a transmission format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>: The position information identifier information transmitting part <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> transmits this data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> exemplarily shows a data configuration of the position information identifier information, and the added road information is exemplarily shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The receiving side device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> which has received the position information identifier information and the supplementary information performs following operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>: The position information identifier information receiving part <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> receives the data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>: The information reflection judging part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> compares the received data with the position information identifiers stored in the position information identifier data base B <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, and selects the position information identifier to be updated from the received data, and stores the selected position information identifier into the position information identifier database B <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> In this case, when the received information is not contained in the position information identifier database, or when the received information is newer than the data stored in the self device, the received position information identifier maybe stored in the position information identifier database B <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>: The map matching part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> carries out a map matching process of the data of the coordinate row contained in the position information identifier information to the data of the digital map database B <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to thereby determine a position of the position information identifier on the digital map. At this time, the map matching part makes a short list of candidate points of the position information identifier positions by referring to the supplementary information, azimuth information of the nodes contained in the position information identifier information, height information and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>: The information reflection judging part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> associates the previously stored position information identifier with the position on the digital map, which is determined by the map matching part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In this way, data of the new position information identifier is stored into the position information identifier database B <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The traffic information transmitting device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> provides traffic information in the following procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>: Position where an event, such as traffic congestion or traffic accident, occurs, is entered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>: A relative distance (relative position) to the event occurring position is computed using a position information identifier (link number) of the road where the event occurs, and the nodes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>: A format of those pieces of position information is converted to a transmission format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>: The information transmission formatted is then transmitted in the form of event information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows event information presented when a traffic accident occurs, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows event information presented at the time of traffic congestion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The receiving side device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> that receives the event information operates in the following way. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>: The traffic information receiving parts <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> receive the event information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>: The traffic-information generating position computing part <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> specifies a road on the digital map, which contains an event occurring position, by using the position information identifier contained in the event information and the data of the position information identifier database B <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and the digital map database B <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, and specifies the event occurring position on the road based on a relative position contained in the event information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Step <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>: The event occurring position is visually presented on the map displayed in the digital map display part <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Thus, in this system, the position information identifiers stored in the receiving side device are automatically updated according to the information from the position information identifier transmitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and the newest position information identifier is stored in the receiving side device. For this reason, the traffic information transmitting device is able to provide traffic information by using only the newest position information identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Also in the system, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the information of the position information identifier may be received from other media than the media providing traffic information, by way of a portable telephone set. In this case, when the position information identifier, which is not found in the self position information identifier database B <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, is contained in the traffic information, the receiving side device requests the position information identifier providing media to send the position information identifier, by way of the portable telephone set. Upon receipt of this, the position information identifier providing media sends the requested position information identifier to the receiving side device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Some examples of the position information identifiers are presented: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> (1) &ldquo;Position information identifier 1&rdquo; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Links&rdquo; each connecting the intersections are numbered every area to advance, and the road interval and direction are expressed by one number assigned to the link. VICS links or the like, currently operated in trunk roads in Japan may be enumerated for this position information identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> (2) &ldquo;Position information identifier 2&rdquo; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> It is defined without using the direction, and the direction is added to dynamic information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> (3) &ldquo;Node identifier&rdquo; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The intersections per se are numbered, and the road interval is expressed by using two numbers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> How to display the traffic congestion information in FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will be described. When the &ldquo;position information identifier 1&rdquo; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) is used, the congestion information is displayed as &ldquo;position information identifier is <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, and the congested block is 250 m to 450 m&rdquo;. When the &ldquo;position information identifier 2&rdquo; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>) is used for displaying the same information, its display is &ldquo;the position information identifier is <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the direction is the reverse direction, and the congested block is 250 m to 450 m&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> When the same information is displayed by using the &ldquo;position information identifier&rdquo; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>), the display is &ldquo;the position information identifier is <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight>, and the congested block is 250 m to 450 m&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> An application other than the transmission of the updated position information identifier in the embodiment system, is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In this example, at the start, the on-board navigation device contains only the digital map, and it sends, as needed, necessary information to a currently traveling area (further it may be what is obtained by extracting only the links from the information provided). Subsequently, the vehicle carrying the on-board navigation device further travels, and the vehicle&apos;s position changes with its traveling. The position information identifier is updated with the changing vehicle&apos;s position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In a specific example, a vehicle which holds only the digital map information at the time of its starting, starts from a location in the Tokyo Metropolitan area, in a state that it is not loaded with the position information identifier. During its traveling in the Tokyo Metropolitan area, the vehicle receives the position information identifiers in the Metropolitan area, and traffic information in the same area. When the vehicle further travels and enters the Kanagawa prefecture area, the vehicle receives the position information identifiers in the Kanagawa prefecture area and traffic information in the same area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> While the present invention has been described in detail and using a specific embodiment, it should be understood that the invention may variously be modified, altered and changed within the true spirits and scope of the invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> This application is based on Japanese Patent Application (Application No 2000-375321), filed Dec. 8, 2000, the content of which is incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> As seen from the foregoing description, the system of the invention is capable of supplementarily supporting a scheme of providing information by using the position information identifiers, and lightening the burden imposed on the map data manufacturer in order to maintain the scheme of providing information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Further, there is no need of transmitting the new and old position information identifiers redundantly to the VICS information. Accordingly, the efficiency of the data transmission is improved, and the resultant energy may be used for enriching the information service. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Where the position information identifier transmitting method of the invention is employed, the receiving side device reliably makes the correspondence between the position information identifier and the position on the digital map even if different digital map data is used. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier providing system comprising: 
<claim-text>information providing means for providing to a receiving device containing a database of position information identifiers and a database of a digital map, only the information using said position information identifiers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>position information identifier information providing means for providing only updated position information identifier information to said receiving device, in addition to said information providing means. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier providing system comprising: 
<claim-text>information providing means for providing only the information using position information identifiers to a receiving device containing a database of a digital map; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>position information identifier information providing means for providing only position information identifier information to said receiving device, in addition to said information providing means. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier providing system comprising: 
<claim-text>information providing means for providing to a receiving device containing at least one of a database of position information identifiers and a database of a digital map, only the information using said position information identifiers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>position information identifier information providing means for providing only updated position information identifier information to said receiving device, in addition to said information providing means. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier providing system any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">3</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said position information identifier information is information of a position information identifier containing a position of or specified by said receiving device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier providing system any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">3</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said information providing means and said position information identifier information providing means provide their information by use of different channels of broadcasting media. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier providing system any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">5</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein one of said information providing means is a beacon. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier providing system any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">3</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said information providing means and said position information identifier information providing means provide their information by use of different media. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier providing system any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">7</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein said position information identifier information providing means provides said position information identifier information upon receipt of a request by a portable telephone set from said receiving device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method for transmitting information on position information identifier to a receiving device including at least one of a data base of position information identifiers and a database of a digital map, said method comprising the steps of; 
<claim-text>transmitting information on said position information identifier and coordinate row information to said receiving device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a map matching process at said receiving device in order to determine a position on said digital map; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said coordinate row information includes nodes and interpolating points, both of which are constituting said position information identifier, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said determined position on said digital map corresponds to said position information identifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>wherein, in the step of transmitting, supplementary information is further transmitted to said receiving device together with said coordinate row information, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, in the step of executing a map matching at said receiving side device, candidate points obtained through the execution of a map matching process are limited by using said supplementary information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A position information identifier transmitter which generates and transmits position information identifier transmitting information including information on a position information identifier and coordinate row information of nodes and interpolating points, both constituting said position information identifier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A receiving device including at least one of a database on a position information identifier and a database on a digital map for receiving information using said position information identifier and displaying a position on a digital map, which corresponds to said position information identifier, said receiving device is characterized in that: 
<claim-text>coordinate row information of nodes and interpolating points, both constituting said position information identifier, and information on said position information identifier are received at said receiving device, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a map matching process is executed at said receiving device by using said coordinate row information, and thereby, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said position of said position information identifier on a digital map is determined.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004637A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
