<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001300A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001300A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001300A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001300A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001300A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001300A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001300A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001300A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001300</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09453328</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>19991202</filing-date>
<continued-prosecution-application>This is a publication of a continued prosecution application (CPA) filed under 37 CFR 1.53(d).</continued-prosecution-application>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B29C045/84</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>264</class>
<subclass>040500</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>264</class>
<subclass>328100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>264</class>
<subclass>328700</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>METHOD OF RELEASING PRESSURE IN NON-METALLIC INJECTION MOLDS</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>CARL E.</given-name>
<family-name>RADZIO</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>BROCKPORT</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>RICHARD C.</given-name>
<family-name>BENSON</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>ROCHESTER</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>ROBYN S.</given-name>
<family-name>CHADDOCK</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>ELBA</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>PATENT LEGAL STAFF</name-1>
<name-2>EASTMAN KODAK COMPANY</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>343 STATE STREET</address-1>
<city>ROCHESTER</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>14650-2201</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of releasing pressure in a non-metallic injection mold has a pressure relief valve positioned in the molten resin flow path for handling excess resin pressure. The pressure relief valve responds to excess resin pressure in the cavity by providing an alternate resin flow path for the pressurized excess resin. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present application is related to U.S. application Ser. No. (Docket 79189), filed herewith, by Radzio, et al., and entitled, &ldquo;Injection Molding Apparatus For A Non-Metallic Injection Mold,&rdquo; and U.S. application Ser. No. (Docket 80027), filed herewith, by Radzio, et al., and entitled, &ldquo;Pressure Relief Valve For Non-Metallic Injection Molds.&rdquo;</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention relates generally to the field of injection molding. More particularly, the invention concerns an injection molding method having a pressure relief valve that provides an alternate resin passage for excess molten resin under a predetermined pressure in a non-metallic injection mold. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Cost reductions in low to mid volume injection molding operations has led to the use of one piece case epoxy molds as an alternative to more expensive steel or aluminum tooling. Several have developed techniques to produce production injection molded parts using these cast epoxy molds. The epoxy molds are cast as a single piece for each half of the mold as opposed to hard tooling that is machined out of steel or aluminum. The main limiting factor of the epoxy mold is its inability to withstand the normal cavity pressures created within a conventional mold. Epoxy molds will only tolerate 10%-15% of the pressure that a steel or aluminum mold will tolerate. But they still require adequate pressure during injection and packing to produce an acceptable part. If cavity pressure should spike during injection or pack, the epoxy mold will fail catastrophically. This means that one half, or in some cases both halves, of the mold will split into pieces, effectively destroying the mold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> It is our experience that epoxy injection molds for molding low to mid volume production parts need protection against catastrophic failure. The method and apparatus for protecting these molds needs to be simple, adjustable for different molding resins, specific to each mold so that the mold is protected in any molding machine, and the method and apparatus needs to reset itself automatically whenever it is actuated to protect the mold. Several known attempts have been made to resolve these problems unique to non-metallic molds but most were rejected because of cost and the problem of modifying all the different molding machines that these molds can run in. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In U.S. Pat. No. 5,350,288, Sep. 27, 1994, by Kimoto et al, entitled Injection Molding Unit, an injection molding unit is disclosed that uses a pressure relief valve in a conventional metallic (steel) mold. A major shortcoming of the aforementioned valve arrangement is that if the relief valve operates and releases excess melt pressure from the mold, the mold and/or relief valve assembly will have to be disassembled to remove the solidified plastic material. Moreover, the relief valve operates as a part of the injection molding machine without any obvious means of adjusting the pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Therefore, a need persists in the art for an injection molding method having a non-metallic mold that resists catastrophic failure under high molten resin pressure. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a method of releasing pressure in an injection molding apparatus having a non-metallic injection mold for molding low to medium volume production parts without catastrophic failures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention is to provide a method using an adjustable pressure relief valve that can be set at a predetermined value for accommodating molten resins having different flow characteristics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the invention to provide a method using an alternate flow path for accommodating excess molten resin produced by excess resin pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> It is a feature of the invention that a method for releasing pressure uses a pressure relief valve associated with the molding apparatus for providing excess molten resin access to the alternate molten resin flow passage when the pressure in the molten resin passage is beyond a predetermined value. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> To achieve one or more of the above objects, features and advantages of the invention, there is provided in one aspect of the invention, a method of releasing pressure in an injection mold having a non-metallic mold and a first, molten resin flow path for receiving a molten resin, comprising the steps of: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> providing a pressure relief valve having an outwardly extending, axially movable, biased pin member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> forming a second molten resin flow path in an adjacent structure associated with said pressure relief valve for excess resin flow away from said non-metallic mold for use when pressure in said first molten resin flow path exceeds a predetermined value, said alternate molten resin flow path being configurable for fluid communications with said first molten resin flow path; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> positioning said axially movable, biased pin member at a terminal end of the first molten resin flow path so as to block the flow of resin beyond said terminal end; and, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> ejecting a molten resin through said molten resin flow path of said non-metallic mold such that any excess molten resin in said molten resin flow path creates excess pressure on said pin member of said pressure relief valve thereby causing said biased pin member to retract away from said terminal end of said first molten resin flow path and then open said excess molten resin to fluid communications with said alternate resin flow path. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The method of the invention, therefore, has numerous advantageous effects over currently existing developments, including: parts can be molded in an epoxy injection mold without the prospects of mold failure; the pressure relief valve is adjustable for different resins (for instance PC requires a heavier spring and less adjustment pre-load than HIPS); the pressure relief valve is specific to the mold, i.e., once it is set up properly and adjusted for a specific resin, it operates to protect the mold in any molding machine that one might use; the pressure relief valve resets itself automatically after it actuates; and, any part molded when the pressure relief valve actuates will eject from the mold with the resin from the escape channel attached. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects, features, and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent when taken in conjunction with the following description and drawings wherein identical reference numerals have been used, where possible, to designate identical features that are common to the figures, and wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-section view of a typical injection molding machine; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross section of the injection molding apparatus of the invention having the pressure relief valve in a molten resin blocking position; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-section of the injection molding apparatus of the invention having the pressure relief valve in a molten resin unblocking position.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Turning now to the drawings, and in particular to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, an injection molding apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated. Broadly defined, according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, injection molding apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has an injection molding machine <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for injecting molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Skilled artisans will appreciate that injection molding machine <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a platen <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> supporting a screw cylinder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> having a tip <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a nozzle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at the tip <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and a screw <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> advanceable in the screw cylinder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for injecting molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> from the nozzle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> According to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the injection molding apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention has a non-metallic injection mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for molding a part (not shown). Non-metallic injection mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> comprises a stationary cavity mold <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and a movable core mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> forming a hollow or first molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> therebetween for forming an injection molded product therein. Core mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is movable by ejector pins <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> arranged in mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for forceably separating the hollow <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> from the core mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Non-metallic injection mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may include various materials such as thermoset materials as well as cast epoxy, stereo lithography urethane and silicone. In the preferred embodiment, the injection mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is constructed of cast epoxy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, hollow or first molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extends from the screw cylinder <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to a terminal end <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the hollow <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is located on the hollow or first molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at the terminal end <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the hollow <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is adapted to release the molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> from the first molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> when the pressure of the molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> exceeds a predetermined level or value, further discussed below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, more particularly, pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is shown in a first position blocking molten resin flow beyond the terminal end <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the first molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In this position, molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is retained in the hollow or first molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by the pressure of movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The pressure of the molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in this position is generally less than a predetermined value determined by the strength of a spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> (described below) biasing movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is shown in a second position unblocking the excess molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in the hollow or first molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> thereby enabling the excess molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to flow into a second molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> beyond the first molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In this configuration, the first molten resin flow path or hollow <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is in fluid communications with the second molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. As depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> has preferably a cylindrically shaped body with a movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> arranged for axial movements in one end <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is disposed between the movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a base plate <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> that affixes the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> under the movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in a biasing relations. In the preferred embodiment, an adjustment screw <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is arranged in the base plate <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> for applying the pre-load to the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the entire pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is cast into the movable core mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of an epoxy injection mold so that the movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> extends through the parting line <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> to shut off the second molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The novel and unobvious design of the second molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> on the surface of the parting line <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> allows the vented molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to come out of the mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> with the part and then allows the pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to reset automatically. Skilled artisans will appreciate that pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may also be cast in the stationary cavity mold <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for epoxy injection molds <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is adjustable by one of two ways. First, the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> may be adjusted to apply more or less resistance on spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Second, the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be selected having a pre-selected strength, as discussed further below. Although either means of adjusting pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> has advantages over the other, we generally prefer adjusting the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to affect the resistance of the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> that governs the movements of movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Referring again to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is actuated directly by the pressurized, molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in the cavity mold <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. As indicated above, movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> shuts off the resin escape channel or second molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> under a predetermined pressure and is held in place by the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. When the cavity pressure exceeds the predetermined pressure limit the movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> pushes back against the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and allows the excess resin and pressure to escape the mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> through the second molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> or escape channel. Not only does this vent the molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> out of the hollow <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, but it also reduces the pressure in the cavity mold <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> below the cavity mold failure point. After the part cures (cools) in the mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> opens and the part is ejected automatically. The molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that flowed into the escape channel or second molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is ejected along with the part and the movable pin <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> resets itself automatically, shutting off the second molten resin flow path <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> We have demonstrated that the test epoxy mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can successfully vent excess molten resin pressure before the cavity mold <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> fails. We were able to accommodate different materials that require different pressures of cavity mold <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> by changing the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in the pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and/or adjusting the pre-load on the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, as described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> An example of the process for selecting the proper strength spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and pre-load adjustment for the cavity mold <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and molten resin <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is illustrated in Table 1. According to Table 1, the amount of pressure in the cavity mold <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> appeared fairly constant as a function of the spring bias <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> between minimum and maximum settings. Thus, one can select the appropriate spring type to enable ejection molding in the mold <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at a certain pressure.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>HOLD</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SETTING</entry>
<entry>PRESS&quest;</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>CAVITY</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>SPRING</entry>
<entry>MIN/MAX</entry>
<entry>YES/NO</entry>
<entry>PIN TRAVEL</entry>
<entry>PRESS. (psi)</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="42PT" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Blue - LIGHT</entry>
<entry>Min</entry>
<entry>No</entry>
<entry>0.060</entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Half</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>0.028</entry>
<entry>875</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Max</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>0.018</entry>
<entry>875</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Orange</entry>
<entry>Min</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>0.050</entry>
<entry>1750</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Half</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>0.025</entry>
<entry>1750</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Max</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>0.015</entry>
<entry>1750</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Blue - HEAVY</entry>
<entry>Min</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>0.025</entry>
<entry>2000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Half</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
<entry>0.012</entry>
<entry>2000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Max</entry>
<entry>Unsafe</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>conditions</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number>  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PARTS LIST</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="77PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="140PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>injection molding apparatus</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>12</entry>
<entry>injection molding machine</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>14</entry>
<entry>molten resin</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>screw cylinder</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>17</entry>
<entry>platen</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>18</entry>
<entry>tip</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>nozzle</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>22</entry>
<entry>screw</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>24</entry>
<entry>non-metallic injection mold</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>26</entry>
<entry>stationary cavity mold</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>28</entry>
<entry>movable core mold</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>29</entry>
<entry>ejector pins</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>30</entry>
<entry>hollow or first molten resin flow path</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>35</entry>
<entry>terminal end of the hollow 30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>pressure relief valve</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>38</entry>
<entry>second molten resin flow path</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>42</entry>
<entry>movable pin</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>44</entry>
<entry>spring bias</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>45</entry>
<entry>one end of pressure relief valve 36</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>46</entry>
<entry>base plate</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>48</entry>
<entry>adjustment screw</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>54</entry>
<entry>parting line</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of releasing pressure in an injection mold having a non-metallic mold and a first molten resin flow path for receiving a molten resin, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a pressure relief valve having an outwardly extending, axially movable, biased pin member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second molten resin flow path in an adjacent structure associated with said pressure relief valve for excess resin flow away from said non-metallic mold for use when pressure in said first molten resin flow path exceeds a predetermined value, said second molten resin flow path being configurable for fluid communications with said first molten resin flow path; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning said axially movable, biased pin member at a terminal end of said first molten resin flow path so as to block the flow of said molten resin beyond said terminal end; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>ejecting said molten resin through said molten resin flow path of said non-metallic mold such that any excess molten resin in said first molten resin flow path creates excess pressure on said pin member of said pressure relief valve thereby causing said biased pin member to retract away from said terminal end of said first molten resin flow path and then open said excess molten resin to fluid communications with said second molten resin flow path. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said step of forming a second molten resin flow path comprises the step of providing said second molten resin flow path along a parting line between movable and stationary structures surrounding said non-metallic mold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of adjusting pressure of said biased pin member to a predetermined value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of adjusting pressure of said biased pin member comprises the step of changing a spring bias member supporting said biased pin member for axial movement under pressure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of adjusting pressure of said biased pin member comprises adjusting an adjustment screw securing said biased pin member in said pressure relief valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001300A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001300A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001300A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001300A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
