<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001381A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001381A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001381</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09897759</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B42D015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>283</class>
<subclass>101000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Self-laminating strip label and method for assembling same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Riley</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>St. Louis</city>
<state>MO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Laser Band, LLC</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>THOMPSON COBURN, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>ONE FIRSTAR PLAZA</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 3500</address-2>
<city>ST LOUIS</city>
<state>MO</state>
<postalcode>63101</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A self-laminating strip label is provided in a business form comprised of a face stock layer joined through a patterned adhesive/release coating layer to a laminating layer wherein separation lines are provided in each of the two layers with the separation lines being substantially aligned with the strip label being positioned above the laminating strip. A novel method is also taught for first separating the strip label from the form, inverting it, and reapplying it to the laminating strip to thus form a matrix within the form with adhesive securing the strip label to the laminating strip. The matrix may then be separated by separating the laminating strip along its defining separation line yielding a self-laminated strip label for application to a marker tab of a file folder or the like. In a second embodiment, the face stock of the two-layer business form includes a first somewhat larger separation line defining a dummy layer and a second separation line defining a somewhat smaller strip label, with the separation lines being appropriately aligned on the face stock with a fold line therebetween such that upon removal of the dummy label, a layer of adhesive is exposed to which the strip label may be adhered upon folding of the form in half. In a third embodiment, a strip label is offset from the lamination so that the form may be folded to bring the lamination layer into register and adhesive contact with the strip label for reliably aligning the two either prior to or after the strip label is adhered to another form. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> It is well know in the art that labels are useful for many types of business forms. In many applications, it has been found that it is much more cost effective and convenient to provide essentially blank forms and then some form of separate customizable or printable label for uniquely identifying that form. One such major application for this technique includes the typical file folder with which those in office settings are imminently familiar. There are many different types of file folders including the ubiquitous manila file folders that have a tab which in the prior art provides a convenient place for the application of a label or even hand scrawling an identifying title for its contents. This tab has been located at the top or side of the file folder to accommodate the particular filing cabinet or shelf used to store what is typically a series of them each holding related information, such as patient files, customer files, etc. As an aid in maintaining them in proper order, avoiding losing or mis-filing files, and retrieving them, various schemes have been developed for all manner of coding systems. These include most predominantly color coding and bar coding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> One example of the type of labeling file folders which is available in the prior art is presently being marketed under the ColorBar&reg; trademark by Smead Mfg. Co. That product essentially comprises self adhering labels provided in roll format or on a sheet which may be as large as 8&frac12; by 11 inches and have multiple labels for convenient processing by a printer such as a laser printer, typically under computer control, with custom software also being provided. This product has become to be known as <custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00001"/>strip labels<custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00002"/>as they take the form of a strip which is approximately twice as wide as the tab and printable on both sides to allow the strip label to be adhered to and cover both sides of the tab. While this product, and other similar products, have allowed for the customized printing of labels that may then be applied to the various types of business forms including file folders, they have been further improved to solve issues that have developed with their use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> One such issue has been the unevenness with which these strip labels have been applied to the folders, thereby interfering with the <custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00003"/>eyeballing<custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00004"/>of a row of files to locate files that are out of place and otherwise making it difficult to locate a particular file due to the <custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00005"/>inconsistent<custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00006"/>appearance of the file labels. As it is desired for files to be kept neat and organized, an <custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00007"/>inconsistent<custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00008"/>appearance detracts from that goal. To solve this problem, there has been developed at least one method in the prior art for consistently aligning the labels as they are applied to the folder tab. That form and method is presently being marketed under the ClickStrip&trade; trademark by Smead Mfg. Co, and may be the subject of a pending patent application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Still another issue which has arisen through the use of these types of labels is the propensity for the customized labeling to be worn away by the constant handling of the file by the strip label, which covers the file tab. As the tab sticks out from what is typically the side or top of the folder, it becomes a convenient <custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00009"/>handle<custom-character file="US20030001381A1-20030102-P00001.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00010"/>for the user to grasp the file for removing it from, or replacing it back into, its location within the drawer or shelf. This usage induces an inordinate amount of wear on the pre-printed color bars or bar code or other identifying indicia as a person&apos;s fingers have contaminants such as perspiration, hand lotion, and other such substances which contact the face of the label and have a deleterious affect thereon. Furthermore, in some instances, the file may be difficult to remove or replace due to the crowding of the file folders so that some appreciable gripping force is applied, and the users fingers may slip, thereby &ldquo;smearing&rdquo; the label as the user attempts to move the file. Again, there has been at least one solution arrived at in the prior art which entails a separate sheet of lamination strips that are sized to cover the face, or one side, of the label strip after it has been printed and before it is removed from its backing sheet. Should the strip labels have been prepared a sheet at time, a sheet of laminating strips may also be applied to the sheet of strip labels in a single application. This technique allows for the application of laminating strips to a plurality of labels in one operation. The laminating strip may have an edge which extends beyond the edge of the strip label, assuming they are aligned properly as the laminating strip is applied to the strip label, with adhesive applied to the edge as an aid in applying the strip/lamination matrix to the file folder tab. However, that alignment issue is only addressed in the context of the aforementioned full sheet having multiple strip labels and separate full sheet having multiple matching laminating strips. As can be appreciated, these separate sheets require extra material, at extra cost. As the lamination material would generally require a lamination carrier, and lamination material is relatively expensive, this solution does represent a significant additional expense. Furthermore, separate sheets of strip labels and laminating strips have to be handled by a staff person in order to assemble the strip labels, which takes time and effort. Unless proper care is taken, it is entirely possible and even likely that the laminating strips will not be properly aligned thereby detracting from the desired overall neatness of appearance, not even considering that improperly aligned laminating strips could result in premature peeling of the strip label/laminating strip from the file tab and thus failure of the strip label. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In order to solve these and other shortcomings of the prior art, and to reduce both material as well as labor cost, the inventor herein has succeeded in designing and developing several embodiments of a self-laminating strip label and a method of assembling the label and laminating strip and applying it to the file folder that virtually eliminates the possibility of incorrect alignment between them and which provides a finished strip label having a lamination applied on both sides. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In a first embodiment of his invention, the self-laminating strip label is assembled from a form having two layers. A first layer of a face stock material suitable for receiving a printed image overlies a second layer of a laminating material which is substantially transparent and which may be made from Mylar or other suitable material as is known in the art. These layers are adhered to each other with a pattern adhesive which allows for assembly of a strip label/laminating strip matrix, as will be explained. More particularly, the face stock has a separation line, which is preferably a die cut or perforation, which defines the strip label with the strip label being sized to fold over the tab and mark both sides of the tab, as known in the art. When the strip label is removed from the form, a layer of adhesive occupies a central portion of the label defined by a periphery where no adhesive is applied and instead a release coat insures that adhesive is left behind on the form as the label is separated therefrom. Thus, the strip label as separated from the form has adhesive at its central portion but not around its periphery which allows for handling of the strip label without a user&apos;s fingers contacting the adhesive. On the opposite side of the form, in the laminating layer, a second separation line or preferably die cut defines a laminating strip which is somewhat larger than the label, with the laminating strip and label being aligned with each other such that while contained within the form, the label is approximately centered over the laminating strip. Furthermore, as dictated by this construction and as will be further explained below, the laminating strip when separated from the form has a central portion which has no adhesive but which has an outer peripheral area surrounding its circumference whereat an adhesive layer is applied. To provide a strip label and laminating strip appropriately sized, an envelope-sized form may be used, or these label/laminating strip separation lines may be arranged in a plurality from top to bottom on an 8&frac12;&times;11 sheet. With this construction, a single form thus contains both the printable label as well as its laminating strip for covering it as it is applied to the file folder tab. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> There are several methods available for using this first embodiment and applying it to the tab including one method which guarantees the self-alignment of the label with the laminating strip. As can be appreciated, the label may be removed from the form by separating the separation line which forms it. Thereafter, the label may simply be inverted and conveniently replaced back into the opening which it left behind. Thus, the form provides a convenient picture frame for receiving the label back into the form which is then self-aligned with the laminating strip on the opposite side of the form. As will be more specifically explained below, the adhesive applied to the laminating strip adheres it to the label as it is placed back in the form such that the two parts thus form an assembled matrix. The user then can conveniently separate the die cut formed in the laminating material layer and, as the label is adhered to the laminating strip, both are then conveniently removed from the form or carrier in one step. Should this method be followed, the user would then have in his hand an assembled matrix of a label and laminating strip which have been self-aligned with each other almost exactly as they had been formed at the factory, and the assembly/matrix is then ready for application to a file folder tab. The first embodiment of this invention, and the method for using it, are more fully explained below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> For convenience, the phrase &ldquo;separating line&rdquo; may be understood as either a die cut or perforation line, or other such impression made into the layer of material, and where &ldquo;separating line&rdquo; or the specific phrase &ldquo;die cut&rdquo; or &ldquo;perforation&rdquo; or &ldquo;score&rdquo; is used, one of ordinary skill in the art will understand that one or the other may be used as suits the particular application. In many instances, it would not significantly matter to the operability of the form should a &ldquo;perf&rdquo; line be used instead of a die cut, although for optimum results and convenience one or the other may well be preferred. Thus, the reader will understand that a separation line could be either, or some other similar line, with the specific preferred type of line being chosen by one of ordinary skill in the art using ordinary skills and teaching readily available to those of skill in the art, and that the subject invention should not be limited to either, unless specifically identified as being required in a particular location. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The inventor has also conceived of a second embodiment which includes a pair of die cuts cut into the face stock layer, with one of the die cuts being slightly larger than the other. These die cuts are arranged, and a perforation or fold line/score may be provided in the form such that as the larger (dummy) label is removed, the form may be folded over and the smaller label be nested within the opening. The slightly larger dimension of the dummy label allows for convenient placement of the smaller label into the opening without exact alignment therebetween. A laminating strip is defined by a cutout in the second layer of the form, as with the first embodiment, with this laminating strip being aligned with the dummy label die cut. With this embodiment, a user may perhaps more conveniently align the label with the laminating strip to form the label/laminating strip matrix prior to its application to the file folder tab. Furthermore, this embodiment may be constructed with alternating strips of release coating and adhesive which is a less complex adhesive/release coating pattern and which is anticipated to be easier to construct and perhaps less expensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The inventor has further developed still a third embodiment of the present invention. This third embodiment includes a strip label defined by a separation line in the face stock layer and a lamination defined by a separation line in the laminating material layer, with the strip label being offset from the lamination but with an edge of each lying in the same plane. Additional separation lines are provided in both layers, as explained more fully below, which allow for assembly of the strip label/lamination matrix in one of two inventive methods. In a first method, approximately half of the strip label is exposed and then adhered to the file folder tab, the lamination is exposed and folded over the strip label to which it is adhered, and then the rest of the strip label is exposed and adhered to the form. In a second method, the lamination may be first exposed and folded over to adhere to the strip label, the strip label then is exposed in steps as before and the strip label/lamination is adhered to the file folder. By constructing the form with the strip label and lamination edges adjacent, a simple folding over of the form reliably brings these two components into alignment so as to guarantee that the strip label/lamination assembly is properly created. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> With each of the foregoing embodiments, the inventor has provided a two-layer form with separation lines and adhesive/release coating for creating a separate strip label and matching laminating strip which completely covers both sides of the strip label as it is applied to the file folder tab. Additionally, with either embodiment, the form conveniently allows for the creation of an assembly or matrix within the form which comprises the strip label and laminating strip aligned and adhered to each other prior to their removal from the form such that a user may &ldquo;pre-assemble&rdquo; the matrix in a reliably aligned fashion prior to applying the assembly/matrix to the file folder tab. Thus, should a user make a mistake, all that is wasted is a strip label form and not the file folder also. All this is achieved in a single, two layer form that may be readily processed by a printer, such as preferably a computer controlled laser or ink jet printer, or other such printers as are already known in the art. Furthermore, alignment markings or perforations may be applied to either embodiment as an aid in aligning the assembly/matrix with the file folder tab so that each assembly/matrix may be properly aligned with the file folder tab prior to its application. This insures that the laminated strip label is oriented properly with respect to each of the file folders in order to create a uniform and orderly filing system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> While the principal advantages and features of the invention have been briefly described above, a more detailed understanding of the invention may be attained by referring to the drawings and Detailed Description Of The Preferred Embodiment which follow.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top view of the envelope-sized form of the present invention detailing the die cut in the face stock layer for forming the strip label; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the envelope-sized form of the present invention detailing the die cut forming the laminating strip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of a sheet sized form having a plurality of self-laminating strip labels of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top view of the second embodiment of the present invention detailing the die cuts for both the dummy label and strip label in the face stock layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the second embodiment detailing the die cut in the lamination for forming the lamination strip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a top view of the third embodiment detailing the face stock layer and corresponding separation lines for forming the strip label; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the third embodiment detailing the separation lines for forming the lamination; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the matrix formed from the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the matrix formed from the second embodiment; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the matrix formed from the third embodiment. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The first embodiment <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the self-laminating strip label of the present invention may be formed in a single enveloped-sized business form <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> which is itself comprised of a top layer of face stock <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and a bottom layer of a laminating material <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> with a layer of patterned adhesive <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> therebetween. The face stock <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may be any material that readily receives and retains a printed image which may be applied by any typical printer found in the prior art, such as preferably a laser printed under computer control. Face stock material may comprise bond, or other suitable types of paper layers as is known in the art. The laminate layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be formed from Mylar, other typical plastic materials, or other materials as would be well known in the art which would exhibit the qualities of a clear or transparent impervious to moisture and the like. The patterned adhesive <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> applied between layers <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> would comprise any suitable adhesive material laid down in particular areas between the layers <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> with a release coating <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> also applied in a particular pattern in order that adhesive would be retained on one of the two layers <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> as desired to form the self-laminating strip label as is explained herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the face stock <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> has a die cut <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which forms a generally rectangular or oval-shaped strip label which is separable from the surrounding portion <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the face stock <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In essence, the face stock <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> acts as a carrier from which the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> may readily be separated at its defining die cut <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. It is noted that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is actually depicted as being transparent so that the pattern adhesive <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and release coating <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are readily observable therein. Thus, in actuality, the pattern adhesive <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and release coating <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is not observable as the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> resides within the face stock <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. This depiction is considered to be an aid in understanding but should not be misunderstood by the reader to imply that the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is not capable of holding an image printed on its upper surface. Preferably, tick marks <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are formed at opposite ends of the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and provide a helpful guide in aligning the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> or for folding the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in half for application to a file folder tab. Additionally, perforation lines <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extend from the edge of the form <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and provide a ready means for separation of the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> from the face stock <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring more particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is formed and defined by a die cut <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> in the same generally oval or rectangular shape as the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> except that it is larger than each of the dimensions of width and height so that it might totally enclose strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and protect it during use. Another perforation <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> may extend from each edge of the form to the ends of laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> as an aid in separating both layers on half of the form as an aid to affixing the assembled material to the file folder so it is aligned correctly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the strip label may preferably be 1&frac12;&Prime;&times;8&Prime; of face stock while laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be 2&Prime;&times;8&frac12; of laminate material, the laminating strip thus being larger in each dimension as noted above. Of course, these dimensions are merely noted as being preferable with respect to existing file folder tabs and these dimensions may be adjusted as desired in order to provide self-laminating strip labels of virtually any dimension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> It is noted that the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is substantially aligned to be directly above laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, and the patterned adhesive <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is immediately above the release coat layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, with release coating <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> being substantially above a portion of the adhesive layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> such that the form <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> when originally assembled may only include a single layer of patterned adhesive applied to it in order to satisfy the adhesive layering requirements for both strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. More particularly, it is noted that the adhesive layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is sufficiently large to enable it to be securely adhered to a file folder tab and that there is sufficient overlap between the adhesive layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the face of label strip <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to adhere the laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> not only to it but also to the underlying file folder tab as the two are applied to the file folder tab. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> One method for use of the first embodiment <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the present invention is to simply separate strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and apply it to a file folder tab, separate laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> from the form, align it with the already applied strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and then adhere it to the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and file folder tab in an overlapping arrangement. Preferably, strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is also aligned using tick marks <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> prior to its being adhered to the file folder tab. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Still another method for use of the first embodiment <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the present invention is to first separate strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> from its surrounding carrier portion <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, invert it, and then reinsert it into the opening from whence it came. This process results in the assembly of the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into a matrix resident within the form <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, it is noted that this matrix is accurately aligned as between strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> due to the alignment of die cuts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> as this form is first manufactured. Thus, there is virtually no possibility for misalignment between the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> which thereby insures that the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> will be fully protected and that both will have adhesive exposed for secure attachment to the file folder tab. After assembly of this matrix, the laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be conveniently removed from the form which will also carry with it the strip label <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> as the two are adhered to each other with adhesive resident on laminating strip <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, as previously explained. The matrix is thus fully assembled, separated from its carrier, and ready for application to a file folder tab, with the matrix having been manufactured and presented for use in a single form and without the need to separately apply a laminating strip to a face stock strip label. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The assembled label/laminate matrix can also be aligned to the folder tab and affixed by first removing the &ldquo;waste&rdquo; face stock and laminate on half of the assembled form via the perforations, with the remaining &ldquo;waste&rdquo; on the other half of the form including &ldquo;tick&rdquo; marks or other markings, providing the user a guide to properly align the label to the file folder tab. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, it is noted that a single sheet <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, which is preferably an 8&frac12;&times;11 sheet, may contain a plurality of self-laminating strip labels <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as exemplified by the construction shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> including the layering of patterned adhesive and release coating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> A view of the top layer of face stock for the second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> and a view of the laminating layer is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. In this second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, a first die cut <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> in the face stock layer <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> defines a dummy label <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> while a second die cut <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> defines the actual strip layer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, immediately beneath it. It is noted that dummy label <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and strip label <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, and the respective die cuts <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, are substantially aligned such that should the second embodiment form <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> be folded along a fold or perforated or score line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, strip label <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> would fit within the opening formed upon removal of dummy label <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> from within its die cut <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. To facilitate this very action, it is noted that a preferable size for dummy label <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is approximately {fraction (1/16)}&Prime; larger in each direction than the corresponding dimension for strip label <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> which is 8&Prime;&times;1&frac12;&Prime;. Referring to FIG. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, it is noted that a laminating strip <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is defined by an associated die cut <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> above a fold or perforated or score line <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> which corresponds to the fold/perforated/score line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> in the face stock layer <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The laminating strip <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is formed from a laminating material and is part of the laminating layer <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, as is similarly found in the first embodiment explained above. It is also noted that a preferred size of the laminating strip <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is approximately &frac14;&Prime; larger in each dimension over the strip label <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> dimensions, and a corresponding {fraction (3/16)}&Prime; larger in each dimension over the dummy label <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> dimensions. With the construction of the second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, a less complex patterned adhesive/release layer coating may be used than that of the first embodiment. Preferably, a layer of adhesive underlies the top half of the laminating layer <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> while a release coating underlies the top half of face stock layer <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. This is reversed for the lower half of the second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in that adhesive is applied to the bottom half of face stock layer <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and a release coating applied to the bottom half of laminating strip layer <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Thus, in essence, alternating strips of adhesive and release coating are applied to each of the layers <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> as the layers are joined to form the second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In use, a convenient method is provided for assembling the matrix comprising the strip label and laminating strip <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> through the following steps. First, the dummy label <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is removed, thereby vacating an opening which is {fraction (1/16)}&Prime; larger in each dimension over the strip label <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Removal of dummy label <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> (which is coated with a release coating so as to leave adhesive behind) exposes the adhesive coating applied to the back of laminating strip <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The form may then be conveniently folded along fold line <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> which brings the upper surface of strip label <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> into contact with the adhesive now exposed on the back of laminating strip <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Thus, strip label <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> becomes adhered to laminating strip <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> thereby rendering it relatively easy to separate the die cut <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> which separates strip label <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> from its surrounding carrier portion of face stock layer <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The form is then conveniently unfolded and the matrix comprising the adhered strip label/laminating strip is formed within the second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. This assembly or matrix may then be separated from the form and applied to a file folder tab using a perforation line <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and perforation <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> to align the matrix with the file folder tab. The dummy label <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> may then be discarded as waste along with the carrier portions of the second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In this second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, it is noted that the additional spacing provided by the dummy label cutout offers more room for &ldquo;play&rdquo; as the matrix is assembled within the form. Thus, exact alignment between the strip label and the dummy label cutout is not required to successfully assemble the matrix. Furthermore, it is not considered that allowing for an exact placement between the strip label and laminating strip will detract from the eventual uniformity of the file folder with strip label applied. While {fraction (3/16)}&Prime; of extra space has been allotted in each of the two dimensions of the strip label, these are a matter of design choice and other dimensions may be utilized to achieve the purposes of the invention depending upon the particular application, materials chosen, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The third embodiment <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 &amp; 7</cross-reference> as the face stock layer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the laminating material layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Referring first to the face stock layer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a die cut <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> surrounds and defines the strip label <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, as before. However, a line of perforation <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> extends to the edge of the layer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> along the bottom of the strip label <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and provides a fold line, as will explained below. A second set of perforations <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> provide for separation of the surrounding carrier <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> adjacent the top half of the strip label <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> as will aid in applying the strip label <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to the file folder tab, as explained below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The laminating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> also includes a die cut which surrounds three sides of the lamination <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, with the fourth side being completed with a perforation line <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. This perforation line <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> extends out to the edge of the laminating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and provides a fold line prior to separation of the lamination from the laminating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> as explained below. Another die cut <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> has perforation line extensions <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> carried out to the edge of the laminating layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Die cut <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> bisects strip label <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> such that separation of the laminating layer at die cut <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and perf line extensions <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> along with separation along perf lines <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and joining die cut <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> will expose the top half of strip label <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the bottom of die cut <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> lies in substantially the same plane as the perf line <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, such that the form may be folded about perf line <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to bring lamination <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> into register with strip label <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. With the bottom half of face stock layer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> removed so as to expose lamination <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, folding over of the form about perf line <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> will cause lamination <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> to also adhere to strip label <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Generally, it is known in the art that carrying die cuts out to the edge of a form is not good practice as it could interfere with printer operation as the form feeds through it. Thus, the choice of perforations versus die cuts may be seen as design choice in many instances even though somewhat superior processing may be experienced by properly choosing which goes where. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As with the second embodiment <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, stripes of adhesive and release coating, such as silicone, are alternated between the top half and the bottom half of the third embodiment <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. In other words, for the top half of the form, a layer of adhesive is applied adjacent the face stock and a layer of release coating is applied adjacent the laminating layer. In the bottom half of the form the release coating is applied adjacent the face stock and the adhesive layer is applied adjacent the laminating layer. Thus, the &ldquo;pattern adhesive&rdquo; devolves into striping. This is anticipated to decrease the cost of manufacture and also make the form easier to manufacture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The third embodiment may be assembled in either of two inventive methods. In a first method, the top half of the strip label is exposed by separating both layers along the previously noted separation lines. The strip layer may then be adhered to the file folder tab, and aligned with the markings as noted. As only half of the strip label is exposed, a user may conveniently align it and adhere the exposed half. The lamination is then exposed and adhered over the top of the strip label. Preferably, in this embodiment, the strip label and lamination are substantially the same dimension so that they may overlie one another without overlap. Then, the rest of the strip label may then be exposed and adhered to the file folder with the carrier being discarded as waste. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> As a second method for assembling the third embodiment, the lamination may first be exposed and adhered to the strip label by removing the bottom half of the face stock layer and folding the form about perf line <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The user may then alternately follow the method described above for first exposing half of the strip label, aligning and adhering it to the file folder, and then exposing and adhering the rest. Or, the user may then peel off and expose the entire strip label and apply it &ldquo;free hand&rdquo; without the alignment markings found on the carrier portion of the form. Once the skill is acquired, a user may choose the second alternative as being probably faster than the first in assembling and applying the strip label. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The matrix <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> formed from each of the embodiments is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, respectively. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, there are three areas of adhesive with only two of them exposed to the other form. A first adhesive area <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is resident on the strip label and acts to adhere the strip label to the other form. A second adhesive area <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> adheres the laminate to the strip label and is not exposed to the other form. Instead, an area of release coating is presented to the other form as the matrix is applied to it. A third area of adhesive <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is resident on the laminate and acts to adhere the laminate to the other form. Thus, there is adhesive to adhere the strip label and laminate to each other and, separately, to the other form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9, a</cross-reference> first area of adhesive <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> is resident on the strip label and acts to adhere the strip label to the other form. Not shown, but underlying the first area, is a layer of adhesive which adheres the laminate to the strip label. A second area of adhesive <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> adheres the laminate to the other form. Thus, as with the first embodiment, there is adhesive to adhere the strip label and laminate to each other and, separately, to the other form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10, a</cross-reference> single area of adhesive <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> is resident on the strip label and acts to adhere the entire matrix to the other form. Not shown, but underlying the single area <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, is a layer of adhesive which adheres the laminate to the strip label. As the laminate and strip label are co-extensive in this embodiment, there is no separate area of adhesive which directly adheres the laminate to the other form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Various changes and modifications may be made to the invention without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as disclosed herein in the form of several preferred embodiments. Several of these changes and modifications have been suggested throughout the specification and others would be readily apparent to those having skill in the art upon reading and understanding the present disclosure. For example, the lines in the form that separate the various portions thereof may be referred to generically as separation lines. They may be chosen as die cuts, scores, perforations, etc. by selection for the particular position and usage. Those of ordinary skill in the art, using the present disclosure as a guide, would have no difficulty determining which of these would be most appropriate for the particular location of interest. Thus, the invention should not be considered as being limited to a particular kind of separation line unless specifically noted as being required. Therefore, the scope of the present invention should be limited solely by the scope of the claims appended hereto and their legal equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A business form, said business form comprising two layers of material, a first of said layers comprising a strip label layer and a second of said layers comprising a lamination layer, said strip label layer having a separation line therein defining a strip label and said lamination layer having a separation line therein defining a lamination and wherein said layers are separated by a patterned adhesive layer so that said strip label and lamination may be removed from the form and adhered with said patterned adhesive to another business form with the lamination overlying the strip layer to protect same. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the separation lines defining the strip label and the lamination are substantially aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the strip label separation line is approximately centered on the lamination separation line. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lamination is larger than the strip label so that as the two are adhered to said other form the lamination may be positioned to overlie substantially the entirety of the strip label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the strip label is void of adhesive around a periphery of its inside surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the patterned adhesive layer includes adhesive around an inner circumference of the inside surface of said lamination which, when the strip label is aligned with and applied to the lamination, overlies the strip label around a periphery of its outside surface so as to adhere the strip label to the lamination. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a plurality of said strip labels and aligned laminations are included therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an alignment marking for aligning the strip label with an edge of a folder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A self laminating strip label separable from a carrier, the carrier being comprised of two layers of material separated by a patterned adhesive layer, the first layer being comprised of face stock and the second layer being comprised of a substantially transparent protective material, each of said layers having a separation line therein defining a strip label and a lamination, respectively, with said separation lines being substantially aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lamination is larger than the strip label so that as the two are aligned and applied to another form the strip label is completely enclosed by the lamination. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the patterned adhesive includes adhesive around an inner circumference of the inside surface of said lamination which, when the strip label is aligned with and applied to the lamination, overlies the strip label around a periphery of its outside surface so as to adhere the strip label to the lamination. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the separation lines defining the strip label and the lamination are substantially aligned so that the strip label separation line is approximately centered on the lamination separation line. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The business form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the patterned adhesive layer does not adhere the strip label and the lamination as they form part of the carrier so that they are separately removable from the carrier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a laminated strip label from the carrier of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>separating the strip label from the carrier, </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the strip label to another form, </claim-text>
<claim-text>separating the lamination from the carrier, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the lamination to the strip label and other form, with the lamination being substantially aligned with the strip label to substantially overlie the strip label. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of applying the lamination to the strip layer and other form includes adhering the lamination to each of them. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a laminated strip label from the carrier of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> and applying it to another form, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>separating the strip label from the carrier, </claim-text>
<claim-text>inverting the strip label, </claim-text>
<claim-text>re-inserting the inverted strip label back into the void in the carrier created by the separation of the strip label to thereby adhere the strip label to the lamination, </claim-text>
<claim-text>separating the lamination/strip label assembly from the carrier, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the lamination/strip label assembly to another form. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of applying the lamination/strip label assembly to another form includes aligning the lamination/strip label assembly to said other form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A form containing a laminated strip label, the form comprising two sheets of material separated by a layer of adhesive, one of said sheets comprising a printable face stock and the other sheet comprising a laminating material, and said sheets having a separation line defining a strip label and a lamination, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the separation lines are substantially aligned with each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said layer of adhesive is a layer of patterned adhesive so that portions of the strip label are covered with adhesive as the strip label is removed from the form and portions of the lamination are covered with adhesive as the lamination is removed from the form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least part of the portion of the lamination which contacts the strip label as the two are aligned for being applied to another form is covered with adhesive to thereby adhere the lamination to the strip label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said form includes a plurality of said laminated strip labels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said form is approximately envelope sized. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said separation lines are aligned to be substantially centered on a common axis, one above the other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A form suitable for processing through a printer to thereby create a printed, self adhering laminated strip label matrix comprises a first layer of a printable face stock and a second layer of a laminating material, and a separation line in each of said layers to form a strip label and a lamination, said separation lines being substantially aligned and said layers being joined by a layer of patterned adhesive so that upon separation of at least the strip label from the form it may be aligned and adhered to the lamination to thereby create the matrix. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lamination is substantially larger than the strip label so that the matrix when formed includes a strip label which is substantially covered by the lamination. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the matrix when formed includes adhesive exposed over portions of both of the strip label and the lamination for adhering to another form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A form suitable for processing through a printer to thereby create a printed, self adhering laminated strip label comprises a first layer of a printable face stock and a second layer of a laminating material, and a separation line in each of said layers to form a strip label and a lamination, the first layer having a second separation line forming a dummy label, wherein the dummy label, strip label, and the lamination are aligned so that upon removal of the dummy label the form may be folded to bring the strip label into contact with the lamination. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said dummy label is slightly larger than the strip label so that upon its removal the strip label will conveniently fit into the dummy label opening. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lamination has a layer of adhesive so that the strip label will be adhered to the lamination to form an assembly and the assembly may then be removed from the form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the form further comprises a set of alignment markings to aid in applying the strip label to a file folder tab. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lamination has a layer of adhesive, the strip label has a layer of adhesive, and the dummy label has a layer of release coating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the dummy label and the lamination are substantially aligned on top of each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lamination is slightly larger than the strip label so that when the assembly is applied to a file folder tab both of the strip label and the lamination adhere thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a laminated strip label from the form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> and applying it to another form, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>separating the dummy label from the form, </claim-text>
<claim-text>folding the form to bring the strip label into contact with the exposed opening formed through removal of the dummy label, the lamination having a layer of adhesive so that the strip label adheres to the lamination to thereby form an assembly, </claim-text>
<claim-text>separating the lamination/strip label assembly from the form, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the lamination/strip label assembly to another form. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of applying the lamination/strip layer assembly to another form includes adhering the lamination to each of the strip label and the other form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of applying the lamination/strip label assembly to another form includes aligning the lamination/strip label assembly to said other form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A form containing a laminated strip label adapted for affixing to another form, the form comprising two sheets of material, one of said sheets comprising a printable face stock and the other sheet comprising a laminating material, said sheets having a separation line defining a strip label and a lamination, respectively, the laminating sheet having a second separation line for partially exposing the strip label so that the strip label may be applied to the other form, the face stock sheet having a second separation line for fully exposing the lamination, and the laminating sheet having a third separation line about which the lamination may be folded to align with and cover the strip label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the laminating sheet has a fourth separation line for exposing the rest of the strip label for being adhered to the other form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second separation line in the laminating sheet exposes approximately one half of the strip label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the strip label half exposed by the second separation line in the laminating sheet is the upper half. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A form containing a laminated strip label, the form comprising two sheets of material separated by a layer of adhesive, one of said sheets comprising a printable face stock and the other sheet comprising a laminating material, said sheets having a separation line defining a strip label and a lamination, respectively, wherein said lamination and strip label are arranged in their respective sheets so that the lamination may be folded over to overlie and become adhered to the strip label prior to either becoming separated from the form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the strip label is arranged to be offset from the lamination, with an edge of each lying substantially in the same plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein one of said separation lines provides an alignment guide for aligning the strip label with the other form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a laminated strip label from the form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> and applying it to another form, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>exposing a portion of the strip label, </claim-text>
<claim-text>adhering the exposed strip label portion to the other form, </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing the lamination, </claim-text>
<claim-text>adhering the lamination to the strip label, </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing the rest of the strip label, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>adhering the rest of the strip label to the other form. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of adhering the lamination to the strip label includes the step of folding the form to bring the lamination into contact with the strip label. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of exposing the strip label includes the step of exposing substantially half of the strip label as an aid in properly aligning the strip label with the other form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a laminated strip label from the form of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> and applying it to another form, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>exposing the lamination, </claim-text>
<claim-text>folding the form over so as to adhere the lamination to the strip label, </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing the strip label, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>adhering the strip label/lamination assembly to the other form. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of exposing the strip label includes first exposing substantially half of the strip label and further comprising the step of aligning the strip label with the other form before adhering the strip label/lamination assembly to the other form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of exposing the rest of the strip label and adhering it to the other form after the step of adhering the first exposed half of the strip label.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001381A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
