<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000294A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000294A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000294</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10180310</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>P. 2001-197782</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01M019/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>073</class>
<subclass>118100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Construction for end portion of line of vehicle which opens to atmosphere</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Taiki</given-name>
<family-name>Yanase</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Masaaki</given-name>
<family-name>Horiuchi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kouichirou</given-name>
<family-name>Toyota</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Honda Giken Kogyo Kabushiki Kaisha</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ARMSTRONG,WESTERMAN &amp; HATTORI, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1725 K STREET, NW.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1000</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20006</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25 </bold></highlight>accommodated in the interior of a vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29 </bold></highlight>having a closed cross section is constructed such that an upper end portion of a tube portion <highlight><bold>31 </bold></highlight>is covered with an inverted cup-like lid <highlight><bold>41 </bold></highlight>which opens on a bottom side thereof and that the height Hc of an opening below the bottom side of the lid <highlight><bold>41 </bold></highlight>is set lower than the height Hp of an end portion of the tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, even if the end portion of the tube portion <highlight><bold>31 </bold></highlight>and the lid <highlight><bold>41 </bold></highlight>are submerged, air captured within the lid can prevent the rise of the level of water to prevent the penetration of water into the tube portion <highlight><bold>31. </bold></highlight></paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a construction for an end portion of a line of a vehicle which opens to the atmosphere. In particular, the present invention relates to a line of a vehicle for introducing the atmospheric pressure to a pressure sensor for detection of a differential pressure from, for example, the atmospheric pressure, and more particularly to a construction for preventing the penetration of water into the line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In the event that an end portion of a line of a vehicle for introducing the atmospheric pressure into a pressure sensor opens upwardly, there is caused a risk that water penetrates into the end portion from above to thereby damage the function of the pressure sensor. Accordingly, a labyrinth has been provided at the end portion of the line of the vehicle to prevent the penetration of water into the line, or the end portion of the line has been made to open at a higher position where the end portion is difficult to be subjected to water to thereby prevent the penetration of water into the line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> However, even if the above labyrinth construction is adopted, in the event that the end portion of the line of the vehicle is submerged, it is not possible to prevent the penetration of water into the line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, in the event that the end portion of the line is placed at a higher position, there is caused a problem that the degree of freedom in designing the layout of the line is damaged. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention was made in view of the situations, and an object thereof is to ensure the prevention of penetration of water into a line of a vehicle with a simple construction even if an end portion of the line is submerged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> With a view to attaining the object, according to a first aspect of the Invention, there is provided a construction for an end portion of a line of a vehicle which opens to the atmosphere wherein an end portion of a line is covered with an inverted cup-like lid which has an opening that opens on a bottom side thereof, and wherein the height of the opening at the bottom side of the lid is set lower than the height of the end portion of the line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> According to the above construction, since the inverted cup-like lid for covering the end portion of the line is constructed such that the height of the opening at the bottom side thereof is made to be lower than the height of the end portion of the line, even if the end portion of the line and the lid are submerged, air captured within the lid prevents the rise of the level of water to thereby prevent the penetration of water into the line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to a second aspect of the invention, there is provided a construction for an end portion of a line of a vehicle which opens to the atmosphere as set forth in the first aspect of the invention, wherein the line is an atmospheric pressure introducing line of a pressure sensor for detecting a differential pressure between the atmospheric pressure and an internal pressure of a fuel vapor processing system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to the above construction, since the line is the atmospheric pressure introducing line of the pressure sensor for detecting a differential pressure between the atmosphere and the internal pressure of the fuel vapor processing system, the penetration of water into the pressure sensor via the line can be securely prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to a third aspect of the invention, there is provided a construction for an end portion of a line of a vehicle which opens to the atmosphere as set forth in the second aspect of the invention, wherein the lid and the end portion of the line are disposed in the interior of a member having a closed cross section at a lower portion of a vehicle body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to the above construction, since the lid and the end portion of the line are disposed in the interior of the member having the closed cross section at the lower portion of the vehicle body, not only can the penetration of water be prevented more securely but also the penetration of dust into the line can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Note that a vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> in embodiments is one of example as the member having a closed cross section according to the present invention, and a tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> in the embodiments is also one of example as the line according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a view showing the overall construction of a fuel vapor processing system for an engine according to a first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an enlarged view showing a main part of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of a waterproofing member according to the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a horizontal cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a vertical cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a horizontal cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a vertical cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is side view of a waterproofing member according to a second embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a view as seen in a direction indicated by an arrow denoted by reference numeral <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a view as seen in a direction indicated by an arrow denoted by reference numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments according to the present invention will be described below based on embodiments of the invention illustrated in the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> show a first embodiment of the invention, in which <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a view showing the overall construction of a fuel vapor processing system for an engine, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of a main part in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of a waterproofing member, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a horizontal cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a vertical cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a horizontal cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a vertical cross-sectional view taken along the line <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, fuel picked up from a fuel tank T via a filter <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a fuel pump <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is supplied to a fuel injection valve <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of an engine E via a feed tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An upper space in the fuel tank T is connected to a downstream position of a throttle valve <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> provided along an air inlet duct <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> via a charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and a purge tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, and a canister C which can be charged with and purged of fuel vapors is disposed between the charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the purge tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The canister C is constructed such that charcoal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> acting as an adsorbent is contained between upper and lower filters <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and the charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> on the fuel tank T side opens to the interior of the charcoal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> while the purge tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> on the engine E side opens to an upper space above the upper filter <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> with a lower space below the lower filter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> opening to the atmosphere via a vent-shut valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A two-way type valve V is disposed along the charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> connecting the fuel tank T with the canister C. In the two-way type valve V, in the event that the internal pressure of the fuel tank T rises to exceed the atmospheric pressure by a predetermined value, a positive pressure one-way type valve <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> supported by a diaphragm <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> opens against the spring force of a spring <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to thereby allow the fuel tank T to communicate with the canister C. In contrast, in the event that the internal pressure of the fuel tank T lowers to exceed the internal pressure of the canister C by a predetermined value, a negative pressure one-way type valve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> opens against the spring force of a spring <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to thereby allow the canister C to communicate with the fuel tank T. In addition, as will be described later, when purging the canister C, there may occur a case where a negative pressure is provided on the canister C side, and as this occurs, both the positive pressure one-way type valve <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the negative pressure one-way type valve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the two-way type valve V are maintained in a closed condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> A bypass valve <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> comprising an electromagnetic valve is provided at an intermediate portion along the length of a bypass tube <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> which branches off the charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> on both sides of the two-way type valve V. When the bypass valve <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> opens a direct communication is provided through the charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> on the both sides of the two-way type valve V, which then substantially becomes out of function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A purge control valve <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> comprising an electromagnetic valve is provided along the purge tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which connects the canister C with the air inlet duct <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the engine E. When the purge control valve <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> opens a communication is established between the canister C and the air inlet duct <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, whereas when the purge control valve <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> closes the communication between the canister C and the air inlet duct <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is cut off. A pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> for detecting a differential pressure between the atmospheric pressure and the internal pressure of the fuel tank T is provided along the charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> at a position closer to the fuel tank T than the two-way type valve V. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> comprises a joint <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> communicating with fuel tank and a joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> communicating with the atmosphere, and the fuel tank communicating joint <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> communicates with the fuel tank T via a primary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and the charge line <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> whereas the atmosphere communicating joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> communicates with the atmosphere via a secondary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and a waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> comprises a sensor chip <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> for converting a differential pressure between the fuel tank communicating joint <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the atmosphere communicating joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> into a voltage, and the sensor chip <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is then connected to an electronic control unit via a connector <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is a unitary part formed of a synthetic resin and most of the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is accommodated in the interior of a vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> (for example, a rear cross beam) which has a closed cross section over most portions thereof. This vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is provided on a bottom side of the vehicle body at a position which is easily submerged. The waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> comprises a tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> which is closed at a lower end while opened at an upper end thereof and which has a quadrangular cross section. In addition, provided on the tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> at an intermediate position which is slightly closer to the lower end is a flange <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> adapted to be brought into abutment with the bottom side of the vehicle body <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, and provided below the flange <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are a joint <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> continuously connecting to the secondary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and a reinforcement rib <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Provided on a portion of the tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> which continuously extends above the flange <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are expanded portions <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, locking projections <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which protrudes from the surfaces of the expanded portions <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and four reinforcement ribs <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> A lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, which is provided so as to be integrated into the upper end of the tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> via a thin hinge portion <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, is an inverted cup-like member which is closed on an upper side while opened on a lower side thereof. A thin partially arc-like overlapping portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed partially along a lower edge of the lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and two locking holes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are formed in the overlapping portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in such a manner as to penetrate therethrough. An annular atmosphere communicating portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is provided integrally at upper ends of the reinforcement ribs <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> which extend upwardly along the tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, and a thin overlapping portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed above the atmosphere communicating portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the overlapping portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is adapted to fittingly engaged with an inner circumference of the overlapping portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and comprises locking projections <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which are adapted to be brought into engagement with the locking holes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the overlapping portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Consequently, when inserting the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> through an opening <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed in the bottom side of the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> with the lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> being oriented upwardly the locking projections <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> elastically deform and pass through the opening <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, whereby the circumferential edge of the opening <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is held between the locking projections <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the flange <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> vertically so that the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is fixed to the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Then, the secondary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is connected to the joint <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> which is exposed to the outside of the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Next, the function of the first embodiment which is constructed as has been described heretofore will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> While the engine E remains off, the purge control valve <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is held in the closed condition. When the temperature in the fuel tank T rises in this condition and the internal pressure in the fuel tank T is increased by the evaporation of fuel, the positive pressure one-way type valve <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the two-way type valve V opens. Accordingly, fuel vapors and air in the fuel tank T are allowed to flow into the canister C via the charge line <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. In the canister C, the fuel vapors are adsorbed by the charcoal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to prevent the leakage of fuel vapors to the outside. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> When the engine E comes to operate stably after a predetermined length of time has elapsed since the start of the engine E, the purge control valve <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> provided along the purge line <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is activated to open to thereby establish a communication between the canister C and the air inlet duct <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the engine E. Accordingly, a negative pressure generated in the air inlet duct <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is transmitted to the canister C and the vent-shut valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. As a result, air is introduced into the canister C from the vent-shut valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and the canister C is purged of fuel vapors which are adsorbed by the charcoal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the canister C, and the fuel vapors are fed to the air inlet duct <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> together with the air. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> When a negative pressure is generated within the internal space of the fuel tank T due to a decrease in the temperature inside the fuel tank T. the negative pressure one-way type valve <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the two-way type valve V opens. Air drawn through the vent-shut valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is then supplied to the fuel tank T through the canister C and the charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to thereby prevent the deformation of the fuel tank T due to an excessive negative pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In order to test the fuel vapor processing system including the fuel tank T for generation of a leakage failure, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the purge control valve <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the bypass valve <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are activated to open with the vent-shut valve <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the canister C being left closed, so that an inlet negative pressure in the air inlet duct <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the engine E is allowed to act on the purge tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the canister C, the charge tube <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the fuel tank T. As this occurs, since the bypass valve <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> remains open, the negative pressure can be made to act directly on the fuel tank T by bypassing the two-way type valve V. Then, after closing the purge control valve <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in this condition, the internal pressure of the fuel vapor processing system is monitored by the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Namely, since the internal pressure of the fuel vapor processing system (in other words, the fuel tank T) acts on the fuel tank communicating joint <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> via the primary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, whereas the internal pressure of the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> (in other words, the atmospheric pressure) acts on the atmosphere communicating joint <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the secondary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the waterproofing member, the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> detects a differential pressure between the atmospheric pressure and the internal pressure of the fuel vapor processing system. Consequently, in the event that there is occurring a leakage failure along the fuel vapor processing system, the differential pressure would decrease gradually in association with the elapse of time since the purge control valve <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> was closed. However, with no leakage failure the differential pressure should be maintained constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As is clear from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, since a highest position Hc of an opening below a bottom face of the lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is disposed at a position lower than the height Hp of the opening at the upper end of the tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> by a distance h, even if water enters the interior of the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is submerged, whereby a slight water pressure is applied, the level of water inside the lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> only has to be slightly higher than the height Hc at the upper end of the opening below the bottom face of the lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and there occurs no case where the level of water reaches the height Hc of the opening at the upper end of the tube portion <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Thus, the penetration of water in the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> into the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> via the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the secondary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can securely be prevented. Moreover, the placement of the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> within the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> can also prevent the penetration of dust into the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> via the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Servicing the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can be easily implemented by drawing the entirety of the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> out of the opening <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and releasing the engagement between the locking projections <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the locking holes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to thereby release the lid <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> so as to be positioned at a location illustrated by chain lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Next, a second embodiment of the present invention will be described based on FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> A waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> according to the second embodiment of the invention is adapted to be inserted through an opening <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed in a side of a vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and comprises a tube portion <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> extending in a horizontal direction, a joint <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> provided to continuously connect to one end of the tube portion <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> via a flange <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, an inverted cup-like lid <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> provided to continuously connect to the other end of the tube portion <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> so in such a manner to open downwardly, upper and lower plate-like portions <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, two locking pawls <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> provided on upper and lower faces of the plate-like portions <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, respectively, and reinforcement ribs <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Consequently, when inserting the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> through the opening <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed in the side of the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, the locking pawls <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> elastically deform and stepped portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>pass through the opening <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, whereby the circumferential edge of the opening <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is held between the locking pawls <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and a flange <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> from the left and right so that the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is fixed to the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Then, the secondary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is connected to a joint <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> of the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> which is exposed to the outside. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As is clear from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, since a highest position Hc of an opening below a bottom face of the lid <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is disposed at a position lower than a lowest position Hp of an opening in the tube portion <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> by a distance h, even if water enters the interior of the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is submerged, whereby a slight water pressure is applied, the level of water inside the lid <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> only has to be slightly higher than the height Hc at the upper end of the opening below the bottom face of the lid <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and there occurs no case where the level of water reaches the height Hp of the opening of the tube portion <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. Thus, the penetration of water in the vehicle body frame <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> into the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> via the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the secondary pressure detecting tube <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can securely be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Thus, while the embodiments of the invention have been described in detail heretofore, the design of the invention may be modified variously without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> For example, the configurations of the tube portions <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and the lids <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>,,<highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the waterproofing member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are not limited to those of the embodiments but may be modified appropriately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In addition, while the line of the vehicle which continuously connect to the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> has been illustrated in the embodiments, the invention may be applied to any other lines of the vehicle that are used for other purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Thus, according to the first aspect of the invention, since the inverted cup-like lid for covering the end portion of the line is constructed such that the height of the opening below the bottom face thereof is made to be lower than the height of the end portion of the line, even if the end portion of the line and the lid are submerged, air captured within the lid prevents the rise of the level of water to thereby prevent the penetration of water into the line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In addition, according to the second aspect of the invention, since the line is the atmospheric pressure introducing line of the pressure sensor for detecting a differential pressure between the atmosphere and the internal pressure of the fuel vapor processing system, the penetration of water into the pressure sensor via the line can be securely prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, according to the third aspect of the invention, since the lid and the end portion of the line are disposed in the interior of the member having the closed cross section at the lower portion of the vehicle body, not only can the penetration of water be prevented more securely but also the penetration of dust into the line can be prevented. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A construction for an end portion of a line of a vehicle which opens to the atmosphere, comprising: 
<claim-text>an inverted cup-like lid which covers the end portion of the line and having an opening that opens on a bottom side thereof, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the height of the opening of said lid is set lower than the height of said end portion of said line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said line is an atmospheric pressure introducing line of a pressure sensor for detecting a differential pressure relative to the atmospheric pressure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pressure sensor detects a differential pressure between the atmospheric pressure and an internal pressure of a fuel vapor processing system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lid and said end portion of said line are disposed in the interior of a member having a closed cross section at a lower portion of a vehicle body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said fuel vapor processing system comprises a fuel tank. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said fuel vapor processing system comprises a fuel tank. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said member having the closed cross section is a vehicle body frame. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said end portion comprises a tube member that includes a mounting structure relative to said vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said mounting structure comprises a locking projection and a flange between which a part of vehicle body frame is clamped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said tube member comprises an engaging member, and said lid comprises an engaged member that is engaged with said engaging member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The construction as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said tube member extends in a vertical or horizontal direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>9</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000294A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
