<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001941A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001941A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001941A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001941A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001941A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001941A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001941A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001941A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001941A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001941A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001941A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001941A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001941A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001941A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001941A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001941A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001941</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10172599</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020614</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B41J002/335</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>347</class>
<subclass>208000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and method of printing on embossed cards</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60298849</doc-number>
<document-date>20010615</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gary</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Pearson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Rosemount</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>PeKarna</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Mathew</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chanhassen</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>DataCard Corporation</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Minnetonka</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MERCHANT &amp; GOULD PC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 2903</address-1>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402-0903</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A thermal printhead for printing on pre-embossed plastic cards, and a method for making a thermal printhead for printing on pre-embossed plastic cards. The printhead includes a means for connecting to a data source, means for connecting to a power source, a data transfer means, and at least one elongated contact member having at least one notch to allow the thermal printhead to pass over the pre-embossed text during the printing process. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application No. 60/298,849, entitled APPARATUS AND METHOD OF PRINTING ON EMBOSSED CARDS, filed Jun. 15, 2001, and is incorporated herewith by reference in its entirety. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention is related to an apparatus and method of printing on embossed cards. More particularly this invention is related to a thermal printhead having at least one notch for printing on a pre-embossed surface such as a plastic card, and is related to a method of making a thermal printhead for printing on pre-embossed cards. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Plastic cards such as credit cards, identification cards, driver&apos;s licenses, access cards, debit cards, insurance cards, and the like are typically printed by thermal printers that utilize thermal transfer technology. Such thermal transfer technology typically is known as dye diffusion thermal transfer (D2T2). The thermal printing process uses thermal energy to transfer a special ink coating onto a substrate, such as a plastic card. The thermally activated ink coating is made up using a wax or resin formulation, or various combinations thereof, and carbon black (in the case of black ink), and is applied from a carrier film or ribbon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A roll of thermal transfer ribbon (TTR) is loaded into the card printer. Application of the ink is carried out by a ceramic print head, which contains special tiny heating elements that are typically smaller than a grain of sand. These heating elements are paper thin, similar to the traces on a printed circuit board, and are attached to the ceramic print head. Because these elements are so thin, the ceramic print head acts as a heat sink, and has the ability to heat up and cool down very quickly. As the thermal transfer ribbon passes across the face of the print head, the ceramic elements in the print head are energized and the heat produced activates the ink coating, transferring it onto the card. Typically, printheads are connected to a data source that provides image and text data. Further, the contact member or ceramic is employed to make contact with a plastic card during the printing process. One example of this type of printhead is model &num;KDE-57 made by Kyocera. Simultaneously, data is transferred from the data source through the transfer means and conductive material of the contact member to print the necessary images onto a plastic card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In addition, these printed cards typically have pre-embossed lettering and numbers, such as names, identification numbers, account numbers, expiration dates, etc. Often a central bank or central card issuer will pre-emboss cards and then send them to branch banks or local issuers who will then print on the card, such as the card holder information and/or branch bank or local issuer information. Currently, thermal printheads have presented a problem for printing on these pre-embossed cards. The contact member or ceramic has been rigidly structured where the pre-embossed text interferes with the conventional flush contact between the plastic card and the thermal printhead needed for printing. Therefore, there is a need for an improved thermal printhead that can print on pre-embossed plastic cards without being obstructed by the pre-embossing of the card, such as pre-embossed text. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, the above and other problems were solved by providing a notched thermal printhead. Further, a method for making a notched printhead and printing on plastic cards is provided, where the thermal printhead has at least one notch. At least one contact member of the thermal printhead includes a notch that enables pre-embossed regions of a substrate, such as text or pictures, to pass under a notch of the printhead while printing on the substrate, such as a plastic card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the present invention, a thermal printhead includes a means for connecting to a data source and a means for connecting to a power source. Further, the thermal printhead includes a data transfer means operatively connected with the means for connecting to a data source for transferring data from the data source. The data transfer means contains at least one elongated contact member operatively connected therewith. The elongated contact member includes a contact surface that contacts a substrate, such as a plastic card, during the printing process. At least one notch is in communication with the contact surface of the elongated contact member, where the notch defines a gap in the contact surface. During the printing process, the notch is positioned to allow an embossed region of the plastic card, such as pre-embossed text, to pass under the thermal printhead where the notch is located. The thermal printhead is allowed to print on the plastic card on at least both sides of the pre-embossed text, while passing over the pre-embossed text at the notch position and maintaining contact with the rest of the card through the contact surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, an elongated contact member of a thermal printhead as above may have a plurality of notches where a pre-embossed substrate may have pre-embossed text at positions of the substrate where such text cannot pass under a first notch. Preferably, the notches are disposed along the longitudinal axis on the contact surface of the elongated contact member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, a plurality of elongated contact members may be attached to a common thermal printhead with a common communication port and power port. The elongated contact members are space apart to create at least one notch resembling a gap or recess so as to enable an embossed region to pass under the printhead at the notch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, a method for making a thermal printhead includes providing a thermal printhead having a means for connecting to a data source and a means for connecting to a power source, and a data transfer means for transferring image data from the data source. Further, the data transfer means is operatively connected with at least one elongated contact member for contacting a substrate, such as a plastic card. The thermal printhead is retrofitted to a plastic card in order to obtain a position where a notch is to be located. After retrofitting the thermal printhead to the plastic card, a step of notching the thermal printhead is performed, thereby making a groove or recess the size of the pre-embossed text allowing the thermal printhead to print on at least both sides of the pre-embossed text of the plastic card while the pre-embossed text may pass under the groove or recess created by the notch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In yet another embodiment of the present invention, a method of making a thermal printhead includes providing a thermal printhead having a means for connecting to a data source and power source, and a data transfer means for transferring image data from the data source. Further, an elongated contact member operatively connected with the data transfer means for contacting a plastic card is provided. The thermal printhead is pre-fitted in accordance with conventional standards for embossed texts on cards. A notch is put into the elongated contact member according to these known positions. A groove at least the size of the pre-embossed text and positioned according to conventional standards allows the thermal printhead to print on at least a surface of the plastic card where there is no pre-embossed text. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the present invention, a plurality of notches may be applied to an elongated contact member where a pre-embossed plastic card may have pre-embossed text at positions of the plastic card where such text cannot pass under a first applied notch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In yet another embodiment of the present invention, a method of printing on pre-embossed cards includes providing a thermal printhead having a means for connecting to a data source, and a data transfer means for transferring image data from the data source. Further, an elongated contact member having at least one notch along a length of a contact surface of the data transferring means is provided. The notch is fitted to allow pre-embossed text to pass under the printhead during the printing process. Plastic cards are pre-embossed with text and supplied to a card processing station. The card processing station employs the printhead to print on a surface of the plastic cards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> An advantage of the present invention provides a thermal printhead that can print on pre-embossed cards without interference or obstruction of the pre-embossed regions of the card, such as text or pictures. Further, the method of the present invention allows for a more convenient way to process cards having pre-embossed text. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> These and other various advantages and features of novelty, which characterize the invention, are pointed out in the following detailed description. For better understanding of the invention, its advantages, and the objects obtained by its use, reference should also be made to the drawings which form a further part hereof, and to accompanying descriptive matter, in which there are illustrated and described specific examples of an apparatus in accordance with the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> represents a side view of one embodiment of a thermal printhead in accordance with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> represents an end view of the thermal printhead in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in accordance with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> represents one embodiment of a pre-embossed card with printed images thereon in accordance with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> represents a flow diagram of one embodiment of a method for making a thermal printhead in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> represents a flow diagram of one embodiment for another method for making a thermal printhead in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> represents a schematic view of one embodiment of a pre-embossed card passing under a thermal printhead in cross-section in accordance with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> represents one embodiment of a conventional standard for embossed text on plastic cards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>represents a side view of one embodiment of a thermal printhead in accordance with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>represents a side view of another embodiment of a thermal printhead in accordance with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In the following description of the illustrated embodiments, reference is made to the accompanying drawings that form a part hereof, and in which is shown by way of illustration of the embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. It is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized as structural changes may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> represent one embodiment of a thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and a means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> operatively connected with a data transfer means <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is a communication port, and the means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is a power port. Preferably, the means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be any suitable port, such as a pronged plug, so as to allow connection for transferring data and powering of the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> enables image data such as pictures, text, and other images to be provided from a data source, such as a known control unit (not shown), to the data transfer means <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated that a control unit may be any suitable control unit used in a printer employing thermal printheads. A frame <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> supports the means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and data transfer means <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> in assembly of the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as a single unit. The thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is structured such that it may contact substrates with embossed regions, such as embossed text on plastic cards. It will be appreciated that substrates other than plastic cards may be printed on using the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the embossed region of such cards may pass under the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> during the printing process without obstructing printing on the card and without comprising contact of the printhead with the card. The data transfer means <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is operatively connected with at least one elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for contacting plastic cards and allowing transfer of the text and/or image data. At least one notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is in communication with the contact surface of the elongated contact member, where the notch defines a gap in the contact surface. As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> has a recess or notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> along a length of the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the notch extends along the longitudinal axis of the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and is disposed on the surface of the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. This notch or recess <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be applied using waterjet techniques. Preferably, the notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a length <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The length <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is constructed such that it is at least long enough for an embossed region, such as text or pictures, to pass through a gap or recess created by the notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and under the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, where the rest of the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> remains in contact with the card. It will be appreciated that other techniques suitable for applying a notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may also be employed. The elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be made of, but is not limited to, a ceramic material having a conductive coating thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In addition, a plurality of notches <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be applied to the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> as needed for printing on particular plastic cards that may have multiple areas of embossed text. For example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>illustrates one preferred embodiment of a thermal printhead <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is similar to the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in that a means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> and a means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> are provided. Further, an elongated contact member <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> is operatively connected with a data transfer means (not shown). A difference is illustrated in that the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> employs a plurality of notches <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> having a length <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>. As shown, the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> employs two notches <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated that more than two notches <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> may be employed. It also will be appreciated that each notch may differ in length from one another. Further, it will be appreciated the length, such as length <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> may vary as needed according to the size of the pre-embossed text or picture on the card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates one preferred embodiment of an embossed plastic card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> having images <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> printed thereon. The embossed plastic card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be a credit card, identification card, driver&apos;s license, access card, debit card, insurance card, etc. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, images <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, such as pictures, photos, and other designs, are printed on both sides of the pre-embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, shown as numbers in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Other types of pre-embossed forms may be employed, such as letters or even picture outlines, for instance, logos, etc. A width <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is shown as a size dimension for the pre-embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The width <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the embossed card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may generally correspond to the notch length, for instance notch length <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In this configuration, the pre-embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can pass under a notch, such as notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) of a thermal printhead during printing. Preferably, the width <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is not larger in dimension than the length, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) created by a notch. Further, the width <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and also the position of the pre-embossed text may be in accordance with conventional ISO standards that define location and size for embossed text on a plastic card. Likewise a notch in the thermal printhead may be accordingly sized along these conventional standards. Employing a printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>can allow printing on at least both sides of the pre-embossed regions, such as pre-embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> of a plastic card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a schematic of one preferred embodiment of the embossed plastic card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> passing under the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; of the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. As shown, the pre-embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can pass under the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; at the notch position <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime;. It will be appreciated that the notch position <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; is sized so as to enable the passing of the pre-embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> therethrough. Preferably, a thermal transfer ribbon <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> passes across the face of the printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;, which remains stationary, and the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; in the printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; is energized where the heat produced activates an ink coating on the ribbon, transferring ink onto the surface of the card. It will be appreciated that substrates other than plastic cards may be printed on using the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. Preferably, the unembossed surface of the card is printed on. It will be appreciated that the notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; of the elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; may contact the pre-embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and print on the embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, while still allowing the embossed card to pass under the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In addition, multiple elongated contact members may be attached to a common printhead where each elongated contact member could be spaced a determined distance from one another to create at least one notch resembling a gap or groove for the embossed region of a plastic card to pass between notch of the elongated contact members and under the printhead. Preferably the gap or groove created by the notch extends along the longitudinal axis of the contact surface of the elongated contact member and is in communication therewith. For example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrates one preferred embodiment of a thermal printhead <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. As above, the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is similar to the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in that a means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>425</bold></highlight> and a means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>426</bold></highlight> are provided. Further, an elongated contact member <highlight><bold>415</bold></highlight> is operatively connected with a data transfer means (not shown). A difference is illustrated in that a plurality of elongated contact members <highlight><bold>415</bold></highlight> are employed that are spaced apart to create a notch <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> with a length <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, two elongated contact members are illustrated creating one notch <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated that more than two elongated members creating more than one notch may be employed. It also will be appreciated that each notch may differ in length from one another. Further, it will be appreciated the length, such as length <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> may vary as needed according to the size of the pre-embossed text or picture on the card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, it will be appreciated that multiple thermal printheads without notches may be employed for printing on pre-embossed cards (not shown). These thermal printheads may vary in length. Similar to above, these printheads also would be positioned such that printing on both sides of pre-embossed text could be allowed. However, employing multiple printheads may be disadvantageous, as multiple components including data communication and power source parts may be required thereby complicating the system. Further, skewed data transfer may occur as a result of the multiple components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> outlines one preferred embodiment of a method <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for making a thermal printhead. The method <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes providing a thermal printhead <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead is similar to the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which includes a means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and a means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and a data transfer means <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> for transferring data from the data source. Preferably as defined above, the means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is a data communication port, and the means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is a power port. Further, at least one elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is operatively connected with the data transfer means <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> for contacting a plastic card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the elongated member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is retrofitted <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to embossed regions, for instance the pre-embossed text <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> on the plastic card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, in order to obtain a position where a notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is to be located. After retrofitting <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> the thermal printhead to the plastic card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a step of notching the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is performed, thereby making a groove or recess at least the size of the pre-embossed text allowing the thermal printhead to print on both sides of the pre-embossed text of the plastic card. The notch is made according to the retrofit position obtained in step <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated that the retrofit position may be in accordance with conventional standards for embossed text on plastic cards, such as ISO standards. In this configuration an existing thermal printhead may be retrofitted to accommodate pre-embossed cards that may or may not be in accordance with conventional ISO standards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> outlines another embodiment of a method <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for making a thermal printhead. The method <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> includes providing a thermal printhead similar to thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As defined above, the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a means for connecting to a data source <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and a means for connecting to a power source <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and a data transfer means <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> for transferring image data from the data source. Further, at least one elongated contact member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is operatively connected with the data transfer means <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> for contacting a plastic card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the thermal printhead is pre-fitted <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> in accordance with conventional standards for embossed texts on cards. For example, at least one of these pre-fitted notches can be measured in accordance with ISO standards defining size and position for embossed text on a plastic card. A notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is formed in communication with the elongated contact member of the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> during the manufacture of the thermal printhead according to these known positions or known ISO specifications for size and position. Basically, at least one notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> or groove having the size of the pre-embossed text is formed and positioned according to these conventional standards. In this configuration, the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can print on the surface of the plastic card <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> where there is no pre-embossed text, and allow a region where there is pre-embossed text to pass under the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> at the notch <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated that substrates other than plastic cards may be printed on using the thermal printhead. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> With regard to ISO standards, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates ISO standards and known positions and sizes for embossed text. For an identification number line <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, a maximum of 19 characters can be used at a nominal spacing of 7 characters per inch. The centerline <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the identification number line <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> may be located a distance <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of 0.843 inches &plusmn;0.005 inches from the bottom edge of the card. A distance <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> between the centerline of the first character position <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the left edge of the card may be 0.401 inches &plusmn;0.010 inches, and a distance <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> between the centerline of the first character position <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and, if needed, the 19th character position <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> should not exceed 2.571 inches &plusmn;0.030 inches. A distance <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> between the 19th character position (if needed) and the right edge of the card may be about 0.403 inches. Further, a maximum distance <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> from a top line <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the identification number line <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> from the bottom edge of the card may be 0.946 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> For other card holder information such as names and addresses, the following standards apply. A maximum height <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> of the name and address line <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> may be 0.572 inches and located under the identification number line <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. A distance <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> between the bottom of the name and address information line <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the bottom edge of the card may be 0.095 inches to 0.130 inches. A distance <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> between the centerline <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of the first character position <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of each line in the name and address information and the left edge of the card may be 0.301 inches &plusmn;0.010 inches. Further, a distance <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> between the centerline <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of the first character position and (if needed) the centerline <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> of the 27th character position <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> should not exceed 2.600 inches &plusmn;0.030. A distance <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> between the 27th character position (if needed) and the right edge of the card may be about 0.474 inches. It will be appreciated that the thermal printhead <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be fitted to accommodate these standard positions and sizes for embossed regions on a card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In addition, it will be appreciated that a plurality of notches (i.e. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) with differing sizes may be applied to a thermal printhead, as necessary, in the printing of plastic cards that may have multiple areas of embossed text and different sizes of embossed text or regions. Also as discussed above, a plurality of elongated members spaced a determined distance apart may be attached to a common thermal printhead (i.e. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> As card issuing institutions pre-emboss cards before sending them to a printing station, such as for security purposes, the present invention provides an advantage of a thermal printhead that can allow printing on pre-embossed plastic cards. The printhead of the present invention is not interfered with or obstructed by pre-embossed text during the printing process. The methods of the present invention allow for a more convenient way to process cards having pre-embossed text. Existing printheads may be inexpensively modified or retrofitted with a notch to perform printing on pre-embossed cards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Having described the embodiments of the present invention, modifications and equivalents may occur to one skilled in the art. It is intended that such modifications and equivalents shall be included with the scope of the invention. Since many embodiments of the invention can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention, the invention resides in the claims hereinafter appended. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A thermal printhead for printing on a substrate having an embossed region, comprising: 
<claim-text>a means for connecting to a data source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a means for connecting to a power source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a data transfer means operatively connected with said means for connecting to a data source; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one elongated contact member operatively connected with said data transfer means and said means for connecting to a power source, said elongated contact member including a contact surface and at least one notch in communication with said contact surface, said notch defining a gap in said contact surface, said contact surface being contactable on said substrate such that said notch enabling said embossed region of said substrate to pass under said notch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby during printing on said substrate, said means for connecting to a power source powers said elongated contact member so as to heat said elongated contact member, and said data transfer means transfers data through said elongated contact member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead according to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, wherein said elongated contact member including a plurality of notches disposed along said contact surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead according to <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, wherein said plurality of notches each having a length differing from one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead according to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, wherein said length of said notch is a retrofitted notch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead according to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, wherein said length of said notch is a pre-fitted notch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead according to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, further comprising a plurality of elongated contact members commonly connected to said data transfer means, said elongated contact members being spaced apart a distance to form said at least one notch between said elongated contact members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead according to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, wherein said notch having a length extending along a longitudinal axis defined by said contact surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead according to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, wherein said elongated contact member including a conductive film, said conductive film being contactable with said substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The thermal printhead according to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, wherein said elongated contact member being a ceramic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A printer including a thermal printhead for printing on a plastic card having embossed regions, said thermal printhead comprising: 
<claim-text>a means for connecting to a data source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a means for connecting to a power source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a data transfer means operatively connected with said means for connecting to a data source; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one elongated contact member operatively connected with said data transfer means and said means for connecting to a power source, said elongated contact member including a contact surface and at least one notch in communication with said contact surface, said notch defining a gap in said contact surface, said contact surface being contactable on said substrate such that said notch enabling said embossed region of said substrate to pass under said notch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby during printing on said substrate, said means for connecting to a power source powers said elongated contact member so as to heat said elongated contact member, and said data transfer means transfers data through said elongated contact member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The printer according to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein said elongated contact member including a plurality of notches disposed along said contact surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The printer according to <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, wherein said plurality of notches each having a length differing from one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The printer according to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, further comprising a plurality of elongated contact members commonly connected to said data transfer means, said elongated contact members being spaced apart a distance to form said at least one notch between said elongated contact members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The printer according to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein said notch having a length extending along a longitudinal axis defined by said contact surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The printer according to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein said elongated contact member including a conductive film, said conductive film being contactable with said substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The printer according to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein said elongated contact member being a ceramic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method for making a thermal printhead for printing on embossed cards, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a thermal printhead including a means for connecting to a data source, a means for connecting to a power source, a data transfer means operatively connected with said means for connecting to a data source, and at least one elongated contact member operatively connected with said data transfer means, said elongated contact member including a contact surface for contacting a surface of said plastic card; </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining at least one notch position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least one notch on said contact surface according to said obtained notch position, said notch in communication with said contact surface, said notch defining a gap in said contact surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method for making a thermal printhead according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of obtaining at least one notch position including retrofitting said thermal printhead to obtain said notch position according to said embossed region of said embossed plastic card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method for making a thermal printhead according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of obtaining at least one notch position including pre-fitting said thermal printhead to obtain said notch position according to a conventional standard for position and size of said embossed region on said embossed plastic card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method for printing on a embossed plastic card, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a printer having a thermal printhead including a means for connecting to a data source, a means for connecting to a power source, a data transfer means operatively connected with said means for connecting to a data source, and at least one elongated contact member operatively connected with said data transfer means, said elongated contact member including a contact surface for contacting a surface of said plastic card and a notch in communication with said contact surface, said notch defining a gap in said contact surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>contacting said plastic card using said thermal printhead; </claim-text>
<claim-text>printing on a surface of said plastic card such that an embossed region of said plastic card passes under said notch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001941A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001941A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001941A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001941A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001941A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001941A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001941A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001941A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
