<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001190A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001190A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001190A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001190A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001190A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001190A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001190A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001190A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001190A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001190A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001190</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10227662</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020826</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/8242</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/76</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/94</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>306000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>686000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>240000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Methods for forming conductive structures and structures regarding same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10227662</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020826</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09711206</doc-number>
<document-date>20001109</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Cem</given-name>
<family-name>Basceri</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gurtej</given-name>
<family-name>Sandhu</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>MICRON TECHNOLOGY, INC.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MUETING, RAASCH &amp; GEBHARDT, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 581415</address-1>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55458</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method for forming a metal/metal oxide structure that includes forming metal oxide regions, e.g.. ruthenium oxide regions, at grain boundaries of a metal layer, e.g., platinum. Preferably, the metal oxide regions are formed by diffusion of oxygen through grain boundaries of the metal layer, e.g., platinum, to oxidize a metal layer thereon, e.g, ruthenium layer. The structure is particularly advantageous for use in capacitor structures and memory devices, such as dynamic random access memory (DRAM) devices. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to the preparation of semiconductor device structures. More particularly, the present invention pertains to methods of forming conductive structures such as electrode structures and the structures resulting therefrom. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In the fabrication of integrated circuits, various conductive layers are used. For example, during the formation of semiconductor devices, such as dynamic random access memories (DRAMs), or any other types of memory devices, conductive materials are used in the formation of storage cell capacitors, and also may be used in interconnection structures, e.g., conductive layers in contact holes, vias, etc. For example, in the fabrication of integrated circuits including capacitor structures, conductive layers are used for capacitor electrodes. Memory circuits, such as DRAMs and the like, use conductive structures to form opposing electrodes of storage cell capacitors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> As memory devices become more dense, it is necessary to decrease the size of circuit components forming such devices. One way to retain storage capacity of storage cell capacitors of the memory devices, and at the same time decrease the memory device size, is to increase the dielectric constant of the dielectric layer of a storage cell capacitor. Therefore, high dielectric constant materials are used in such applications and interposed between two electrodes. One or more layers of various conductive materials may be used as the electrode material. Generally, one or more of the layers of conductive material used for the electrodes (particularly the bottom electrode of the cell capacitor) has certain diffusion barrier properties, e.g., silicon or oxygen diffusion barrier properties. Such properties are particularly required when high dielectric constant materials are used for the dielectric layer of the storage cell capacitor because of the processes used in forming such high dielectric constant materials, e.g., deposition of high dielectric constant materials usually occurs at high temperatures (generally, greater than about 500&deg; C.) in an oxygen-containing atmosphere. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Various metals and metallic compounds, for example, metals such as platinum, and conductive metal oxides such as ruthenium oxide, have been proposed as the electrode materials or at least one of the layers of an electrode stack for use with high dielectric constant materials. However, electrodes generally need to be constructed such that they do not diminish the beneficial properties of the high dielectric constant materials. For example, for platinum to function well as a bottom electrode or as one of the layers of an electrode stack, an effective barrier to the diffusion of silicon from the substrate or other silicon-containing region to the top of the electrode needs to be provided. This is typically required since silicon at the surface of the electrode stack will tend to be oxidized during the oxygen anneal of the high dielectric constant materials and/or during deposition of oxide dielectrics, e.g., Ta<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>5 </subscript></highlight>or BaSrTiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, which will result in a decreased series capacitance, thus degrading the storage capacity of the capacitor. In addition, oxygen diffusion through the platinum electrode layer during high temperature oxidizing processes, e.g., BaSrTiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>deposition processes, needs to be prevented. Such oxygen diffusion through the platinum occurs generally through the platinum grain boundaries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Further, during high temperature processing of devices (e.g., high dielectric constant material formation processes) that include platinum conductive layers, stress occurs in the platinum layer. Such stress may result in the formation of a discontinuous platinum layer, such as in the form of platinum islands, which are undesirable. The formation of such platinum islands may result in films that are unstable for use as capacitor electrodes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In addition to the use of high dielectric constant materials for capacitor structures, it is desirable to take other steps to increase or preserve capacitance without increasing the occupied area. For example, electrode surfaces may be roughened to increase the effective surface area of electrodes without increasing the area occupied by the capacitor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> One method for providing a roughened surface for a plate of a storage cell capacitor is to form the plate of hemispherical grain polysilicon (HSG), possibly with an overlying metal layer. The hemispherical grains of HSG enhance the surface area of the plate without increasing its occupied area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> However, HSG presents difficulties in fabrication because of the formation of silicon dioxide on and near the HSG. A silicon dioxide layer may form on the HSG, particularly during deposition of the capacitor&apos;s dielectric layer. Even with an intervening metal layer present, oxygen from the deposition of the dielectric layer can diffuse through the metal layer, forming silicon dioxide at the polysilicon surface. Silicon diffusion through the metal layer may also produce an undesirable silicon dioxide layer between the metal and the dielectric layers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> To avoid these negative effects caused by formation of silicon dioxide, a diffusion barrier layer may be employed between the HSG and the metal layer. But, in a typical capacitor geometry, the greater the total number of layers, the larger the required minimum area occupied by the capacitor. Further, the upper surface of each additional layer deposited over the HSG tends to be smoother than the underlying surface, reducing the increased surface area provided by the HSG. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a stable metal/metal oxide structure (e.g., a platinum/ruthenium oxide composite structure) for use in integrated circuits, e.g., capacitor electrodes. Such a metal/metal oxide composite structure is especially beneficial for use with high permittivity materials, e.g., high dielectric constant materials used with capacitor structures. Further, the present invention also provides for an enhanced surface area electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A method for use in fabrication of integrated circuits according to the present invention includes providing a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion and forming a first metal layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion. A second metal layer is formed on at least a portion of the first metal layer and an oxidation diffusion barrier layer is provided on at least a portion of the second metal layer. One or more regions of the second metal layer are oxidized to form metal oxide regions corresponding to one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer by thermally treating the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon. The oxidation diffusion barrier layer and unoxidized portions of the second metal layer are then removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In another method for use in fabrication of integrated circuits according to the present invention, a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion is provided and a first metal layer (e.g., platinum) is formed on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion. The first metal layer has grain boundaries extending therethrough. A second metal layer (e.g., ruthenium) is formed on at least a portion of the first metal layer. Metal oxide regions are formed on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof through selective oxidation of the second metal layer by diffusion of oxygen from the oxygen-containing surface portion through the one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer. For example, the metal oxide regions may be formed by providing an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the second metal layer, thermally treating the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon to selectively oxidize one or more regions of the second metal layer at the one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer resulting in the one or more metal oxide regions and unoxidized portions of the second metal layer therebetween, and then removing the oxidation diffusion barrier layer and the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In various embodiments of the methods, the thermal treatment may be performed at a temperature greater than 300&deg; C., the thermal treatment may be performed in a non-oxidizing atmosphere, the first metal layer may be formed of at least one metal selected from the group of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium (preferably platinum), the second metal layer may be formed of at least one metal selected from the group of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium (preferably ruthenium), the oxidation diffusion barrier layer may be formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide (preferably silicon nitride), and the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer may be removed using at least one of a wet etch and a dry etch. Yet further, in other embodiments, the methods above may be used in the formation of capacitors, e.g., electrodes thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A semiconductor structure according to the present invention includes a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion and a first metal layer (e.g., platinum) on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion. One or more metal oxide regions (e.g., ruthenium oxide) are formed from a second metal layer on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the structure, the structure includes an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the second metal layer over at least the one or more metal oxide regions and unoxidized portions of the second metal layer between the one or more metal oxide regions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In various other embodiments of the structure, the oxidation diffusion barrier layer may be formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide, the first metal layer may be formed of at least one metal selected from the group of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium (preferably platinum), and the second metal layer may be formed of at least one metal selected from the group of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium (preferably ruthenium). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Further, in other embodiments of the structure, the structure may be used as part of or in the formation of a capacitor structure and/or a memory cell structure.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic of one embodiment of a substrate assembly having a composite metal/metal oxide conductive structure formed thereon in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E show one illustrative embodiment of a method for forming a composite metal/metal oxide electrode for use in an illustrative capacitor application, e.g., a platinum/ruthenium oxide composite electrode used in combination with high dielectric constant materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows an alternate capacitor structure using the metal/metal oxide composite electrode formed as shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the use of a metal/metal oxide composite electrode in a storage cell container capacitor application, e.g., a DRAM storage cell capacitor.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The present invention shall be generally described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, other embodiments, illustrations, and applications of the present invention shall be described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a substrate assembly <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and a metal/metal oxide composite structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> formed according to the present invention on a surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, e.g., an oxygen-containing surface portion. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is illustrative of the use of a composite metal/metal oxide structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for any application such as those requiring the benefits provided thereby as further described below. For example, the application may be a capacitor electrode application. As such an electrode, the composite metal/metal oxide structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be used to prevent oxygen diffusion through the electrode of the capacitor, provide an enhanced surface area, etc. Further, for example, the composite metal/metal oxide structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be used in the formation of storage cell capacitors for use in semiconductor devices, e.g., memory devices. As further described herein, the structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be used within a stack of layers forming an electrode of a capacitor, or may be used as the capacitor electrode by itself. One skilled in the art will recognize that various semiconductor processes and structures for various devices, e.g., CMOS devices, memory devices, etc., would benefit from the characteristics of the composite metal/metal oxide structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the present invention, and in no manner is the present invention limited to the illustrative embodiments described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> As used in this application, &ldquo;substrate assembly&rdquo; refers to either a semiconductor substrate, such as the base semiconductor layer, e.g., the lowest layer of a silicon material in a wafer, or a silicon layer deposited on another material, such as silicon on sapphire, or a semiconductor substrate having one or more layers or structures formed thereon or regions formed therein. When reference is made to a substrate assembly in the following description, various process steps may have been previously used to form or define regions, junctions, or various structures or features and openings, such as vias, contact openings, high aspect ratio openings, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> includes at least a portion thereof that is an oxygen-containing surface portion upon which at least a portion of the composite metal/metal oxide structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is formed. Such an oxygen-containing surface portion is shown as the dashed line surface portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The oxygen-containing surface portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> may be, for example, formed of any oxygen-containing material such as any oxide material. For example, the oxide material may include borophosphosilicate glass (BPSG), phosphosilicate glass (PSG), tetraethylorthosilicate glass (TEOS), ozone-enhanced TEOS, or any other oxygen-containing material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The composite metal/metal oxide structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> including grain boundaries <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> thereof illustratively shown within first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Further, the composite structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> formed on at least portions of the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> at grain boundaries <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> thereof. The metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are formed, as described further below with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, through selective oxidation of a second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> (as shown by dashed line <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) formed on the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The selective oxidation of the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is performed by diffusion of oxygen from the oxygen-containing surface portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of substrate assembly <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> through the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are formed on at least portions of the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> at one or more grain boundaries <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> thereof by providing an oxygen diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (also shown in dashed line form in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) on at least a portion of the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> which is to be selectively oxidized. Upon thermal treatment of the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> having the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and the oxygen diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> formed thereon, selective oxidation of the one or more regions of the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> occurs at one or more grain boundaries <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> resulting in the metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and unoxidized portions of the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> generally between the metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> formed at the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The composite metal/metal oxide structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is thereafter formed by removing the oxidation diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> resulting in the non-dashed composite structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is formed of at least one metal selected from a group of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium. More preferably, as shall be described further below with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the first metal layer is formed of at least platinum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is formed of at least one metal selected from a group of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium. More preferably, the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is formed of at least ruthenium. As such, with a second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> formed of such materials, the metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> will include, for example, ruthenium oxide, osmium oxide, etc. depending upon the material used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the oxygen diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is a layer that is less permeable to oxygen than the oxygen-containing surface portion <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. As such, oxygen diffusing through the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> during thermal treatment will oxidize localized regions about the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at the surface <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to form the metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. For example, the oxidation diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide. Preferably, a silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is used to passivate the underlying structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The first and second metal layers <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are preferably formed by chemical vapor deposition processes (CVD) as known to those skilled in the art. However, such layers may be formed by atomic layer deposition (ALD), evaporation, sputtering, or any other method suitable to form such layers. Preferably, however, CVD is used to obtain uniformity so as to provide enhanced step coverage. The present invention, however, is not limited to any particular method of forming such layers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is formed to a thickness of about 20 &angst; to about 1000 &angst;. More preferably, the first metal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> has a thickness in the range of about 50 &angst; to about 200 &angst;. In addition, the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is formed to a thickness of about 20 &angst; to about 1000 &angst;. More preferably, the second metal layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> has a thickness of about 50 &angst; to about 200 &angst;. Yet still further, the oxidation diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is preferably formed to a thickness of about 100 &angst; to about 500 &angst;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The method of forming a composite metal/metal oxide structure <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> according to the present invention will be better understood from the more detailed description provided with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. However, for clarity and simplicity, and with reference to preferred materials, the method of forming the metal/metal oxide structure shall be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> wherein a composite platinum/ruthenium oxide electrode structure <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</cross-reference> (e.g., where the first metal layer is platinum and the second metal layer is ruthenium) is formed according to the present invention. However, one skilled in the art will recognize that such processing is applicable to the other materials described herein as well. Further, the method as described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E shall be described with respect to the composite platinum/ruthenium oxide structure <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> being used as a bottom electrode of a capacitor structure <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2E</cross-reference>. However, although the present invention is particularly advantageous for use of the composite structure as a bottom electrode, the present invention is not limited to this application only and may well be used for any other applications wherein a conductive structure is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> shows a substrate assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> including an oxygen-containing surface portion <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. As described previously herein, the oxygen-containing surface portion <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be formed of any oxygen-containing material such as BPSG. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A, a</cross-reference> platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is formed on surface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is formed by CVD. As CVD of platinum is known in the art, further details with respect to the formation thereof shall not be provided in any further detail. For example, an oxidizing ambient in the CVD of platinum may be used (e.g., an O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O ambient environment). With control of the oxidizing environment, excess oxygen can be added during deposition of the platinum to enhance oxidation of the ruthenium during the subsequent thermal treatment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> After formation of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> on surface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a ruthenium layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is formed on the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The ruthenium layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is also preferably deposited by CVD. Again, as CVD of ruthenium is known in the art, further details with respect thereto shall not be further provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The deposited metal layers <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> each have respective grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> therein. As illustratively shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> has grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> extending therethrough from the surface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of substrate assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> on which it is formed to the upper surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Likewise, ruthenium layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> includes grain boundaries <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> extending from surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> on which it is formed through the upper surface <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Further, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B, a</cross-reference> silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is formed on the ruthenium layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Formation of the silicon nitride as the oxidation diffusion barrier layer may be attained by any suitable method as known to those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> One skilled in the art will recognize that the thickness of layers will vary depending on various factors, including but not limited to the application where the structure is to be used. Generally, however, preferably, the layers are formed to thicknesses in the ranges as described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The ruthenium layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> preferably has a thickness such that it is entirely oxidized in the local region about the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> through the surface <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> thereof during the thermal treatment of the structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> With the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the ruthenium layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and the silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> formed on the oxygen-containing surface portion <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> of substrate assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a thermal treatment is performed. The resultant structure following the thermal treatment is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</cross-reference>. Preferably, the stack of layers is annealed at elevated temperatures under vacuum or reducing conditions to allow oxygen diffusion from the oxygen-containing surface portion <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> through grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. As a result of such oxygen diffusion through the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, selective oxidation of localized regions of the ruthenium layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> occurs at the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> on surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> thereof. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>C, such oxidation results in a ruthenium/ruthenium oxide layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> including ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> formed on surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and unoxidized portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the ruthenium layer located between such ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> at portions of surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> that are relatively distant from the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, e.g., outside of the local regions about the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the anneal of the stack of layers on substrate assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is performed at temperatures greater than about 300&deg; C. More preferably, such temperatures are greater than about 500&deg; C. Also preferably, the anneal is performed in a non-oxidizing atmosphere, e.g, a nitrogen atmosphere. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The anneal preferably is a furnace anneal performed at such elevated temperatures. However, an anneal may be performed using rapid thermal processing (RTP) techniques and further may be performed by a combination of steps at varied temperatures. However, preferably, at least one anneal temperature is in the ranges described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> With the local ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> formed at the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the composite platinum/ruthenium oxide structure <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</cross-reference> may be formed upon the removal of the silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the unoxidized portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the ruthenium/ruthenium oxide layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The removal of the silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may be accomplished by any suitable process. For example, silicon nitride may be removed by various fluorine-containing etch gases such as CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>/O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>/H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, C<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>, etc., in a dry etch or plasma etch process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The ruthenium/ruthenium oxide layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> including both unoxidized ruthenium portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is processed to selectively remove the unoxidized ruthenium portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> relative to the ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and desirably relative to the underlying platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Such removal of the unoxidized ruthenium portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be accomplished using any suitable selective wet etch process or dry etch process. As one specific example of a wet etch process used to selectively remove the unoxidized ruthenium portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, a wet etchant comprising ceric ammonium nitrate and acetic acid may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> One skilled in the art will recognize that any processes that remove the unoxidized ruthenium portions <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> preferentially over the ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> may be used according to the present invention. The remaining ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> constitute, together with the underlying platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, an enhanced surface area layer compatible with high dielectric constant materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>E, capacitor structure <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is completed by the formation of dielectric material <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> on the platinum/ruthenium oxide composite electrode <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and formation of a second electrode or top electrode <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> formed on at least a portion of the dielectric layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The dielectric material <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is preferably a high dielectric constant material interposed between the composite electrode <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and second electrode <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. As used herein, a high dielectric constant material preferably has a dielectric constant of at least 9, and more preferably a dielectric constant of at least 20. For example, the high dielectric constant material may be any suitable material having a desirable dielectric constant, such as Ta<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>, Ba<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>Sr<highlight><subscript>(1&minus;x)</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&lsqb;BST&rsqb;, BaTiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>,SrTiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>,PbTiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, Pb(Zr, Ti)O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&lsqb;PZT&rsqb;, (Pb,La)(Zr,Ti)O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&lsqb;PLZT&rsqb;, (Pb,La)TiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&lsqb;PLT&rsqb;, KNO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, LiNbO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, ZrO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, HfO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, Zr-silicate, Hf-silicate, and Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> With use of the high dielectric constant material <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, diffusion barrier properties of electrodes is particularly important. For example, to function well as a bottom electrode of a capacitor structure, the electrode layer or stack of layers must act as an effective barrier to the diffusion of silicon and oxygen, particularly due to the processes used to form the high dielectric constant materials. Such diffusion barrier properties are required when the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a silicon-containing surface upon which the capacitor is formed, e.g., polysilicon, silicon substrate material, n-doped silicon, p-doped silicon, etc., since oxidation of the diffused silicon may result in degraded capacitance, e.g., capacitance for a memory device. In addition, the electrode stack must act as an oxygen barrier, for example, to prevent an underlying silicon-containing surface from oxidizing. The formation of the composite structure <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> according to the present invention provides such barrier properties. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The second electrode or top electrode <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> may be formed of any suitable conductive material. For example, the electrode may include a stack of layers or a single layer. The electrode <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> may be formed of any suitable material such as those typically used in the formation of electrodes such as tungsten nitride, titanium nitride, tantalum nitride, ruthenium, rhodium, iridium, ruthenium oxide, iridium oxide, platinum, palladium, any combination thereof, or any other conductive material typically used as an electrode or electrode layer of a storage cell capacitor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>E, grain boundaries <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> of the dielectric material <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> match the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In other words, such grain boundaries of the high dielectric layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and of the composite structure <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are aligned. However, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, such grain boundaries may be mismatched between the dielectric material and platinum layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> capacitor structure <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> shows such a mismatch. The capacitor structure <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> includes the composite platinum-ruthenium oxide composite structure <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> as the bottom electrode with dielectric material <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and second electrode <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> formed thereover. As shown, grain boundaries <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of the dielectric material <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are not aligned with the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> After the high dielectric constant material is deposited, the two scenarios described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2E and 3</cross-reference> may be attained. In other words, either the grain boundaries of the dielectric material match with the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum as illustratively shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>E, or such grain boundaries are mismatched as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. However, in both cases, whether matched or mismatched, the bottom composite platinum/ruthenium oxide electrode provides various advantages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> For example, the present invention utilizes the diffusion of oxygen through the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to obtain a composite bottom electrode <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> that includes platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and local ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> formed on grain boundaries thereof. This composite platinum/ruthenium oxide electrode <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is an advantageous barrier to oxygen diffusion during high temperature processes in oxidizing atmospheres. For example, during high temperature oxidizing processes, such as those used to form the high dielectric constant material (e.g., a BST deposition process), oxygen diffusion through the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is prevented by having the ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> on the grain boundaries <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the platinum material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Such barrier properties are generally important in forming such high dielectric constant materials. Further, the composite platinum/ruthenium oxide electrode also acts as a sink for oxygen vacancies in high permittivity oxide materials. This provides for improved dielectric performance, e.g., improved resistance degradation lifetime or fatigue for ferroelectric oxide dielectrics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Further, high temperature processing in conjunction with use of platinum may create various problems. For example, a balling out problem, e.g., the formation of islands in the platinum, can sometimes occur. With the use of the ruthenium and silicon nitride layers on top of the platinum material layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, such island formation problems can be prevented during high temperature processing. Also, stress in the platinum layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which causes the island formation, can be reduced by having the ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> formed at the grain boundaries. Such stress relief can be thought of as the ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> generally gluing the platinum material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at the grain boundaries. This enables the platinum material <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to be a stable bottom electrode for use with high dielectric constant materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Yet further, the dielectric properties of the high dielectric constant material <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> can be tailored using the platinum/ruthenium oxide bottom electrode <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. For example, the size of the ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> can be controlled by the oxidation process used to form such oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, e.g., time of oxidation, temperature, ambient, pressure, etc. Further, the unoxidized ruthenium removal process may also be used to control the size of such metal oxide regions or islands, e.g., time of etching, temperature, type of etchant used (such as an etchant that is less selective to ruthenium oxide), etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Generally, the size of the ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> will determine, permittivity, leakage, resistance degradation, fatigue and other properties of the structure. For example, with smaller ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, less leakage occurs with more platinum at the interface with the high dielectric constant material <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. However, with the use of larger ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, longer resistance degradation over the lifetime of the structure occurs. Such resistance degradation involves oxygen vacancy migration. For example, ruthenium oxide regions will act as a sink for oxygen vacancies. Further, for example, permittivity can be affected by the texture of the dielectric films which can be affected by the density of the platinum/ruthenium oxide areas. Therefore, generally the process can be optimized to achieve a size of ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> desired in the capacitor structure <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. As such, the present invention provides flexibility for tailoring the dielectric properties of the high dielectric material <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the capacitor structure <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the use of a metal/metal oxide composite electrode in a storage cell container capacitor application, e.g., a DRAM storage cell capacitor. In this illustrative application of the present invention, device structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is fabricated according to conventional processing techniques through the formation of an opening <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> prior to depositing a bottom composite electrode structure <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> therein. A bottom electrode <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight>, including a metal/metal oxide composite structure as previously described herein, is formed in opening <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The substrate assembly <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> may include various elements, such as field oxide regions, active regions, i.e., those regions of a silicon substrate not covered by field oxide, word lines, field effective transistors (FETs), source/drain regions created in the silicon substrate, etc. An insulative layer, e.g., BPSG, of oxide material <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> is formed over the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight>. The opening <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> in the insulative layer <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> may be a small high aspect ratio opening. As described herein, small high aspect ratio openings have feature sizes or critical dimensions below about 1 micron (e.g., such as a diameter width of an opening being less than about 1 micron) and aspect ratios greater than about 1. For example, an opening of 1 micron and a depth of 3 microns has an aspect ratio of 3. The present invention is particularly beneficial for forming the bottom electrode <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> in small high aspect ratio features due to the use of CVD or ALD processes for forming conformal platinum and ruthenium layers over step structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, electrode <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight>, including the composite metal/metal oxide structure as previously described herein, is formed on the one or more side wall surfaces <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> and may also be formed on the bottom surface <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight>; the surfaces <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> defining opening <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. For example, the electrode may be formed by planarizing a composite metal/metal oxide material that is formed over the entire structure. As such, the planarization would remove desired regions such that the composite metal/metal oxide material only remains in opening <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> for forming the bottom electrode <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight>. The electrode <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> includes metal layer <highlight><bold>189</bold></highlight> and metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> formed at grain boundaries thereof according to the present invention. Substantially the same processing techniques as described elsewhere herein may be used to form the composite metal/metal oxide structure. For example, the oxidation diffusion barrier layer used to form the metal oxide regions may be formed such that it fills the opening during performance of the process as described previously herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Such metal oxide regions <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> may form at the platinum grain boundaries of the platinum adjacent the bottom surface <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> of the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> even though the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> may not include oxygen at this location. For example, during deposition of the platinum, an excess amount of oxygen may be incorporated into the platinum as previously mentioned herein. As such, for example, preferential oxidation of ruthenium over the oxidation of the substrate assembly <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight>, e.g., a silicon containing bottom surface region, may occur to form the ruthenium oxide regions <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> in such regions adjacent the bottom surface <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> during the thermal treatment. Further, this region at the bottom surface <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> is typically very small, e.g., such as in small aspect ratio openings, compared to the other regions, e.g., sidewalls <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>, at which the ruthenium oxide will readily form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, dielectric layer <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>, e.g., a high dielectric constant material, is formed relative to the electrode <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight>. Further thereafter, the second electrode <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> is formed relative to the dielectric material <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>. For example, such an electrode may be of any conductive material or materials typically used for electrodes. One example of a container capacitor typically including electrodes formed on surfaces requiring conformal formation of a bottom electrode is described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,270,241 to Dennison, et al., entitled &ldquo;Optimized container stacked capacitor DRAM cell utilizing sacrificial oxide deposition and chemical mechanical polishing,&rdquo; issued Dec. 14, 1993. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> All patents, patent documents, and references cited herein are incorporated in their entirety as if each were incorporated separately. This invention has been described with reference to illustrative embodiments and is not meant to be construed in a limiting sense. As described previously, one skilled in the art will recognize that various other illustrative applications may use the techniques as described herein to take advantage of the beneficial characteristics of structures formed thereby. Various modifications of the illustrative embodiments, as well as additional embodiments to the invention, will be apparent to persons skilled in the art upon reference to this description. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for use in fabrication of integrated circuits comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first metal layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second metal layer on at least a portion of the first metal layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the second metal layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>oxidizing one or more regions of the second metal layer to form metal oxide regions corresponding to one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer by thermally treating the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the oxidation diffusion barrier layer and unoxidized portions of the second metal layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein oxidizing one or more regions of the second metal layer comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon at a temperature greater than 300&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon in a non-oxidizing atmosphere. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least platinum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least ruthenium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidation diffusion barrier layer is formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein removing the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer comprises removing the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer relative to the metal oxide regions using at least one of a wet etch and a dry etch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method for use in fabrication of integrated circuits comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first metal layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion, the first metal layer having grain boundaries extending therethrough; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second metal layer on at least a portion of the first metal layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming metal oxide regions on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof through selective oxidation of the second metal layer by diffusion of oxygen from the oxygen-containing surface portion through the one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming metal oxide regions on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof comprises: 
<claim-text>providing an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the second metal layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>thermally treating the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon to selectively oxidize one or more regions of the second metal layer at the one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer resulting in the one or more metal oxide regions and unoxidized portions of the second metal layer therebetween; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the oxidation diffusion barrier layer and the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein thermally treating the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon at a temperature greater than 300&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon in a non-oxidizing atmosphere. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein removing the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer comprises removing the unoxidized portions of the second metal relative to the metal oxide regions using at least one of a wet etch and a dry etch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least platinum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least ruthenium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidation diffusion barrier layer is formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method for use in fabrication of integrated circuits comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a platinum layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion, the platinum layer having grain boundaries extending therethrough; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a ruthenium layer on at least a portion of the platinum layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming ruthenium oxide regions on at least portions of the platinum layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof through selective oxidation of the ruthenium layer by diffusion of oxygen from the oxygen-containing surface portion through the one or more grain boundaries of the platinum layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming ruthenium oxide regions on at least portions of the platinum layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof comprises: 
<claim-text>providing an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the ruthenium layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>thermally treating the substrate assembly having the platinum layer, ruthenium layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon to selectively oxidize one or more regions of the ruthenium layer at the one or more grain boundaries of the platinum layer resulting in the one or more ruthenium oxide regions and unoxidized ruthenium portions of the ruthenium layer therebetween; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the oxidation diffusion barrier layer and the unoxidized ruthenium portions of the ruthenium layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein thermally treating the substrate assembly having the platinum layer, ruthenium layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the platinum layer, ruthenium layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon at a temperature greater than 300&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein annealing the substrate assembly having the platinum layer, ruthenium layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the platinum layer, ruthenium layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon in a non-oxidizing atmosphere. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein removing the unoxidized ruthenium portions of the ruthenium layer comprises removing the unoxidized ruthenium portions of the ruthenium layer relative to the ruthenium oxide regions using at least one of a wet etch and a dry etch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidation diffusion barrier layer is formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein removing the unoxidized ruthenium portions of the ruthenium layer results in a first electrode of a capacitor structure comprising the first metal layer and the one or more ruthenium oxide regions formed thereon, and further wherein the method comprises: 
<claim-text>forming a high dielectric constant material over at least a portion of the first electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second electrode on at least a portion of the high dielectric constant material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A method for use in formation of a capacitor comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first electrode on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion, wherein forming the first electrode comprises: 
<claim-text>forming a first metal layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second metal layer on at least a portion of the first metal layer, </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the second metal layer, </claim-text>
<claim-text>oxidizing one or more regions of the second metal layer to form metal oxide regions corresponding to one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer by thermally treating the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the oxidation diffusion barrier layer and unoxidized portions of the second metal layer; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a high dielectric constant material over at least a portion of the first electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second electrode on at least a portion of the high dielectric constant material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein oxidizing one or more regions of the second metal layer comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon at a temperature greater than 300&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon in a non-oxidizing atmosphere. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least platinum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least ruthenium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidation diffusion barrier layer is formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein removing the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer comprises removing the unoxidized portions of the second metal relative to the metal oxide regions using at least one of a wet etch and a dry etch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A method for use in formation of a capacitor comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first electrode on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion, wherein forming the first electrode comprises: </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first metal layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion, the first metal layer having grain boundaries extending therethrough, </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second metal layer on at least a portion of the first metal layer, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming metal oxide regions on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof through selective oxidation of the second metal layer by diffusion of oxygen from the oxygen-containing surface portion through the one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a high dielectric constant material over at least a portion of the first electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second electrode on at least a portion of the high dielectric constant material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming metal oxide regions on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof comprises: 
<claim-text>providing an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the second metal layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>thermally treating the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon to selectively oxidize one or more regions of the second metal layer at the one or more grain boundaries of the first metal layer resulting in the one or more metal oxide regions and unoxidized portions of the second metal layer therebetween; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the oxidation diffusion barrier layer and the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein thermally treating the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon at a temperature greater than 300&deg; C. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon comprises annealing the substrate assembly having the first metal layer, second metal layer, and oxidation diffusion barrier layer formed thereon in a non-oxidizing atmosphere. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein removing the unoxidized portions of the second metal layer comprises removing the unoxidized portions of the second metal relative to the metal oxide regions using at least one of a wet etch and a dry etch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least platinum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least ruthenium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidation diffusion barrier layer is formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first metal layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more metal oxide regions formed from a second metal layer on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the second metal layer over at least the one or more metal oxide regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>unoxidized portions of the second metal layer between the one or more metal oxide regions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidation diffusion barrier layer is formed at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least platinum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least ruthenium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a platinum layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more ruthenium oxide regions formed from a ruthenium layer on at least portions of the platinum layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an oxidation diffusion barrier layer on at least a portion of the ruthenium layer over at least the one or more ruthenium oxide regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>unoxidized ruthenium portions of the ruthenium layer between the one or more ruthenium oxide regions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxidation diffusion barrier layer is formed of at least one of silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, and aluminum oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the platinum layer and the one or more ruthenium oxide regions form at least a portion of a first electrode of a capacitor structure, and further wherein the capacitor structure comprises: 
<claim-text>a high dielectric constant material formed over at least a portion of the first electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second electrode on at least a portion of the high dielectric constant material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. A capacitor structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate assembly including an oxygen-containing surface portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first electrode comprising a first metal layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion and one or more metal oxide regions formed from a second metal layer on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a high dielectric constant material formed over at least a portion of the first electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second electrode on at least a portion of the high dielectric constant material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The capacitor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 57</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The capacitor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 58</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least platinum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The capacitor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 57</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The capacitor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 60</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least ruthenium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. A memory cell structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate assembly including at least one active device and having an oxygen-containing surface portion; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor formed relative to the at least one active device, the capacitor comprising: 
<claim-text>a first electrode comprising a first metal layer on at least a portion of the oxygen-containing surface portion and one or more metal oxide regions formed from a second metal layer on at least portions of the first metal layer at one or more grain boundaries thereof, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a high dielectric constant material formed over at least a portion of the first electrode, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second electrode on at least a portion of the high dielectric constant material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of platinum, palladium, rhodium, and iridium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first metal layer is formed of at least platinum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of ruthenium, osmium, rhodium, iridium, and cerium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 65</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second metal layer is formed of at least ruthenium.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001190A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001190A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001190A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001190A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001190A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
