<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005361A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005361A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005361A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005361A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005361A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005361A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005361A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005361A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005361A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005361A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005361</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10106414</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020326</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>101 15 880.7</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010330</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04L001/22</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>714</class>
<subclass>025000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Test circuit for testing a synchronous memory circuit</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Wolfgang</given-name>
<family-name>Ernst</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Munchen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gunnar</given-name>
<family-name>Krause</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Marht Schwaben</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Justus</given-name>
<family-name>Kuhn</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Munchen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jens</given-name>
<family-name>Lupke</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Munchen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<family-name>Poechmuller</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Colchester</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jochen</given-name>
<family-name>Mueller</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Munchen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<family-name>Schittenhelm</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Poing</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JENKINS &amp; WILSON, PA</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>3100 TOWER BLVD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1400</address-2>
<city>DURHAM</city>
<state>NC</state>
<postalcode>27707</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Test circuit for testing a synchronous memory circuit Test circuit for testing a synchronous memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) having a frequency multiplication circuit (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) which multiplies a clock frequency of a low-frequency clock signal received from an external test unit by a particular frequency multiplication factor in order to produce a high-frequency clock signal for the synchronous memory chip (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) to be tested, a test data generator (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) which produces test data on the basis of data control signals received from the external test unit (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and outputs them to a data output driver (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) in order to write them to the synchronous memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) to be tested, a first signal delay circuit (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>) for delaying the test data which are output by the test data generator (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) by an adjustable first delay time, a second signal delay circuit (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) for delaying data which are read out of the synchronous memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) to be tested and are received by a data input driver (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) in the test circuit (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) by an adjustable second delay time, and having a data comparison circuit (<highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>) which compares the test data produced by the zest data generator (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) with the data read out of the memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and, on the basis of the comparison result, outputs an indicator signal to the external test unit (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) which indicates whether the synchronous memory circuit to be tested is operable. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a test circuit for testing a synchronous memory circuit, in particular a high-frequency DRAM memory module, in which the latencies can be adjusted for testing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Synchronous memory circuits contain a multiplicity of addressable memory cells for storing data. Following the manufacturing process, the memory circuits produced are tested for operability by a test arrangement before they are delivered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a teat arrangement based on the prior art. The circuit to be tested CUT (DUT: Device Under Test) is clocked with a clock signal CLK via a clock signal line by the external test unit and receives test control signals via a control bus for the purpose of testing a synchronous memory circuit. The test unit uses a data bus to write test data patterns to the memory cells addressed via the address bus and to read them out of the memory cells again. The test unit compares the applied test data with the data which are read out and, on the basis of the data discrepancies established, establishes which memory cells within the synchronous memory are faulty. These memory cells are generally replaced with redundant memory cells by means of readdressing. If the number of faulty memory cells within the synchronous memory circuit is too high, the memory to be rested DUT is disposed of as being irreparable. Testing the synchronous memory DUT involves data being written to the memory and then being read out again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows signal diagrams to illustrate the writing of data to the synchronous memory chip. The memory chip is clocked with a clock signal CLK by the test unit and receives via the control bus a command to write data to the addressed memory cell, After a latency L<highlight><subscript>WR</subscript></highlight>, the data to be written D<highlight><subscript>ln </subscript></highlight>are applied to the data connection of the synchronous memory chip. For critical testing of the memory chip DUT, the latencies can be adjusted by the external lest unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows flow diagrams to illustrate the read operation for data from the synchronous memory chip. The memory cells contained in the memory chip are arranged in the form of a matrix and are addressed by means of a row address strobe signal (RAS) and a column address strobe signal (CAS). The RAS control signal, which the test unit applies to the synchronous memory chip via the control bus, indicates that the address present on the address bus is a row address, while a CAS control signal indicates that the address present on the address bus is a column address. Successive application of a column address and a row address allows a specific memory cell to be addressed The use of an RAS control signal and a CAS control signal allows the width of the address bus to be kept down. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> reveals, the test unit applies a read command to the synchronous memory chip via the control bus, and the data on the data connections DO are read out after a CAS latency. In this case, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows various CAS latencies which can be adjusted by the external test unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The synchronous memory chip DUT operates at a particular operating clock frequency CLK. In modern memory chips, the operating clock frequencies are becoming higher and higher and are already in the region of a few hundred megahertz. Conventional test units operate at operating clock frequencies of, by way of example, 100 megahertz and are not able to test such high-frequency memory chips reliably. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is therefore the object of the present invention to provide a test circuit for reliably testing a synchronous memory circuit which operates at a very high clock frequency, for which the test latencies are adjustable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The invention achieves this object by means of a test circuit having the features specified in patent claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The invention provides a test circuit for testing a synchronous memory circuit having </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> a frequency multiplication circuit which multiplies a clock frequency of a low-frequency clock signal received from an external test unit by a particular frequency multiplication factor in order to produce a high-frequency cloak signal for the Synchronous memory chip, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> a test data generator which produces test data on the basis of data control signals received from the external test unit and outputs them to a data output driver in order to write them to the synchronous memory circuit, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> a first signal delay circuit for delaying the test data which are output by the test data generator by an adjustable first delay time, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> a second signal delay circuit for delaying data which are read out of the synchronous memory circuit to be tested and are received by a data input driver in the test circuit by an adjustable second delay time, and having a data comparison circuit which compares the test data produced by the test data generator with the data read out of the memory circuit and, on the basis of the comparison result, outputs an indicator signal to the external test unit which indicates whether the synchronous memory circuit to be tested is operable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The use of the inventive test circuit makes it possible to test a synchronous memory which operates at a very high operating clock frequency reliably using a conventional test unit which operates at a low clock frequency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment of the inventive test circuit, the signal delay circuits each have registers for storing the delay times, which can be adjusted by the external test unit via initialization lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The signal delay circuits are preferably clocked with the high-frequency clock signal which is output by the frequency multiplication circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The clock signals for clocking the clock signal delay circuit can preferably be delayed themselves. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the inventive test circuit, the frequency multiplication factor is adjustable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the test circuit is integrated in the synchronous memory circuit.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the inventive test circuit for testing a synchronous memory circuit is explained below with reference to the appended figures, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a test arrangement based on the prior art: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows timing diagrams to illustrate the writing of data to a synchronous memory circuit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows timing diagrams to illustrate the reading of data out of a synchronous memory circuit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a test arrangement which contains the inventive test circuit.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> reveals, the inventive test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is arranged between an external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and a synchronous memory circuit <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to be tested. The test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> contains a frequency multiplication circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and receives a relatively low-frequency clock signal of, by way of example, 100 megahertz from the external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> via a line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The frequency multiplication circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> multiplies the clock frequency of the received clock signal by a particular frequency multiplication factor in order to generate a high-frequency clock signal for the synchronous memory chip <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In this case, the frequency multiplication factor is preferably adjustable and is four, for example. The frequency multiplication circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> outputs the high-frequency clock signal to a clock signal input <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> on the synchronous memory chip <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> via a line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> also contains a parallel/serial converter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which receives control signals relating to the memory chip <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> via control lines <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> from the external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In this case, the control signals are transferred from the external rest unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to the parallel/serial converter a via the wide control signal bus <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, in each case in parallel via a plurality of control lines, and the parallel/serial converter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> outputs them serially via a control signal bus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, having a narrower bus width, to a control input <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> on the circuit to be tested <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The control signals output by the external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> via the control line <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are also output to an evaluation logic unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> within the inventive test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, where they are decoded in order to produce internal control signals. The decoder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> uses the internal control signals via an internal control signal bus <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in order to control internal components, namely a data output driver <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a data input driver <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. On the basis of the external control signals applied, the evaluation logic unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> generates a read/write control signal for actuating the data output driver <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the data input driver <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. This makes it possible to obviate additional control lines from the external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to the test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> also contains a test data generator <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which receives data control signals from the external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> via data control lines <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and generates test data on the basis thereof. In this case, the test data generator <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> preferably contains registers storing test data patterns. On the basis of the data control signals received for the test data generator <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, these test data patterns are read out at a high clock frequency. The test data patterns read out are output by the test data generator <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to an internal data bus <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in the test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The generated test data present on the internal data bus <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are delayed by a first signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> in the test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, having an adjustable first delay time, and are applied to the data output driver <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via data lines <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> If a write command is applied to the control signal line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a data output driver <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is activated and the test data which are generated by the test data generator <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and are delayed by the first signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are applied via a data bus <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to a data connection <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> on the synchronous memory <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to be tested. Conversely, data which are read out of the synchronous memory circuit <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are applied by the data input driver <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, via data lines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, to a second signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which delays the applied data by at adjustable second delay time. To this end, the data input driver <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is activated by a read control signal applied to the control signal bus <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The received and delayed data which have been read out are applied by the second signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, via an internal data bus <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, to a first data input <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of a data comparison circuit <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> which compares the received data with the test data generated by the test data generator <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, which are applied to a second data input <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The data comparison circuit <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> compares the test data produced by the test data generator with the data which have been read out of the memory circuit <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and, on the basis of the comparison result, produces an indicator signal which is output to the external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> via a signal line <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The indicator signal indicates whether the test data block which has just been written and then read out again contains a data discrepancy indicating that the associated addressed memory cells within the synchronous memory chip are faulty. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The inventive test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> also preferably contains an address generator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> which receives address control signals from the external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> via address control signal lines <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and, on the basis thereof, produces address signals which are applied via an address bus <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to an address input <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> on the synchronous memory chip <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> for the purpose of addressing memory cells. The inventive test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> operates at the high operating clock frequency of the synchronous memory chip <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. To this end, the parallel/serial converter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the decoder or the evaluation logic unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the test data generator <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the data comparison circuit <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> have clock inputs which are clocked via an internal clock signal line <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with the high-frequency operating clock signal produced by the frequency multiplication circuit <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The first signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and the second signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are likewise clocked via clock signal lines <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> with the high-frequency operating clock signal, with the clock signal delay elements <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> being able to be delayed by a fixed rime delay. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The first signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> delays the test data which are output by the test data generator <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> by an adjustable first delay time buffer-stored in a register <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The second signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> delays the data read out from the synchronous memory <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by a second delay time buffer-stored in a register <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The buffer-stored delay times are initialized by the external test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> during an initialization phase via initialization lines <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in order to adjust the delay times. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The inventive test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, allows a synchronous memory chip which operates at a very high operating clock frequency of, by way of example, 400 megahertz to be tested reliably by a conventional test unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which operates, by way of example, at a clock frequency of 100 megahertz. In this case, initialization of the registers <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> allows the test latencies to be tested critically according to the specification of the synchronous memory chip. The programmable signal delay in the data&apos;s write signal path and read signal path allows the test circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to send and receive data to and from the memory chip <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> with the adjusted signal delay in units of the clock cycles or fractions thereof. The duration of the signal delay is buffer-stored in the two registers <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The registers <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are written to by the external test unit in an initialization phase before the start of the actual actuation of the memory chip <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In this case, the signal delays in the data&apos;s write path and read path can be adjusted independently of one another. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is arranged on the input side of the data output driver <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. In an alternative embodiment, the first signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> can also be connected downstream of the data output driver <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the second signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is arranged downstream of the data input driver <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. In an alternative embodiment, the signal delay circuit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is provided on the input side of the data input driver <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>List of reference numerals</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="133PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>Test circuit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>External test unit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>Circuit to be tested</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>Frequency multiplication circuit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>Clock signal line</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>Clock signal line</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>7</entry>
<entry>Clock input</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>8</entry>
<entry>Parallel/serial converter</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>9</entry>
<entry>Control lines</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>Control bus</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>11</entry>
<entry>Control input</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>12</entry>
<entry>Evaluation logic unit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>13</entry>
<entry>Internal control lines</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>14</entry>
<entry>Data output driver</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>15</entry>
<entry>Data input driver</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>Test data generator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>17</entry>
<entry>Data control lines</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>18</entry>
<entry>Internal data bus</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>19</entry>
<entry>Clock time delay circuit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>Internal data lines</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>21</entry>
<entry>Data bus</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>22</entry>
<entry>Data input</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>23</entry>
<entry>Data lines</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>24</entry>
<entry>Second signal delay circuit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>25</entry>
<entry>Internal data bus</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>26</entry>
<entry>Data input</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>27</entry>
<entry>Data comparison circuit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>28</entry>
<entry>Data input</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>29</entry>
<entry>Indicator line</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>30</entry>
<entry>Address generator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>31</entry>
<entry>Address control lines</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>32</entry>
<entry>Address bus</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>33</entry>
<entry>Address input</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>34</entry>
<entry>Clock signal line</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>35</entry>
<entry>Clock signal line</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>Clock signal line</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>37</entry>
<entry>Delay circuit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>38</entry>
<entry>Delay circuit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>39</entry>
<entry>Register</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>40</entry>
<entry>Register</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>41</entry>
<entry>Initialization lines</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Test circuit for testing a synchronous memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) having: 
<claim-text>(a) a frequency multiplication circuit (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) which multiplies a clock frequency of a low-frequency clock signal received from an external test unit by a particular frequency multiplication factor in order to produce a high-frequency clock signal for the synchronous memory chip (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) to be tested; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a test data generator (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) which produces test data on the basis of data control signals received from the external test unit (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and outputs them to a data output driver (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) in order to write them to the synchronous memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) to be tested; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a first signal delay circuit (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>) for delaying the test data which are output by the test data generator (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) by an adjustable first delay time; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a second signal delay circuit (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) for delaying data which are read out of the synchronous memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) to be tested and are received by a data input driver (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) in the test circuit (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) by an adjustable second delay time; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) and having a data comparison circuit (<highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>) which compares the test data produced by the test data generator (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) with the data read out of the memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and, on the basis of the comparison result, outputs an indicator signal to the external test unit (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) which indicates whether the synchronous memory circuit to be tested is operable. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Test circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>characterized </claim-text>
<claim-text>in that the signal delay circuits (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) are, connected to a register (<highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>) for storing the delay times, with the delay times being able to be adjusted by the external test unit (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) via initialization lines (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Test circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, 
<claim-text>characterized </claim-text>
<claim-text>in that the signal delay circuits (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) are clocked with the high-frequency clock signal which is output by the frequency multiplication circuit (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Test circuit according to one of the preceding claims, 
<claim-text>characterized </claim-text>
<claim-text>in that the clock signals for clocking the signal delay circuits (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) can be delayed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Test circuit according to one of the preceding claims, 
<claim-text>characterized </claim-text>
<claim-text>in that the frequency multiplication factor is adjustable. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Test circuit according to one of the preceding <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">5</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>characterized </claim-text>
<claim-text>in that the test circuit (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) is integrated in the synchronous memory circuit (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>).</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005361A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005361A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005361A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005361A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005361A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
