<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002945A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002945A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002945</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10175605</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020618</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-195081</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B23C001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>409</class>
<subclass>140000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>409</class>
<subclass>131000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Chip collecting apparatus for tip dresser</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shouichi</given-name>
<family-name>Sunaga</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yuichiro</given-name>
<family-name>Haruyama</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Fuji Jukogyo Kabushiki Kaisha</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>DARBY &amp; DARBY P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>805 Third Avenue</address-1>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10022</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In a chip collecting apparatus for a tip dresser of the present invention, a chip pickup case mounted on a dresser main body is divided into an upper case and a lower case, and the lower end of an arm admission port formed in the upper case is opened downward. During teaching operation, the lower case is rotated to open the lower end of the upper case, through which the insertion of a first gun arm into a lower chamber can be visually checked, and thus an electrode tip provided at the end thereof and a dressing body for dressing the end of the electrode tip are guided such that the central axes thereof conform to each other. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a chip collecting apparatus for a tip dresser for collecting chips generated when dressing electrode tips. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, electrode tips used for spot welding or the like are worn out (or deformed) when welding work is repeated. When welding work is performed with a worn-out electrode tip, welding of desired quality cannot be obtained; accordingly, electrode tips are periodically dressed to maintain welding quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> For example, Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. 6-122082 discloses a tip dresser for dressing electrode tips in which after the upper and lower surfaces of a dressing body have been tightly pressed by a pair of electrode tips provided at opposed ends of a welding gun, and the welding gun is swung around the central axis of each electrode tip for grinding, thereby dressing the electrode tips. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Recently, the recycle of chips is contemplated in view of cost reduction and environmental issues. Accordingly, a collection vessel is disposed under the dressing body to recycle the collected chips. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> However, there is a problem in that the chips tend to be released by the relative swing or rotation of the dressing body and the electrode tips during grinding work, and all the chips cannot be collected into the collection vessel, resulting in a low collection rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, when air is blown to the dressing body to prevent clogging of the dressing body, the chips are released by the blown air, so that the collection rate of the chips is further decreased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Generally, copper is often used as an electrode tip for spot welding and the like. In order to maintain a proper welding quality, the frequency of grinding is increased to increase the amount of ground chips of the electrode tip, so that, in order to reduce material cost, it is necessary to increase the collection rate of the chips and effectively recycle them. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> For this purpose, various techniques are proposed in which a chip collecting apparatus is mounted on the dresser main body having a dressing body for collecting chips generated during dressing the electrode tips. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> For example, Japanese Examined Utility Model Publication No. 3-18067 discloses a technique of collecting chips generated during polishing or grinding electrode tips in such a way that a cover main body is mounted on a dresser main body, and an air inlet and an air outlet are formed between the upper and lower surfaces of the cover main body and the dresser main body. Compressed air after driving a dressing body held by a holder is guided through the air inlet to the holder, and then the compressed air is guided through the air outlet to a chip collection vessel connected to the end of the cover main body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In general, the operation of moving the welding gun provided at the end of the welding robot toward the chip dresser is often memorized by teaching in advance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> However, when the cover main body for collecting the chips generated during dressing operation is mounted on the dresser main body, as in the above prior art, it becomes difficult to visually recognize the positional relationship between the electrode tips and the dressing body; therefore, it is necessary to temporarily remove the cover main body from the dresser main body and to perform teaching, posing a problem in increasing the number of processing steps required for teaching. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, since the dresser main body is covered by the cover main body, the dressed state of the electrode tips cannot be checked from the exterior, causing inconvenience of being unable to check faulty dressing such as insufficient dressing and excessive dressing. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to provide a chip collecting apparatus for a tip dresser capable of easily checking the positional relationship between electrode tips and a dressing body during teaching operation without detaching the whole device, significantly reducing processing steps required for teaching, and easily checking the presence or absence of faulty dressing during dressing operation from the exterior. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In the chip collecting apparatus for a tip dresser according to the present invention, including a tip dresser for dressing the electrode tips by pressing the electrode tips to a dressing body held by a dresser main body and relatively sliding the dressing body and the electrode tips, the dresser main body has a chip pickup case for covering the dressing body mounted thereon, the chip pickup case has an arm admission port allowing the insertion of gun arms having the electrode tips at the ends, the arm admission port has a shielding member allowing the insertion of the gun arms by elastic deformation, and the chip pickup case is divided in the vicinity of the arm admission port such that it can freely be opened and closed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> With such a configuration, the chip pickup case is divided in the vicinity of the arm admission port such that it can be opened and closed. Accordingly, during teaching operation, the divided portion of the chip pickup case is opened, so that the positional relationship between the electrode tips held at the ends of the gun arms and the dressing body can be recognized from the exterior. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects, features and advantages of the invention will become more clearly understood from the following description referring to the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> show a chip collecting apparatus according to a first embodiment of the present invention; wherein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a general perspective view of the chip collecting apparatus; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front view of the chip collecting apparatus; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> taken along the line III-III; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, in a different operation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> show a chip collecting apparatus according to a second embodiment of the present invention; wherein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a chip pickup case seen from the front downward; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the chip pickup case into which a welding gun advances, seen from the front obliquely downward; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the chip pickup case during dressing operation, seen from the front obliquely above; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the chip pickup case during teaching operation, seen from the front downward; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a chip pickup case according to a third embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> show a first embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Reference numeral <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> denotes a welding gun <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, such as a C-type welding gun, connected to a welding robot. The welding gun <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has first and second gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, to the ends of which electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are detachably attached to face each other. The electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are coaxially disposed and are relatively brought into close proximity to and apart from each other by advancing and retracting motions of at least one of the gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, a tip dresser <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for dressing the ends of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is disposed at a position not to interfere with welding work in the range of operation of the welding robot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> A dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>extending laterally from the tip dresser <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a holder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> at the end thereof for rotatably holding a dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is driven to rotate by a motor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> hung from the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and has concave cutters <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on the lower and upper surfaces thereof, the cutters being capable of dressing the ends of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> into a predetermined shape by polishing or grinding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has a chip pickup case <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> mounted at the end thereof. The chip pickup case <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is formed by working a resin mold or a thin steel sheet, and is divided into an upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The top of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is slanting obliquely upward toward the rear. Also, an arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with a predetermined width is opened from the front to the top of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and the lower end of the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>passes through the lower end of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A hole <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>penetrating the end of the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed at the upper back of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A shielding member <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is secured to the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The shielding member <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is composed of a pair of brush sections <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> arranged to face each other on the right and left sides of the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The bases of brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>made of nylon or the like and provided at the brush sections <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, respectively, are fastened to the rim of the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with plates <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The ends of the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are brought into contact with each other substantially at the center of the width of the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, so that the whole arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is covered from the front to the top by the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Thus, the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>prevent chips generating while the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are dressed from flying off to the exterior through the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Also, supporting plates <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are disposed at the upper and lower four corners of the hole <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed at the back of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The front end of each supporting plate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is extended horizontally toward the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the end of which is connected to the inner edge of the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and contact portion with the hole <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is joined together. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> When the end of the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is inserted into the hole <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the upper and lower edges are positioned in a state in which they are supported by the supporting plates <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is divided into an upper chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>and a lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>by the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and the upper and lower surfaces of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> supported by the holder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> provided at the end of the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are exposed to the upper chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>and the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The rear portions of the supporting plates <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> project outward from the hole <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. A pair of fixing blocks <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is brought into contact with the projecting portions from above and down, and both ends of the fixing blocks <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> are fastened with bolts <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, thereby fixing the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> An air nozzle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is secured to the back of the upper chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and the end of the air nozzle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is oriented to the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> exposed to the upper chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. Chips adhered to the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is released by air blown out from the air nozzle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, thereby preventing clogging of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, the upper chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>and the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>are communicated with each other through a void formed between the inner wall of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a void formed in the holder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the upper end back of the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is rotatably supported at the lower end back of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> with a hinge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The upper end outer periphery of the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is formed along the lower end outer periphery of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> freely opens and closes the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> around the hinge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. A bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> projects from the back of the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and a slotted hole <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>extending vertically is formed in the bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> An end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of a plunger <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of an air cylinder <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the rear end of which is secured to a column (not shown) or the like of the tip dresser <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, is engaged with the slotted hole <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The plunger <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the air cylinder <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is retracted and held ready in a state in which the front of the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is opened, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. When the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> provided for the welding gun <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is positioned in the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>, the plunger <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>projects, and thus, the upper end of the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is brought into contact with the lower end of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for closing, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> has a tapered chip guide surface <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>converging downward at the upper part thereof, under which a chip discharge port <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>opened downward is formed. Furthermore, a chip collection vessel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is formed under the chip discharge port <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In this case, it is possible to use the lower part of a plastic bottle, the upper part of which is cut off under the neck, as a chip collection vessel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In this case, the rim of the upper opening of the chip collection vessel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> formed of a plastic bottle may be hung from the chip discharge port <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Next, the operation of this embodiment with such a configuration will be discussed. The lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> provided for the chip pickup case <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is held ready with the front part opened, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. When the welding robot is taught the operation of dressing, the pair of electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> provided at the ends of the welding robot, which is set in a teaching mode, is guided to the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> held by the holder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, with the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> being in a standby state (in a state in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). At this time, since the lower end of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is opened, the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> mounted at the end of the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can easily be guided into the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and the central axis of the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can be accurately conformed to the central axis of the cutter <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> while it is visually checked, high workability is provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Since the lower end of the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>covered by the pair of opposite brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is also opened, the gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can smoothly be guided into the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>. At this time, when the chip collection vessel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is obstructive, it is moved out of the way in advance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> When the teaching during dressing operation has been completed in a predetermined way, the welding robot is moved, and the welding gun <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is moved apart from the chip pickup case <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and held ready in position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, dressing operation of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> will be described. First, the pair of gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> provided for the welding gun <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is moved toward the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with a predetermined space left therebetween, in accordance with preset teaching. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Both the gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are brought in close vicinity of the front of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> passes through the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to advance into the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; and the second gun arm <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is arranged at the upper part of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. At this time, since the lower end of the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is opened, the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be advanced from the lower part of the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>into the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>without interfering with the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Then, the central axis of the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> mounted at the end of the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is arranged onto the central axis of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> disposed on the holder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> provided for the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. At this time, since the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the electrode tip <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> mounted at the end of the second gun arm <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are arranged on the same axis, the electrode tip <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is also arranged on the central axis of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are moved to bring the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> relatively close to each other. Then, the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> rises toward the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, elastically deforms the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>blocking the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>along the outside shape of the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and brings the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> provided at the end thereof into contact with the cutter <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>provided at the lower surface of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. At the same time, the electrode tip <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> provided at the end of the second gun arm <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> passes through the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from the above of the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to be positioned in the upper chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> At this time, the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>disposed at the front and top of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are elastically deformed along the outer peripheries of the gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and the peripheries of the gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are closed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is placed in position in the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the plunger <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the air cylinder <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> projects in synchronization therewith to rotate the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> clockwise, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, and to bring the upper end of the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> into contact with the lower end of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, thereby integrating the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>therein with the chip guide surface <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> When the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are further brought close to each other, they are brought into contact with the cutters <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provided on the lower and upper surfaces of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, respectively, and press the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> therebetween. The dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is driven to rotate by the motor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> provided for the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and air is blown out from the air nozzle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> positioned in the upper chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>toward the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Chips adhered to the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is blown off by the air. The air blown to the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> flows through a gap in the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and the void formed around the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>toward the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>, and is blown to the exterior through the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>blocking the front of the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>and the chip discharge port <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the chips generated when the cutters <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provided for the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> dress the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> by polishing or grinding are guided toward the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>by air blow from the air nozzle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> positioned in the upper chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. At this time, the chips guided by air leaking out through the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>come into collision with the inner side of the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and drop toward the bottom of the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The chips dropping toward the bottom of the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>are guided toward the chip discharge port <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>along the chip guide surface <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and are collected into a chip collection vessel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> disposed under the chip discharge port <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> When dressing of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has been completed in a predetermined way, the plunger <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the air cylinder <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> retracts in synchronization therewith, and the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is thereby rotated around the hinge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and is set in a standby state in which the front lower end of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is opened, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Next, the welding robot is operated to separate the first and second gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> from the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by a reverse operation to that when advancing them and to bring them into a standby state for the next spot welding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> When the chips collected into the chip collection vessel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> reach a designated amount, or periodically, the chips collected in the chip collection vessel <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are recycled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> According to this embodiment, as described above, since the chip pickup case <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is divided into the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, when teaching is performed to the welding robot, the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> provided at the end of the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be positioned while the positional relationship therebetween is checked visually; therefore, high workability can be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Since the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> maintains an opened state until the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is located in position in the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be advanced into the lower chamber <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>from the lower part of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. As a result, there is no need to downwardly expand the arm admission port <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed at the front of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in order to prevent the interference with the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, allowing the entire length of the chip pickup case <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to be significantly decreased in a state in which the lower case <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is closed, so that downsizing can be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> show a second embodiment of the invention. A chip pickup case <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> according to this embodiment is divided into an upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and a lower case <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> having a bottom and acting as a chip collection vessel. The upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be freely opened and closed left and right at the front side thereof. More specifically, the upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes a back plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, and front flanges <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed by bending the front edges of the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The rear edges of the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and both side edges of the back plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are connected with each other with spring hinges <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The spring hinges <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> constantly apply a force to open the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> outward around it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Also, the base ends of receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, which extend in opposite directions and the ends of which overlap vertically in a state in which the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are closed (a state of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>), are supported by the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> on the bottom side of the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with hinges <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> such that they can freely rotate vertically. One end of a stay <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is rotatably supported at the lower surface of each receiving plate <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, and the other end of the stay <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is freely brought into and out of engagement with the hook <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> secured to the inside lower part of each of the side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In a state in which the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are opened, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the ends of the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> extending from the inner surfaces of the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> intersect each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> With such a configuration, when the operation at the time of dressing is taught to the welding robot, first, the ends of the stays <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> supporting the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are disengaged from the hooks <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> secured to the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Then, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are rotated downwards around the hinges <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> and stand still in substantially parallel to the inner surfaces of the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, the welding robot set in a teaching mode is operated, as is the first embodiment, to guide the gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> provided for the welding gun (C-type welding gun in the drawing) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> toward the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> held by the holder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from the front toward the upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> At this time, since the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are opened outwards by the urging force of the spring hinges <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> mounted at the ends of the gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be accurately guided to the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from the front, and also, the central axes of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> can be accurately conformed to the central axes of the cutters <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provided at both sides of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> while it is visually checked from the outside. Accordingly, high workability can be obtained while teaching is performed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> After the teaching operation has been completed in a predetermined way, the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are raised, and an end of each stay <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the other end of which is supported on the bottom of the receiving plate <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, is engaged with the hook <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> secured to the inner surface of each of the side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, and the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are set in a standby state in which the ends thereof overlap, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, a case of dressing the ends of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> will be described. First, the pair of gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> provided for the C-type welding gun <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is moved toward the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in accordance with preset teaching. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Next, the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is advanced into the upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> from the front of the upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Then, the end of the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> provided at the end of the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is brought into contact with the ends of the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> extending from the inner surfaces of the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The ends of the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> intersect each other. When the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is further advanced into the interior, the ends of the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are pushed, and the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> connected to the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are rotated in a direction to close each other around the spring hinges <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> against the urging force of the spring hinges <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> When the central axes of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are positioned on the central axis of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> disposed on the holder <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> provided for the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the ends of the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which are secured to the front flanges <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>bent from the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> forwardly, are brought into contact with each other to block the front and the top of the upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and also to block the peripheries of the gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by elastic deformation of the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The positional relationship between the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is controlled by adjusting the attachment positions of the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> or varying the widths of the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> After the dressing of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has been completed in a predetermined way, the welding robot is operated to separate the first and second gun arms <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> from the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by the reverse operation to that when the first and second gun arms are advanced, the pushing force of the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or the electrode tip <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to the receiving plates <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is gradually released, and the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are gradually opened in synchronization with the retracting motion of the first gun arm <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by the urging force of the spring hinges <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, thereby being returned to a standby state, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> According to this embodiment, as described above, the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the upper case <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are supported on the back plate <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with the spring hinges <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, and they are opened at the front in a standby state. Accordingly, when teaching is performed to the welding robot, the central axes of the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> can be conformed to the central axes of the cutters <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> while the positional relationship therebetween is checked visually; therefore, high workability can be provided. Furthermore, during dressing operation, since it can be visually checked immediately before the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> come close to the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, faulty dressing can be found relatively easily. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Also, since opening and closing operations of the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are performed by the advancing and retracing motions of the welding gun <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which needs no power, the apparatus has a simple structure, and can be manufactured at low cost, and also it can easily be mounted on the dresser main body <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, so that high operability can be provided. Of course, it is also possible that the both-side plates <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are positively opened and closed by combination with the air cylinder and a link. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows a third embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> A chip pickup case <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> according to this embodiment has a window <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>opened in a side <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>thereof, through which the positional relationship between the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> can be visually checked, the window <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>being blocked by a transparent plate <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> made of acryl or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> An arm insertion port <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>opened in the front of the chip pickup case <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is blocked by a pair of brushes <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>constituting a shielding member <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, and un upper-arm insertion port <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is formed in the top of the chip pickup case <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> whereas a chip guide surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>is formed in a tapered shape at the bottom and a chip discharge port <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>is opened at the end thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> According to this embodiment, since the positional relationship between the electrode tips <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supported by the welding gun <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and advancing into the chip pickup case <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and the dressing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be visually recognized through the window <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from the exterior, not only the state in which teaching is performed but also the state in which dressing is performed can be recognized, so that faulty dressing such as insufficient dressing and excessive dressing can be prevented before they occur. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> It is also possible that the window <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is formed at both sides or at the back of the case <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Also, it is possible that the window <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is covered with a lid capable of being freely opened and closed, in stead of the transparent plate <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, and only when necessary, the lid is opened and the inside can be viewed therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The present invention is not limited to the above embodiments; for example, the brushes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be rubber blades, and it is also possible to form the window shown in the third embodiment at the side or the back of the upper case <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, shown in the first and second embodiments, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Having described the preferred embodiments of the invention referring to the accompanying drawings, it should be understood that the present invention is not limited to those precise embodiments and various changes and modifications thereof could be made by one skilled in the art without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention as defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, as described above, the positional relationship between the electrode tips and the dressing body during teaching operation can easily be checked without detaching the whole device, thereby reducing the number of processing steps required for teaching. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Also, the presence or absence of faulty dressing during dressing operation can easily be checked from the exterior, thereby preventing faulty dressing. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A chip collecting apparatus for a tip dresser, comprising: 
<claim-text>a tip dresser for dressing electrode tips by pressing the electrode tips to a dressing body held in a dresser main body and relatively sliding the dressing body and the electrode tips; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a chip pickup case mounted on the dresser main body for covering the dressing body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an arm admission port opened in the chip pickup case, into which gun arms having the electrode tips at the ends thereof are inserted; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shielding member disposed at the arm admission port for allowing the insertion of the gun arms by elastic deformation, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the chip pickup case is divided in the vicinity of the arm admission port such that it can freely be opened and closed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The chip collecting apparatus for the tip dresser, according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the chip pickup case is divided into an upper case and a lower case at the midpoint or the lower part of the arm admission port. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The chip collecting apparatus for the tip dresser, according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the chip pickup case is divided to right and left at the arm admission port such that it can freely be opened and closed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A chip collecting apparatus for a tip dresser, comprising: 
<claim-text>a tip dresser for dressing electrode tips by pressing the electrode tips to a dressing body held in a dresser main body and relatively sliding the dressing body and the electrode tips: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a chip pickup case mounted on the dresser main body for covering the dressing body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an arm admission port opened in the chip pickup case, into which gun arms having the electrode tips at the ends thereof are inserted; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shielding member disposed at the arm admission port for allowing the insertion of the gun arms by elastic deformation; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a window provided at one side of the chip pickup case, through which the positional relationship between the dressing body and the electrode tips can be viewed.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002945A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
