<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003782A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003782A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003782</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10235580</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020906</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-145148</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000517</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05K001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>439</class>
<subclass>073000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Contact pin assembly, contact pin assembly manufacturing method, contact pin assembling structure, contact pin assembling structure manufacturing method, and socket for electrical parts</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10235580</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020906</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09855504</doc-number>
<document-date>20010516</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shuichi</given-name>
<family-name>Satoh</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kawaguchi-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Masami</given-name>
<family-name>Fukunaga</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kawaguchi-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>ENPLAS CORPORATION</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Kawaguchi</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>STAAS &amp; HALSEY LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>700 11TH STREET, NW</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 500</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A contact pin assembly for a socket for electrical parts comprises a plurality of contact pins provided for a socket body of a socket for electrical parts and a connection member, formed separately, connecting all the contact pins with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones. The predetermined distance is made substantially equal to a distance between adjacent ones of terminals provided for an electrical part which is held in the socket body. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a socket for an electrical part used for carrying out an electrical test of electrical parts such as electronic circuit board such as IC package and to parts or assembly constituting such socket. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">PRIOR ART OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> For example, in a case where a burn-in test of an IC package (electrical part) such as BGA or LGA, the IC package is accommodated in a socket for electrical parts provided with contact pins formed of electrically conductive metal, and terminals formed to the lower surface of the IC package in shape of matrix are contacted to the contact pins to thereby establish an electrical connection, through the contact pins, between the terminals of the IC package and an external test circuit means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Recent technology has provided the following technical ideas as prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;First Prior Art&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Recently, in an IC package such as BGA or LGA, there is a requirement of realizing a small or compact structure of the IC package, and for this reason, contact pins having various shapes have been provided. For instance, one example is shown in FIG. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, in which a contact pin <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> comprises a tubular (cylindrical) member <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> formed of an electrically conductive metal, a rod-shape contact (contact piece) <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> which is formed of an electrically conductive metal and disposed inside the tubular member <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> to be vertically movable, and a spring <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> by which the contact <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is urged upward so as to contact the contact <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> to a terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of an IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> so that the terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> contacts electrically to an external test circuit means, not shown, through the rod-shape contact <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and the tubular member <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The contact pins <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> each of such structure are mounted inside the socket (not shown) for electrical parts so as to accord in numbers with the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Second Prior Art&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> also shows another example of a contact pin of conventional structure, and, the contact pin <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> is formed of an electrically conductive material in form of a coil spring, which has one end contacting a terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of an IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the other end contacting an external test circuit means, not shown, so as to accommodate the contact pin <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> in the socket body in a manner opposing to the terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> However, the contact pin <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the first prior art has a complicated structure and, it is hence difficult to easily manufacture the same. Moreover, since the contact pin <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is not easily manufactured, a price or selling cost of the contact pin as a product is made expensive. Accordingly, a socket for electrical parts provided with a number of such expensive contact pins are also made expensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the contact pin <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> has a simple structure in comparison with the first example, and hence, it is relatively easily manufactured with cheap cost of product. However, in this contact pin <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, as the electrically conductive material is formed in shape of spiral coil having a long length, a large resistance is provided, thus being defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in these first and second prior art examples (conventional contact pins <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>), the contact pins <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>) must be mounted one by one to a contact pin accommodation portion of the socket body so as to be coincident with a number of terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, requiring a troublesome mounting working, thus being not effective. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to substantially eliminate defects or drawbacks encountered in the prior art mentioned above and to provide a structural part or member for the socket for electrical parts and provide such socket capable of reducing assembling working or steps and manufacturing cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> This and other objects of the present invention can be achieved by providing, in one aspect, a contact pin assembly for a socket for electrical parts comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> a plurality of contact pins provided for a socket body of a socket for electrical parts; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> a connection member connecting all the contact pins with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> the predetermined distance being made substantially equal to a distance between adjacent ones of terminals provided for an electrical part which is held in the socket body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In a preferred example, each of the contact pins comprises a spring function portion having elasticity, a contact portion which is formed to a top end side of the spring function portion and contacts the terminal of the electrical part, a conductive portion extending from the spring function portion on the side opposite to the contact portion, and a connection leg portion further extending from the conductive portion, the conductive portions of the respective contact pins being connected together by the connection member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The contact pins are arranged laterally symmetrically with respect to a center line of the contact pin arrangement and when the contact portions of the contact pins are contacted to the terminals and pressed thereby, the contact portions of the laterally arranged contact pins are displaced respectively to a center line side and a side opposite to the center line side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In this aspect, there is further provided a method of manufacturing a contact pin assembly which comprises a plurality of contact pins and a connection member connecting all the contact pins, the manufacturing method comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> forming a plurality of contact pins and contact pin connection portions integrally from a conductive elastic plate member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> arranging and fixing the contact pins by using a connection member with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> removing thereafter the contact pin connection portions from the respective contact pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> According to this aspect, since a plurality of contact pins are arranged with a predetermined distance (interval) by the connection member, the workability at the time of assembling to the socket for electrical parts can be improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The connection of the conductive portion between the spring function portion and the connection leg portion through the connection member does not give an adverse affect on the elastic deformation of the spring function portion and the connection of the connection leg portion to the external test circuit means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, according to the symmetric arrangement of the contact pins, when the contact pin assembly is incorporated in the socket and the contact portions of the contact pins are pressed by the terminals, the contact portions, separated into lateral two portions, are displaced in opposing directions from the center line of the contact pin arrangement. Therefore, the electrical part is not moved in one direction and good wiping effect can be achieved between the terminals of the electrical part and the contact portions of the contact pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, according to the contact pin assembly manufacturing method of the above aspect, a plurality of contact pins can be extremely easily and exactly connected with a predetermined distance by using the connection member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, there is also provided a contact pin assembling structure for a socket for electrical parts comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> a plurality of contact pins provided for a socket body of a socket for electrical parts, each of the contact pins comprising a spring function portion having elasticity, a contact portion which is formed to a top end side of the spring function portion and contacts the terminal of the electrical part, a conductive portion extending from the spring function portion on the side opposite to the contact portion, and a connection leg portion further extending from the conductive portion, the conductive portions of the respective contact pins being connected together by the connection member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> a connection member connecting all the contact pins with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones, the predetermined distance being made substantially equal to a distance between adjacent ones of terminals provided for an electrical part which is held in the socket body; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> a contact pin holding member formed of an insulating resin material, the contact pin holding member holding and fixing together the conductive portion and the spring function portion and the conductive portion and the connection leg portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In this aspect, there is further provided a method of manufacturing a contact pin assembling structure defined above, wherein the conductive portion and the spring function portion of the contact pin and the conductive portion and the connection leg portion of the contact pin are fixed to the contact pin holding member formed of an insulating resin material and, thereafter, the connection member is removed from the conductive portions of the contact pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> According to this aspect, the conductive portion and the spring function portion of the contact pin and the conductive portion and the connection leg portion of the contact pin are fixed to the contact pin holding member, respectively, so that the contact pins can be held with predetermined distance in a stable fashion without causing positional shifting of the contact pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In a further aspect of the present invention, there is also provided a socket for electrical parts in which a plurality of terminals provided for an electrical part are electrically connected to an external test circuit means through a plurality of contact pins arranged in accordance with the arrangement of the terminals, wherein a plurality of contact pin assembling structures each having the structure defined above are laminated in numbers corresponding to the number of rows of the terminals of the electrical part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In a more specific mode in this aspect, there is provided a socket for electrical parts comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> a socket body formed of an insulating resin material; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> a cover mounted to the socket body to be opened or closed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> a plurality of contact pin assembling structures mounted to the socket body; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> a floating plate elastically supported by the socket body through a spring, the floating plate having a terminal accommodation portion in which terminals of an electrical part is accommodated, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> the plurality of contact pin assembling structures being laminated in numbers corresponding to the number of rows of the terminals of the electrical part, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> each of the contact pin assembling structure comprising: a plurality of contact pins provided for the socket body, each of the contact pins comprising a spring function portion having elasticity, a contact portion which is formed to a top end side of the spring function portion and contacts the terminal of the electrical part, a conductive portion extending from the spring function portion on the side opposite to the contact portion, and a connection leg portion further extending from the conductive portion, the conductive portions of the respective contact pins being connected together by the connection member; a connection member connecting all the contact pins with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones, the predetermined distance being made substantially equal to a distance between adjacent ones of terminals provided for an electrical part which is held in the socket body; and a contact pin holding member formed of an insulating resin material, the contact pin holding member holding and fixing together the conductive portion and the spring function portion and together the conductive portion and the connection leg portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> According to this aspect, a socket for electrical parts having an improved structure and attaining a stable function can be provided by disposing a plurality of contact pin assembling structures in a laminated state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The nature and further characteristic features of the present invention will be made more clear from the following descriptions made with reference to the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In the accompanying drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a socket for an electrical part according to a first embodiment of the present invention, the section being taken along the line I-I in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> mentioned herinlater; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a sectional view corresponding to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, in which a cover member is opened upward; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a plan view of the socket of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, partially cut away; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a view showing an engaged state of a contact pin and a floating plate, in an enlarged scale; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a view showing a contacting state of a terminal contact portion of the contact pin of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> to a terminal of the electrical part, in an enlarged scale; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> is a front view of an IC package as the electrical part and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> is a view of the IC package viewed from the direction VIB in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a front view of a contact pin assembly structure according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a front view of a contact pin assembly according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a front view showing a state that contact pins corresponding, in numbers, to one row of terminals in a matrix arrangement of an IC package are connected to other contact pins; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a front view showing a state that contact pins corresponding, in numbers, to one row of terminals in a matrix arrangement of an IC package are bonded and fixed to a resin film having an insulating property; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference> is a plan view of a contact pin holding member, viewed from a direction XIA in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>B, which is a front view of the contact pin holding member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing a combined arrangement of the contact pin assembly structure and a press (holding) plate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a plan view showing a state that the contact pin assembly structure, corresponding to the row numbers of the terminals of the IC package, is assembled with the socket body; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a front view of a contact pin assembly structure according to a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> shows a structure of a contact pin according to a first prior art; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> shows a structure of a contact pin according to a second prior art.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments of the present invention will be described hereunder with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;First Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> represent a socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts according to the present invention, in which <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the socket with a cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> being closed, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the same state of the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> with the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> being opened and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a plan view of the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> including a portion partially cut away. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Entire Structure of Socket for Electrical Parts&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> With reference to these figures, the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts comprises a socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> formed of an insulating material, a cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> attached to an upper portion, as viewed in an installed state, of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to be opened or closed, a plurality of contact pin assembling structures <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> mounted to the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> elastically supported by a spring <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> with respect to the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In such socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts, an IC package (electrical part) <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> equipped with terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in form of matrix is accommodated in a accommodation portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The contact pin assembling structure <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is provided with a number of contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, through which the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and an external test circuit means such as tester, not shown, are electrically connected to each other as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. Further, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> or <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>B, the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is composed of a number of terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in form of matrix. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Contact Pin Assembling Structure&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a contact pin assembling structure <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which is to be assembled with the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and used for electrically connecting the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC-package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the external test circuit means, not shown. This contact pin assembling structure <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> comprises a contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and a contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> made of insulating resin (resin material having insulating property) and adapted to accommodate and hold the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> comprises a number of contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> corresponding, in numbers, to one row of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and an insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, as a connection member, to which the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are bonded and fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Contact Pin Assembly&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, which is composed of, as mentioned above, a number of contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> corresponding, in numbers, to one row of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for positioning and fixing the contact pins in one row. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is formed in the following manner. That is, with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is formed by effecting an etching working or pressing working to an electrically conductive elastic plate so that a number of contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> corresponding, in number, to one row of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are connected in one assembly by means of contact pin connecting member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> which integrally connects the lower end portions of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in a fashion such that the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are arranged in a laterally symmetrical manner with respect to a central portion thereof (center line CL in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Each of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is composed of (comprises), as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, 7</cross-reference> or <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, a terminal contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> contacting the terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, a spring function portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> having approximately S- or inverted S-shape, a mount base portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to be engaged with a positioning mount groove <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> formed to the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a conductive portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> bonded and fixed to the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a connection leg portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for connecting the conductive portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to the external electrical test circuit means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In these structural portions or pieces, the mount base portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is shown in detail. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the mount base portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed with a groove <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> having an approximately rectangular, i.e. box, shape. This rectangular groove <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> has upper and lower wall sections <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is engaged with the positioning mount groove <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> so that the wall sections <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are engaged with upper and lower wall sections <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of a positioning mount portion <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. According to such structures, the positioning of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the lateral and vertical directions can be performed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The conductive portions <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the respective contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are formed, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, such that the lower portions thereof are gradually widened from adjacent ones towards the lower distal ends. The connection leg portions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are engaged with leg portion accommodation portions <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> formed to the lower end portion of the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7, 11A</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>B). Further, engaging projections <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are formed to the upper both side portions of the connection leg portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and these engaging projections <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are engaged with positioning grooves <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> formed to the lower end portion of the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> so as to prevent the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> from shifting or displacing upward as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, for example, thus contact pins being positioned and fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a view of the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> partially in an enlarged scale and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a detail of the terminal contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (a portion contacting the terminal of the IC package). With reference to these figures, the terminal contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is engageable with a contact pin accommodation (receiving) hole <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> to be vertically slidable therein, and in the case where the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is pressed downward as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and the spring function portion <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is bent and deformed, an upper end portion of one of the side surfaces is obliquely cut away to form a cutout <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and a thickness reduced portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is formed to a lower end portion of the other one of the side surfaces so as not to abut the left upper end portion or right lower end portion of the contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> against the contact pin accommodation hole <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. As a result, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, even if the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is bent and deformed by being depressed by the terminal of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and then displaced to a position shown with two-dot-chain line, the upper end portion and the lower end portion of the terminal contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> move along the contact pin accommodation hole <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> so as not to obstruct the smooth displacement of the contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the vertical direction as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, an upper end-portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the terminal contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is formed to be round (arc-shape), so that even if the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is displaced from a position shown with a solid line to a portion shown with a two-dot-chain line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> stably contacts and slides on the surface of the terminal with maintaining substantially the same attitude of the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> with respect to the terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to thereby scrape an oxide film adhering on the surface of the terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, thus establishing an electrical contact therebetween. Further, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the contact pin connection portion <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> has both ends to which positioning arms <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are formed so as to stand upward, and positioning holes <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are formed to the front end portions <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> of the positioning arms <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is formed so as to have a height dimension H substantially the same as a height dimension of a conductive line (wire) portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and a width W slightly longer than a dimension between positioning arms <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the contact pin connection portion <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and further, a positioning hole <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is formed to a position corresponding to the positioning hole <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the positioning arm <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, a bonding agent is applied to a portion of the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> corresponding to the conductive portion (wire-like portion) <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of each of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are bonded and fixed to the resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in a state of positional alignment of the positioning hole <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the positioning hole <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the positioning arm <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> by means of positioning pin, not shown. Thereafter, the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is cut at the position shown with two-dot-chain line shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> and, thereby, the contact pin connection portion <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is cut off from the connection leg <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. According to the described manner, the respective contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are electrically separated from each other to thereby form the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The thus formed contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is assembled with the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, whereby the contact pin assembling structure is constructed. Further, it is necessary for the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to be formed of a material having a resistance or durability against heat at the time of burn-in test. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> (Contact Pin Holding Member) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> As shown in detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11A and 11B</cross-reference>, the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is a plate-like member formed of an insulating resin and having an approximately rectangular shape provided with positioning steps <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> at both lower side portions. The contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is provided with an upper recess <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> in which an upper portion of the mount base portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the spring function portion section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are accommodated and a lower recess <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in which a lower portion of the mount base portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the conductive portion <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are accommodated together with the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the state shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> A positioning mount portion <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is positioned between these upper recess <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and lower recess <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and to this positioning mount portion <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, there are formed a plurality of positioning mount groove <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, which are engageable with the mount base section <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in an arrangement laterally symmetrical with respect to the center line CL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, a plurality of leg section accommodation grooves <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, which are engageable with the connection leg portions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, are formed to a lower end edge <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the lower recess <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and a positioning groove <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, which is also engageable with an engaging projection <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the connection leg portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is formed to this lower end edge of the lower recess <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Further, the engaging groove <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is formed so as to connect the leg portion accommodation grooves <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> in the lateral (horizontal) direction as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference> to thereby prevent the connection leg portions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> from being shifted in the vertical direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference>. Further, the leg portion accommodation grooves <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> prevent the connection leg portions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> from being shifted in the horizontal direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Socket for Electrical Parts&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> A plurality of contact pin assembling structures <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, each being formed as mentioned above, are gathered in a predetermined number corresponding to the rows (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to n) of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</cross-reference>, and the assembled structures <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are then accommodated in the contact pin assembling structure accommodation portion <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> so as to be clamped between press plates <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> having high rigidity and, thereafter, fastened evenly to the positioning wall section <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> by a pair of screws <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> or like. At this time, in the contact pin assembling structure <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the positioning stage <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is engaged with a support stage <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to thereby carry out the vertical positioning and, hence, to position the upper end portions of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> With reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a cover mount portion <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is formed to the upper portion of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> so as to mount the cover to be opened or closed. A support shaft (pin) <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> engaged with the shaft support portion <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is fitted to the cover mount portion <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> to be pivotal, and shaft stop rings <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> are disposed to both end portions of the support shaft <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, a spring <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> is disposed around the support shaft <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> in a state that one end thereof is engaged with the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the other end thereof is engaged with the cover to thereby always urge the cover towards its opening direction (clockwise direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Further, with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is accommodated in the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> at a position above substantially the central portion thereof. The floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is urged upward by means of spring <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and its upper position is positioned by a stopper member <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Furthermore, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is provided with a plurality of contact pin accommodation (receiving) holes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> so as to correspond, in position, to the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> so that the terminal contact portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the respective contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are engaged with these contact pin accommodation holes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to be slidable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is provided, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</cross-reference>, with IC package positioning projections <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> at portions corresponding to four sides of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, rectangular in a plane shape, so as to guide the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to predetermined portions on the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and to position the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with respect to the terminal contact portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> As mentioned above, the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is always urged upward, and accordingly, a hook <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is attached to a portion opposite to the shaft support portion <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> (left side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) to be rotatable and the hook <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is engaged with an engagement projection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to thereby close the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is opened, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, by the elastic force of the spring <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> by releasing the engagement between the hook <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and the engagement projection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, and in this state, the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be set on the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> or taken out therefrom. Furthermore, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is formed with an IC package pressing portion <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> for pressing the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> towards the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> against the elastic (spring) force of the spring <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> The socket for electrical parts <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the structures mentioned above will operate as follows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> In the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts, the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is mounted to the IC accommodation portion <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> with the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> being opened, and thereafter, the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is closed to engage the hook <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> with the engagement projection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. According to this operation, the pressing portion <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> depresses the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> against the elastic force of the spring <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, thus the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> being pressed by the contact portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Each of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is contacted to the terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> such that the spring function portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> thereof is elastically deformed and the contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> contacts the terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package while performing wiping function thereto. Thereafter, the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is electrically connected to the external electrical test device through the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, thus performing the electrical test of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Upon the completion of the electrical test, the engagement between the hook <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the engagement projection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is released. According to this operation, the cover <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is rotated to the position of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> from the position of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and then separated from the upper surface of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In this positional state, the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> after the electrical testing is taken out from the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and a new IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is mounted on the floating plate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The functions and effects of the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts according to the described embodiment will be described hereunder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts of this embodiment, since the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the numbers corresponding to one row of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> arranged in matrix are positioned and fixed integrally to the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for one row of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> can be easily assembled to the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for a worker by adjusting the position of the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with respect to the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and the assembling steps and working can be remarkably reduced in comparison with a case in which the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are engaged with the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> one by one. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts of the described embodiment, the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the structure mentioned above is assembled with the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to thereby construct the contact pin assembling structure <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and the plural contact pin assembling structure <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> corresponding, in numbers, to the rows (1 ton) of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are assembled to the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the assembling steps and working can be remarkably reduced in comparison with a case in which the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are directly assembled to the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> one by one and the shape of the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be made simple. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Still furthermore, in the described embodiment, the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has the spring function portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in form of substantially S-shape or inverted S-shape, so that this portion is easily bent and deformed in comparison with a spring function portion which merely has an arcuate shape, and hence, the contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is less tilted (i.e., an inclination &thgr; in the vertical direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). Accordingly, it is possible for the spring function portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the present invention to have a large displacement in flexibility in comparison with a spring function portion merely having an arcuate shape, which results in easy absorption of an error in performances in forming and/or assembling the respective members and portions of the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts, and hence, the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be easily designed and manufactured. Furthermore, since the contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the contact pin <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a small inclination (tilting) in attitude, the contacting state between the contact portion <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the terminal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> can be made stable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Still furthermore, the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of this embodiment has a laterally symmetrical arrangement with respect to its central position as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, so that the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are deformed laterally symmetrically with respect to the center line CL at the time when the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is pressed. As a result, the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> becomes free from the shifting in the lateral direction in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> by the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and hence smoothly moves in the vertical direction. Accordingly, the contact portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> suitably perform the wiping function to the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the electrical contact between the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be ensured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Further, it is to be noted that, in an arrangement in which all the contact pins are displaced in the same direction, the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are displaced in the same direction together with the terminal contact portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Thus, in such arrangement, different from that mentioned above of the present invention, sufficient wiping effect could not be attained between the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the terminal contact portions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Still furthermore, in the described embodiment, since the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> corresponding, in numbers, to one row of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are manufactured from an electrically conductive elastic plate through an etching process or press working, the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can be easily manufactured particularly in comparison with the first example of the prior art, thus reducing the manufacturing cost thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Still furthermore, in the described embodiment, since the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> corresponding, in numbers, to one row of the terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are manufactured from an electrically conductive elastic plate through an etching process or press working, the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can be easily manufactured with reduced distance between adjacent ones in arrangement, it becomes possible to carry out the electrical test of the IC package having extremely narrow pitch distance between the respective terminals <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, which was difficult for the conventional technology such as first and second prior arts mentioned hereinbefore. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> In the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrical parts of the described embodiment, if the bonding and fixing force of the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is sufficiently large and the postioning and holding of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can be done only by the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, it will be not necessary to form the positioning groove <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the leg portion accommodation groove <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and the positioning groove <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> may not be formed to the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and hence, the shape of the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> will be made compact, which results in the easy engagement between the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, enabling the socket <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to be more easily assembled with reduced labour and cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> In the described embodiment, the surface of the conductive wire portion of the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> may be coated with an insulating resin material to make further sure the insulation between the respective contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;Second Embodiment&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> represents a second embodiment of the present invention, which corresponds to the state shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> and in which like reference numerals are added to portions and members corresponding to those of the first embodiment and duplicated explanation is hence omitted herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, in this second embodiment, the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is engaged with the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> so that the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is positioned to the front surface side. The mount base portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the respective contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the contact pin assembly <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are engaged with the positioning mount grooves <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, respectively, and the connection leg portions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and engagement projections <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are respectively engaged with the leg portion accommodation grooves <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and the positioning grooves <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, thereby surely positioning and fixing the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to the contact pin holding member <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is peeled from the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, thus constructing the contact pin assembling structure <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Then, the contact pin assembling structure <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is assembled to the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as like as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> In the described second embodiment, an adhesive tape will be preferably utilized as bonding means for bonding and fixing the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> corresponding to single row of the terminals of the IC package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and the bonding means is peeled from the contact pins <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> before the assembling to the socket body <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, so that paper tape and other heat-resistant tape or film having no insulating property may be instead utilized other than the insulating resin film <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Further, in this second embodiment, as like as in the first embodiment, the assembling steps or workings for the socket for electrical parts can be also reduced and a socket having simple shape and size can be realized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> It is further to be noted that the present invention is not limited to the described embodiments and many other changes and modifications may be made without departing from the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A contact pin assembly for a socket for electrical parts comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of contact pins provided for a socket body of the socket for electrical parts; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection member connecting all the contact pins with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said predetermined distance being made substantially equal to a distance between adjacent ones of terminals provided for an electrical part which is held in the socket body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A contact pin assembly according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said contact pins comprises a spring function portion having elasticity, a contact portion which is formed to a top end side of the spring function portion and contacts the terminal of the electrical part, a conductive portion extending from the spring function portion on the side opposite to the contact portion, and a connection leg portion further extending from the conductive portion, said conductive portions of the respective contact pins being connected together by said connection member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A contact pin assembly according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said contact pins are arranged laterally symmetrically with respect to a center line of the contact pin arrangement and when the contact portions of the contact pins are contacted to the terminals and pressed thereby, the contact portions of the laterally arranged contact pins are displaced respectively to a center line side and a side opposite to the center line side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a contact pin assembly which comprises a plurality of contact pins and a connection member connecting all the contact pins, the manufacturing method comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a plurality of contact pins and contact pin connection portions integrally from a conductive elastic plate member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>arranging and fixing the contact pins by using the connection member with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing thereafter the contact pin connection portions from the respective contact pins. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A contact pin assembling structure for a socket for electrical parts comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of contact pins provided for a socket body of a socket for electrical parts, each of said contact pins comprising a spring function portion having elasticity, a contact portion which is formed to a top end side of the spring function portion and contacts the terminal of the electrical part, a conductive portion extending from the spring function portion on the side opposite to the contact portion, and a connection leg portion further extending from the conductive portion, said conductive portions of the respective contact pins being connected together by said connection member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection member connecting all the contact pins with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones, said predetermined distance being made substantially equal to a distance between adjacent ones of terminals provided for an electrical part which is held in the socket body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a contact pin holding member formed of an insulating resin material, said contact pin holding member holding and fixing together said conductive portion and said spring function portion and together said conductive portion and said connection leg portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a contact pin assembling structure defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said conductive portion and said spring function portion of the contact pin and said conductive portion and said connection leg portion of the contact pin are fixed to the contact pin holding member formed of an insulating resin material and, thereafter, said connection member is removed from the conductive portions of the contact pins. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A socket for electrical parts in which a plurality of terminals provided for an electrical part are electrically connected to an external test circuit means through a plurality of contact pins arranged in accordance with the arrangement of said terminals, wherein a plurality of contact pin assembling structures each having the structure defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> are laminated in numbers corresponding to the number of rows of the terminals of the electrical part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A socket for electrical parts comprising: 
<claim-text>a socket body formed of an insulating resin material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover mounted to the socket body to be opened or closed; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of contact pin assembling structures mounted to the socket body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a floating plate elastically supported by the socket body through a spring, said floating plate having a terminal accommodation portion in which terminals of an electrical part is accommodated, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said plurality of contact pin assembling structures being laminated in numbers corresponding to the number of rows of the terminals of the electrical part, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said contact pin assembling structure comprising: a plurality of contact pins provided for the socket body, each of said contact pins comprising a spring function portion having elasticity, a contact portion which is formed to a top end side of the spring function portion and contacts the terminal of the electrical part, a conductive portion extending from the spring function portion on the side opposite to the contact portion, and a connection leg portion further extending from the conductive portion, said conductive portions of the respective contact pins being connected together by said connection member; a connection member connecting all the contact pins with a predetermined distance between adjacent ones, said predetermined distance being made substantially equal to a distance between adjacent ones of terminals provided for an electrical part which is held in the socket body; and a contact pin holding member formed of an insulating resin material, said contact pin holding member holding and fixing together said conductive portion and said spring function portion and said conductive portion and said connection leg portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003782A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
