<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001761A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001761A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001761</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894523</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H03M007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>341</class>
<subclass>061000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>VARIABLE RATE DECIMATOR</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Xiaoshu</given-name>
<family-name>Qian</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Cupertino</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Nina</given-name>
<family-name>Shu</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Edwin H. Taylor</name-1>
<name-2>Blakely, Sokoloff, Taylor &amp; Zafman LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Seventh Floor</address-1>
<address-2>12400 Wilshire Boulevard</address-2>
<city>Los Angeles</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90025-1030</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A variable rate decimator is described, intended to reduce a digital signal sample rate while maintaining a level of digital signal integrity at a relatively low cost. It is also a goal of the variable rate decimator described herein to provide a scalable decimator architecture while maintaining relatively low complexity of use. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> As digital signal processing technology increases in complexity and cost in applications such as cable modems, designers search for ways in which to reduce system cost while maintaining digital signal processing quality. For example, as Internet users demand more bandwidth, broadband technologies, such as cable modem, and Digital Subscriber Line (DSL) have responded by enabling increased processing rates in data receiving equipment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> However, increasing Internet connection bandwidth is not without a cost. As higher data rates are enabled in Internet equipment, such as cable modem receivers, complexity and cost can rise accordingly. As a result, designers continue to look for ways to cut costs without sacrificing digital signal quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Decimator devices are used in applications, such as cable modem receivers, to reduce the digital signal sampling rate of an input digital signal received from a cable-modem transmitter in order to enable further processing of the digital signal. In so doing, signal quality in decimator devices may be traded for system cost improvements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> However, current decimator device architectures have not enabled signal decimation to be easily scaled in order to achieve cost advantages. Furthermore, decimator devices have not been easily configurable, such that designers could easily adapt and port software between decimator devices. Scalability and adaptability are important when choosing digital signal processing devices, such as a decimator device, in order to enable reuse of software and hardware in subsequent generations of digital signal processing systems, such as cable-modem receivers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In particular, scalable and portable decimator devices are important to cable-modem receiver designers in order to avoid having to rely on numerous decimator device architectures to achieve cost/quality targets among cable-modem designs. Relying on numerous decimator device solutions can result in increased development cost and time to market. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The features and advantages will become apparent from the following detailed description in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a cable modem receiver in accordance with one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a high-level block diagram of a variable rate decimator device according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram of various stages of a variable rate decimator according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a table illustrating filter coefficients, gain, and input/output widths within a variable rate decimator according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic of a half-band filter used in a variable rate decimator according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic of a half-band filter used in a variable rate decimator according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic of a half-band filter used in a variable rate decimator according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a resampler unit used in a variable rate decimator according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates one implementation of a PW quadratic and Zero-crossing circuit of a resampler unit according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>illustrates a half-band filter according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrates overlapping spectral side-bands of a half-band filter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>illustrates a digital signal being filtered by a half-band filter according to one embodiment. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> A variable rate decimator is described, intended to reduce a digital signal sample rate while maintaining a level of digital signal integrity at a relatively low cost. It is also a goal of the variable rate decimator described herein to provide a scalable decimator architecture while maintaining relatively low complexity of use. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">A Cable Modem Receiver </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a cable modem receiver in accordance with one embodiment. The cable modem receiver of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> consists of a tuner <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, which receives a signal from a cable modem transmitter. In one embodiment, the tuner receives a Radio Frequency (RF) signal <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and converts it into an Intermediate Frequency (IF) signal <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> before passing the signal to a digital demodulation device <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> where the signal is digitally processed. In one embodiment, the digital processing includes sampling the IF signal, filtering the signal, then dividing (decimating) the digital signal sample rate in order to enable further digital signal processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Once the signal is processed by the digital demodulation device, the digital signal may be further processed before being passed to subsequent stages within the cable modem system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A Variable Rate Decimator </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a high-level block diagram of a decimator device according to one embodiment. In one embodiment the decimator unit <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> receives a digital signal of a certain sample rate on the data_in input <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> and transmits a decimated digital signal on the data_out output <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The decimator device can decimate the input digital signal according to a decimation value controlled by the user. In one embodiment, the decimation value is controlled by two decimation ratio inputs, ratio<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and ratio<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> that control a first and second stage of the decimator device, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the gain of an input digital signal may be adjusted to offset signal attenuation effects caused by the decimation process. In one embodiment, the gain of an input digital signal is controlled by gain inputs, gain<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and gain<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>, which control the gain of a first and second decimator stage of the decimator device, respectively. In one embodiment, gain<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is controlled as a function of ratio<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, and gain<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is controlled as a function of ratio<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, thereby simplifying the control of the decimator unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram of various stages of a variable rate decimator according to one embodiment. In one embodiment, the decimator unit is divided into two main stages. The first stage <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> consists of one or more decimator units that each divide a sample rate of an input digital signal by a fixed decimation value. The decimator units can be arranged in a suitable topology so as to allow for scalability, low cost, and simplicity of use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the decimator units are arranged in a serial topology. The serial topology allows the decimator units to be of relatively low quality by enabling them to be interconnected in such a manner so as to realize a cumulative product of fixed decimation values that is greater than each fixed decimation value. By using multiple decimator units containing half-band filters of relatively low quality, cost benefits can be realized over using a fewer number of decimator units with higher quality half-band filters. Furthermore, the cumulative product of fixed decimation values may be scaled as further serial fixed-rate decimation units are enabled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> By enabling or disabling the decimation units, a cumulative decimation ratio may be increased or decreased accordingly. For example, in one embodiment, each decimator unit is a divide-by-two decimator unit, which divides a digital signal sample rate by two. Therefore, to achieve a decimation ratio of 1/2 a user would enable D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> while disabling D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B-D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>. Similarly, in order to achieve a cumulative decimation ratio of 1/16, a user would enable D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D while disabling D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E. The desired decimation ratio of 1/16 is realized by multiplying the decimation ratio of each enabled fixed-rate decimator unit (e.g., 1/2*1/2*1/2*1/2&equals;1/16). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments, a desired cumulative decimation ratio may be achieved by enabling a non-adjacent sequence of enabled decimator units. Furthermore, in other embodiments, a desired cumulative decimation ratio may be achieved by enabling decimator units of varying fixed decimation values, thereby affecting the number of decimator units that must be enabled to achieve a particular cumulative fixed decimation value. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The order in which decimator units are enabled to achieve a particular cumulative fixed decimation value is determined by decoder units <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> that intercouple the decimator units. In one embodiment, the decoder units are enabled to receive a control signal <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight> consisting of a number of bits. The number of bits may be determined by the number of decimator units intercoupled in a series topology. The bits may then be decoded so as to enable the appropriate decimator units necessary to achieve a particular cumulative fixed decimation value. For example, in one embodiment, the decoder units decode a control signal consisting of 3 bits that are decoded to enable any of 5 decimator units. The order of enabled decimator units necessary to achieve a particular cumulative fixed decimation value is sequential starting with D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A when the control signal is of value <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>h. Likewise, D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B are enabled when the control signal is <highlight><bold>01</bold></highlight>h, <highlight><bold>02</bold></highlight>h, and so forth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> A digital signal represented by a number of bits may be represented with more or fewer bits as the signal propagates through a serially intercoupled array of decimator units. Using extra bits to represent a digital signal may be necessary to compensate for signal quality loss caused by decimator units. For example, in one embodiment, an input digital signal consisting of 10 bits is propagated from D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E through D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A, all of which are enabled to decimate the signal by a value of 1/2 to achieve a cumulative fixed-rate signal decimation value of 1/32. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> However, imperfections in digital filters used in the decimator units may cause signal integrity, and therefore information contained within the signal, to be compromised as the signal propagates from one fixed-rate decimator unit to the next. It may therefore be necessary to impose extra bits into the digital signal as the digital signal propagates through the decimator units. In one embodiment, one bit is added to the 10-bit input signal after the signal propagates through the D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E fixed-rate decimator unit for a total of 11 bits. More bits may be imposed on the digital signal as it propagates through subsequent enabled decimator units. However, when the signal propagates through the final fixed-rate decimator unit (D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A, in one embodiment), the digital signal is truncated back to the original 10 bits, thereby preserving as much signal integrity as possible while maintaining the original signal width for subsequent filtering and processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In addition to degradation in signal integrity caused by the limitations of digital filters within the decimator units, signal integrity may also be degraded by attenuation effects as the digital signal propagates through multiple decimator units. In order to compensate for signal integrity loss from attenuation, each enabled fixed-rate decimator unit may impose a gain on the signal as it decimates the signal sample rate. In one embodiment, the gain of some of the decimator units is fixed, while the gain of other fixed-rate decimator unit are variable. For example, in one embodiment, the gain of decimator units D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B-D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E is constant whereas the gain of D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A is specified by gain<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). In one embodiment, gain<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> may vary as a function of the cumulative fixed decimation value indicated by ratio<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), thereby adjusting the gain of the digital signal automatically as a function of the amount of decimation experienced by the digital signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a table of possible gain values of fixed-gain decimator units as well as the range of gain values for variable-gain decimator units. In one embodiment, decimator units, D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B, D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>C, and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D impart a gain of 1.5 on a digital signal when enabled, whereas D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E imparts a gain of 1.25. Furthermore, decimator unit, D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A imparts a variable gain within the range of (0:63)/32 when enabled. In other embodiments, the fixed-gain value and the variable-gain range may have different values than described above. In one embodiment, the variable and fixed-gain values depend on the particular signal attenuation effects of the filters used in the decimator units as well as the signal quality needs of the system in which the decimator units are used. In one embodiment, the variable gain value is a function of the decimation value specified by the ratio<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> further illustrates a resampler unit <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> connected to the D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A decimator unit by a decoder unit <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> similar to those intercoupling the decimator units to each other. In one embodiment, the decimation ratio of the resampler block ranges from 1 through 5:2 and is specified by the inputl with 24-bit precision to realize a variable decimation value. When enabled, the resampler unit may further divide a sample rate of a digital signal after it has been divided by the decimator units, thereby creating an effective overall digital signal decimation value that is equal to the arithmetic product of the cumulative product of fixed decimation values and the resampler variable decimation value. For example, to realize an overall decimation value of 23.334, ratio<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> would be configured to enable the last four D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> blacks (D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A through D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D) to achieve a decimation ratio of 16 and configure ratiol to be 1:458375, thereby enabling an overall decimation ratio of 1.458375*16 (23.334). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In order to compensate for signal attenuation caused by the resampler unit, a resampler gain controlled by the gain<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> signal may be imposed on the digital signal by the resampler unit. In one embodiment, gain<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is varied as a function of ratio<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which controls the decimation value of the resampler unit, thereby automatically adjusting the digital signal gain as a function of the decimation experienced by the digital signal from the resampler unit. Furthermore, when a cumulative decimator unit gain is multiplied with the resampler gain, an overall digital signal gain can be realized. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Digital Filters </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Decimation of a digital signal sample rate can be realized by the use of digital signal filters. A digital signal filter can be represented by its impulse response function or transfer function. An impulse response function is a filter&apos;s output function in response to an impulse function, which has a unit value of 1 at sample point <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and has a value of 0 at all other sample points. A transfer function can be defined as the Fourier Transform of the impulse response function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> A digital filter&apos;s response to an impulse function can be represented by a quadratic formula containing a summation of delay functions each weighted by a coefficient. For example, a digital half-band filter&apos;s impulse response as a function of delay function, d(n), can be represented by the quadratic formula, H(d)&equals;h<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>d(n)&plus;h<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&plus;. . . etc., where h<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, h<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and h<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are weighting coefficients for each term of the impulse response function. A half-band filter is characterized by its impulse response shape, in which only half of a filtered signal&apos;s frequency band and its negative mirrored image is captured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In general, a digital filter response quality will be affected by the number of terms realized in its transfer function. For example, a 3-term quadratic formula representation of a half-band filter&mdash;H(d)&equals;h<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&mdash; may produce an impulse response similar to that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> When an input signal is passed through a half-band filter similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>the signal integrity may suffer by capturing neighboring frequency bands within the filter&apos;s bandwidth, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The neighboring frequencies <highlight><bold>1001</bold></highlight> captured in the same filter band as the intended signal <highlight><bold>1005</bold></highlight> can cause aliasing in the digital signal. Aliasing causes the signal quality to be reduced by imposing unwanted spectral noise into the signal. However, by increasing the number of terms in the quadratic formula representing the transfer function of the half-band filter, the filter quality can be improved such that only the intended signal is captured within the filter bandwidth. For example, by using more non-zero terms in the above quadratic formula, a transfer function for a filter can be represented by the function, H(d)&equals;h<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>d(n)&plus;h<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, resulting in a transfer function similar to that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>the intended frequency range of the signal is captured within the filter bandwidth, resulting in improved signal quality for future processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, several half-band filters are used to divide the input signal sample rate by a factor of two. Each half-band filter may be of varying quality in order to optimize filter cost and signal integrity. For example, in one embodiment a variable-rate decimator may contain five fixed-rate divide-by-two decimator units connected together in a series configuration, such that an input signal passes through each before being resampled by a resampler unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Decimator units D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E in the series of decimator units may contain a digital half-band filter as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The half-band filter of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is represented by a 3-term quadratic formula, which is realized by a digital half-band filter circuit. Decimator unit D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>C may contain a half-band filter illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The half-band filter of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is represented by a 5-term quadratic formula, which is realized by a digital half-band filter circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Decimator units D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B may contain a half-band filter illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The half-band filter of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is represented by a 7-term quadratic formula, which is realized by a digital half-band filter circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> By varying the number of terms used in the quadratic formulas representing each digital half-band filter, filter quality can be modified to optimize cost while realizing a desired signal integrity, as previously discussed. The values of the coefficients used in the quadratic formulas representing each half-band filter may vary and are determined by the desired filter quality and digital output-signal characteristics. The coefficients used in one embodiment are summarized in the table shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In one embodiment, half-band filters used in the decimator units are of a progressively increasing quality due to the progressively increasing number of terms realized in the half-band filters used within the decimator units. For example, decimator units D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E may be represented by quadratic formulas containing three terms. Decimator unit D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>C may be represented by a quadratic formula containing five terms. Decimator units D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A may be represented by a quadratic formula containing seven terms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In each of the digital filters illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5, 6</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, every other filter &ldquo;tap&rdquo; is enabled by using a non-zero coefficient in the corresponding quadratic equation terms. By using non-zero decimator filter coefficients in every other quadratic formula term, fewer circuit elements may be used to realize the corresponding digital filter, resulting in lower filter cost. However, lower filter quality also results by implementing only every other filter tap relative to a filter that implements non-zero coefficients in every term of a corresponding quadratic formula. For example, although cheaper to implement, the quadratic formula, H(d)&equals;h<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, would produce a lower quality impulse response than a filter that implemented the quadratic formula, H(d)&equals;h<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>d(n)&plus;h<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&plus;h<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>d(n)<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> . However, by implementing half-band filters of relatively low quality while enabling decimator units to be coupled in series, signal quality can be maintained while enabling lower filter cost. Decimator units, D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A, D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>B, D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>C, D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D, and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>E may contain digital half-band filters with coefficients shown, but other coefficients may also be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Half-band filter cost is further reduced by virtue of filter symmetry. Symmetric filters are those that have the same filter response characteristics about a base frequency. In one embodiment, the half-band filter response is symmetric about a base frequency equal to the sample frequency (rate) of the digital signal to be filtered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, a digital signal passed through the fixed-rate divide-by-two decimator units described above may experience a digital signal sample rate reduction by a divisor of 1, 2, 4, 8, 16, or 32, depending on the number of decimator units that have been enabled by a 3-bit input control signal. In order to more precisely decimate a a digital signal, a variable-rate resampler unit may be connected in series with the decimator units as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the decimation ratio of the resampler unit ranges from 1 through 5:2 and is specified by input ratio<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> with 24-bit precision. The gain of the resampler unit is specified by input gain<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which in one embodiment, is controlled automatically by the decimation value specified by ratio<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Therefore, to achieve an overall decimation value of 23.334, for example, ratio<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> would be used to enable the last four decimator units (D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A through D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D) to achieve a decimation ratio of 16 and ratio<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> would be used to specify a resampler unit decimation ratio of 1:458375. An overall ratio of 23.334 is achieved by multiplying the decimation ratios of the cumulative fixed-rate decimator value and the variable-rate decimator value (16*1.458375). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the variable-rate resampler unit contains a digital filter blocks shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The PW Quadratic and Zero-crossing blocks may be realized, in one embodiment, by the digital filter circuits illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. Other filter circuits may be used to realize the resampler unit in other embodiments depending on factors, such as cost, decimation capabilities, and desired signal quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> While this invention has been described with reference to illustrative embodiments, this description is not intended to be construed in a limiting sense. Various modifications of the illustrative embodiments, as well as other embodiments , which are apparent to persons skilled in the art to which the invention pertains are deemed to lie within the spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Appendix A </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> William E. Alford, Reg. No. 37,764; Farzad E. Amini, Reg. No. 42,261; William Thomas Babbitt, Reg. No. 39,591; Carol F. Barry, Reg. No. 41,600; Jordan Michael Becker, Reg. No. 39,602; Lisa N. Benado, Reg. No. 39,995; Bradley J. Bereznak, Reg. No. 33,474; Michael A. Bernadicou, Reg. No. 35,934; Roger W. Blakely, Jr., Reg. No. 25,831; R. Alan Burnett, Reg. No. 46,149; Gregory D. Caldwell, Reg. No. 39,926; Thomas M. Coester, Reg. No. 39,637; Donna Jo Coningsby, Reg. No. 41,684; Florin Corie, Reg No. 46,244, Mimi Diemmy Dao, Reg. No. 45,628; Dennis M. deGuzman, Reg. No. 41,702; Stephen M. De Kierk, Reg. No. 46,503; Michael Anthony DeSanctis, Reg. No. 39,957; Daniel M. De Vos, Reg. No. 37,813; Justin M. Dillon, Reg. No. 42,486; Sanjeet Dutta, Reg. No. 46,145; Matthew C. Fagan, Reg. No. 37,542; Tarek N. Fahmi, Reg. No. 41,402; Thomas S. Ferrill, Reg. No. 42,532; George Fountain, Reg. No. 37,374; James Y. Go, Reg. No. 40,621; James A. Henry, Reg. No. 41,064; Libby N. Ho, Reg. No. 46,774; Willmore F. Holbrow III, Reg. No. 41,845; Sheryl Sue Holloway, Reg. No. 37,850; George W Hoover II, Reg. No. 32,992; Eric S. Hyman, Reg. No. 30,139; William W. Kidd, Reg. No. 31,772; Sang Hui Kim, Reg. No. 40,450; Walter T. Kim, Reg. No. 42,731; Eric T. King, Reg. No. 44,188; George Brian Leavell, Reg. No. 45,436; Kurt P. Leyendecker, Reg. No. 42,799; Gordon R. Lindeen III, Reg. No. 33,192; Jan Carol Little, Reg. No. 41,181; Robert G. Litts, Reg. No. 46,876; Julio Loza, Reg. No. P47,758; Joseph Lutz, Reg. No. 43,765; Michael J. Mallie, Reg. No. 36,591; Andre L. Marais, Reg. No. P048,095; Paul A. Mendonsa, Reg. No. 42,879; Clive D. Menezes, Reg. No. 45,493; Chun M. Ng, Reg. No. 36,878; Thien T. Nguyen, Reg. No. 43,835; Thinh V. Nguyen, Reg. No. 42,034; Robert B. O&apos;Rourke, Reg. No. 46,972; Daniel E. Ovanezian, Reg No. 41,236; Kenneth B. Paley, Reg. No. 38,989; Gregg A. Peacock, Reg. No. 45,001; Marina Portnova, Reg. No. 45,750; William F. Ryann, Reg. 44,313; James H. Salter, Reg. No. 35,668; William W. Schaal, Reg. No. 39,018; James C. Scheller, Reg. No. 31,195; Jeffrey S. Schubert, Reg. No. 43,098; George Simion, Reg. No. P47,089; Maria McCormack Sobrino, Reg. No. 31,639; Stanley W. Sokoloff, Reg. No. 25,128; Judith A. Szepesi, Reg. No. 39,393; Edwin H. Taylor, Reg. No. 25,129; John F. Travis, Reg. No. 43,203; Joseph A. Twarowski, Reg. No. 42,191; Mark C. Van Ness, Reg. No. 39,865; Tom Van Zandt, Reg. No. 43,219; Brent E. Vecchia, Reg. No. P48,011; Lester J. Vincent, Reg. No. 31,460; Archana B. Vittal, Reg. No. 45,182; Glenn E. Von Tersch, Reg. No. 41,364; John Patrick Ward, Reg. No. 40,216; Mark L. Watson, Reg. No. 46,322; Thomas C. Webster, Reg. No. 46,154; and Norman Zafman, Reg. No. 26,250; my patent attorneys, and Firasat Ali, Reg. No. 45,715; and Raul Martinez, Reg. No. 46,904, my patent agents, of BLAKELY, SOKOLOFF, TAYLOR &amp; ZAFMAN LLP, with offices located at 12400 Wilshire Boulevard, 7th Floor, Los Angeles, Calif. 90025, telephone (310) 207-3800, and Alan K. Aldous, Reg. No. 31,905; Ben Burge, Reg. No. 42,372; Richard C. Calderwood, Reg. No. 35,468; Paul W. Churilla, Reg. No. P47,495; Jeffrey S. Draeger, Reg. No. 41,000; Cynthia Thomas Faatz, Reg No. 39,973; John N. Greaves, Reg. No. 40,362; Seth Z. Kalson, Reg. No. 40,670; David J. Kaplan, Reg. No. 41,105; John Kacvinsky, Reg. No. 40,040; Peter Lam, Reg. No. 44,855; Charles A. Mirho, Reg. No. 41,199; Paul Nagy, Reg. No. 37,896; Leo V. Novakoski, Reg. No. 37,198; Thomas C. Reynolds, Reg. No. 32,488; Kenneth M. Seddon, Reg. No. 43,105; Mark Seeley, Reg. No. 32,299; Steven P. Skabrat, Reg. No. 36,279; Howard A. Skaist, Reg. No. 36,008; Steven C. Stewart, Reg. No. 33,555; Gene I. Su, Reg. No. 45,140; Calvin E. Wells, Reg. No. P43,256, Raymond J. Werner, Reg. No. 34,752; Robert G. Winkle, Reg. No. 37,474; Sharon Wong, Reg. No. 37,760; Steven D. Yates, Reg. No. 42,242; and Charles K. Young, Reg. No. 39,435; my patent attorneys, and Michael J. Nesheiwat, Reg. No. P47,819, my patent agent of INTEL CORPORATION; and James R. Thein, Reg. No. 31,710, my patent attorney with full power of substitution and revocation, to prosecute this application and to transact all business in the Patent and Trademark Office connected herewith. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Appendix B </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Title 37, Code of Federal Regulations, Section 1.56 Duty to Disclose Information Material to Patentability </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> (a) A patent by its very nature is affected with a public interest. The public interest is best served, and the most effective patent examination occurs when, at the time an application is being examined, the Office is aware of and evaluates the teachings of all information material to patentability. Each individual associated with the filing and prosecution of a patent application has a duty of candor and good faith in dealing with the Office, which includes a duty to disclose to the Office all information known to that individual to be material to patentability as defined in this section. The duty to disclose information exists with respect to each pending claim until the claim is cancelled or withdrawn from consideration, or the application becomes abandoned. Information material to the patentability of a claim that is cancelled or withdrawn from consideration need not be submitted if the information is not material to the patentability of any claim remaining under consideration in the application. There is no duty to submit information which is not material to the patentability of any existing claim. The duty to disclose all information known to be material to patentability is deemed to be satisfied if all information known to be material to patentability of any claim issued in a patent was cited by the Office or submitted to the Office in the manner prescribed by &sect;&sect;1.97(b)-(d) and 1.98. However, no patent will be granted on an application in connection with which fraud on the Office was practiced or attempted or the duty of disclosure was violated through bad faith or intentional misconduct. The Office encourages applicants to carefully examine: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> (1) Prior art cited in search reports of a foreign patent office in a counterpart application, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> (2) The closest information over which individuals associated with the filing or prosecution of a patent application believe any pending claim patentably defines, to make sure that any material information contained therein is disclosed to the Office. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> (b) Under this section, information is material to patentability when it is not cumulative to information already of record or being made of record in the application, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> (1) It establishes, by itself or in combination with other information, a prima facie case of unpatentability of a claim; or </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> (2) It refutes, or is inconsistent with, a position the applicant takes in: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="4"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> (i) Opposing an argument of unpatentability relied on by the Office, or </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="4"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> (ii) Asserting an argument of patentability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="5"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> A prima facie case of unpatentability is established when the information compels a conclusion that a claim is unpatentable under the preponderance of evidence, burden-of-proof standard, giving each term in the claim its broadest reasonable construction consistent with the specification, and before any consideration is given to evidence which may be submitted in an attempt to establish a contrary conclusion of patentability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> (c) Individuals associated with the filing or prosecution of a patent application within the meaning of this section are. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> (1) Each inventor named in the application; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> (2) Each attorney or agent who prepares or prosecutes the application; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> (3) Every other person who is substantively involved in the preparation or prosecution of the application and who is associated with the inventor, with the assignee or with anyone to whom there is an obligation to assign the application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> (d) Individuals other than the attorney, agent or inventor may comply with this section by disclosing information to the attorney, agent, or inventor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> (e) In any continuation-in-part application, the duty under this section includes the duty to disclose to the Office all information known to the person to be material to patentability, as defined in paragraph (b) of this section, which became available between the filing date of the prior application and the national or PCT international filing date of the continuation-in-part application. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a series of decimator units, said series of decimator units comprising a plurality of half-band filters of progressively increasing quality, said series of decimator units being enabled to divide a signal sample rate according to a plurality of fixed decimation values and produce a plurality of decimator gains, at least one of said plurality of decimator gains being a cumulative product of said plurality of fixed decimation values. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising at least one resampler unit, said at least one resampler unit being coupled to at least one of said series of decimator units, said at least one resampler unit being enabled to divide a signal sample rate according to a variable decimation value, said at least one resampler unit being enabled to produce a resampler gain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said resampler gain is a function of said variable decimation value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a plurality of decoder units, said plurality of decoder units being coupled to said series of decimator units, at least one of said plurality of decoder units being further coupled to said at least one resampler unit, said plurality of decoder units being enabled to decode at least one control signal, said at least one control signal being decoded to enable at least one of said series of decimator units or said at least one resampler unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said cumulative product is proportional to an enabled number of said series of decimator units. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein an overall signal gain is realized by multiplying said decimator gain and said resampler gain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein an overall signal decimation value is realized by multiplying said cumulative product of said plurality of fixed decimation values and said resampler decimation value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said signal sample rate may be further divided by coupling additional decimator units to said series of decimator units. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one half-band filter is symmetric and every other filter tap is zero. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>receiving a signal, said signal having an input signal sample rate and an input signal gain; </claim-text>
<claim-text>dividing said input signal sample rate by a first decimation ratio, said </claim-text>
<claim-text>dividing said input signal sample rate by said first decimation ratio resulting in an intermediate signal sample rate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>filtering said signal, said filtering resulting from propogating said signal through at least one of a series of filtering steps of progressively increasing quality; dividing said intermediate signal sample rate by a second decimation ratio, said second decimation ratio having a greater range than said first decimation ratio, said dividing said intermediate signal sample rate by said second decimation ratio resulting in an output signal sample rate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first decimation ratio is proportional to an enabled number of a series of decimator units. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said enabled number of said series of decimator units is determined by a first decimation control signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said second decimation ratio is determined by a second decimation control signal, said second decimation control signal enabling at least one resampler unit to divide said intermediate signal sample rate by said second decimation ratio. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising compensating for attenuation to said input signal gain, said attenuation resulting, at least in part, from said input signal propagating through said series of decimator units and said at least one resampler unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said compensating comprises adjusting said input signal gain as a function of said first decimation ratio, adjusting said input signal gain resulting in an intermediate signal gain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said compensating further comprises adjusting said intermediate signal gain as a function of said second decimation ratio, adjusting said intermediate signal gain resulting in an output signal gain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first decimation ratio is proportional to an enabled number of said series of decimator units, said enabled number of said series of decimator units each being enabled to divide said input signal sample rate by a fixed value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one of a plurality of relatively low-quality filtering steps comprises propogating said signal through at least one half-band filter, said at least one half-band filter being symmetric and having every other filter tap be zero. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A system comprising: 
<claim-text>a tuner; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a microprocessor, said microprocessor being coupled to said tuner; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a digital demodulation device, said digital demodulation device being coupled to said microprocessor, said digital demodulation device comprising a variable-rate decimator, said variable-rate decimator comprising a series of decimator units, said series of decimator units comprising a plurality of half-band filters of progressively increasing quality. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said variable-rate decimator further comprises a resampler unit, said resampler unit being coupled to at least one of said series of decimator units. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said series of decimator units are enabled to divide a signal sample rate according to a plurality of fixed decimation values and produce a plurality of decimator gains, at least one of said plurality of decimator gains being a function of a cumulative product of said plurality of fixed decimation values. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one resampler unit is enabled to divide a signal sample rate according to a variable decimation value, said at least one resampler unit being enabled to produce a resampler gain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said cumulative product is proportional to an enabled number of said series of decimator units. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein an overall signal gain is realized by multiplying said decimator gain and said resampler gain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein an overall signal decimation value is realized by multiplying said cumulative product of said plurality of fixed decimation values and said resampler decimation value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said signal sample rate may be further divided by coupling additional decimator units to said series of decimator units.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001761A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
