<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003790A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003790A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003790A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003790A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003790A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003790A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003790A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003790A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003790A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003790A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003790A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003790A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003790A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003790A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003790</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10160303</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020529</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01R011/22</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>439</class>
<subclass>266000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>ZIF Socket and actuator for DIP</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301518</doc-number>
<document-date>20010627</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<family-name>Cuevas</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Los Gatos</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>QualiTau, Inc.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TOWNSEND AND TOWNSEND AND CREW, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>TWO EMBARCADERO CENTER</address-1>
<address-2>EIGHTH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>SAN FRANCISCO</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94111-3834</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A socket for use in testing packaged integrated circuits having leads depending therefrom includes a first member for receiving the integrated package and having a plurality of first holes for receiving leads extending from the package. A second member has a plurality of wires for engaging the leads, each wire being anchored at ends to the second member with an intermediate portion engaging a lead. Each intermediate portion is aligned with a first hole and capable of being flexed out of alignment with the first hole for insertion of an integrated circuit package into the socket. The first member includes a second plurality of holes aligned with the wires of the second member, and an actuator has a plurality of pins arranged to extend into the second plurality of holes for engaging the plurality of wires and flexing the intermediate portions of the wires out of alignment with the first plurality of holes. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This patent application claims the benefit of copending Provisional Application 60/301,518, filed Jun. 27, 2001, for HIGH TEMPERATURE MINIMAL (ZERO) INSERTION FORCE SOCKET WITH AN EXTERNAL ACTUATOR, and is related to U.S. Pat. No. 6,179,640 for HIGH TEMPERATURE MINIMAL (ZERO) INSERTION FORCE SOCKET assigned to the present assignee, which are incorporated herein by reference for all purposes.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to the testing of electrical integrated circuits, and more particularly the invention relates to sockets for receiving packaged integrated circuits for test purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The packaged integrated circuit typically includes a polymer or ceramic housing for a semiconductor chip with electrical leads extending from the package which are electrically connected to the semiconductor chip. In a dual in-line package (DIP), the electrical leads are arranged in two parallel rows with the leads depending from the bottom of the housing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Packaged integrated circuits must undergo a number of different tests, each test requiring the insertion of the integrated circuit package and leads into a test socket. To prevent bending or damage to the leads, zero insertion force (ZIF) sockets have been devised to limit the force exerted on the leads when the package is inserted into a test socket. The most widely known and used ZIF sockets are from 3M Corporation and Aries Corporation. In these sockets the leads of a DIP (dual in-line package) are pinched between two pieces of metal which are, in turn, soldered to a printed circuit board. The metal pieces are held in place by the body of the ZIF socket which is typically made of plastic. The metal pieces are electrically conducting to provide a good electrical path from the DIP lead to the printed circuit board in which the ZIF socket is attached. In all cases, the bodies of these sockets are made of some organic material (plastics or polymers) which can only withstand temperatures as high as 250&deg; C. for extended periods of time. The metal used to pinch the leads of the IC DIP packages are beryllium copper alloy or beryllium nickel alloy for a high temperature operation not to exceed 250&deg; C. While these sockets perform well within their stated specifications, they cannot be used at temperatures in excess of 250&deg; C. because the materials will decompose and fail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top view of the &apos;640 patent socket in an empty position. The socket <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> includes a bottom plate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and a top plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (shown by outline) with the lower plate including two arrays of parallel wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which are respectively anchored to bottom plate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in holes at anchor points <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and anchor points <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Top plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes two rows of holes <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> for receiving pins of a dual inline pin (DIP) package. A yieldable metal spring <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> maintains top plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> positioned on bottom plate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> centrally disposed over holes <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The bottom plate has elongated slots (not shown) through which package pins extend. In this socket design, the bottom plate is fixed, while the top plate is made laterally translatable with respect to the bottom plate by means of a cam drive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the socket in an actuated position with the top plate moved laterally to the right against spring <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> with holes <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> moved from wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In this position the Unit Under Test (UUT) pins can be placed in the holes or withdrawn from the holes without the wires obstructing the pins. Once pins are inserted in the holes, and the actuating force is removed, spring <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> will then push the top plate to the left whereby the pins engage wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A, 3B</cross-reference> show UUT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> positioned in the socket with pins <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> engaging wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> UUT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is removed to expose the underlying interaction between the pins <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to such a ZIF socket, but in which the top and bottom plates are fixed and a wire actuator is employed for inserting and removing a UUT. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the invention, a ZIF socket has top and bottom plates which are attached in a unitary structure, and an external wire actuator is employed for inserting and removing a UUT. The top plate has first and second rows of holes for receiving UUT pins with the holes aligned with the contact wires. Larger third and fourth rows of holes are provided for receiving pins of the actuator which engage and laterally flex the wires for inserting and removing a UUT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the actuator comprises a rectangular-shaped body with an open central portion through which a UUT package can pass. The body has two rows of pins depending therefrom for insertion into the third and fourth rows of holes in the socket and engaging the wire contacts. Each pin of the actuator preferably has a tapered point for facilitating the engagement with a wire contact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the actuator comprises a frame with depending pins which are received in the third and fourth rows of holes. The frame is laterally translatable by means of a screw or lever, for example, whereby the depending pins can engage and flex the wires for inserting and removing a UUT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> By using a wire actuator in accordance with the invention, the ZIF socket has a simplified design and can be more economically manufactured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The invention and objects and features thereof will be more readily apparent from the following detailed description and appended claims when taken with the drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> are plan views of a ZIF socket in accordance with the prior art in an empty position and in an actuated position, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A, 3B</cross-reference> illustrate the ZIF socket of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> with a unit under test inserted therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a plan view of a ZIF package in accordance with one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A, 5B</cross-reference> are a top view and side view of a wire actuator for use with the socket of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> in accordance with one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6, 7</cross-reference> illustrate the socket of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> with the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> inserted therein for the insertion of a UUT, and with the actuator removed and wire contacts engaging pins of the UUT, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a plan view of a frame actuator in accordance with another embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A, 9B</cross-reference> are a plan view and a side view of the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> after forming the wire-actuating pins and the actuating screw plate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10, 11</cross-reference> illustrate a ZIF socket with the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8, 9</cross-reference> before and after wire actuation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a plan view of a frame actuator in accordance with another embodiment of the invention prior to forming of the actuating pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13A, 13B</cross-reference> are a plan view and side view of the frame actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> after forming of the wire actuating pins and lever plate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12, 13</cross-reference> with an actuating lever. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15A, 15B</cross-reference> are plan views of the actuator of FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> prior to wire actuation and after wire actuation, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a plan view of another embodiment of a wire actuator for use with a plurality of ZIF packages in accordance with an embodiment of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Like elements in the several views have the same reference numerals. </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a plan view of a ZIF socket in accordance with one embodiment of the invention. Again, a bottom plate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> supports contact wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and top plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has contact holes <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> for receiving pins of a UUT. In accordance with this embodiment, top plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> further includes two rows of holes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> with each of the holes being larger than the contact holes <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the contact wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> between top plate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and bottom plate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are slightly offset from the center of holes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for receiving an actuating mechanism, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Since there is no need for the top plate to move laterally with respect to the bottom plate, the two plates can be joined together for comprising a unitary structure, and the cam actuation mechanism in accordance with the prior art is eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A, 5B</cross-reference> are a plan view and side view, respectively, of an actuator for use with the socket of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The actuator comprises a body <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> having a central opening through which a UUT <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> (shown by dotted lines) can be inserted. Body <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of pins <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> which mate with holes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the socket of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Preferably, the tips of pins <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> are tapered to a point to facilitate insertion in holes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and engagement with wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view illustrating the socket of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> with pins <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> inserted in holes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> which deflect wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> away from holes <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> thereby allowing the insertion of a UUT or removal of a UUT from the socket. To facilitate the illustration of the deflecting wires, body portion <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the actuator is not shown. As seen, the actuator pins effectively push the center portion of the wires enough to the left so that the wires are no longer over the holes <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> for the UUT pins. The wires are consistently forced to move to the left rather than to the right as long as there is some sufficient actuator offset of the wires over holes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The magnitude of the wire movement as effected by the actuator pins is a function of both the actuator offset and the diameter of the actuator pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a plan view showing the ZIF socket with the wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> engaging pins <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of a UUT. This position is attained when the actuator is removed while the UUT is mated to the ZIF socket. Again, the body of the UUT is removed from view to expose the underlying interaction between the UUT pins <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the ZIF socket wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a plan view of a frame for an actuator in accordance with another embodiment of the invention. The frame <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> cut from a thin sheet of stainless steel, for example, includes a plurality of unbent pins <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and an unbent screw plate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> for an actuating screw. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A, 9B</cross-reference> are a plan view and a side view, respectively, of the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> after the screwplate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and pins <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> have been bent 90 degrees, and an actuating screw <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is placed in a tapped hole in screwplate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the ends of the pins <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are blunt and this eliminates the sharper pins in the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Further, since the actuator is cut from a thin sheet of stainless steel, which can be placed over the top plate of the socket, the actuator presents less of an obstruction for the placement or removal of the UUT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</cross-reference> illustrate application of the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> on the ZIF socket of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. It would be noted that the actuator pins are sized small enough to slip into the large holes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the socket without being impeded by contact wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Hence, the placement of the actuator is itself a zero insertion force (ZIF) event. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, screw <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> engages the socket and forces the actuator pins against wires <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> thereby clearing contact holes <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> for receipt of the UUT pins. Once a UUT is placed in the socket, the actuating screw is unscrewed to its original position and the actuator is removed from the ZIF socket. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a plan view of another frame actuator which is similar to the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> and has the same reference numerals. However, in this embodiment plate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is placed inside of body <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> for closer placement to the ZIF socket, as illustrated in the plan view and side view of the actuator in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13A and 13B</cross-reference> after bending of pins <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and plate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the actuator of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> with a cooperating lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> which is positioned between plate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the ZIF socket (not shown). In this view, actuator pins <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are not shown for simplification of the drawing. Lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is shown in its position prior to actuation motion with the arrow indicating the rotational path of lever arm <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to arrive at an actuated position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15A, 15B</cross-reference> are plan views of actuator <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> on a ZIF socket illustrating lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> prior to actuation and after actuation, respectively. The actuator is identical in function to the actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10, 11</cross-reference> except lever <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> effects the motion of the actuator rather than a screw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of the ZIF socket and actuator in accordance with the invention lies in the use of one actuator for a plurality of sockets, as illustrated in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. Here the actuator is similar to the lever actuator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> with a single actuator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> functioning with a plurality of sockets <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. In the area of reliability testing where statistics play a major role, several hundreds of UUTs may be tested at the same time, usually having an array of sockets mounted on a UUT board and using many such boards. In this situation, instead of having a multiplicity of complex and expensive ZIF sockets, the socket and actuator in accordance with the invention allows for the implementation of a much more cost effective alternative. Each person responsible for loading and unloading UUTs would need the use of only one or a small number of external actuators, thereby reducing the cost of the ZIF sockets and actuators and facilitating the use thereof by operators. While <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> illustrates the lever mechanism <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> actuating two sockets at the same time, it will be appreciated that a larger number of sockets could be actuated by a single lever. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The ZIF socket and actuator in accordance with the present invention simplifies the design of the socket, reduces cost, and facilitates use thereof by human operators in testing integrated circuit packages. While the invention has been described with reference to specific embodiments, the description is illustrative of the invention and is not to be construed as limiting the invention. Various modifications and applications may occur to those skilled in the art without departing from the true spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A socket and actuator for use in testing a packaged integrated circuit having a plurality of leads extending therefrom, said socket comprising: 
<claim-text>a) a first member for receiving an integrated circuit package and having a first plurality of holes for receiving leads extending from the package, </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a second member having a plurality of wires for engaging leads extending through the first plurality of holes of the first member, each wire being anchored at ends to the second member with an intermediate portion engaging a lead, each intermediate portion being aligned with a hole and capable of being flexed out of alignment with the hole for insertion of an integrated circuit package into the socket, </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) the first member including a second plurality of holes aligned with the wires of the second member, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) an actuator having a plurality of pins arranged to extend into the second plurality of holes for engaging the plurality of wires and flexing the intermediate portions of the wires out of alignment with the first plurality of holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the actuator comprises a body having a central opening for the passage of an integrated circuit package and a plurality of pins having tapered ends for insertion into the second plurality of holes and engaging the plurality of wires. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the actuator comprises a body having a central opening for passage of an integrated circuit package and a plurality of pins for insertion into the second plurality of holes, the body being laterally translated whereby the plurality of pins engage the plurality of wires. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the actuator further includes means for translating the body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the means for translating the body includes a plate depending from the body and a screw extending through the plate for engaging the second member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the means for translating the body includes a lever positioned between the body and the second member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the body includes a depending plate which is engaged by the lever. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the body is formed from a metal plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first member and the second member are fastened together as a unitary structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the packaged integrated circuit comprises a DIP package and the package requires minimal insertion force. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The socket and actuator as defined by <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the actuator is shared with other sockets.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003790A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003790A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003790A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003790A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003790A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003790A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003790A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
