<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002775A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002775A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002775A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002775A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002775A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002775A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002775A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002775A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002775A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002775A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002775A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002775A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002775A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002775A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002775</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09881330</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010613</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B006/35</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>016000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>110000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Multistage photonic switch fault isolation</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ken</given-name>
<middle-name>N.</middle-name>
<family-name>Cook</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dale</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Schroeder</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Scotts Valley</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>AGILENT TECHNOLOGIES, INC.</name-1>
<name-2>Legal Department, DL429</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Intellectual Property Administration</address-1>
<address-2>P.O. Box 7599</address-2>
<city>Loveland</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80537-0599</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention is a method for isolating faults in multi-stage photonic switch networks. Photonic switches in a photonic switch network are first verified individually, using self-test paths built into the photonic switch. Then, interconnecting optical fibers of the photonic switch network are checked. Each photonic switch is equipped with a transmitter and detector. During test, a photonic switch uses its transmitter to transmit light through an optical fiber interconnection to a second photonic switch. Pre-existing pathways within the photonic switches are used to access and route the light. When the second photonic switch detects the transmitted light, the optical fiber interconnection passes the continuity test. When the light cannot be detected, the optical fiber interconnection has a fault that must be repaired. By repeating this process for all optical fiber interconnections between all photonic switches, the photonic switch network can be checked for faults. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to photonic switches, and more particularly to a method for isolating faults in interconnections between photonic switches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Optical fibers are increasingly prevalent in the transmission lines of data networks, due to their higher bandwidth capabilities compared to wire transmission lines. Before the photonic switch was invented, light signals switching from one optical fiber to another first were converted to and from electrical impulses using optical-to-electrical-to-optical equipment. The conversion process was time-consuming and slowed the speed of data traveling in the network. The photonic switch provided a way to keep the data network completely optical and thus speed up data transfer rates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Many photonic switches are designed to be modular, so that several photonic switches can be connected together using optical fibers to create one larger photonic switch, hereinafter called a photonic switch network. The modularity of the photonic switches gives the customer the flexibility to make a photonic switch network as large or small as desired. The optical fibers in a photonic switch network have to be tested for continuity and proper operation. Typically, an optical fiber is tested by transmitting light through one end of the optical fiber, and checking for the light at the other end with a detector. When the light is detected, the optical fiber is working correctly. When no light is detected, a break in continuity&mdash;also known as a fault&mdash;exists within the optical fiber, and the optical fiber must either be fixed or replaced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In the past, testing the continuity of the interconnecting optical fibers in a photonic switch network was not a simple matter. The optical fibers are connected directly from the data output of one switch to the data input of another, making it difficult to access any of the test light signals. One prior art solution was to use an optical fiber with a light-dividing device, such as a tap or splitter, for each interconnection between photonic switches. A tap or splitter is an optical device that splits the original signal into two or more signals. These split-off signals may or may not differ from each other in signal strength, but are identical in data content. One of the split signals would lead to the normal data path, maintaining the data connection; another signal can be drawn off into a test system. There are drawbacks to this method. First, an optical fiber with a light-dividing device is more expensive than a plain optical fiber. When there are thousands of interconnections to be tested, the additional cost of the light-dividing devices can be quite high. Secondly, the light-dividing device itself can introduce faults into the photonic switch network. This makes it difficult to determine whether a fault lies in an optical fiber, or the associated light-dividing device. Finally, the power of each split-off signal is less than the original, which can cause problems during testing. If the split-off test signal from an optical fiber is too weak, the detector will be unable to detect it, and would instead indicate a fault in that particular optical fiber where none exists. This mistake can cause a flawless optical fiber to be needlessly replaced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, there remains a need for an improved method for testing interconnecting optical fibers in a photonic switch network. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a simple and reliable method for isolating faults in interconnections between photonic switches. The photonic switches are first verified individually, using self-test paths built into every photonic switch. Once each individual photonic switch has been verified, the interconnecting optical fibers of the photonic switch network are checked. Each photonic switch is equipped with a transceiver consisting of a transmitter and a receiver. During test, a photonic switch uses its transmitter to transmit light through an optical fiber interconnection to a second photonic switch. Pre-existing pathways within the photonic switches are used to access and route the test light signals, thus eliminating the need for light-dividing devices altogether. When the second photonic switch detects the transmitted light with its receiver, the optical fiber interconnection passes the continuity test. When the second photonic switch cannot detect the light, the optical fiber interconnection has a fault that must be repaired. By repeating this process for all optical fiber interconnections between all photonic switches, the photonic switch network can be tested for proper operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Further features of the present invention, as well as the structure and operation of preferred embodiments of the present invention, are described in detail below with reference to the accompanying exemplary drawings. In the drawings, like reference numbers indicate identical or functionally similar elements. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a flowchart of the method used to isolate faults in a photonic switch network, made in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. A fault is defined as any problem that would prevent a signal from been routed correctly through the photonic switch network, such as a discontinuity within the waveguide, or an improperly functioning switch point. In step <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the individual photonic switches in the photonic switch network are verified to ensure there are no faults within. This verification is performed using self-test mechanisms built into every photonic switch. In step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, a test signal is transmitted from the first switch. The test signal may be, but is not limited to being, infrared light. Infrared light is defined as the region of the electromagnetic spectrum having wavelengths between 0.7 micrometer and 1 millimeter, inclusive. In step <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the test signal is routed through a redundant path of the first switch. The redundant path is a bypass path through the photonic switch in case one of the other paths should fail. In step <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, the test signal is routed through an optical fiber connecting the first photonic switch to a second photonic switch. In step <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, the test signal is routed through a redundant path of the second photonic switch. Finally, in step <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, a detector at the second photonic switch checks for the test signal. If the test signal is detected, then there are no faults in the optical fiber. Otherwise, a fault exists and the optical fiber must be fixed or replaced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an example of a prior art photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, as described by U.S. Pat. No. 6,160,928 to Schroeder and U.S. Pat. No. 6,198,856 to Schroeder et al., both assigned to Agilent Technologies. The photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a waveguide array <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a built-in transmitter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and a built-in detector <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The waveguide array <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> has horizontal waveguides A, B, C, D, E, (also designated as inputs <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) and vertical waveguides <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> (also designated as outputs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>). At the intersection of each waveguide is a switch point, as exemplified by reference number <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Each switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is uniquely identified in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> by the combined reference numbers of its intersecting waveguides. For example, the switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> at the intersection of horizontal waveguide A and vertical waveguide <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is uniquely identified by the coordinate A<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> can either be inactive or active, at any given point in time. When the switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is inactive, a signal in a waveguide that intersects the switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> passes straight through, unchanged. When the switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is active, the signal in the waveguide passing through the switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is deflected to an intersecting waveguide. For example, if switch point B<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is inactive, an incoming signal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> passing through switch point B<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> will continue straight through as signal <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. If switch point B<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is active, an incoming signal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> will be deflected as signal <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the same photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Within the waveguide array <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a few waveguides are reserved for performing special functions. A test path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, comprising a vertical and horizontal waveguide, is designated for performing self-tests on the photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In this example, the test path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> consists of waveguide <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and waveguide E. It is optically connected to the built-in transmitter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and to the built-in detector <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The signal emitted by the built-in transmitter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is intended for transmission of optical data, such as infrared light. Another set of waveguides&mdash;waveguide D and waveguide <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in this example&mdash;form a redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is unused under normal circumstances. It is used as a backup path in case one of the other waveguides or switch points malfunction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The test path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is used to find faults within the waveguide array <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. By selectively activating switch points along test path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the waveguide array <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be tested for faults. For example, to verify the functionality of switch point C<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the switch points C<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and E<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> on test path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, along with switch point C<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> itself, should be activated. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> signal <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> transmitted from the built-in transmitter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> travels along test path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, reflects off the activated switch points back to the test path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and finally ends at built-in detector <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. When the built-in detector <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> detects the signal <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, all the activated switch points are operating correctly, and switch point C<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in particular has been verified. When the built-in detector <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> cannot detect the signal <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, a fault must exist somewhere along the path. After methodically testing each waveguide and switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in this manner, the entire waveguide array <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can be verified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the same photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, with a fault <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> located at switch point A<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is used as a detour when a problem exists somewhere in the waveguide array <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. For instance, due to the location of fault <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, switch point A<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> cannot be activated, and a signal cannot be directly deflected from horizontal waveguide A to vertical waveguide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. However, by using switch points along redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, the fault <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> can be bypassed. When switch points A<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, D<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and D<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are activated, a signal <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> can still be routed from waveguide A to waveguide <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is a useful feature that provides robustness to the waveguide array <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> depicts a preferred embodiment for testing a photonic switch network <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, made in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. Stage <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a single photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A, stage <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a single photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>B, and each photonic switch is illustrated with only the relevant waveguides visible. Photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A has a redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>A intersected by a waveguide M, and a switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A located at their intersection. A transmitter <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>A and a detector <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>A are optically connected to the redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>A through a self-test loop <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>A. The transmitter <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>A and detector <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>A may be separate components, or combined into a single transceiver <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>A. Photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>B has a redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>B intersected by a waveguide N, and a switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> located at their intersection. The redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>B intersects itself at switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A transmitter <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>B and a detector <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>B are optically connected to the redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>B through a self-test loop <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>B. The transmitter <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>B and detector <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>B may be separate components, or combined into a single transceiver <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>B. An optical connection <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> connects the output of waveguide M to the input of waveguide N, and must be verified to ensure proper operation of the photonic switch network <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Before verifying optical connection <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, each photonic switch must first check for faults within itself. Each photonic switch runs an internal self-test using its built-in transmitter <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, built-in detector <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and test path <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Each photonic switch also verifies its own self-test loop <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> by transmitting a test signal from its transmitter <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. When the detector <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> detects the test signal, the self-test loop <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is working correctly. These first two steps constitute step <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, eliminating the individual photonic switches as possible sources of faults. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Finally, the interconnecting optical connection <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can be tested, as described in steps <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Referring back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> test signal <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is transmitted from the transmitter <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>A to redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>A. The test signal <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is routed from the redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>A to waveguide M by activating switch point <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A. The test signal <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is output from waveguide M to the optical connection <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. When the test signal <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> reaches photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>B, it continues on to waveguide N. By activating switch points <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the test signal <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is deflected onto the redundant path <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>B of photonic switch <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>B. It then travels through self-test loop <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>B, where it finally reaches the receiver. When the detector <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>B detects the test signal <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, no faults exist in optical connection <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. When the detector <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>B cannot detect the test signal <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, a fault must lie in the optical connection <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. By repeating this process for any optical connections that exist between any two photonic switches, the entire photonic switch network <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> can be verified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> While <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a photonic switch network <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> with only two stages, and only one photonic switch per stage, there are many other possible arrangements for interconnecting photonic switches. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> depicts a few alternative arrangements for a photonic switch network <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>&prime;. A few examples are listed in Table 1.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="112PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="105PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Alternative Arrangement</entry>
<entry>Example in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>More than one photonic switch per</entry>
<entry>Stage 2 has photonic switches 1D</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>stage</entry>
<entry>and 1E</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Stage N has photonic switches 1F</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>and 1G</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>A single photonic switch connected</entry>
<entry>Photonic switch 1C is connected to</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>to more than one photonic switch</entry>
<entry>photonic switches 1D and 1E</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>More than two stages in a photonic</entry>
<entry>Stage N represents the last stage of</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>switch network</entry>
<entry>any number of stages greater than</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>two</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>A photonic switch connected to other</entry>
<entry>Photonic switch 1F is connected to</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>photonic switches within the same</entry>
<entry>photonic switch 1G within Stage N</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>stage</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> There are many other methods, not illustrated due to space considerations, for interconnecting the photonic switches. One arrangement is a multi-stage Clos, a method for networking switches well known in the art. The photonic switches can be connected to other photonic switches that are not in adjacent stages. The photonic switches do not have to be grouped into stages, either. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for detecting faults in interconnecting optical fibers, for selected pairs of interconnected photonic switches in a photonic switch network, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>transmitting a first test signal through a redundant path of a first photonic switch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>routing the first test signal from the first photonic switch, through an interconnecting optical fiber, to a second photonic switch; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting the first test signal through a redundant path of the second photonic switch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>running a self-test on each photonic switch for internal faults, prior to the step of transmitting, wherein test paths within the photonic switches are conduits for a second test signal to eliminate the photonic switches as fault sources. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transmitting and detecting steps are performed by a transceiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first test signal is light, with a wavelength between 0.7 micrometer and 1 millimeter, inclusive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second test signal is light, with a wavelength between 0.7 micrometer and 1 millimeter, inclusive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for fault detection within a photonic switch network, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first stage and a second stage, the first stage having a first stage photonic switch, the second stage having a second stage photonic switch, each photonic switch having inputs, outputs, and a redundant path; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical fiber, connecting an output of the first stage photonic switch to an input of the second stage photonic switch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first stage photonic switch further including a signal source, optically connected to the redundant path of the first stage photonic switch; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second stage photonic switch further including a signal detector, optically connected to the redundant path of the second stage photonic switch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, the first stage photonic switch further including a signal detector optically connected to the redundant path of the first stage photonic switch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, the second stage photonic switch further including a signal source optically connected to the redundant path of the second stage photonic switch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the first stage consists of X photonic switches, X&gt;1; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second stage consists of Y photonic switches, Y&gt;1; </claim-text>
<claim-text>each photonic switch in each stage has inputs, outputs, a redundant path, a signal source optically connected to the redundant path, and a signal detector optically connected to the redundant path; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a photonic switch in the first stage is optically connected to more than one photonic switch in the second stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least two photonic switches in the first stage are optically connected to at least two photonic switches in the second stage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>there are a total of N stages, N&gE;2, each stage having at least one photonic switch; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>for each number I in the numeric series (1 through N&minus;1), one photonic switch in the (I)<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>stage is optically connected to one photonic switch in the (I&plus;1)<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the N stages are arranged in a Clos multistage network. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each photonic switch has its own test path, used in a self-test to eliminate the photonic switch as a source of faults. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the signal source and signal detector are found in a single transceiver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the signal source transmits light, and the signal detector detects light. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light has a wavelength between 0.7 micrometer and 1 millimeter, inclusive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for fault detection within a photonic switch network, comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of photonic switches, each photonic switch having inputs, outputs, a redundant path, a signal source optically connected to the redundant path, and a signal detector optically connected to the redundant path; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>optical fibers interconnecting inputs and outputs of the photonic switches. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the signal source transmits light, and the signal detector detects light. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the light has a wavelength between 0.7 micrometer and 1 millimeter, inclusive.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002775A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002775A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002775A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002775A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002775A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002775A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002775A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
